<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for javascript - JavaScript Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for javascript.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[zen-browser/desktop]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to a calmer internet]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop">zen-browser/desktop</a></h1>
            <p>Welcome to a calmer internet</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 38,903</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,239</p>
            <p>Stars today: 44 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!--
   - This Source Code Form is subject to the terms of the Mozilla Public
   - License, v. 2.0. If a copy of the MPL was not distributed with this
   - file, You can obtain one at http://mozilla.org/MPL/2.0/.
   --&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO: Get a job --&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/zen-dark.svg&quot; width=&quot;100px&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;

### `Zen Browser`

[![Downloads](https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/zen-browser/desktop/total.svg)](https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop/releases)
[![Crowdin](https://badges.crowdin.net/zen-browser/localized.svg)](https://crowdin.com/project/zen-browser)
[![Zen Release builds](https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?branch=stable)](https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop/actions/workflows/build.yml)

Zen is a firefox-based browser with the aim of pushing your productivity to a new level!

&lt;div flex=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zen-browser.app/download&quot;&gt;
    Download
  &lt;/a&gt;
  •
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zen-browser.app&quot;&gt;
    Website
  &lt;/a&gt;
  •
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.zen-browser.app&quot;&gt;
    Documentation
  &lt;/a&gt;
  •
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zen-browser.app/release-notes/latest&quot;&gt;
    Release Notes
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

### Firefox Versions

- [`Release`](https://zen-browser.app/download) - Is currently built using Firefox version `146.0.1`! 🚀
- [`Twilight`](https://zen-browser.app/download?twilight) - Is currently built using Firefox version `RC 146.0.1`!

### Contributing

If you&#039;d like to report a bug, please do so on our [GitHub Issues page](https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop/issues/) and for feature requests, you can use [Github Discussions](https://github.com/zen-browser/desktop/discussions).

Zen is an open-source project, and we welcome contributions from the community! Please take a look at the [contribution guidelines](./docs/contribute.md) before getting started!

#### Partners

Thanks to all the partners of Zen for their support and contributions:

&lt;a href=&quot;https://blacksmith.sh&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/blacksmith-yellow.png&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[codemirror/dev]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/codemirror/dev</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/codemirror/dev</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Development repository for the CodeMirror editor project]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/codemirror/dev">codemirror/dev</a></h1>
            <p>Development repository for the CodeMirror editor project</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,351</p>
            <p>Forks: 453</p>
            <p>Stars today: 4 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># CodeMirror

[![Build Status](https://github.com/codemirror/dev/workflows/main/badge.svg)](https://github.com/codemirror/codemirror.next/actions)

This is the central repository for [CodeMirror](https://codemirror.net/). It holds the bug tracker and development scripts.

If you want to **use** CodeMirror, install the separate packages from npm, and ignore the contents of this repository. If you want to **develop on** CodeMirror, this repository provides scripts to install and work with the various packages.

To get started, make sure you are running [node.js](https://nodejs.org/) version 16. After cloning the repository, run

    node bin/cm.js install

to clone the packages that make up the system, install dependencies, and build the packages. At any time you can rebuild packages, either by running `npm run prepare` in their subdirectory, or all at once with

    node bin/cm.js build

Developing is best done by setting up

    npm run dev

which starts a server that automatically rebuilds the packages when their code changes and exposes a dev server on port 8090 running the [demo](http://localhost:8090) and [browser tests](http://localhost:8090/test/).

Please see [the website](https://codemirror.net/) for more information and [docs](https://codemirror.net/docs/ref).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[betaflight/betaflight-configurator]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Cross platform configuration and management application for the Betaflight firmware]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator">betaflight/betaflight-configurator</a></h1>
            <p>Cross platform configuration and management application for the Betaflight firmware</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,019</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,017</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![Betaflight](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/.github/main/profile/images/bf_logo.svg#gh-light-mode-only)
![Betaflight](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/.github/main/profile/images/bf_logo_dark.svg#gh-dark-mode-only)

# Betaflight App

[![Latest version](https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/betaflight/betaflight-configurator)](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases)
[![Build](https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/deploy.yml?branch=master)](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/actions/workflows/deploy.yml)
[![Crowdin](https://d322cqt584bo4o.cloudfront.net/betaflight-configurator/localized.svg)](https://crowdin.com/project/betaflight-configurator)
[![Quality Gate Status](https://sonarcloud.io/api/project_badges/measure?project=betaflight_betaflight-configurator&amp;metric=alert_status)](https://sonarcloud.io/dashboard?id=betaflight_betaflight-configurator)
[![License: GPL v3](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-GPLv3-blue.svg)](https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0)
[![Join us on Discord!](https://img.shields.io/discord/868013470023548938)](https://discord.gg/n4E6ak4u3c)


Betaflight App is a crossplatform configuration and management application for the Betaflight flight control system.

The Betaflight App is a Progressive Web Application (PWA). The most recent release of the Betaflight App is available at [app.betaflight.com](https://app.betaflight.com)

NOTE: If you are considering testing the latest unstable release then it is at [master.app.betaflight.com](https://master.app.betaflight.com)

Various types of aircraft are supported by the tool and by Betaflight, e.g. quadcopters, hexacopters, octocopters and fixed-wing aircraft.

## Historical Releases

These are still available under different operating systems and allows you to configure the Betaflight software running on any supported Betaflight target. [Downloads are available in Releases.](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases)

## Installation

### Standalone

We provide a standalone program for Windows, Linux, Mac and Android.

Download the installer from [Releases.](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases)

### Notes

#### Windows users

The minimum required version of windows is Windows 8.

#### MacOS X users

Changes to the security model used in the latest versions of MacOS X 10.14 (Mojave) and 10.15 (Catalina) mean that the operating system will show an error message (&#039;&quot;Betaflight Configurator.app&quot; is damaged and can’t be opened. You should move it to the Trash.&#039;) when trying to install the application. To work around this, run the following command in a terminal after installing: `sudo xattr -rd com.apple.quarantine /Applications/Betaflight\ Configurator.app`.

#### Linux users

First step is to download the installer and keep it in your working directory, which can be done with the following command:
```
wget https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases/download/10.10.0/betaflight-configurator_10.10.0_amd64.deb
```

In most Linux distributions your user won&#039;t have access to serial interfaces by default. To add this access right type the following command in a terminal, log out your user and log in again:

```
sudo usermod -aG dialout ${USER}
```

Post-installation errors can be prevented by making sure the directory `/usr/share/desktop-directories` exists. To make sure it exists, run the following command before installing the package:

```
sudo mkdir /usr/share/desktop-directories/
```

The `libatomic` library must also be installed before installing Betaflight App. (If the library is missing, the installation will succeed but Betaflight App will not start.) Some Linux distributions (e.g. Fedora) will install it automatically. On Debian or Ubuntu you can install it as follows:

```
sudo apt install libatomic1
```

On Ubuntu 23.10 please follow these alternative steps for installation:

```
sudo echo &quot;deb http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/ lunar universe&quot; &gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/lunar-repos-old.list
sudo apt update
sudo dpkg -i betaflight-configurator_10.10.0_amd64.deb
sudo apt-get -f install
```

On Ubuntu 24.10 and above, please follow these steps, as some deprecated modules are no longer available through apt on this distro:
```
sudo apt update
wget http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/pool/universe/g/gconf/libgconf-2-4_3.2.6-4ubuntu1_amd64.deb
wget http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/pool/universe/g/gconf/gconf2-common_3.2.6-4ubuntu1_all.deb
sudo dpkg -i gconf2-common_3.2.6-4ubuntu1_all.deb
sudo dpkg -i libgconf-2-4_3.2.6-4ubuntu1_amd64.deb
sudo dpkg -i betaflight-configurator_10.10.0_amd64.deb
sudo apt-get -f install
```

#### Graphics Issues

If you experience graphics display problems or smudged/dithered fonts display issues in Betaflight App, try invoking the `betaflight-configurator` executable file with the `--disable-gpu` command line switch. This will switch off hardware graphics acceleration. Likewise, setting your graphics card antialiasing option to OFF (e.g. FXAA parameter on NVidia graphics cards) might be a remedy as well.

### Unstable Testing Versions

The future of the Betaflight App is moving to a PWA (Progressive Web Application). In this way it will be easier to maintain specially to support different devices like phones, tablets. etc. Is a work in progress but you can have access to the latest snapshot in PWA way without installing anything (take into account that some things don&#039;t work and are in development).

- Latest PWA master snapshot of the App: [https://master.app.betaflight.com/](https://master.app.betaflight.com/)

**Be aware that this version is intended for testing / feedback only, and may be buggy or broken, and can cause flight controller settings to be corrupted. Caution is advised when using this version.**

## Languages

**Please do not submit pull requests for translation changes, but read and follow the instructions below!**

Betaflight App has been translated into several languages. The application will try to detect and use your system language if a translation into this language is available. You can help [translating the application into your language](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/tree/master/README.md#translators);

If you prefer to have the application in English or any other language, you can select your desired language in the first screen of the application.

## Build and Development

### Technical details

The next versions of the App will be a modern tool that based on PWA (Progressive Web Application) and uses principally Node, Yarn, Vite and Vue for development and building. For Android we use Capacitor as wrapper over the PWA. To build and develop over it, follow the instructions below.

### Prepare your environment

1. Install [node.js](https://nodejs.org/) (refer to [.nvmrc](./.nvmrc) for minimum required version)
2. Install yarn: `npm install yarn -g`

### PWA version

#### Run development version

1. Change to project folder and run `yarn install`.
2. Run `yarn dev`.

The web app will be available at http://localhost:8000 with full HMR.

#### Run production version

1. Change to project folder and run `yarn install`.
2. Run `yarn build`.
3. Run `yarn preview` after build has finished.

Alternatively you can run `yarn review` to build and preview in one step.

The web app should behave directly as in production, available at http://localhost:8080.

### Android version

NOTE: The Android version is not fully functional yet. It is in development.

#### Prerequisites

You need to install [Android Studio](https://developer.android.com/studio) as Capacitor apps are configured and managed through it.

#### Run development version

1. Change to project folder and run `yarn install`.
2. Run `yarn android:run`.

The command will ask for the device to run the app. You need to have some Android virtual machine created or some Android phone [connected using ADB](https://developer.android.com/tools/adb).

As alternative to the step 2, you can execute a `yarn android:open` to open de project into Android Studio and run or debug the app from there.

#### Run development version with live reload

1. Change to project folder and run `yarn install`.
2. Run `yarn dev --host`. It will start the vite server and will show you the IP address where the server is listening.
3. Run `yarn android:dev` 

This will ask for the IP where the server is running (if there are more than one network interfaces). You need to have some Android virtual machine created or some Android phone [connected using ADB](https://developer.android.com/tools/adb).
Any change make in the code will reload the app in the Android device.

### Running tests

`yarn test`

## Support and Developers Channel

There&#039;s a dedicated Discord server here:

https://discord.gg/n4E6ak4u3c

We also have a Facebook Group. Join us to get a place to talk about Betaflight, ask configuration questions, or just hang out with fellow pilots.

https://www.facebook.com/groups/betaflightgroup/

Etiquette: Don&#039;t ask to ask and please wait around long enough for a reply - sometimes people are out flying, asleep or at work and can&#039;t answer immediately.

### Issue trackers

For Betaflight App issues raise them here

https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/issues

For Betaflight Firmware issues raise them here

https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/issues

## Developers

We accept clean and reasonable patches, submit them!

## Credits

For the full details of the contributions made to the Betaflight App (and its predecessors) please check out the [Github contributors page](https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/graphs/contributors).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[parcoil/sparkle]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/parcoil/sparkle</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/parcoil/sparkle</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Windows app to debloat and optimize your PC]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/parcoil/sparkle">parcoil/sparkle</a></h1>
            <p>A Windows app to debloat and optimize your PC</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 559</p>
            <p>Forks: 31</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;

&lt;body&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;SPARKLE IS BEING REMADE &lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;icon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Sparkle Logo&quot; width=&quot;100&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Sparkle - ✨ The Finest Windows Optimizer ✨&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkle&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful and user-friendly Windows optimizer designed to enhance your computer&#039;s performance and keep it running smoothly. Say goodbye to sluggishness and hello to a faster, more efficient Windows experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✨ &lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Sparkle covers all aspects of Windows optimization, from cleaning up junk files to optimizing system settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🧹 &lt;strong&gt;Junk File Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;: Remove temporary files, cache, and other unnecessary data that clogs up your storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🚀 &lt;strong&gt;System Speedup&lt;/strong&gt;: Boost your PC&#039;s speed by optimizing startup programs and system resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🛠️ &lt;strong&gt;Registry Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;: Fix registry errors to improve system stability and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🌐 &lt;strong&gt;Internet Speed Booster&lt;/strong&gt;: Optimize your internet connection for faster browsing and downloads. (Coming Soon!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🔄 &lt;strong&gt;Automatic Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Stay up-to-date with the latest performance improvements and bug fixes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the latest Sparkle installer from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://parcoil.com/sparkle&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the installer and follow the on-screen instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch Sparkle after installation and let it scan your system for optimization opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch Sparkle and click the &quot;Scan Now&quot; button to analyze your system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review the scan results and select the optimization options you want to apply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click &quot;Optimize Now&quot; to start the optimization process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sparkle will automatically apply the selected optimizations and provide a summary of the improvements made.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Support and Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues, have questions, or want to provide feedback, please reach out to our support team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://parcoil.com/sparkle&quot;&gt;https://parcoil.com/sparkle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@parcoil.com&quot;&gt;info@parcoil.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We value your input and are committed to making Sparkle the best Windows optimizer on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The license is here &lt;a href=&quot;LICENSE&quot;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for choosing Sparkle to keep your Windows PC running smoothly and efficiently. We hope you enjoy the optimized experience! ✨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[anuraghazra/github-readme-stats]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/anuraghazra/github-readme-stats</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/anuraghazra/github-readme-stats</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[⚡ Dynamically generated stats for your github readmes]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/anuraghazra/github-readme-stats">anuraghazra/github-readme-stats</a></h1>
            <p>⚡ Dynamically generated stats for your github readmes</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 77,639</p>
            <p>Forks: 28,501</p>
            <p>Stars today: 26 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[huggingface/transformers.js]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[State-of-the-art Machine Learning for the web. Run 🤗 Transformers directly in your browser, with no need for a server!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js">huggingface/transformers.js</a></h1>
            <p>State-of-the-art Machine Learning for the web. Run 🤗 Transformers directly in your browser, with no need for a server!</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,131</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,058</p>
            <p>Stars today: 5 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt; 
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://huggingface.co/datasets/Xenova/transformers.js-docs/resolve/main/transformersjs-dark.svg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://huggingface.co/datasets/Xenova/transformers.js-docs/resolve/main/transformersjs-light.svg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;transformers.js javascript library logo&quot; src=&quot;https://huggingface.co/datasets/Xenova/transformers.js-docs/resolve/main/transformersjs-light.svg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;NPM&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;NPM Downloads&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dw/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jsdelivr.com/package/npm/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;jsDelivr Hits&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/jsdelivr/npm/hw/@huggingface/transformers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;License&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/huggingface/transformers.js?color=blue&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/index&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Documentation&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/website/http/huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/index.svg?down_color=red&amp;down_message=offline&amp;up_message=online&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;State-of-the-art Machine Learning for the Web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;

Run 🤗 Transformers directly in your browser, with no need for a server!

Transformers.js is designed to be functionally equivalent to Hugging Face&#039;s [transformers](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers) python library, meaning you can run the same pretrained models using a very similar API. These models support common tasks in different modalities, such as:
  - 📝 **Natural Language Processing**: text classification, named entity recognition, question answering, language modeling, summarization, translation, multiple choice, and text generation.
  - 🖼️ **Computer Vision**: image classification, object detection, segmentation, and depth estimation.
  - 🗣️ **Audio**: automatic speech recognition, audio classification, and text-to-speech.
  - 🐙 **Multimodal**: embeddings, zero-shot audio classification, zero-shot image classification, and zero-shot object detection.

Transformers.js uses [ONNX Runtime](https://onnxruntime.ai/) to run models in the browser. The best part about it, is that you can easily [convert](#convert-your-models-to-onnx) your pretrained PyTorch, TensorFlow, or JAX models to ONNX using [🤗 Optimum](https://github.com/huggingface/optimum#onnx--onnx-runtime). 

For more information, check out the full [documentation](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js).


## Installation


To install via [NPM](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@huggingface/transformers), run:
```bash
npm i @huggingface/transformers
```

Alternatively, you can use it in vanilla JS, without any bundler, by using a CDN or static hosting. For example, using [ES Modules](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Modules), you can import the library with:
```html
&lt;script type=&quot;module&quot;&gt;
    import { pipeline } from &#039;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@huggingface/transformers@3.8.1&#039;;
&lt;/script&gt;
```


## Quick tour


It&#039;s super simple to translate from existing code! Just like the python library, we support the `pipeline` API. Pipelines group together a pretrained model with preprocessing of inputs and postprocessing of outputs, making it the easiest way to run models with the library.

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th width=&quot;440px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Python (original)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&quot;440px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Javascript (ours)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

```python
from transformers import pipeline

# Allocate a pipeline for sentiment-analysis
pipe = pipeline(&#039;sentiment-analysis&#039;)

out = pipe(&#039;I love transformers!&#039;)
# [{&#039;label&#039;: &#039;POSITIVE&#039;, &#039;score&#039;: 0.999806941}]
```

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

```javascript
import { pipeline } from &#039;@huggingface/transformers&#039;;

// Allocate a pipeline for sentiment-analysis
const pipe = await pipeline(&#039;sentiment-analysis&#039;);

const out = await pipe(&#039;I love transformers!&#039;);
// [{&#039;label&#039;: &#039;POSITIVE&#039;, &#039;score&#039;: 0.999817686}]
```

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


You can also use a different model by specifying the model id or path as the second argument to the `pipeline` function. For example:
```javascript
// Use a different model for sentiment-analysis
const pipe = await pipeline(&#039;sentiment-analysis&#039;, &#039;Xenova/bert-base-multilingual-uncased-sentiment&#039;);
```

By default, when running in the browser, the model will be run on your CPU (via WASM). If you would like
to run the model on your GPU (via WebGPU), you can do this by setting `device: &#039;webgpu&#039;`, for example:
```javascript
// Run the model on WebGPU
const pipe = await pipeline(&#039;sentiment-analysis&#039;, &#039;Xenova/distilbert-base-uncased-finetuned-sst-2-english&#039;, {
  device: &#039;webgpu&#039;,
});
```

For more information, check out the [WebGPU guide](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/guides/webgpu).

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; The WebGPU API is still experimental in many browsers, so if you run into any issues,
&gt; please file a [bug report](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/issues/new?title=%5BWebGPU%5D%20Error%20running%20MODEL_ID_GOES_HERE&amp;assignees=&amp;labels=bug,webgpu&amp;projects=&amp;template=1_bug-report.yml).

In resource-constrained environments, such as web browsers, it is advisable to use a quantized version of
the model to lower bandwidth and optimize performance. This can be achieved by adjusting the `dtype` option,
which allows you to select the appropriate data type for your model. While the available options may vary
depending on the specific model, typical choices include `&quot;fp32&quot;` (default for WebGPU), `&quot;fp16&quot;`, `&quot;q8&quot;`
(default for WASM), and `&quot;q4&quot;`. For more information, check out the [quantization guide](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/guides/dtypes).
```javascript
// Run the model at 4-bit quantization
const pipe = await pipeline(&#039;sentiment-analysis&#039;, &#039;Xenova/distilbert-base-uncased-finetuned-sst-2-english&#039;, {
  dtype: &#039;q4&#039;,
});
```


## Examples

Want to jump straight in? Get started with one of our sample applications/templates, which can be found [here](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js-examples).

| Name              | Description                      | Links                   |
|-------------------|----------------------------------|-------------------------------|
| Whisper Web       | Speech recognition w/ Whisper    | [code](https://github.com/xenova/whisper-web), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/whisper-web) |
| Doodle Dash       | Real-time sketch-recognition game | [blog](https://huggingface.co/blog/ml-web-games), [code](https://github.com/xenova/doodle-dash), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/doodle-dash) |
| Code Playground   | In-browser code completion website | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/code-completion/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/ai-code-playground) |
| Semantic Image Search (client-side) | Search for images with text | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/semantic-image-search-client/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/semantic-image-search-client) |
| Semantic Image Search (server-side) | Search for images with text (Supabase) | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/semantic-image-search/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/semantic-image-search) |
| Vanilla JavaScript | In-browser object detection     | [video](https://scrimba.com/scrim/cKm9bDAg), [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/vanilla-js/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Scrimba/vanilla-js-object-detector) |
| React             | Multilingual translation website | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/react-translator/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/react-translator) |
| Text to speech (client-side) | In-browser speech synthesis | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/text-to-speech-client/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/text-to-speech-client) |
| Browser extension | Text classification extension    | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/extension/) |
| Electron          | Text classification application  | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/electron/)  |
| Next.js (client-side) | Sentiment analysis (in-browser inference) | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/next-client/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/next-example-app) |
| Next.js (server-side) | Sentiment analysis (Node.js inference) | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/next-server/), [demo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/Xenova/next-server-example-app) |
| Node.js           | Sentiment analysis API           | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/node/)      |
| Demo site         | A collection of demos | [code](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/tree/main/examples/demo-site/), [demo](https://huggingface.github.io/transformers.js/) |

Check out the Transformers.js [template](https://huggingface.co/new-space?template=static-templates%2Ftransformers.js) on Hugging Face to get started in one click!


## Custom usage



By default, Transformers.js uses [hosted pretrained models](https://huggingface.co/models?library=transformers.js) and [precompiled WASM binaries](https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@huggingface/transformers@3.8.1/dist/), which should work out-of-the-box. You can customize this as follows:

### Settings

```javascript
import { env } from &#039;@huggingface/transformers&#039;;

// Specify a custom location for models (defaults to &#039;/models/&#039;).
env.localModelPath = &#039;/path/to/models/&#039;;

// Disable the loading of remote models from the Hugging Face Hub:
env.allowRemoteModels = false;

// Set location of .wasm files. Defaults to use a CDN.
env.backends.onnx.wasm.wasmPaths = &#039;/path/to/files/&#039;;
```

For a full list of available settings, check out the [API Reference](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/env).

### Convert your models to ONNX

We recommend using our [conversion script](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/blob/main/scripts/convert.py) to convert your PyTorch, TensorFlow, or JAX models to ONNX in a single command. Behind the scenes, it uses [🤗 Optimum](https://huggingface.co/docs/optimum) to perform conversion and quantization of your model.

```bash
python -m scripts.convert --quantize --model_id &lt;model_name_or_path&gt;
```

For example, convert and quantize [bert-base-uncased](https://huggingface.co/bert-base-uncased) using:
```bash
python -m scripts.convert --quantize --model_id bert-base-uncased
```

This will save the following files to `./models/`:

```
bert-base-uncased/
├── config.json
├── tokenizer.json
├── tokenizer_config.json
└── onnx/
    ├── model.onnx
    └── model_quantized.onnx
```

For the full list of supported architectures, see the [Optimum documentation](https://huggingface.co/docs/optimum/main/en/exporters/onnx/overview).


## Supported tasks/models

Here is the list of all tasks and architectures currently supported by Transformers.js.
If you don&#039;t see your task/model listed here or it is not yet supported, feel free
to open up a feature request [here](https://github.com/huggingface/transformers.js/issues/new/choose).

To find compatible models on the Hub, select the &quot;transformers.js&quot; library tag in the filter menu (or visit [this link](https://huggingface.co/models?library=transformers.js)).
You can refine your search by selecting the task you&#039;re interested in (e.g., [text-classification](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=text-classification&amp;library=transformers.js)).


### Tasks

#### Natural Language Processing

| Task                     | ID | Description | Supported? |
|--------------------------|----|-------------|------------|
| [Fill-Mask](https://huggingface.co/tasks/fill-mask)                     | `fill-mask`   | Masking some of the words in a sentence and predicting which words should replace those masks. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.FillMaskPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=fill-mask&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Question Answering](https://huggingface.co/tasks/question-answering)   | `question-answering`   | Retrieve the answer to a question from a given text. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.QuestionAnsweringPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=question-answering&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Sentence Similarity](https://huggingface.co/tasks/sentence-similarity) | `sentence-similarity`  | Determining how similar two texts are. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.FeatureExtractionPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=sentence-similarity&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Summarization](https://huggingface.co/tasks/summarization)             |  `summarization`  | Producing a shorter version of a document while preserving its important information. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.SummarizationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=summarization&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Table Question Answering](https://huggingface.co/tasks/table-question-answering) |  `table-question-answering`  | Answering a question about information from a given table. | ❌ |
| [Text Classification](https://huggingface.co/tasks/text-classification)      | `text-classification` or `sentiment-analysis`  | Assigning a label or class to a given text. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.TextClassificationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=text-classification&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Text Generation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/text-generation#completion-generation-models)          | `text-generation`  | Producing new text by predicting the next word in a sequence. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.TextGenerationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=text-generation&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Text-to-text Generation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/text-generation#text-to-text-generation-models)  | `text2text-generation`  | Converting one text sequence into another text sequence. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.Text2TextGenerationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=text2text-generation&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Token Classification](https://huggingface.co/tasks/token-classification)     | `token-classification` or `ner`  | Assigning a label to each token in a text. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.TokenClassificationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=token-classification&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Translation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/translation)              |  `translation`  | Converting text from one language to another. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.TranslationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=translation&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Zero-Shot Classification](https://huggingface.co/tasks/zero-shot-classification) | `zero-shot-classification`  | Classifying text into classes that are unseen during training.  | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.ZeroShotClassificationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=zero-shot-classification&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Feature Extraction](https://huggingface.co/tasks/feature-extraction)         |  `feature-extraction`  | Transforming raw data into numerical features that can be processed while preserving the information in the original dataset. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.FeatureExtractionPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=feature-extraction&amp;library=transformers.js) |

#### Vision

| Task                     | ID | Description | Supported? |
|--------------------------|----|-------------|------------|
| [Background Removal](https://huggingface.co/tasks/image-segmentation#background-removal)       | `background-removal`   | Isolating the main subject of an image by removing or making the background transparent. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.BackgroundRemovalPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?other=background-removal&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Depth Estimation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/depth-estimation)         |  `depth-estimation`  | Predicting the depth of objects present in an image. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.DepthEstimationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=depth-estimation&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Image Classification](https://huggingface.co/tasks/image-classification)                | `image-classification`   | Assigning a label or class to an entire image. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.ImageClassificationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=image-classification&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Image Segmentation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/image-segmentation)       | `image-segmentation`   | Divides an image into segments where each pixel is mapped to an object. This task has multiple variants such as instance segmentation, panoptic segmentation and semantic segmentation. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.ImageSegmentationPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=image-segmentation&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Image-to-Image](https://huggingface.co/tasks/image-to-image)      |  `image-to-image` | Transforming a source image to match the characteristics of a target image or a target image domain. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.ImageToImagePipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=image-to-image&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Mask Generation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/mask-generation)            |  `mask-generation`  | Generate masks for the objects in an image. | ❌ |
| [Object Detection](https://huggingface.co/tasks/object-detection)            | `object-detection`   | Identify objects of certain defined classes within an image. | ✅ [(docs)](https://huggingface.co/docs/transformers.js/api/pipelines#module_pipelines.ObjectDetectionPipeline)&lt;br&gt;[(models)](https://huggingface.co/models?pipeline_tag=object-detection&amp;library=transformers.js) |
| [Video Classification](https://huggingface.co/tasks/video-classification) |  n/a  | Assigning a label or class to an entire video. | ❌ |
| [Unconditional Image Generation](https://huggingface.co/tasks/unconditional-image-generation)      |  n/a   | Generating images with no condition in any context (like a prompt text or another image). | ❌ |
| [

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[sugarlabs/musicblocks]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Music Blocks -- A musical microworld]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks">sugarlabs/musicblocks</a></h1>
            <p>Music Blocks -- A musical microworld</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 751</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,286</p>
            <p>Stars today: 1 star today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com//sugarlabs/musicblocks/graphs/contributors&quot; alt=&quot;Contributors&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/sugarlabs/musicblocks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;#license&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/sugarlabs/musicblocks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

# Music Blocks

“_All musicians are subconsciously mathematicians._” — Monk

“_Music is a hidden arithmetic exercise of the soul, which does not
know that it is counting._” — Leibniz

Music Blocks is a _Visual Programming Language_ and collection of
_manipulative tools_ for exploring musical and mathematical concepts
in an integrative and entertaining way.

## Getting Started

Music Blocks is an interactive Web Application &amp;mdash; the interaction
is done via basic mouse events like _click_, _right click_, _click and
drag_, etc. and keyboard events like _hotkey press_.  The application
is audio-visual; it produces graphics, artwork and music. Here are a
couple of screenshots to give you an idea of how the application looks
like:

![alt tag](./screenshots/Screenshot-1.png)

![alt tag](./screenshots/Screenshot-2.png)

Visit the Music Blocks website for a hands on experience:
[https://musicblocks.sugarlabs.org](https://musicblocks.sugarlabs.org).

Or download Music Blocks from the [Google Play Store](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=my.musicblock.sugarlab)

Additional background on why we combine music and programming can be found
[here](./WhyMusicBlocks.md).

**Refer to the following sections to get familiar with this application:**

- [Running Music Blocks](#RUNNING-MUSIC-BLOCKS)
- [How to set up a local server](#HOW-TO-SET-UP-A-LOCAL-SERVER)
- [Using Music Blocks](#USING-MUSIC-BLOCKS)

If you are a developer (beginner, experienced, or pro), you are very
welcome to participate in the evolution of Music Blocks.

**Refer to the following sections to get an idea:**

- [Code of Conduct](#CODE-OF-CONDUCT)
- [Contributing](#CONTRIBUTING)
- [Modifying Music Blocks](#MODIFYING-MUSIC-BLOCKS)
- [Reporting Bugs](#REPORTING-BUGS)

**Refer to the following for more information regarding the evolution
  of this project:**

- [Credits](#CREDITS)
- [Music Blocks in Japan](#MUSIC-BLOCKS-IN-JAPAN)

## &lt;a name=&quot;RUNNING_MUSIC_BLOCKS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Running Music Blocks

Music Blocks is available under the _GNU Affero General Public License
(AGPL) v3.0_, a free, copyleft license.

Music Blocks is designed to run on a web browser. The ideal way to run
Music Blocks is to visit the URL
[_musicblocks.sugarlabs.org_](https://musicblocks.sugarlabs.org) in
your browser — _Google Chrome_ (or _Chromium_), _Microsoft Edge_
(_Chromium-based_), _Mozilla Firefox_, and _Opera_ work best.

To run from the most recent master branch (experimental), visit
[_sugarlabs.github.io/musicblocks_](https://sugarlabs.github.io/musicblocks).

## &lt;a name=&quot;HOW_TO_SET_UP_A_LOCAL_SERVER&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How to set up a _local server_

Music Blocks is written using native browser technologies. The bulk of
the functionality is in vanilla _JavaScript_. Therefore, most of
the functionality can be accessed by launching the
[index.html](./index.html) file in the browser using
`file:///absolute/path/to/index.html`.

However, doing so, some functionality will be unavailable. Therefore, it is
best to launch a _local web server_ from the directory of Music
Blocks.

1. [Download](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/archive/master.zip)
Music Blocks, or clone (`https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks.git`
for _HTTPS_, or `gh repo clone sugarlabs/musicblocks` for _GitHub
CLI_), on your local machine.

2. In a terminal, `cd` to the directory where you downloaded/cloned
Music Blocks, using `cd path/to/musicblocks/`.

3. After you are in `path/to/musicblocks/` directory, install the dependencies using the following command

    ```bash
    npm install
    ```

4. After cloning the musicblocks repository, you can start a local server using npm

    ```bash
    npm run dev
    ```

6. You should see a message `Serving HTTP on 127.0.0.1 port 3000
(http://127.0.0.1:3000/) ...` since the HTTP Server is set to start
listening on port 3000.

7. Open your favorite browser and visit `localhost:3000` or `127.0.0.1:3000`.

**NOTE:** _Use `ctrl + c` or `cmd + c` to quit the HTTP Server to avoid
`socket.error:[Errno 48]`_.



## Local Setup with Docker

## Prerequisites

Before you begin, ensure you have Docker installed on your machine. You can download and install Docker from the [official Docker website](https://www.docker.com/get-started).

## Installation

1. Clone the Music Blocks repository to your local machine:

   ```bash
   git clone https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks.git
   ```

2. Navigate to the cloned repository:

   ```bash
   cd musicblocks
   ```

3. Build the Docker image using the provided Dockerfile:

   ```bash
   docker build -t musicblocks .
   ```
## Running Music Blocks

1. Run the Docker container using the built image:

   ```bash
   docker run -p 3000:3000 musicblocks
   ```

   This command will start a Docker container running Music Blocks and expose it on port 3000.

2. Access Music Blocks in your web browser by navigating to `http://localhost:3000`.

## Stopping the Docker container

To stop the Docker container, use `Ctrl + C` in your terminal. This will stop the container and free up the port it was using.

## Additional Notes

- Make sure to replace `musicblocks` with the appropriate image name if you have tagged the Docker image differently.
- You can customize the port mapping (`-p`) if you prefer to use a different port for accessing Music Blocks.

---

This documentation provides a basic setup for running Music Blocks locally using Docker. Feel free to customize it further based on your specific requirements and environment.
## &lt;a name=&quot;USING_MUSIC_BLOCKS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Using Music Blocks

Once Music Blocks is running, you&#039;ll want suggestions on how to use
it. Follow [Using Music Blocks](./Docs/documentation/README.md) and [Music
Blocks Guide](./Docs/guide/README.md).

For Scratch and Snap users, you may want to look at [Music Blocks for
Snap Users](./Music_Blocks_for_Snap_Users.md).

Looking for a block? Find it in the
[Palette Tables](./Docs/guide/README.md#6-appendix).

## &lt;a name=&quot;CODEOFCONDUCT&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Code of Conduct

The Music Blocks project adheres to the [Sugar Labs Code of
Conduct](https://github.com/sugarlabs/sugar-docs/blob/master/src/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md)

## &lt;a name=&quot;CONTRIBUTING&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Contributing

Please consider contributing to the project, with your ideas, your
music, your lesson plans, your artwork, and your code.

### Special Notes

Music Blocks is being built from the ground-up, to address several
architectural problems with this run. Since Music Blocks is a fork of
Turtle Blocks JS, musical functionality was added on top of it.
However, music is fundamental to Music Blocks. Besides, the Turtle
Blocks JS started initially with handful of features and was written
without a complex architecture. As Music Blocks was built on top of
that, it became incrementally complex, but the architecture remained
simple, thus resulting in a monolith. Also, the functionality is
tightly coupled with the interface and native client API (Web API).

Keeping these problems in mind, we have considered a foundational
rebuild that will address all these issues, whilst adding buffers for
future additions. Additionally, we will make use of a more elegant tech-stack to
develop and maintain this project given its scale. After the core is
built, we&#039;ll be porting features from this application to it.

Refer to the repository
[**sugarlabs/musicblocks-v4**](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks-v4)
for more information about the new project &amp;mdash; _Music Blocks 4.0_.

### Tech Stack

Music Blocks is a Web Application and is written using browser
technologies &amp;mdash; `HTML`, `CSS` (`SCSS`), `JavaScript`, `SVG`, etc.

If you&#039;re just getting started with development, you may refer to the
following resources:

- [HTML tutorial - w3schools.com](https://www.w3schools.com/html/default.asp)
- [HTML reference - MDN Web Docs](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML)
- [CSS tutorial - w3schools.com](https://www.w3schools.com/css/default.asp)
- [CSS reference - MDN Web Docs](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS)
- [JavaScript tutorial - w3schools.com](https://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp)
- [JavaScript reference - MDN Web Docs](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript)

Programmers, please follow these general [guidelines for
contributions](https://github.com/sugarlabs/sugar-docs/blob/master/src/contributing.md).

### License Header

Music Blocks is licensed under the [AGPL](https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.en.html).
If you add a new file to the Music Blocks code base, please be
sure to include a license header as per below:

```js
/**
 * MusicBlocks v3.6.2 (ADD THE UP-TO-DATE VERSION)
 *
 * @author Walter Bender (MODIFY THE AUTHOR AS NEEDED)
 *
 * @copyright 2025 Walter Bender (MODIFY THE AUTHOR AND YEAR AS NEEDED)
 *
 * @license
 * This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
 * it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published by
 * the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
 * (at your option) any later version.
 *
 * This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
 * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
 * MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the
 * GNU Affero General Public License for more details.
 *
 * You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
 * along with this program. If not, see &lt;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.
 */
```

This header must be added at the top of **all source code files** to ensure compliance
with the project&#039;s open-source license.

### Translators

Music Blocks uses
[PO files](https://www.gnu.org/software/gettext/manual/html_node/PO-Files.html)
to maintain translations of the text strings used in the
interface. The PO files are available through an
[interactive website](https://weblate.sugarlabs.org/projects/music-blocks/music-blocks/).

Alternatively, translators can clone the
[git repo](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks.git), edit the PO files
locally, and make a pull request.

Note that once the PO files are updated, they are compiled into an INI
file, which is the file used by Music Blocks.

### New Contributors

Use the
[discussions](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/discussions)
tab at the top of the repository to:

- Ask questions you’re wondering about.
- Share ideas.
- Engage with other community members.

Feel free. But, please don&#039;t spam :p.

### Keep in Mind

1. Your contributions need not necessarily have to address any
discovered issue. If you encounter any, feel free to add a fix through
a PR, or create a new issue ticket.

2. Use [labels](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/labels) on
your issues and PRs.

3. Please do not spam with many PRs consisting of little changes.

4. If you are addressing a bulk change, divide your commits across
multiple PRs, and send them one at a time. The fewer the number of
files addressed per PR, the better.

5. Communicate effectively. Go straight to the point. You don&#039;t need
to address anyone using &#039;_sir_&#039;. Don&#039;t write unnecessary comments;
don&#039;t be over-apologetic. There is no superiority hierarchy. Every
single contribution is welcome, as long as it doesn&#039;t spam or distract
the flow.

6. Write useful, brief commit messages. Add commit descriptions if
necessary. PR name should speak about what it is addressing and not
the issue. In case a PR fixes an issue, use `fixes #ticketno` or
`closes #ticketno` in the PR&#039;s comment. Briefly explain what your PR
is doing.

7. Always test your changes extensively before creating a PR. There&#039;s
no sense in merging broken code. If a PR is a _work in progress
(WIP)_, convert it to draft. It&#039;ll let the maintainers know it isn&#039;t
ready for merging.

8. Read and revise the concepts about programming constructs you&#039;re
dealing with. You must be clear about the behavior of the language or
compiler/transpiler. See [JavaScript
docs](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript).

9. If you have a question, do a _web search_ first. If you don&#039;t find
any satisfactory answer, then ask it in a comment. If it is a general
question about Music Blocks, please use the new
[discussions](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/discussions)
tab on top the the repository, or the _Sugar-dev Devel
&lt;[sugar-devel@lists.sugarlabs.org](mailto:sugar-devel@lists.sugarlabs.org)&gt;_
mailing list. Don&#039;t ask silly questions (unless you don&#039;t know it is
silly ;p) before searching it on the web.

10. Work on things that matter. Follow three milestones: `Port Ready`,
`Migration`, and `Future`.  Those tagged `Port Ready` are
priority. Those tagged with `Migration` will be taken care of during
or after the foundation rebuild. Feel free to participate in the
conversation, adding valuable comments. Those tagged with `Future`
need not be addressed presently.

_Please note there is no need to ask permission to work on an
issue. You should check for pull requests linked to an issue you are
addressing; if there are none, then assume nobody has done
anything. Begin to fix the problem, test, make your commits, push your
commits, then make a pull request. Mention an issue number in the pull
request, but not the commit message. These practices allow the
competition of ideas (Sugar Labs is a meritocracy)._

## &lt;a name=&quot;MODIFYING_MUSIC_BLOCKS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Modifying Music Blocks

The core functionality for Music Blocks resides in the [`js/`
directory](./js/). Individual modules are described in more detail in
[js/README.md](./js/README.md).

**NOTE:** As for any changes, please make a local copy by cloning this
[repository](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks.git). Make your
changes, test them, and only then make a pull request.

[Contributing
Code](https://github.com/sugarlabs/sugar-docs/blob/master/src/contributing.md)
provides a general overview of Sugar Lab&#039;s guidelines. See
[Contributing](#CONTRIBUTING) section for specific details about this
repository.

## &lt;a name=&quot;REPORTING_BUGS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Reporting Bugs

Bugs can be reported in the [issues
tab](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/issues) of this
repository.

If possible, please include the browser _console log output_, and
_steps to reproduce_, when reporting bugs. To access the console, type
`Ctrl-Shift-J`/`F12` on most browsers. Alternately, _right click_ and
select `Inspect`. You may need to set the `Default levels` for the
console to `Verbose` in order to see all of the output, however, in
most cases that won&#039;t be required. In fact, it&#039;ll only clutter the
list, so select it only when required.

## &lt;a name=&quot;CREDITS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Credits

Music Blocks is a fork of [Turtle Blocks
JS](https://github.com/sugarlabs/turtleblocksjs) created by _Walter
Bender ([@walterbender](https://github.com/walterbender))_.

[_Devin Ulibarri_](http://www.devinulibarri.com/) has contributed
functional and user-interface designs. Many of his contributions were
inspired by the music education ideas, representations and practices
(e.g. aspects of matrix, musical cups) developed and published by
[_Larry
Scripp_](https://web.archive.org/web/20160204212801/http://www.larryscripp.net/)
with whom _Devin_ studied at New England Conservatory and for whom he
worked at Affron Scripp &amp; Associates, LLC, [Center for Music and the
Arts in Education
(CMAIE)](https://web.archive.org/web/20210713204847/http://centerformie.org/),
and [Music in
Education](https://web.archive.org/web/20231130103746/http://music-in-education.org/). Some
of the initial graphics were contributed by [_Chie
Yasuda_](https://www.chieyasuda.com).

Much of the initial coding specific to Music Blocks was done by _Yash
Khandelwal ([@khandelwalYash](https://github.com/khandelwalYash))_ as
part of Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2015. _Hemant Kasat
([@hemantkasat](https://github.com/hemantkasat))_ contributed to
additional widgets as part of GSoC 2016. Additional contributions were
made by _Tayba Wasim ([@Tabs16](https://github.com/Tabs16))_, _Dinuka
Tharangi Jayaweera ([@Tharangi](https://github.com/Tharangi))_,
_Prachi Agrawal
([@prachiagrawal269](https://github.com/prachiagrawal269))_, _Cristina
Del Puerto ([@cristinadp](https://github.com/cristinadp))_, and
_Hrishi Patel ([@Hrishi1999](https://github.com/Hrishi1999))_ as part
of GSoC 2017. During GSoC 2018, _Riya Lohia
([@riyalohia](https://github.com/riyalohia))_ developed a Temperament
widget.  _Ritwik Abhishek ([@a-ritwik](https://github.com/a-ritwik))_
added a keyboard widget and a pitch-tracking widget. During GSoC 2019,
_Favor Kelvin ([@fakela](https://github.com/fakela))_ refactored much
of the code to use promises. During GSoC 2020, _Anindya Kundu
([@meganindya](https://github.com/meganindya))_ did a major
refactoring of the code base to support JavaScript export. _Aviral
Gangwar ([@aviral243](https://github.com/aviral243))_ enhanced the
internal representation of mode and key.  _Saksham Mrig
([@sksum](https://github.com/sksum))_ fixed 70+ bugs and added support
for pitch tracking and MIDI import.

Many students contributed to the project as part of Google Code-in
(2015&amp;ndash;2019).  _Sam Parkinson
([@samdroid-apps](https://github.com/samdroid-apps))_ built the Planet
during GCI.  _Emily Ong ([@EmilyOng](https://github.com/EmilyOng))_
designed our mouse icon and _Euan Ong
([@eohomegrownapps](https://github.com/eohomegrownapps))_ redesigned
the Planet code as a series of GCI tasks.  _Austin George
([@aust-n](https://github.com/aust-n))_ refactored the toolbars as a
series of GCI tasks. _Bottersnike
([@Bottersnike](https://github.com/Bottersnike))_ redesigned the
widgets and the Block API, _Andrea Gonzales
([@AndreaGon](https://github.com/AndreaGon))_ made the widgets
responsive, _Marcus Chong ([@pidddgy](https://github.com/pidddgy))_
refactored the update code, resulting in an order-of-magnitude
improvement in CPU usage, and _Samyok Nepal
([@nepaltechguy2](https://github.com/nepaltechguy2))_ updated the
local storage mechanism to use localForage.

A full list of
[contributors](https://github.com/sugarlabs/musicblocks/graphs/contributors)
is available.

## &lt;a name=&quot;MUSIC_BLOCKS_IN_JAPAN&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Music Blocks in Japan

[Gakken STEAM](https://gakken-steam.jp/music_blocks/)

## License

Music Blocks is licensed under the
[AGPL](https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.en.html), which means it
will always be free to copy, modify, and hopefully improve. We respect
your privacy: while Music Blocks stores your session information in
your browser&#039;s local storage, it does not and will never access these
data for purposes other than to restore your session. Music Blocks will
never share these data with any third parties.

There is a Planet where you can share your projects with others and
remix projects created by other Music Blocks users. Use of the Planet
is anonymous and not required in order to enjoy Music Blocks.

Have fun, play hard, and learn.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ToolJet/ToolJet]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ToolJet is the open-source foundation of ToolJet AI - the AI-native platform for building internal tools, dashboard, business applications, workflows and AI agents 🚀]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet">ToolJet/ToolJet</a></h1>
            <p>ToolJet is the open-source foundation of ToolJet AI - the AI-native platform for building internal tools, dashboard, business applications, workflows and AI agents 🚀</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 37,081</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,914</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>ToolJet is an **open-source low-code framework** to build and deploy internal tools with minimal engineering effort. ToolJet&#039;s drag-and-drop frontend builder allows you to create complex, responsive frontends within minutes. Additionally, you can integrate various data sources, including databases like PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Elasticsearch; API endpoints with OpenAPI spec and OAuth2 support; SaaS tools such as Stripe, Slack, Google Sheets, Airtable, and Notion; as well as object storage services like S3, GCS, and Minio, to fetch and write data.

 :star: If you find ToolJet useful, please consider giving us a star on GitHub! Your support helps us continue to innovate and deliver exciting features.

![Docker Cloud Build Status](https://img.shields.io/docker/cloud/build/tooljet/tooljet-ce)
![Number of GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/tooljet/tooljet)
[![Number of GitHub issues that are open](https://img.shields.io/github/issues/ToolJet/ToolJet)](https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet/issues)
[![Number of GitHub stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/ToolJet/ToolJet)](https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet/stargazers)
![Number of GitHub closed issues](https://img.shields.io/github/issues-closed/tooljet/tooljet)
![Number of GitHub pull requests that are open](https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr-raw/tooljet/tooljet)
![GitHub release; latest by date](https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/tooljet/tooljet)
![GitHub commit activity](https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/tooljet/tooljet)
[![GitHub license which is AGPL license](https://img.shields.io/github/license/ToolJet/ToolJet)](https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet)
[![Follow us on X, formerly Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/ToolJet?style=social)](https://twitter.com/ToolJet)

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7828962/211444352-4d6d2e4a-13c9-4980-9e16-4aed4af9811b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tooljet dashboard showing inventory and orders&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet/assets/25361949/0e711f3a-edb7-496b-8833-107de3826933&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## All features

- **Visual App Builder:** 45+ built-in responsive components, including Tables, Charts, Lists, Forms, and Progress Bars.
- **ToolJet Database:** Built-in no-code database.
- **Multi-Page:** Build an application with multiple pages.
- **Multiplayer editing:** Allows simultaneous app building by multiple developers.
- **50+ data sources:** Integrate with external databases, cloud storage, and APIs.
- **Desktop &amp; mobile:** Customize layout widths to fit various screen sizes.
- **Self-host:** Supports Docker, Kubernetes, AWS EC2, Google Cloud Run, and more.
- **Collaborate:** Add comments anywhere on the canvas and tag your team members.
- **Extend with plugins:** Use our [command-line tool](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@tooljet/cli) to easily bootstrap new connectors.
- **Version control:** Manage multiple application versions with a structured release cycle.
- **Run JS &amp; Python code:** Execute custom JavaScript and Python snippets.
- **Granular access control:** Set permissions at both group and app levels.
- **Low-code:** Use JS code almost anywhere within the builder, such as setting text color based on status with 
`status === &#039;success&#039; ? &#039;green&#039; : &#039;red&#039;`.
- **No-code query editors:** Query Editors are available for all supported data sources.
- **Join and transform data:** Transform query results using JavaScript or Python code.
- **Secure:** All the credentials are securely encrypted using `aes-256-gcm`.
- **Data Privacy:** ToolJet serves solely as a proxy and does not store data.
- **SSO:** Supports multiple Single Sign-On providers.

&lt;hr&gt;

## Quickstart
The easiest way to get started with ToolJet is by creating a [ToolJet Cloud](https://tooljet.ai) account. ToolJet Cloud offers a hosted solution of ToolJet. If you want to self-host ToolJet, kindly proceed to [deployment documentation](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/).

### Try using Docker
Want to give ToolJet a quick spin on your local machine? You can run the following command from your terminal to have ToolJet up and running right away.


```bash
docker run \
  --name tooljet \
  --restart unless-stopped \
  -p 80:80 \
  --platform linux/amd64 \
  -v tooljet_data:/var/lib/postgresql/13/main \
  tooljet/try:ee-lts-latest
```

*For users upgrading their ToolJet version, we recommend choosing the LTS version over the latest version. The LTS version ensures stability with production bug fixes, security patches, and performance enhancements.*

## Tutorials and examples

[Time Tracker Application](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/#quickstart-guide)&lt;br&gt;
[Build your own CMS using low-code](https://blog.tooljet.ai/build-cms-using-lowcode-and-mongodb/)&lt;br&gt;
[AWS S3 Browser](https://blog.tooljet.ai/build-an-aws-s3-broswer-with-tooljet/)&lt;br&gt;

## Documentation
Documentation is available at https://docs.tooljet.ai.

- [Getting Started](https://docs.tooljet.ai)&lt;br&gt;
- [Data source Reference](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/data-sources/airtable/)&lt;br&gt;
- [Component Reference](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/widgets/button)

## Self-hosted
You can use ToolJet Cloud for a fully managed solution. If you want to self-host ToolJet, we have guides on deploying ToolJet on Kubernetes, AWS EC2, Docker, and more.

| Provider  | Documentation |
| :------------- | :------------- |
| Digital Ocean | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/digitalocean)  |
| Docker  | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/docker)   |
| AWS EC2 | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/ec2)  |
| AWS ECS | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/ecs)   |
| OpenShift | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/openshift)   |
| Helm | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/helm)   |
| AWS EKS (Kubernetes) | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/kubernetes)   |
| GCP GKE (Kubernetes) | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/kubernetes-gke)   |
| Azure AKS (Kubernetes) | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/kubernetes-aks)   |
| Azure Container | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/azure-container)   |
| Google Cloud Run  | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/google-cloud-run)   |
| Deploying ToolJet client  | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/client)   |
| Deploying ToolJet on a Subpath  | [Link](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/setup/tooljet-subpath/)   |

## Marketplace 
ToolJet can now be found on both AWS and Azure Marketplaces, making it simpler than ever to access and deploy our app-building platform.

Find ToolJet on AWS Marketplace [here](https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/pp/prodview-fxjto27jkpqfg?sr=0-1&amp;ref_=beagle&amp;applicationId=AWSMPContessa) and explore seamless integration on Azure Marketplace [here](https://azuremarketplace.microsoft.com/en-us/marketplace/apps/tooljetsolutioninc1679496832216.tooljet?tab=Overview).

## Community support
For general help using ToolJet, please refer to the official [documentation](https://docs.tooljet.ai/docs/). For additional help, you can use one of these channels to ask a question:

- [Slack](https://tooljet.ai/slack) - Discussions with the community and the team.
- [GitHub](https://github.com/ToolJet/ToolJet/issues) - For bug reports and feature requests.
- [𝕏 (Twitter)](https://twitter.com/ToolJet) - Get the product updates quickly.

## Roadmap
Check out our [roadmap](https://github.com/orgs/ToolJet/projects/15) to stay updated on recently released features and learn about what&#039;s coming next.

## Branching model
We use the git-flow branching model. The base branch is `develop`. If you are looking for a stable version, please use the main branch or tags labeled as v1.x.x.

## Contributing
Kindly read our [Contributing Guide](CONTRIBUTING.md) to familiarize yourself with ToolJet&#039;s development process, how to suggest bug fixes and improvements, and the steps for building and testing your changes. &lt;br&gt;

## Contributors
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tooljet/tooljet/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=tooljet/tooljet&amp;max=400&amp;columns=20&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://us-central1-tooljet-hub.cloudfunctions.net/github&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

## License
ToolJet © 2023, ToolJet Solutions Inc - Released under the GNU Affero General Public License v3.0.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7Sageer/sublink-worker]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/7Sageer/sublink-worker</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/7Sageer/sublink-worker</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[One Worker, All Subscriptions]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/7Sageer/sublink-worker">7Sageer/sublink-worker</a></h1>
            <p>One Worker, All Subscriptions</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,890</p>
            <p>Forks: 7,482</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;public/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sublink Worker&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;120&quot;/&gt;

  &lt;h1&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sublink Worker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;h5&gt;&lt;i&gt;One Worker, All Subscriptions&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A lightweight subscription converter and manager for proxy protocols, deployable on Cloudflare Workers, Vercel, Node.js, or Docker.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/12291&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/12291&quot; alt=&quot;7Sageer%2Fsublink-worker | Trendshift&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;display: flex; align-items: center; gap: 10px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://deploy.workers.cloudflare.com/?url=https://github.com/7Sageer/sublink-worker&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://deploy.workers.cloudflare.com/button&quot; alt=&quot;Deploy to Cloudflare Workers&quot; style=&quot;height: 32px;&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://vercel.com/new/clone?repository-url=https://github.com/7Sageer/sublink-worker&amp;env=KV_REST_API_URL,KV_REST_API_TOKEN&amp;envDescription=Vercel%20KV%20credentials%20for%20data%20storage&amp;envLink=https://vercel.com/docs/storage/vercel-kv&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://vercel.com/button&quot; alt=&quot;Deploy to Vercel&quot; style=&quot;height: 32px;&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3&gt;📚 Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.sublink.works&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;⚡ Live Demo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublink.works/en/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Documentation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublink.works&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;中文文档&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;·
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublink.works/guide/quick-start/&quot;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/a&gt; ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublink.works/api/&quot;&gt;API Reference&lt;/a&gt; ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublink.works/guide/faq/&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 🚀 Quick Start

### One-Click Deployment
- Choose a &quot;deploy&quot; button above to click
- That&#039;s it! See the [Document](https://sublink.works/guide/quick-start/) for more information.

### Alternative Runtimes
- **Node.js**: `npm run build:node &amp;&amp; node dist/node-server.cjs`
- **Vercel**: `vercel deploy` (configure KV in project settings)
- **Docker**: `docker pull ghcr.io/7sageer/sublink-worker:latest`
- **Docker Compose**: `docker compose up -d` (includes Redis)

## ✨ Features

### Supported Protocols
ShadowSocks • VMess • VLESS • Hysteria2 • Trojan • TUIC

### Client Support
Sing-Box • Clash • Xray/V2Ray • Surge

### Input Support
- Base64 subscriptions
- HTTP/HTTPS subscriptions
- Full configs (Sing-Box JSON, Clash YAML, Surge INI)

### Core Capabilities
- Import subscriptions from multiple sources
- Generate fixed/random short links (KV-based)
- Light/Dark theme toggle
- Flexible API for script automation
- Multi-language support (Chinese, English, Persian, Russian)
- Web interface with predefined rule sets and customizable policy groups

## 🤝 Contributing

Issues and Pull Requests are welcome to improve this project.

## 📄 License

This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the [LICENSE](LICENSE) file for details.

## ⚠️ Disclaimer

This project is for learning and exchange purposes only. Please do not use it for illegal purposes. All consequences resulting from the use of this project are solely the responsibility of the user and are not related to the developer.

## 💰 Sponsorship

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;Thanks to the following sponsors for their support of this project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://yxvm.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;YXVM&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://image.779477.xyz/yxvm.png&quot; alt=&quot;YXVM&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NodeSeekDev/NodeSupport&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;NodeSupport&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://image.779477.xyz/ns.png&quot; alt=&quot;NodeSupport&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; hspace=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you would like to sponsor this project, please contact the developer &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/7Sageer&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;@7Sageer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## ⭐ Star History

Thanks to everyone who has starred this project! 🌟

&lt;a href=&quot;https://star-history.com/#7Sageer/sublink-worker&amp;Date&quot;&gt;
 &lt;picture&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=7Sageer/sublink-worker&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=7Sageer/sublink-worker&amp;type=Date&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Star History Chart&quot; src=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=7Sageer/sublink-worker&amp;type=Date&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>