<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for javascript - JavaScript Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for javascript.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[⭐️ Companies that don't have a broken hiring process]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards">poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards</a></h1>
            <p>⭐️ Companies that don't have a broken hiring process</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 48,828</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,789</p>
            <p>Stars today: 19 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Hiring Without Whiteboards

A list of companies (or teams) that don&#039;t do &quot;whiteboard&quot; interviews. &quot;Whiteboards&quot; is used as a metaphor, and is a _symbol_ for the kinds of CS trivia questions that are associated with bad interview practices. Whiteboards are not bad – CS trivia questions are. Using sites like HackerRank/LeetCode _probably_ fall into a similar category.

The companies and teams listed here use interview techniques and questions that resemble day-to-day work. For example, pairing on a real world problem or a paid/unpaid take home exercise. Read (and contribute to) [our recommendations](RECOMMENDATIONS.md) for ways to conduct better interviews.

### tl;dr

- Discussing a real world problem (with or without whiteboard) is 👍
- Solving CS trivia, technical puzzles, riddles, brainteasers (with or without whiteboard) is 👎

Please open a [PR](https://github.com/poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards/pull/new/master) to be added.

### Duds

If you&#039;ve been through an interview with one of these companies recently, and your experience suggests otherwise from their description, please open a [PR](https://github.com/poteto/hiring-without-whiteboards/pull/new/master) to remove them from this list.

### I want to search/sort/filter/group by X!

Check out our [Airtable](https://airtable.com/shr3eGPDm3wGjT2gA)!

Additions to this document that are properly formatted will automatically be pushed and added to Airtable. Keywords from the description will also be extracted. You can see (and contribute!) to the [API here](https://github.com/poteto/hww-api).

Also check out [No Whiteboards](https://www.nowhiteboard.org) to search for jobs at these companies.

### Discussion and other reads

&lt;!--lint disable--&gt;

- Discussion
  - [HackerNews (2017)](https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13874026)
  - [HackerNews (2020)](https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23981795)
- [Finding a better alternative to the whiteboard interview](https://theoutline.com/post/1256/finding-a-better-alternative-to-the-whiteboard-interview)
- [How to hire engineering talent without the BS](https://jes.al//2023/03/how-to-hire-engineering-talent-without-the-bs/)
- [How I Hire Programmers](http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/hiring.en) by Aaron Swartz

&lt;!--lint enable--&gt;

---

## 0 - 9

- [1000.software](https://www.1000.software/careers) | Krakow, Poland / Remote | Series of 2 interviews first on soft skills, second on technical skills (how to build things, how to solve specific, real world problem, best practice) and meeting with a team leader. Sometimes a take home, simple project.

## A - C

- [Aalyria](https://www.aalyria.com/jobs) | Remote | Timeboxed design exercise and related coding exercise, followed by a technical/behavioral discussion with the team, and behavioral interview with leadership
- [Able](https://able.co/careers) | Lima, PE / Remote | Coding interview, Technical interview (Backlog Refinement + System Design), Leadership interview (Behavioural)
- [Abstract](https://angel.co/abstract/jobs) | San Francisco, CA
- [Accenture](https://www.accenture.com/us-en/careers) | San Francisco, CA / Los Angeles, CA / New York, NY / Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Technical phone discussion with architecture manager, followed by behavioral interview focusing on soft skills
- [Accredible](https://www.accredible.com/careers) | Cambridge, UK / San Francisco, CA / Remote | Take home project, then a pair-programming and discussion onsite / Skype round.
- [Acko](https://www.acko.com/careers) | Mumbai, India | Phone interview, followed by a small take home problem. Finally a F2F or skype pair programming session
- [Acumen](https://www.acumenci.com/careers/) | London, UK | Small take home test, and sit in on some sprint rituals on-site
- [Ad Hoc](https://adhoc.team) | Remote / Washington, DC | Technical take-home assignment, followed by multiple video calls that are discussions of technical background and experience.
- [Adaface](https://www.adaface.com) | Remote/ Singapore, Singapore / Bangalore, India | Conversational on-the-job technical assessment, followed by video calls with technical lead and founders
- [AdCellerant](https://adcellerant.com/career-job-listing/) | Denver, CO | Technical phone screen, 5-day take home code challenge, then on-site interview comprised of cultural and technical discussions
- [Adeva](https://adevait.com) | New York, USA | 4 steps interviewing process that includes online coding assignment + lead engineer call.
- [AdEx Network](https://www.adex.network) | Sofia, Bulgaria / Remote | Email screening process, followed by a take-home assignment
- [Admiral](https://getadmiral.com) | Gainesville, FL / Remote | Intro phone call with hiring manager, take-home assignment, (mostly) non-technical on-site with team/leadership
- [Adnymics](https://adnymics.com) | Munich, DE | Take home project, then work with the team for a day
- [Adthena](https://adthena.com) | London, UK | Takehome project and discussion on-site
- [Adyen](https://www.adyen.com) | Amsterdam, NL | Take-home assignment, design discussion based on take home, culture fit etc. Provides visa sponsorship to the Netherlands.
- [Affinipay](https://www.affinipay.com) | Austin, TX | Short takehome project + video interview about coding with engineering manager
- [Agency Enterprise Studio](https://ae.studio) | Remote / Los Angeles, CA / Florianópolis, Brazil | Live coding of a task you&#039;d do daily
- [Ageno](https://ageno.pl) | Bielsko-Biala, Poland | Simple Magento Take-home project and discussion on the real world problems.
- [AgileMD](https://angel.co/agilemd/jobs) | San Francisco, CA | Takehome project
- [AImotive](https://aimotive.com/career/) | Budapest, Hungary | Small take-home project, then in-person interview about technical background
- [Airbase](https://www.airbase.com/careers) | San Francisco, CA; Bangalore, India; Remote | Intro Call with HR or EMs, small take-home project, two tech rounds with Airbase Engineers (based on real world engineering problems), followed by a final values round with the Founder or Director of Engineering.
- [Airtable](https://airtable.com/careers) | San Francisco, CA; Austin, TX; Mountain View, CA; New York, NY; Remote | Take home project that resembles a problem Airtable solves for. Five hour on-site which includes a discussion of the project, UI design, discussing architectural tradeoffs, and code debugging.
- [Aiwip](https://aiwip.com) | London, UK | Skype/phone interview followed by takehome project or worksample (or whiteboard)
- [Albert](https://jobs.lever.co/meetalbert/) | Los Angeles, CA | Discussion with senior engineer, and then practical pair programming related to my experience + the position
- [Algolia](https://www.algolia.com/careers) | Paris, France / San Francisco, CA | Takehome project &amp; Onsite discussions and presentation
- [all about apps GmbH](https://www.allaboutapps.at/jobs) | Vienna, Austria | 2-phase technical discussion &amp; examination with department heads and management.
- [Allegro](https://allegro.pl/praca) | Warsaw, Poland; Poznan, Poland; Torun, Poland; Wroclaw, Poland; Krakow, Poland | Take home, simple project. Series of 2 technical interviews (how to build things, how to solve specific, real world problem) and meeting with a team leader.
- [Alluxi](https://www.alluxi.mx) | Monterrey, Mexico | Initial skype interview, technical interview with Senior engineer and work sample review.
- [Almabase](https://www.almabase.com/careers#believe) | Bengaluru, India | Take-home assignment, design discussion based on take home, low level and high level design rounds based on real life problems, culture fit etc. during onsite.
- [AlphaSights](https://www.alphasights.com/careers/open-roles/) | London, UK / New York, NY / Remote | Initial interview, pair programming then final round with general technical questions
- [AMAGI](https://amagi.io) | Makati, Philippines | 1) Review of your resume, portfolio, and/or GitHub profile; 2) 1 hour discussion (in-person or Skype) about your goals, experience, personal culture, and how to apply technical solutions to real problems;
- [Analytical Flavor Systems](https://gastrograph.com) | Manhattan, New York | Code sample or take-home project, both with discussion.
- [Anderson Merchandisers](https://amerch.com) | Remote / Dallas, TX | Technical discussion about the technologies they are currently using. Going over background and resume.
- [Angaza](https://www.angaza.com/careers/) | San Francisco, CA | Take-home assignment with guaranteed feedback, on-site interviews involving actual day-to-day work
- [Animech](https://careers.animech.com) | Uppsala, Sweden | Multiple interviews with technical staff with real problem discussions.
- [Anyfin](https://career.anyfin.com) | Stockholm, Sweden | Takehome project &amp; Onsite discussions and presentation.
- [Aparkado](https://aparkado.de) | Cologne, Germany / Remote | Intro with Co-Founder, team fit with the team plus a small real-world problem to solve, followed by final round with CEO / Co-Founder.
- [Apollo Agriculture](https://apolloagriculture.com) | Nairobi, Kenya / Remote | Takehome project or Worksample (or whiteboard)
- [Applied](https://www.beapplied.com) | London, UK | Situational judgement tests focusing on real-world soft skills (online then in structured interview)
- [Arachnys](https://angel.co/arachnys/jobs/220465-software-engineer) | London, UK | Take home test, real world pair programming
- [Articulate](https://www.articulate.com/about/careers/) | Remote | Take-home project &amp; pair program on a problem similar to daily work
- [Artsy](https://www.artsy.net/jobs#engineering) | New York, NY / London, UK / Berlin, Germany / Los Angeles, CA / Hong Kong, Hong Kong / Remote | Our process: 1) Informal chat 2) Application 3) Phone screen 4) In-person interview with 1 lead, 2 individual contributors and 1 non-engineer (30-45 mins each), focusing on your work habits and expertise as demonstrated in your previous work 5) ~4 in-depth professional reference calls (30-45 mins each).
- [ASI Data Science](https://www.asidatascience.com/careers) | London, UK | Project to work at home, general technical questions, pair programming with engineers
- [ASOS](https://www.asoscareers.com) | London, UK | Take home or in-person code refactoring exercise, in-person walk-though of solution including software craftsmanship principles and design decisions, in-person freestyle architecture walk-through
- [Ataccama](https://jobs.ataccama.com) | Prague, Czech Republic | Face to face interview (skype or onsite), coding task for 30 min, meeting with team members
- [aTech Media](https://atech.media) | London, UK | Face to face interview, review of existing open source contributions or, if none are available, asked to write a library for something that interests them
- [Atlan](https://atlan.com) | New Delhi, India | A mini project (to be done within 8 days), followed by a discussion with the team you&#039;re applying to. Then as the final step, a call with one of the founders.
- [Aura Frames](https://auraframes.com/jobs?gh_src=2ef5cfa32) | New York, NY / San Francisco, CA | Simplified real-world coding task on Coderpad.io, followed by a few hours onsite writing code in our actual codebase.
- [Auto1](https://www.auto1-group.com/jobs) | Berlin, DE | Series of Skype interviews which covers general technical questions, followed by a take-home assignment
- [Automattic](https://automattic.com/work-with-us/) | Remote | short take-home code test, then a part-time, paid project.
- [AutoScout24](https://github.com/AutoScout24/hiring) | Munich, Germany | Skype interview followed by home assignment from our day-to-day business and then on-site interview including lunch with a team
- [Avant](https://avant.com/jobs) | Chicago, IL | Pair programming interviews.
- [Avarteq GmbH](https://www.avarteq.com/career) | Berlin, Germany / Saarbrücken, Germany | Technical interview with our developers on-site or remote followed by a work sample in a pair programming session or a previous take-home project with a follow-up discussion and detailed feedback.
- [Axelerant](https://www.axelerant.com/careers) | Remote | Take-home project, interviews with hr and engineering team.
- [Axiacore](https://axiacore.com) | Bogota, Colombia | We talk about on how is your process when solving problems.
- [Axios](https://www.axios.com/careers) | Arlington, VA / New York, NY / San Francisco, CA / Remote | Take-home project, with discussion.
- [B12](https://boards.greenhouse.io/b12#.WMlLfRIrJTa) | New York, NY | Take-home exercises and pair-programming with the team.
- [Babylon Health iOS Team](https://github.com/Babylonpartners/iOS-Interview-Demo) | London, UK | Take-home project, on-site presentation and discussion, design and product interview.
- [Backbase](https://workatbackbase.com) | Amsterdam, Netherlands; Cardiff, Wales; London, UK; Atlanta, GA | Takehome project, interviews
- [Badi](https://jobs.badi.com) | Barcelona, Spain | Phone Screen, Take-home project, then a discussion onsite round.
- [Badoo](https://team.badoo.com/jobs) | London, UK | Take-home project, then a discussion onsite round.
- [BAE Systems Digital Intelligence](https://cybercareers.baesystems.com) | London, UK / Manchester, UK / Guildford, UK / Gloucester, UK | Initial interview with experience based technical questions, second interview pair programming on problem similar to daily work
- [Bakken &amp; Bæck](https://bakkenbaeck.com/jobs) | Oslo, Norway; Amsterdam, Netherlands; Bonn, Germany | Skype interview followed by take-home assignment and a visit to one of our offices
- [Balabit](https://career.balabit.com) | Budapest, Hungary | Take-home project (medium size, with restrictions, e.g. only stdlib may be used), then discussion on-site
- [Barracuda View Team](https://www.barracuda.com/company/careers) | Chelmsford, MA / Remote | Phone screen, remote pair programming session, technical discussion interview, culture fit interview
- [Basecamp](https://basecamp.com/about/jobs) | Chicago, IL / Remote
- [BCW Group](https://www.bcw.group) | Remote | Behavioral interview with the technical lead and hiring manager, followed by a take-home project, and finally a brief discussion about how the exercise went.
- [Beam Dental](https://jobs.lever.co/beam) | Columbus, OH / Remote | Phone Screen, Take Home Project, In-Person or remote Pairing and Cross-Functional Interview
- [Belka](https://www.belkadigital.com) | Trento, Italy; Munich, Germany | We give you a small task that you can do alone and then we evaluate your work with you
- [Bemind](https://www.bemind.me) | Biella, Italy / Latina, Italy / Remote | Series of interviews, discussion about technical background and past experiences, take-home project &amp; pair programming
- [Bendyworks](https://bendyworks.com/careers) | Madison, WI | Interviews and pair programming on personal projects
- [Benefex](https://hellobenefex.com/about-us/careers) | Southampton, UK / Remote | A short, 3-stages interview process. The first stage is with HR. The second stage is a take-home assignment. The third stage is discussing the take-home assignment solution with two engineers.
- [Benshi.ai](https://www.benshi.ai) | Barcelona, Spain | Initial 15-30 mins interview with HR, followed by 15-30 mins chat with hiring manager to clear out basic concepts, then followed by take-home task for 5 days
- [Betterment](https://www.betterment.com/careers) | New York, NY | Phone interview followed by on-site pair programming to simulate a Betterment feature build.
- [BetterPT](https://www.betterhealthcare.co/careers) | New York, NY | Initial phone interview, project using our tech stack, on-site code review/pair programming and &quot;meet the team&quot;.
- [bevelop](https://bevelop.de) | Aschaffenburg, BY / Remote | Initial introductory call, on-sight or remote trial day with project
- [Big Nerd Ranch](https://bignerdranch.com/careers) | Atlanta, GA &amp; Remote | Interviews and pair programming on an internal project or problem.
- [BigaBid](https://www.bigabid.com/careers) | Tel Aviv, Israel | Design a real time solution to a problem relevant to the business, followed by a take home project implementing a lean version of the solution
- [BigBinary](https://www.bigbinary.com/jobs) | Remote | Phone discussion with a developer and the CEO
- [BioConnect](https://bioconnect.com) | Toronto, Canada | Take-home assignment &amp; discussion
- [Bitchief Technology Services](https://www.bitchief.com) | India, Gurgaon | Screening Round: General comms and aptitude, Technical Round: Questions related to required technology, Home Assignments
- [bitExpert AG](https://www.bitexpert.de/karriere) | Mannheim, Germany | Interview with experience based technical questions
- [Bitpanda](https://www.bitpanda.com/en/career) | Cracow, Poland / Remote | HR talk, take-home task, tech interview, culture fit interview
- [Bits of Love](https://www.bitsoflove.be/careers) | Bruges, Belgium | In-person interview to evaluate experience and motivation, potentially followed by take-home project.
- [Bitso](https://bitso.com/jobs) | Mexico City, Mexico / Remote | Intro phone or hangouts/skype call with People team, take home project followed by walkthrough of your code and some tech questions focused on your experience, founders video call with one of the founders
- [Blackdot Solutions](https://blackdotsolutions.com) | Cambridge, UK | Take-home project followed by on-site face-to-face walkthru of your code focusing on decisions/reasoning/technology used.
- [BlackTech](https://blacktech.com.np) | Pokhara, NP | Take-home project followed by on-site face to face or remote video conference interview.
- [Bleacher Report](https://bleacherreport.com) | San Francisco, CA, USA | Take-home project; on-site discussion about the project and meeting with different teams
- [Blendle](https://blendle.homerun.co/?lang=en) | Utrecht, The Netherlands | Take-home project &amp; pair program on a problem similar to daily work
- [blogfoster](https://github.com/blogfoster/join-the-engineering-team) | Berlin, Germany | Take-home project, discussion on-site
- [Bloom Works](https://bloomworks.digital/jobs) | Remote | Discussion, pair-programming exercise
- [Blue Bottle Coffee](https://www.bluebottlecoffee.com) | Oakland, CA | Technical Phone Screen, Take Home Challenge, Technical in-persons.
- [Bluesoft](http://www.bluesoft.com.br) | São Paulo, Brazil | Takehome project and an interview to evaluate the candidate&#039;s previous experience.
- [Bocoup](https://bocoup.com/careers) | Boston, MA / Remote | Pair programming with personal laptop on typical problem seen at work
- [Bonusly](https://bonus.ly/careers) | Boulder, CO | Values &amp; Tech focused interview - Process: 30 minute with HR, 45 minute Google Meet interview with 2 team members, ~2-4 hour take-home project, on-site interview involving 2 values-alignment interviews and 1 technical interview going over your take home project
- [BookingSync](https://www.bookingsync.com/en/jobs) | Remote | Small takehome project, interviews over skype with team members.
- [BoomTown](https://boomtownroi.com) | Charleston, SC / Atlanta, GA / Remote | Conversational in-person interviews with potential team members and managers that revolve around past experience and how that could be applied to future work
- [Botika](https://botika.ai) | San Marino, RSM | View code, projects, libraries or any other open source story that you have been a part of, take-home project followed by on-site face-to-face walkthru of your code focusing on decisions/reasoning/technology used.
- [Bouvet](https://www.bouvet.no) | Bergen, Norway | Pair programming with senior engineers
- [brainn.co](https://brainn.co) | São Paulo, BR | Zoom/On-site interview, take-home project and interview with a team leader.
- [BrainStation-23](https://brainstation-23.com) | Dhaka, BD | A practical project followed by series of in-person interview sessions
- [Bramble](https://www.brmbl.io) | Remote | Slack interview, take home test, pairing, culture-fit interview.
- [Breather

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mendableai/firecrawl-mcp-server]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mendableai/firecrawl-mcp-server</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mendableai/firecrawl-mcp-server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Official Firecrawl MCP Server - Adds powerful web scraping to Cursor, Claude and any other LLM clients.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mendableai/firecrawl-mcp-server">mendableai/firecrawl-mcp-server</a></h1>
            <p>Official Firecrawl MCP Server - Adds powerful web scraping to Cursor, Claude and any other LLM clients.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,567</p>
            <p>Forks: 339</p>
            <p>Stars today: 16 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Firecrawl MCP Server

A Model Context Protocol (MCP) server implementation that integrates with [Firecrawl](https://github.com/mendableai/firecrawl) for web scraping capabilities.

&gt; Big thanks to [@vrknetha](https://github.com/vrknetha), [@knacklabs](https://www.knacklabs.ai) for the initial implementation!


## Features

- Web scraping, crawling, and discovery
- Search and content extraction
- Deep research and batch scraping
- Automatic retries and rate limiting
- Cloud and self-hosted support
- SSE support

&gt; Play around with [our MCP Server on MCP.so&#039;s playground](https://mcp.so/playground?server=firecrawl-mcp-server) or on [Klavis AI](https://www.klavis.ai/mcp-servers).

## Installation

### Running with npx

```bash
env FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=fc-YOUR_API_KEY npx -y firecrawl-mcp
```

### Manual Installation

```bash
npm install -g firecrawl-mcp
```

### Running on Cursor

Configuring Cursor 🖥️
Note: Requires Cursor version 0.45.6+
For the most up-to-date configuration instructions, please refer to the official Cursor documentation on configuring MCP servers:
[Cursor MCP Server Configuration Guide](https://docs.cursor.com/context/model-context-protocol#configuring-mcp-servers)

To configure Firecrawl MCP in Cursor **v0.48.6**

1. Open Cursor Settings
2. Go to Features &gt; MCP Servers
3. Click &quot;+ Add new global MCP server&quot;
4. Enter the following code:
   ```json
   {
     &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
       &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;: {
         &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
         &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;],
         &quot;env&quot;: {
           &quot;FIRECRAWL_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR-API-KEY&quot;
         }
       }
     }
   }
   ```
   
To configure Firecrawl MCP in Cursor **v0.45.6**

1. Open Cursor Settings
2. Go to Features &gt; MCP Servers
3. Click &quot;+ Add New MCP Server&quot;
4. Enter the following:
   - Name: &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot; (or your preferred name)
   - Type: &quot;command&quot;
   - Command: `env FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=your-api-key npx -y firecrawl-mcp`



&gt; If you are using Windows and are running into issues, try `cmd /c &quot;set FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=your-api-key &amp;&amp; npx -y firecrawl-mcp&quot;`

Replace `your-api-key` with your Firecrawl API key. If you don&#039;t have one yet, you can create an account and get it from https://www.firecrawl.dev/app/api-keys

After adding, refresh the MCP server list to see the new tools. The Composer Agent will automatically use Firecrawl MCP when appropriate, but you can explicitly request it by describing your web scraping needs. Access the Composer via Command+L (Mac), select &quot;Agent&quot; next to the submit button, and enter your query.

### Running on Windsurf

Add this to your `./codeium/windsurf/model_config.json`:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;mcp-server-firecrawl&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### Running with SSE Local Mode

To run the server using Server-Sent Events (SSE) locally instead of the default stdio transport:

```bash
env SSE_LOCAL=true FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=fc-YOUR_API_KEY npx -y firecrawl-mcp
```

Use the url: http://localhost:3000/sse

### Installing via Smithery (Legacy)

To install Firecrawl for Claude Desktop automatically via [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/server/@mendableai/mcp-server-firecrawl):

```bash
npx -y @smithery/cli install @mendableai/mcp-server-firecrawl --client claude
```

### Running on VS Code

For one-click installation, click one of the install buttons below...

[![Install with NPX in VS Code](https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-NPM-0098FF?style=flat-square&amp;logo=visualstudiocode&amp;logoColor=white)](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect/mcp/install?name=firecrawl&amp;inputs=%5B%7B%22type%22%3A%22promptString%22%2C%22id%22%3A%22apiKey%22%2C%22description%22%3A%22Firecrawl%20API%20Key%22%2C%22password%22%3Atrue%7D%5D&amp;config=%7B%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22firecrawl-mcp%22%5D%2C%22env%22%3A%7B%22FIRECRAWL_API_KEY%22%3A%22%24%7Binput%3AapiKey%7D%22%7D%7D) [![Install with NPX in VS Code Insiders](https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code_Insiders-NPM-24bfa5?style=flat-square&amp;logo=visualstudiocode&amp;logoColor=white)](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect/mcp/install?name=firecrawl&amp;inputs=%5B%7B%22type%22%3A%22promptString%22%2C%22id%22%3A%22apiKey%22%2C%22description%22%3A%22Firecrawl%20API%20Key%22%2C%22password%22%3Atrue%7D%5D&amp;config=%7B%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22firecrawl-mcp%22%5D%2C%22env%22%3A%7B%22FIRECRAWL_API_KEY%22%3A%22%24%7Binput%3AapiKey%7D%22%7D%7D&amp;quality=insiders)

For manual installation, add the following JSON block to your User Settings (JSON) file in VS Code. You can do this by pressing `Ctrl + Shift + P` and typing `Preferences: Open User Settings (JSON)`.

```json
{
  &quot;mcp&quot;: {
    &quot;inputs&quot;: [
      {
        &quot;type&quot;: &quot;promptString&quot;,
        &quot;id&quot;: &quot;apiKey&quot;,
        &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Firecrawl API Key&quot;,
        &quot;password&quot;: true
      }
    ],
    &quot;servers&quot;: {
      &quot;firecrawl&quot;: {
        &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
        &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;],
        &quot;env&quot;: {
          &quot;FIRECRAWL_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;${input:apiKey}&quot;
        }
      }
    }
  }
}
```

Optionally, you can add it to a file called `.vscode/mcp.json` in your workspace. This will allow you to share the configuration with others:

```json
{
  &quot;inputs&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;promptString&quot;,
      &quot;id&quot;: &quot;apiKey&quot;,
      &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Firecrawl API Key&quot;,
      &quot;password&quot;: true
    }
  ],
  &quot;servers&quot;: {
    &quot;firecrawl&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;${input:apiKey}&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

## Configuration

### Environment Variables

#### Required for Cloud API

- `FIRECRAWL_API_KEY`: Your Firecrawl API key
  - Required when using cloud API (default)
  - Optional when using self-hosted instance with `FIRECRAWL_API_URL`
- `FIRECRAWL_API_URL` (Optional): Custom API endpoint for self-hosted instances
  - Example: `https://firecrawl.your-domain.com`
  - If not provided, the cloud API will be used (requires API key)

#### Optional Configuration

##### Retry Configuration

- `FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_ATTEMPTS`: Maximum number of retry attempts (default: 3)
- `FIRECRAWL_RETRY_INITIAL_DELAY`: Initial delay in milliseconds before first retry (default: 1000)
- `FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_DELAY`: Maximum delay in milliseconds between retries (default: 10000)
- `FIRECRAWL_RETRY_BACKOFF_FACTOR`: Exponential backoff multiplier (default: 2)

##### Credit Usage Monitoring

- `FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_WARNING_THRESHOLD`: Credit usage warning threshold (default: 1000)
- `FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_CRITICAL_THRESHOLD`: Credit usage critical threshold (default: 100)

### Configuration Examples

For cloud API usage with custom retry and credit monitoring:

```bash
# Required for cloud API
export FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=your-api-key

# Optional retry configuration
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_ATTEMPTS=5        # Increase max retry attempts
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_INITIAL_DELAY=2000    # Start with 2s delay
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_DELAY=30000       # Maximum 30s delay
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_BACKOFF_FACTOR=3      # More aggressive backoff

# Optional credit monitoring
export FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_WARNING_THRESHOLD=2000    # Warning at 2000 credits
export FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_CRITICAL_THRESHOLD=500    # Critical at 500 credits
```

For self-hosted instance:

```bash
# Required for self-hosted
export FIRECRAWL_API_URL=https://firecrawl.your-domain.com

# Optional authentication for self-hosted
export FIRECRAWL_API_KEY=your-api-key  # If your instance requires auth

# Custom retry configuration
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_ATTEMPTS=10
export FIRECRAWL_RETRY_INITIAL_DELAY=500     # Start with faster retries
```

### Usage with Claude Desktop

Add this to your `claude_desktop_config.json`:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;mcp-server-firecrawl&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;firecrawl-mcp&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY_HERE&quot;,

        &quot;FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_ATTEMPTS&quot;: &quot;5&quot;,
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_RETRY_INITIAL_DELAY&quot;: &quot;2000&quot;,
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_RETRY_MAX_DELAY&quot;: &quot;30000&quot;,
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_RETRY_BACKOFF_FACTOR&quot;: &quot;3&quot;,

        &quot;FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_WARNING_THRESHOLD&quot;: &quot;2000&quot;,
        &quot;FIRECRAWL_CREDIT_CRITICAL_THRESHOLD&quot;: &quot;500&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### System Configuration

The server includes several configurable parameters that can be set via environment variables. Here are the default values if not configured:

```typescript
const CONFIG = {
  retry: {
    maxAttempts: 3, // Number of retry attempts for rate-limited requests
    initialDelay: 1000, // Initial delay before first retry (in milliseconds)
    maxDelay: 10000, // Maximum delay between retries (in milliseconds)
    backoffFactor: 2, // Multiplier for exponential backoff
  },
  credit: {
    warningThreshold: 1000, // Warn when credit usage reaches this level
    criticalThreshold: 100, // Critical alert when credit usage reaches this level
  },
};
```

These configurations control:

1. **Retry Behavior**

   - Automatically retries failed requests due to rate limits
   - Uses exponential backoff to avoid overwhelming the API
   - Example: With default settings, retries will be attempted at:
     - 1st retry: 1 second delay
     - 2nd retry: 2 seconds delay
     - 3rd retry: 4 seconds delay (capped at maxDelay)

2. **Credit Usage Monitoring**
   - Tracks API credit consumption for cloud API usage
   - Provides warnings at specified thresholds
   - Helps prevent unexpected service interruption
   - Example: With default settings:
     - Warning at 1000 credits remaining
     - Critical alert at 100 credits remaining

### Rate Limiting and Batch Processing

The server utilizes Firecrawl&#039;s built-in rate limiting and batch processing capabilities:

- Automatic rate limit handling with exponential backoff
- Efficient parallel processing for batch operations
- Smart request queuing and throttling
- Automatic retries for transient errors

## How to Choose a Tool

Use this guide to select the right tool for your task:

- **If you know the exact URL(s) you want:**
  - For one: use **scrape**
  - For many: use **batch_scrape**
- **If you need to discover URLs on a site:** use **map**
- **If you want to search the web for info:** use **search**
- **If you want to extract structured data:** use **extract**
- **If you want to analyze a whole site or section:** use **crawl** (with limits!)
- **If you want to do in-depth research:** use **deep_research**
- **If you want to generate LLMs.txt:** use **generate_llmstxt**

### Quick Reference Table

| Tool                | Best for                                 | Returns         |
|---------------------|------------------------------------------|-----------------|
| scrape              | Single page content                      | markdown/html   |
| batch_scrape        | Multiple known URLs                      | markdown/html[] |
| map                 | Discovering URLs on a site               | URL[]           |
| crawl               | Multi-page extraction (with limits)      | markdown/html[] |
| search              | Web search for info                      | results[]       |
| extract             | Structured data from pages               | JSON            |
| deep_research       | In-depth, multi-source research          | summary, sources|
| generate_llmstxt    | LLMs.txt for a domain                    | text            |

## Available Tools

### 1. Scrape Tool (`firecrawl_scrape`)

Scrape content from a single URL with advanced options.

**Best for:**
- Single page content extraction, when you know exactly which page contains the information.

**Not recommended for:**
- Extracting content from multiple pages (use batch_scrape for known URLs, or map + batch_scrape to discover URLs first, or crawl for full page content)
- When you&#039;re unsure which page contains the information (use search)
- When you need structured data (use extract)

**Common mistakes:**
- Using scrape for a list of URLs (use batch_scrape instead).

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Get the content of the page at https://example.com.&quot;

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_scrape&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com&quot;,
    &quot;formats&quot;: [&quot;markdown&quot;],
    &quot;onlyMainContent&quot;: true,
    &quot;waitFor&quot;: 1000,
    &quot;timeout&quot;: 30000,
    &quot;mobile&quot;: false,
    &quot;includeTags&quot;: [&quot;article&quot;, &quot;main&quot;],
    &quot;excludeTags&quot;: [&quot;nav&quot;, &quot;footer&quot;],
    &quot;skipTlsVerification&quot;: false
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Markdown, HTML, or other formats as specified.

### 2. Batch Scrape Tool (`firecrawl_batch_scrape`)

Scrape multiple URLs efficiently with built-in rate limiting and parallel processing.

**Best for:**
- Retrieving content from multiple pages, when you know exactly which pages to scrape.

**Not recommended for:**
- Discovering URLs (use map first if you don&#039;t know the URLs)
- Scraping a single page (use scrape)

**Common mistakes:**
- Using batch_scrape with too many URLs at once (may hit rate limits or token overflow)

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Get the content of these three blog posts: [url1, url2, url3].&quot;

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_batch_scrape&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;urls&quot;: [&quot;https://example1.com&quot;, &quot;https://example2.com&quot;],
    &quot;options&quot;: {
      &quot;formats&quot;: [&quot;markdown&quot;],
      &quot;onlyMainContent&quot;: true
    }
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Response includes operation ID for status checking:

```json
{
  &quot;content&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
      &quot;text&quot;: &quot;Batch operation queued with ID: batch_1. Use firecrawl_check_batch_status to check progress.&quot;
    }
  ],
  &quot;isError&quot;: false
}
```

### 3. Check Batch Status (`firecrawl_check_batch_status`)

Check the status of a batch operation.

```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_check_batch_status&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;id&quot;: &quot;batch_1&quot;
  }
}
```

### 4. Map Tool (`firecrawl_map`)

Map a website to discover all indexed URLs on the site.

**Best for:**
- Discovering URLs on a website before deciding what to scrape
- Finding specific sections of a website

**Not recommended for:**
- When you already know which specific URL you need (use scrape or batch_scrape)
- When you need the content of the pages (use scrape after mapping)

**Common mistakes:**
- Using crawl to discover URLs instead of map

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;List all URLs on example.com.&quot;

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_map&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com&quot;
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Array of URLs found on the site

### 5. Search Tool (`firecrawl_search`)

Search the web and optionally extract content from search results.

**Best for:**
- Finding specific information across multiple websites, when you don&#039;t know which website has the information.
- When you need the most relevant content for a query

**Not recommended for:**
- When you already know which website to scrape (use scrape)
- When you need comprehensive coverage of a single website (use map or crawl)

**Common mistakes:**
- Using crawl or map for open-ended questions (use search instead)

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_search&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;query&quot;: &quot;latest AI research papers 2023&quot;,
    &quot;limit&quot;: 5,
    &quot;lang&quot;: &quot;en&quot;,
    &quot;country&quot;: &quot;us&quot;,
    &quot;scrapeOptions&quot;: {
      &quot;formats&quot;: [&quot;markdown&quot;],
      &quot;onlyMainContent&quot;: true
    }
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Array of search results (with optional scraped content)

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Find the latest research papers on AI published in 2023.&quot;

### 6. Crawl Tool (`firecrawl_crawl`)

Starts an asynchronous crawl job on a website and extract content from all pages.

**Best for:**
- Extracting content from multiple related pages, when you need comprehensive coverage.

**Not recommended for:**
- Extracting content from a single page (use scrape)
- When token limits are a concern (use map + batch_scrape)
- When you need fast results (crawling can be slow)

**Warning:** Crawl responses can be very large and may exceed token limits. Limit the crawl depth and number of pages, or use map + batch_scrape for better control.

**Common mistakes:**
- Setting limit or maxDepth too high (causes token overflow)
- Using crawl for a single page (use scrape instead)

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Get all blog posts from the first two levels of example.com/blog.&quot;

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_crawl&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://example.com/blog/*&quot;,
    &quot;maxDepth&quot;: 2,
    &quot;limit&quot;: 100,
    &quot;allowExternalLinks&quot;: false,
    &quot;deduplicateSimilarURLs&quot;: true
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Response includes operation ID for status checking:

```json
{
  &quot;content&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
      &quot;text&quot;: &quot;Started crawl for: https://example.com/* with job ID: 550e8400-e29b-41d4-a716-446655440000. Use firecrawl_check_crawl_status to check progress.&quot;
    }
  ],
  &quot;isError&quot;: false
}
```

### 7. Check Crawl Status (`firecrawl_check_crawl_status`)

Check the status of a crawl job.

```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_check_crawl_status&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;id&quot;: &quot;550e8400-e29b-41d4-a716-446655440000&quot;
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Response includes the status of the crawl job:
  
### 8. Extract Tool (`firecrawl_extract`)

Extract structured information from web pages using LLM capabilities. Supports both cloud AI and self-hosted LLM extraction.

**Best for:**
- Extracting specific structured data like prices, names, details.

**Not recommended for:**
- When you need the full content of a page (use scrape)
- When you&#039;re not looking for specific structured data

**Arguments:**
- `urls`: Array of URLs to extract information from
- `prompt`: Custom prompt for the LLM extraction
- `systemPrompt`: System prompt to guide the LLM
- `schema`: JSON schema for structured data extraction
- `allowExternalLinks`: Allow extraction from external links
- `enableWebSearch`: Enable web search for additional context
- `includeSubdomains`: Include subdomains in extraction

When using a self-hosted instance, the extraction will use your configured LLM. For cloud API, it uses Firecrawl&#039;s managed LLM service.
**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Extract the product name, price, and description from these product pages.&quot;

**Usage Example:**
```json
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;firecrawl_extract&quot;,
  &quot;arguments&quot;: {
    &quot;urls&quot;: [&quot;https://example.com/page1&quot;, &quot;https://example.com/page2&quot;],
    &quot;prompt&quot;: &quot;Extract product information including name, price, and description&quot;,
    &quot;systemPrompt&quot;: &quot;You are a helpful assistant that extracts product information&quot;,
    &quot;schema&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;object&quot;,
      &quot;properties&quot;: {
        &quot;name&quot;: { &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot; },
        &quot;price&quot;: { &quot;type&quot;: &quot;number&quot; },
        &quot;description&quot;: { &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot; }
      },
      &quot;required&quot;: [&quot;name&quot;, &quot;price&quot;]
    },
    &quot;allowExternalLinks&quot;: false,
    &quot;enableWebSearch&quot;: false,
    &quot;includeSubdomains&quot;: false
  }
}
```

**Returns:**
- Extracted structured data as defined by your schema

```json
{
  &quot;content&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
      &quot;text&quot;: {
        &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Example Product&quot;,
        &quot;price&quot;: 99.99,
        &quot;description&quot;: &quot;This is an example product description&quot;
      }
    }
  ],
  &quot;isError&quot;: false
}
```

### 9. Deep Research Tool (`firecrawl_deep_research`)

Conduct deep web research on a query using intelligent crawling, search, and LLM analysis.

**Best for:**
- Complex research questions requiring multiple sources, in-depth analysis.

**Not recommended for:**
- Simple questions that can be answered with a single search
- When you need very specific information from a known page (use scrape)
- When you need results quickly (deep research can take time)

**Arguments:**
- query (string, required): The research question or topic to explore.
- maxDepth (number, optional): Maximum recursive depth for crawling/search (default: 3).
- timeLimit (number, optional): Time limit in seconds for the research session (default: 120).
- maxUrls (number, optional): Maximum number of URLs to analyze (default: 50).

**Prompt Example:**
&gt; &quot;Research the environmental impact of electric vehicles versus gasoline vehicles.&quot;

**Usage Example:**
``

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HumanSignal/label-studio]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/HumanSignal/label-studio</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/HumanSignal/label-studio</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Label Studio is a multi-type data labeling and annotation tool with standardized output format]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/HumanSignal/label-studio">HumanSignal/label-studio</a></h1>
            <p>Label Studio is a multi-type data labeling and annotation tool with standardized output format</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 22,729</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,839</p>
            <p>Stars today: 22 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/master/images/ls_github_header.png&quot;/&gt;

![GitHub](https://img.shields.io/github/license/heartexlabs/label-studio?logo=heartex) ![label-studio:build](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/workflows/label-studio:build/badge.svg) ![GitHub release](https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/heartexlabs/label-studio?include_prereleases)

[Website](https://labelstud.io/) • [Docs](https://labelstud.io/guide/) • [Twitter](https://twitter.com/heartexlabs) • [Join Slack Community &lt;img src=&quot;https://app.heartex.ai/docs/images/slack-mini.png&quot; width=&quot;18px&quot;/&gt;](https://slack.labelstudio.heartex.com/?source=github-1)


## What is Label Studio?

&lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://labelstud.io/blog/release-130.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/raw/master/docs/themes/htx/source/images/release-130/LS-Hits-v1.3.png&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; --&gt;

Label Studio is an open source data labeling tool. It lets you label data types like audio, text, images, videos, and time series with a simple and straightforward UI and export to various model formats. It can be used to prepare raw data or improve existing training data to get more accurate ML models.

- [Try out Label Studio](#try-out-label-studio)
- [What you get from Label Studio](#what-you-get-from-label-studio)
- [Included templates for labeling data in Label Studio](#included-templates-for-labeling-data-in-label-studio)
- [Set up machine learning models with Label Studio](#set-up-machine-learning-models-with-Label-Studio)
- [Integrate Label Studio with your existing tools](#integrate-label-studio-with-your-existing-tools)

![Gif of Label Studio annotating different types of data](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/master/images/annotation_examples.gif)

Have a custom dataset? You can customize Label Studio to fit your needs. Read an [introductory blog post](https://towardsdatascience.com/introducing-label-studio-a-swiss-army-knife-of-data-labeling-140c1be92881) to learn more. 

## Try out Label Studio

Install Label Studio locally, or deploy it in a cloud instance. Also you can try [Label Studio Teams](https://app.heartex.com).

- [Install locally with Docker](#install-locally-with-docker)
- [Run with Docker Compose (Label Studio + Nginx + PostgreSQL)](#run-with-docker-compose)
- [Install locally with pip](#install-locally-with-pip)
- [Install locally with Anaconda](#install-locally-with-anaconda)
- [Install for local development](#install-for-local-development)
- [Deploy in a cloud instance](#deploy-in-a-cloud-instance)

### Install locally with Docker
Official Label Studio docker image is [here](https://hub.docker.com/r/heartexlabs/label-studio) and it can be downloaded with `docker pull`. 
Run Label Studio in a Docker container and access it at `http://localhost:8080`.


```bash
docker pull heartexlabs/label-studio:latest
docker run -it -p 8080:8080 -v `pwd`/mydata:/label-studio/data heartexlabs/label-studio:latest
```
You can find all the generated assets, including SQLite3 database storage `label_studio.sqlite3` and uploaded files, in the `./mydata` directory.

#### Override default Docker install
You can override the default launch command by appending the new arguments:
```bash
docker run -it -p 8080:8080 -v `pwd`/mydata:/label-studio/data heartexlabs/label-studio:latest label-studio --log-level DEBUG
```

#### Build a local image with Docker
If you want to build a local image, run:
```bash
docker build -t heartexlabs/label-studio:latest .
```

### Run with Docker Compose
Docker Compose script provides production-ready stack consisting of the following components:

- Label Studio
- [Nginx](https://www.nginx.com/) - proxy web server used to load various static data, including uploaded audio, images, etc.
- [PostgreSQL](https://www.postgresql.org/) - production-ready database that replaces less performant SQLite3.

To start using the app from `http://localhost` run this command:
```bash
docker-compose up
```

### Install locally with pip

```bash
# Requires Python &gt;=3.7 &lt;=3.9
pip install label-studio

# Start the server at http://localhost:8080
label-studio
```

### Install locally with Anaconda

```bash
conda create --name label-studio
conda activate label-studio
pip install label-studio
```

### Install for local development

You can run the latest Label Studio version locally without installing the package with pip. 

```bash
# Install all package dependencies
pip install -e .
# Run database migrations
python label_studio/manage.py migrate
# Start the server in development mode at http://localhost:8080
python label_studio/manage.py runserver
```

### Deploy in a cloud instance

You can deploy Label Studio with one click in Heroku, Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform: 

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.herokucdn.com/deploy/button.svg&quot; height=&quot;30px&quot;&gt;](https://heroku.com/deploy?template=https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/tree/heroku-persistent-pg)
[&lt;img src=&quot;https://aka.ms/deploytoazurebutton&quot; height=&quot;30px&quot;&gt;](https://portal.azure.com/#create/Microsoft.Template/uri/https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Fheartexlabs%2Flabel-studio%2Fmaster%2Fazuredeploy.json)
[&lt;img src=&quot;https://deploy.cloud.run/button.svg&quot; height=&quot;30px&quot;&gt;](https://deploy.cloud.run)


#### Apply frontend changes

The frontend part of Label Studio app lies in the `frontend/` folder and written in React JSX. In case you&#039;ve made some changes there, the following commands should be run before building / starting the instance:

```
cd label_studio/frontend/
npm ci
npx webpack
cd ../..
python label_studio/manage.py collectstatic --no-input
```

### Troubleshoot installation
If you see any errors during installation, try to rerun the installation

```bash
pip install --ignore-installed label-studio
```

#### Install dependencies on Windows 
To run Label Studio on Windows, download and install the following wheel packages from [Gohlke builds](https://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs) to ensure you&#039;re using the correct version of Python:
- [lxml](https://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/#lxml)

```bash
# Upgrade pip 
pip install -U pip

# If you&#039;re running Win64 with Python 3.8, install the packages downloaded from Gohlke:
pip install lxml‑4.5.0‑cp38‑cp38‑win_amd64.whl

# Install label studio
pip install label-studio
```

#### Run test suite
```bash
pip install -r deploy/requirements-test.txt
cd label_studio

# postgres (assumes default postgres user,db,pass)
DJANGO_DB=default DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE=core.settings.label_studio python -m pytest -vv -n auto

# sqlite3
DJANGO_DB=sqlite DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE=core.settings.label_studio python -m pytest -vv -n auto
```


## What you get from Label Studio

![Screenshot of Label Studio data manager grid view with images](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/master/images/labelstudio-ui.gif)

- **Multi-user labeling** sign up and login, when you create an annotation it&#039;s tied to your account.
- **Multiple projects** to work on all your datasets in one instance.
- **Streamlined design** helps you focus on your task, not how to use the software.
- **Configurable label formats** let you customize the visual interface to meet your specific labeling needs.
- **Support for multiple data types** including images, audio, text, HTML, time-series, and video. 
- **Import from files or from cloud storage** in Amazon AWS S3, Google Cloud Storage, or JSON, CSV, TSV, RAR, and ZIP archives. 
- **Integration with machine learning models** so that you can visualize and compare predictions from different models and perform pre-labeling.
- **Embed it in your data pipeline** REST API makes it easy to make it a part of your pipeline

## Included templates for labeling data in Label Studio 

Label Studio includes a variety of templates to help you label your data, or you can create your own using specifically designed configuration language. The most common templates and use cases for labeling include the following cases:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/master/images/templates-categories.jpg&quot; /&gt;

## Set up machine learning models with Label Studio

Connect your favorite machine learning model using the Label Studio Machine Learning SDK. Follow these steps:

1. Start your own machine learning backend server. See [more detailed instructions](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio-ml-backend).
2. Connect Label Studio to the server on the model page found in project settings.

This lets you:

- **Pre-label** your data using model predictions. 
- Do **online learning** and retrain your model while new annotations are being created. 
- Do **active learning** by labeling only the most complex examples in your data.

## Integrate Label Studio with your existing tools

You can use Label Studio as an independent part of your machine learning workflow or integrate the frontend or backend into your existing tools.  

* Use the [Label Studio Frontend](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio-frontend) as a separate React library. See more in the [Frontend Library documentation](https://labelstud.io/guide/frontend.html). 

## Ecosystem

| Project | Description |
|-|-|
| label-studio | Server, distributed as a pip package |
| [label-studio-frontend](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio-frontend) | React and JavaScript frontend and can run standalone in a web browser or be embedded into your application. |  
| [data-manager](https://github.com/heartexlabs/dm2) | React and JavaScript frontend for managing data. Includes the Label Studio Frontend. Relies on the label-studio server or a custom backend with the expected API methods. | 
| [label-studio-converter](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio-converter) | Encode labels in the format of your favorite machine learning library | 
| [label-studio-transformers](https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio-transformers) | Transformers library connected and configured for use with Label Studio |


## Roadmap

Want to use **The Coolest Feature X** but Label Studio doesn&#039;t support it? Check out [our public roadmap](roadmap.md)!

## Citation

```tex
@misc{Label Studio,
  title={{Label Studio}: Data labeling software},
  url={https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio},
  note={Open source software available from https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio},
  author={
    Maxim Tkachenko and
    Mikhail Malyuk and
    Andrey Holmanyuk and
    Nikolai Liubimov},
  year={2020-2022},
}
```

## License

This software is licensed under the [Apache 2.0 LICENSE](/LICENSE) © [Heartex](https://www.heartex.ai/). 2020-2021

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/heartexlabs/label-studio/blob/master/images/opossum_looking.png?raw=true&quot; title=&quot;Hey everyone!&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[swagger-api/swagger-ui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Swagger UI is a collection of HTML, JavaScript, and CSS assets that dynamically generate beautiful documentation from a Swagger-compliant API.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui">swagger-api/swagger-ui</a></h1>
            <p>Swagger UI is a collection of HTML, JavaScript, and CSS assets that dynamically generate beautiful documentation from a Swagger-compliant API.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 27,520</p>
            <p>Forks: 9,115</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swagger-api/swagger.io/wordpress/images/assets/SWU-logo-clr.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;

[![NPM version](https://badge.fury.io/js/swagger-ui.svg)](http://badge.fury.io/js/swagger-ui)
[![Build Status](https://jenkins.swagger.io/view/OSS%20-%20JavaScript/job/oss-swagger-ui-master/badge/icon?subject=jenkins%20build)](https://jenkins.swagger.io/view/OSS%20-%20JavaScript/job/oss-swagger-ui-master/)
[![npm audit](https://jenkins.swagger.io/buildStatus/icon?job=oss-swagger-ui-security-audit&amp;subject=npm%20audit)](https://jenkins.swagger.io/job/oss-swagger-ui-security-audit/lastBuild/console)
[![total GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors-anon/swagger-api/swagger-ui.svg)](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/graphs/contributors)

[![monthly npm installs](https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/swagger-ui.svg?label=npm%20downloads)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui)
![docker registry](https://img.shields.io/badge/docker-docker.swagger.io%2Fswaggerapi%2Fswagger--ui-blue)
![monthly packagist installs](https://img.shields.io/packagist/dm/swagger-api/swagger-ui.svg?label=packagist%20installs)
[![gzip size](https://img.shields.io/bundlephobia/minzip/swagger-ui.svg?label=gzip%20size)](https://bundlephobia.com/package/swagger-ui)

## Introduction
[Swagger UI](https://swagger.io/tools/swagger-ui/) allows anyone — be it your development team or your end consumers — to visualize and interact with the API’s resources without having any of the implementation logic in place. It’s automatically generated from your OpenAPI (formerly known as Swagger) Specification, with the visual documentation making it easy for back end implementation and client side consumption.

## General
**👉🏼 Want to score an easy open-source contribution?** Check out our [Good first issue](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22Good+first+issue%22) label.

**🕰️ Looking for the older version of Swagger UI?** Refer to the [*2.x* branch](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/2.x).


This repository publishes three different NPM modules:

* [swagger-ui](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui) is a traditional npm module intended for use in single-page applications that are capable of resolving dependencies (via Webpack, Browserify, etc.).
* [swagger-ui-dist](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui-dist) is a dependency-free module that includes everything you need to serve Swagger UI in a server-side project, or a single-page application that can&#039;t resolve npm module dependencies.
* [swagger-ui-react](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui-react) is Swagger UI packaged as a React component for use in React applications.

We strongly suggest that you use `swagger-ui` instead of `swagger-ui-dist` if you&#039;re building a single-page application, since `swagger-ui-dist` is significantly larger.

If you are looking for plain ol&#039; HTML/JS/CSS, [download the latest release](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/releases/latest) and copy the contents of the `/dist` folder to your server.


## Compatibility
The OpenAPI Specification has undergone 5 revisions since initial creation in 2010.  Compatibility between Swagger UI and the OpenAPI Specification is as follows:

| Swagger UI Version | Release Date | OpenAPI Spec compatibility                           | Notes                                                                 |
|--------------------|--------------|------------------------------------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------|
| 5.19.0             | 2025-02-17   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3, 3.0.4, 3.1.0, 3.1.1 | [tag v5.19.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v5.19.0) |
| 5.0.0              | 2023-06-12   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3, 3.1.0               | [tag v5.0.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v5.0.0)   |
| 4.0.0              | 2021-11-03   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3                      | [tag v4.0.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v4.0.0)   |
| 3.18.3             | 2018-08-03   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3                      | [tag v3.18.3](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v3.18.3) |
| 3.0.21             | 2017-07-26   | 2.0                                                  | [tag v3.0.21](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v3.0.21) |
| 2.2.10             | 2017-01-04   | 1.1, 1.2, 2.0                                        | [tag v2.2.10](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.2.10) |
| 2.1.5              | 2016-07-20   | 1.1, 1.2, 2.0                                        | [tag v2.1.5](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.1.5)   |
| 2.0.24             | 2014-09-12   | 1.1, 1.2                                             | [tag v2.0.24](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.0.24) |
| 1.0.13             | 2013-03-08   | 1.1, 1.2                                             | [tag v1.0.13](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v1.0.13) |
| 1.0.1              | 2011-10-11   | 1.0, 1.1                                             | [tag v1.0.1](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v1.0.1)   |

## Anonymized analytics

SwaggerUI uses [Scarf](https://scarf.sh/) to collect [anonymized installation analytics](https://github.com/scarf-sh/scarf-js?tab=readme-ov-file#as-a-user-of-a-package-using-scarf-js-what-information-does-scarf-js-send-about-me). These analytics help support the maintainers of this library and ONLY run during installation. To [opt out](https://github.com/scarf-sh/scarf-js?tab=readme-ov-file#as-a-user-of-a-package-using-scarf-js-how-can-i-opt-out-of-analytics), you can set the `scarfSettings.enabled` field to `false` in your project&#039;s `package.json`:

```
// package.json
{
  // ...
  &quot;scarfSettings&quot;: {
    &quot;enabled&quot;: false
  }
  // ...
}
```

Alternatively, you can set the environment variable `SCARF_ANALYTICS` to `false` as part of the environment that installs your npm packages, e.g., `SCARF_ANALYTICS=false npm install`.

## Documentation

#### Usage
- [Installation](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/installation.md)
- [Configuration](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/configuration.md)
- [CORS](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/cors.md)
- [OAuth2](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/oauth2.md)
- [Deep Linking](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/deep-linking.md)
- [Limitations](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/limitations.md)
- [Version detection](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/version-detection.md)

#### Customization
- [Overview](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/overview.md)
- [Plugin API](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/plugin-api.md)
- [Custom layout](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/custom-layout.md)

#### Development
- [Setting up](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/development/setting-up.md)
- [Scripts](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/development/scripts.md)

#### Contributing
- [Contributing](https://github.com/swagger-api/.github/blob/HEAD/CONTRIBUTING.md)

##### Integration Tests

You will need JDK of version 7 or higher as instructed here
https://nightwatchjs.org/guide/getting-started/installation.html#install-selenium-server

Integration tests can be run locally with `npm run e2e` - be sure you aren&#039;t running a dev server when testing!

### Browser support
Swagger UI works in the latest versions of Chrome, Safari, Firefox, and Edge.

### Known Issues

To help with the migration, here are the currently known issues with 3.X. This list will update regularly, and will not include features that were not implemented in previous versions.

- Only part of the parameters previously supported are available.
- The JSON Form Editor is not implemented.
- Support for `collectionFormat` is partial.
- l10n (translations) is not implemented.
- Relative path support for external files is not implemented.

## Security contact

Please disclose any security-related issues or vulnerabilities by emailing [security@swagger.io](mailto:security@swagger.io), instead of using the public issue tracker.

## License

SwaggerUI is licensed under [Apache 2.0 license](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/master/LICENSE).
SwaggerUI comes with an explicit [NOTICE](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/master/NOTICE) file
containing additional legal notices and information.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[upstash/context7]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/upstash/context7</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/upstash/context7</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Context7 MCP Server -- Up-to-date code documentation for LLMs and AI code editors]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/upstash/context7">upstash/context7</a></h1>
            <p>Context7 MCP Server -- Up-to-date code documentation for LLMs and AI code editors</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,257</p>
            <p>Forks: 759</p>
            <p>Stars today: 240 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Context7 MCP - Up-to-date Code Docs For Any Prompt

[![Website](https://img.shields.io/badge/Website-context7.com-blue)](https://context7.com) [![smithery badge](https://smithery.ai/badge/@upstash/context7-mcp)](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp) [&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-VS_Code?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Context7%20MCP&amp;color=0098FF&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)

[![繁體中文](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-繁體中文-yellow)](./docs/README.zh-TW.md) [![简体中文](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-简体中文-yellow)](./docs/README.zh-CN.md) [![日本語](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-日本語-b7003a)](./docs/README.ja.md) [![한국어 문서](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-한국어-green)](./docs/README.ko.md) [![Documentación en Español](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Español-orange)](./docs/README.es.md) [![Documentation en Français](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Français-blue)](./docs/README.fr.md) [![Documentação em Português (Brasil)](&lt;https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Português%20(Brasil)-purple&gt;)](./docs/README.pt-BR.md) [![Documentazione in italiano](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Italian-red)](./docs/README.it.md) [![Dokumentasi Bahasa Indonesia](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Bahasa%20Indonesia-pink)](./docs/README.id-ID.md) [![Dokumentation auf Deutsch](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Deutsch-darkgreen)](./docs/README.de.md) [![Документация на русском языке](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Русский-darkblue)](./docs/README.ru.md) [![Türkçe Doküman](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Türkçe-blue)](./docs/README.tr.md) [![Arabic Documentation](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Arabic-white)](./docs/README.ar.md)

## ❌ Without Context7

LLMs rely on outdated or generic information about the libraries you use. You get:

- ❌ Code examples are outdated and based on year-old training data
- ❌ Hallucinated APIs don&#039;t even exist
- ❌ Generic answers for old package versions

## ✅ With Context7

Context7 MCP pulls up-to-date, version-specific documentation and code examples straight from the source — and places them directly into your prompt.

Add `use context7` to your prompt in Cursor:

```txt
Create a basic Next.js project with app router. use context7
```

```txt
Create a script to delete the rows where the city is &quot;&quot; given PostgreSQL credentials. use context7
```

Context7 fetches up-to-date code examples and documentation right into your LLM&#039;s context.

- 1️⃣ Write your prompt naturally
- 2️⃣ Tell the LLM to `use context7`
- 3️⃣ Get working code answers

No tab-switching, no hallucinated APIs that don&#039;t exist, no outdated code generations.

## 📚 Adding Projects

Check out our [project addition guide](./docs/adding-projects.md) to learn how to add (or update) your favorite libraries to Context7.

## 🛠️ Installation

### Requirements

- Node.js &gt;= v18.0.0
- Cursor, Windsurf, Claude Desktop or another MCP Client

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Installing via Smithery&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

To install Context7 MCP Server for any client automatically via [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp):

```bash
npx -y @smithery/cli@latest install @upstash/context7-mcp --client &lt;CLIENT_NAME&gt; --key &lt;YOUR_SMITHERY_KEY&gt;
```

You can find your Smithery key in the [Smithery.ai webpage](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Cursor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Go to: `Settings` -&gt; `Cursor Settings` -&gt; `MCP` -&gt; `Add new global MCP server`

Pasting the following configuration into your Cursor `~/.cursor/mcp.json` file is the recommended approach. You may also install in a specific project by creating `.cursor/mcp.json` in your project folder. See [Cursor MCP docs](https://docs.cursor.com/context/model-context-protocol) for more info.

&gt; Since Cursor 1.0, you can click the install button below for instant one-click installation.

#### Cursor Remote Server Connection

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL21jcC5jb250ZXh0Ny5jb20vbWNwIn0%3D)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### Cursor Local Server Connection

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoibnB4IC15IEB1cHN0YXNoL2NvbnRleHQ3LW1jcCJ9)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Alternative: Use Bun&lt;/summary&gt;

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoiYnVueCAteSBAdXBzdGFzaC9jb250ZXh0Ny1tY3AifQ%3D%3D)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;bunx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Alternative: Use Deno&lt;/summary&gt;

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoiZGVubyBydW4gLS1hbGxvdy1lbnYgLS1hbGxvdy1uZXQgbnBtOkB1cHN0YXNoL2NvbnRleHQ3LW1jcCJ9)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;deno&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;run&quot;, &quot;--allow-env=NO_DEPRECATION,TRACE_DEPRECATION&quot;, &quot;--allow-net&quot;, &quot;npm:@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Windsurf&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Windsurf MCP config file. See [Windsurf MCP docs](https://docs.windsurf.com/windsurf/mcp) for more info.

#### Windsurf Remote Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;serverUrl&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/sse&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### Windsurf Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in VS Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

[&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-VS_Code?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Context7%20MCP&amp;color=0098FF&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)
[&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code Insiders (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code_Insiders-VS_Code_Insiders?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Context7%20MCP&amp;color=24bfa5&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode-insiders%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)

Add this to your VS Code MCP config file. See [VS Code MCP docs](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/copilot/chat/mcp-servers) for more info.

#### VS Code Remote Server Connection

```json
&quot;mcp&quot;: {
  &quot;servers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### VS Code Local Server Connection

```json
&quot;mcp&quot;: {
  &quot;servers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;stdio&quot;,
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Visual Studio 2022&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

You can configure Context7 MCP in Visual Studio 2022 by following the [Visual Studio MCP Servers documentation](https://learn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/ide/mcp-servers?view=vs-2022).

Add this to your Visual Studio MCP config file (see the [Visual Studio docs](https://learn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/ide/mcp-servers?view=vs-2022) for details):

```json
{
  &quot;mcp&quot;: {
    &quot;servers&quot;: {
      &quot;context7&quot;: {
        &quot;type&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
        &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

Or, for a local server:

```json
{
  &quot;mcp&quot;: {
    &quot;servers&quot;: {
      &quot;context7&quot;: {
        &quot;type&quot;: &quot;stdio&quot;,
        &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
        &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
      }
    }
  }
}
```

For more information and troubleshooting, refer to the [Visual Studio MCP Servers documentation](https://learn.microsoft.com/visualstudio/ide/mcp-servers?view=vs-2022).
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Zed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

It can be installed via [Zed Extensions](https://zed.dev/extensions?query=Context7) or you can add this to your Zed `settings.json`. See [Zed Context Server docs](https://zed.dev/docs/assistant/context-servers) for more info.

```json
{
  &quot;context_servers&quot;: {
    &quot;Context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: {
        &quot;path&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
        &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
      },
      &quot;settings&quot;: {}
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Gemini CLI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Gemini CLI Configuration](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/blob/main/docs/cli/configuration.md) for details.

1.  Open the Gemini CLI settings file. The location is `~/.gemini/settings.json` (where `~` is your home directory).
2.  Add the following to the `mcpServers` object in your `settings.json` file:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

If the `mcpServers` object does not exist, create it.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Claude Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Run this command. See [Claude Code MCP docs](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/agents-and-tools/claude-code/tutorials#set-up-model-context-protocol-mcp) for more info.

#### Claude Code Remote Server Connection

```sh
claude mcp add --transport http context7 https://mcp.context7.com/mcp
```

Or using SSE transport:

```sh
claude mcp add --transport sse context7 https://mcp.context7.com/sse
```

#### Claude Code Local Server Connection

```sh
claude mcp add context7 -- npx -y @upstash/context7-mcp
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Claude Desktop&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Claude Desktop `claude_desktop_config.json` file. See [Claude Desktop MCP docs](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/quickstart/user) for more info.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;Context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Install in Cline&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/summary&gt;

You can easily install Context7 through the [Cline MCP Server Marketplace](https://cline.bot/mcp-marketplace) by following these instructions:

1. Open **Cline**.
1. Click the hamburger menu icon (☰) to enter the **MCP Servers** section.
2. Use the search bar within the **Marketplace** tab to find *Context7*.
3. Click the **Install** button.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in BoltAI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Open the &quot;Settings&quot; page of the app, navigate to &quot;Plugins,&quot; and enter the following JSON:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

Once saved, enter in the chat `get-library-docs` followed by your Context7 documentation ID (e.g., `get-library-docs /nuxt/ui`). More information is available on [BoltAI&#039;s Documentation site](https://docs.boltai.com/docs/plugins/mcp-servers). For BoltAI on iOS, [see this guide](https://docs.boltai.com/docs/boltai-mobile/mcp-servers).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Using Docker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

If you prefer to run the MCP server in a Docker container:

1. **Build the Docker Image:**

   First, create a `Dockerfile` in the project root (or anywhere you prefer):

   &lt;details&gt;
   &lt;summary&gt;Click to see Dockerfile content&lt;/summary&gt;

   ```Dockerfile
   FROM node:18-alpine

   WORKDIR /app

   # Install the latest version globally
   RUN npm install -g @upstash/context7-mcp

   # Expose default port if needed (optional, depends on MCP client interaction)
   # EXPOSE 3000

   # Default command to run the server
   CMD [&quot;context7-mcp&quot;]
   ```

   &lt;/details&gt;

   Then, build the image using a tag (e.g., `context7-mcp`). **Make sure Docker Desktop (or the Docker daemon) is running.** Run the following command in the same directory where you saved the `Dockerfile`:

   ```bash
   docker build -t context7-mcp .
   ```

2. **Configure Your MCP Client:**

   Update your MCP client&#039;s configuration to use the Docker command.

   _Example for a cline_mcp_settings.json:_

   ```json
   {
     &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
       &quot;Сontext7&quot;: {
         &quot;autoApprove&quot;: [],
         &quot;disabled&quot;: false,
         &quot;timeout&quot;: 60,
         &quot;command&quot;: &quot;docker&quot;,
         &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;run&quot;, &quot;-i&quot;, &quot;--rm&quot;, &quot;context7-mcp&quot;],
         &quot;transportType&quot;: &quot;stdio&quot;
       }
     }
   }
   ```

   _Note: This is an example configuration. Please refer to the specific examples for your MCP client (like Cursor, VS Code, etc.) earlier in this README to adapt the structure (e.g., `mcpServers` vs `servers`). Also, ensure the image name in `args` matches the tag used during the `docker build` command._

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Windows&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

The configuration on Windows is slightly different compared to Linux or macOS (_`Cline` is used in the example_). The same principle applies to other editors; refer to the configuration of `command` and `args`.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;github.com/upstash/context7-mcp&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;cmd&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;/c&quot;, &quot;npx&quot;, &quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp@latest&quot;],
      &quot;disabled&quot;: false,
      &quot;autoApprove&quot;: []
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Augment Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

To configure Context7 MCP in Augment Code, you can use either the graphical interface or manual configuration.

### **A. Using the Augment Code UI**

1. Click the hamburger menu.
2. Select **Settings**.
3. Navigate to the **Tools** section.
4. Click the **+ Add MCP** button.
5. Enter the following command:

   ```
   npx -y @upstash/context7-mcp@latest
   ```

6. Name the MCP: **Context7**.
7. Click the **Add** button.

Once the MCP server is added, you can start using Context7&#039;s up-to-date code documentation features directly within Augment Code.

---

### **B. Manual Configuration**

1. Press Cmd/Ctrl Shift P or go to the hamburger menu in the Augment panel
2. Select Edit Settings
3. Under Advanced, click Edit in settings.json
4. Add the server configuration to the `mcpServers` array in the `augment.advanced` object

&quot;augment.advanced&quot;: {
&quot;mcpServers&quot;: [
{
&quot;name&quot;: &quot;context7&quot;,
&quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
&quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
}
]
}

Once the MCP server is added, restart your editor. If you receive any errors, check the syntax to make sure closing brackets or commas are not missing.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Roo Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Roo Code MCP configuration file. See [Roo Code MCP docs](https://docs.roocode.com/features/mcp/using-mcp-in-roo) for more info.

#### Roo Code Remote Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;streamable-http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### Roo Code Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Zencoder&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

To configure Context7 MCP in Zencoder, follow these steps:

1. Go to the Zencoder menu (...)
2. From the dropdown menu, select Agent tools
3. Click on the Add custom MCP
4. Add the name and server configuration from below, and make sure to hit the Install button

```json
{
    &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
    &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;-y&quot;,
        &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp@latest&quot;
    ]
}
```

Once the MCP server is added, you can easily continue using it.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Amazon Q Developer CLI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Amazon Q Developer CLI configuration file. See [Amazon Q Developer CLI docs](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-mcp-configuration.html) for more details.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp@latest&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Qodo Gen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Qodo Gen docs](https://docs.qodo.ai/qodo-documentation/qodo-gen/qodo-gen-chat/agentic-mode/agentic-tools-mcps) for more details.

1. Open Qodo Gen chat panel in VSCode or IntelliJ.
2. Click Connect more tools.
3. Click + Add new MCP.
4. Add the following configuration:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in JetBrains AI Assistant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [JetBrains AI Assistant Documentation](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/ai-assistant/configure-an-mcp-server.html) for more details.

1. In JetBrains IDEs go to `Settings` -&gt; `Tools` -&gt; `AI Assistant` -&gt; `Model Context Protocol (MCP)`
2. Click `+ Add`.
3. Click on `Command` in the top-left corner of the dialog and select the As JSON option from the list
4. Add this configuration and click `OK`

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

5. Click `Apply` to save changes.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Warp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Warp Model Context Protocol Documentation](https://docs.warp.dev/knowledge-and-collaboration/mcp#adding-an-mcp-server) for details.

1. Navigate `Settings` &gt; `AI` &gt; `Manage MCP servers`.
2. Add a new MCP server by clicking the `+ Add` button.
3. Paste the configuration given below:

```json
{
  &quot;Context7&quot;: {
    &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
    &quot;args&quot;: [
      &quot;-y&quot;,
      &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;
    ],
    &quot;env&quot;: {},
    &quot;working_directory&quot;: null,
    &quot;start_on_launch&quot;: true
  }
}
```

4. Click `Save` to apply the changes.

&lt;/details&gt;

## 🔨 Available Tools

Context7 MCP provides the following tools that LLMs can use:

- `resolve-library-id`: Resolves a general library name into a Context7-compatible library ID.

  - `libraryName` (required): The name of the library to search for

- `get-library-docs`: Fetches documentation for a library using a Context7-compatible library ID.
  - `context7CompatibleLibraryID` (required): Exact Context7-compatible library ID (e.g., `/mongodb/docs`, `/vercel/next.js`)
  - `topic` (optional): Focus the docs on a specific topic (e.g., &quot;routing&quot;, &quot;hooks&quot;)
  - `tokens` (optional, default 10000): Max number of tokens to return. Values less than the default value of 10000 are automatically increased to 10000.

## 💻 Development

Clone the project and install dependencies:

```bash
bun i
```

Build:

```bash
bun run build
```

Run the server:

```bash
bun run dist/index.js
```

### CLI Arguments

`context7-mcp` accepts the following CLI flags:

- `--transport &lt;stdio|http|sse&gt;` – Transport to use (`stdio` by default).
- `--port &lt;number&gt;` – Port to listen on when using `http` or `sse` transport (default `3000`).

Example with http transport and port 8080:

```bash
bun run dist/index.js --transport http --port 8080
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Local Configuration Example&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;tsx&quot;, &quot;/path/to/folder/context7-mcp/src/index.ts&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Testing with MCP Inspector&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```bash
npx -y @modelcontextprotocol/inspector npx @upstash/context7-mcp
```

&lt;/details&gt;

## 🚨 Troubleshooting

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Module Not Found Errors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

If you encounter `ERR_MODULE_NOT_FOUND`, try using `bunx` instead of `npx`:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;bunx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

This often resolves module resolution issues in environments where `npx` doesn&#039;

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[danielmiessler/fabric]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. It provides a modular system for solving specific problems using a crowdsourced set of AI prompts that can be used anywhere.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric">danielmiessler/fabric</a></h1>
            <p>Fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. It provides a modular system for solving specific problems using a crowdsourced set of AI prompts that can be used anywhere.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 31,679</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,292</p>
            <p>Stars today: 46 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
Fabric is graciously supported by…

[![Github Repo Tagline](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/96ab3d81-9b13-4df4-ba09-75dee7a5c3d2)](https://warp.dev/fabric)

&lt;img src=&quot;./images/fabric-logo-gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;fabriclogo&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;

# `fabric`

![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/mission-human_flourishing_via_AI_augmentation-purple)
&lt;br /&gt;
![GitHub top language](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/top/danielmiessler/fabric)
![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/danielmiessler/fabric)
[![License: MIT](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-green.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;align center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;fabric&lt;/code&gt; is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

[Updates](#updates) •
[What and Why](#what-and-why) •
[Philosophy](#philosophy) •
[Installation](#installation) •
[Usage](#usage) •
[Examples](#examples) •
[Just Use the Patterns](#just-use-the-patterns) •
[Custom Patterns](#custom-patterns) •
[Helper Apps](#helper-apps) •
[Meta](#meta)

![Screenshot of fabric](images/fabric-summarize.png)

&lt;/div&gt;

## What and why

Since the start of modern AI in late 2022 we&#039;ve seen an **_extraordinary_** number of AI applications for accomplishing tasks. There are thousands of websites, chatbots, mobile apps, and other interfaces for using all the differnet AI out there.

It&#039;s all really exciting and powerful, but _it&#039;s not easy to integrate this functionality into our lives._

&lt;p class=&quot;align center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;In other words, AI doesn&#039;t have a capabilities problem—it has an &lt;em&gt;integration&lt;/em&gt; problem.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

**Fabric was created to address this by creating and organizating the fundamental units of AI—the prompts themselves!**

Fabric organizes prompts by real-world task, allowing people to create, collect, and organize their most important AI solutions in a single place for use in their favorite tools. And if you&#039;re command-line focused, you can use Fabric itself as the interface!

## Intro videos

Keep in mind that many of these were recorded when Fabric was Python-based, so remember to use the current [install instructions](#installation) below.

- [Network Chuck](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbDyjIIGaxQ)
- [David Bombal](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vF-MQmVxnCs)
- [My Own Intro to the Tool](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPEyyigh10g)
- [More Fabric YouTube Videos](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=fabric+ai)


## Navigation

- [`fabric`](#fabric)
  - [Navigation](#navigation)
  - [Updates](#updates)
  - [What and why](#what-and-why)
  - [Intro videos](#intro-videos)
  - [Philosophy](#philosophy)
    - [Breaking problems into components](#breaking-problems-into-components)
    - [Too many prompts](#too-many-prompts)
  - [Installation](#installation)
    - [Get Latest Release Binaries](#get-latest-release-binaries)
      - [Windows](#windows)
      - [macOS (arm64)](#macos-arm64)
      - [macOS (amd64)](#macos-amd64)
      - [Linux (amd64)](#linux-amd64)
      - [Linux (arm64)](#linux-arm64)
    - [Using package managers](#using-package-managers)
      - [macOS (Homebrew)](#macos-homebrew)
      - [Arch Linux (AUR)](#arch-linux-aur)
    - [From Source](#from-source)
    - [Environment Variables](#environment-variables)
    - [Setup](#setup)
    - [Add aliases for all patterns](#add-aliases-for-all-patterns)
      - [Save your files in markdown using aliases](#save-your-files-in-markdown-using-aliases)
    - [Migration](#migration)
    - [Upgrading](#upgrading)
    - [Shell Completions](#shell-completions)
      - [Zsh Completion](#zsh-completion)
      - [Bash Completion](#bash-completion)
      - [Fish Completion](#fish-completion)
  - [Usage](#usage)
  - [Our approach to prompting](#our-approach-to-prompting)
  - [Examples](#examples)
  - [Just use the Patterns](#just-use-the-patterns)
    - [Prompt Strategies](#prompt-strategies)
  - [Custom Patterns](#custom-patterns)
  - [Helper Apps](#helper-apps)
    - [`to_pdf`](#to_pdf)
    - [`to_pdf` Installation](#to_pdf-installation)
    - [`code_helper`](#code_helper)
  - [pbpaste](#pbpaste)
  - [Web Interface](#web-interface)
    - [Installing](#installing)
    - [Streamlit UI](#streamlit-ui)
      - [Clipboard Support](#clipboard-support)
  - [Meta](#meta)
    - [Primary contributors](#primary-contributors)
    - [Contributors](#contributors)

&lt;br /&gt;

## Updates

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt;June 17, 2025
&gt;
&gt;- Fabric now supports Perplexity AI. Configure it by using `fabric -S` to add your Perlexity AI API Key,
&gt;   and then try:
&gt;
&gt;   ```bash
&gt;   fabric -m sonar-pro &quot;What is the latest world news?&quot;
&gt;   ```
&gt;
&gt;June 11, 2025
&gt;
&gt;- Fabric&#039;s YouTube transcription now needs `yt-dlp` to be installed. Make sure to install the latest
&gt; version (2025.06.09 as of this note). The YouTube API key is only needed for comments (the `--comments` flag)
&gt; and metadata extraction (the `--metadata` flag).

## Philosophy

&gt; AI isn&#039;t a thing; it&#039;s a _magnifier_ of a thing. And that thing is **human creativity**.

We believe the purpose of technology is to help humans flourish, so when we talk about AI we start with the **human** problems we want to solve.

### Breaking problems into components

Our approach is to break problems into individual pieces (see below) and then apply AI to them one at a time. See below for some examples.

&lt;img width=&quot;2078&quot; alt=&quot;augmented_challenges&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/assets/50654/31997394-85a9-40c2-879b-b347e4701f06&quot;&gt;

### Too many prompts

Prompts are good for this, but the biggest challenge I faced in 2023——which still exists today—is **the sheer number of AI prompts out there**. We all have prompts that are useful, but it&#039;s hard to discover new ones, know if they are good or not, _and manage different versions of the ones we like_.

One of `fabric`&#039;s primary features is helping people collect and integrate prompts, which we call _Patterns_, into various parts of their lives.

Fabric has Patterns for all sorts of life and work activities, including:

- Extracting the most interesting parts of YouTube videos and podcasts
- Writing an essay in your own voice with just an idea as an input
- Summarizing opaque academic papers
- Creating perfectly matched AI art prompts for a piece of writing
- Rating the quality of content to see if you want to read/watch the whole thing
- Getting summaries of long, boring content
- Explaining code to you
- Turning bad documentation into usable documentation
- Creating social media posts from any content input
- And a million more…

## Installation

To install Fabric, you can use the latest release binaries or install it from the source.

### Get Latest Release Binaries

#### Windows

`https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest/download/fabric-windows-amd64.exe`

#### macOS (arm64)

`curl -L https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest/download/fabric-darwin-arm64 &gt; fabric &amp;&amp; chmod +x fabric &amp;&amp; ./fabric --version`

#### macOS (amd64)

`curl -L https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest/download/fabric-darwin-amd64 &gt; fabric &amp;&amp; chmod +x fabric &amp;&amp; ./fabric --version`

#### Linux (amd64)

`curl -L https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest/download/fabric-linux-amd64 &gt; fabric &amp;&amp; chmod +x fabric &amp;&amp; ./fabric --version`

#### Linux (arm64)

`curl -L https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest/download/fabric-linux-arm64 &gt; fabric &amp;&amp; chmod +x fabric &amp;&amp; ./fabric --version`

### Using package managers

**NOTE:** using Homebrew or the Arch Linux package managers makes `fabric` available as `fabric-ai`, so add
the following alias to your shell startup files to account for this:

```bash
alias fabric=&#039;fabric-ai&#039;
```

#### macOS (Homebrew)

`brew install fabric-ai`

#### Arch Linux (AUR)

`yay -S fabric-ai`

### From Source

To install Fabric, [make sure Go is installed](https://go.dev/doc/install), and then run the following command.

```bash
# Install Fabric directly from the repo
go install github.com/danielmiessler/fabric@latest
```

### Environment Variables

You may need to set some environment variables in your `~/.bashrc` on linux or `~/.zshrc` file on mac to be able to run the `fabric` command. Here is an example of what you can add:

For Intel based macs or linux

```bash
# Golang environment variables
export GOROOT=/usr/local/go
export GOPATH=$HOME/go

# Update PATH to include GOPATH and GOROOT binaries
export PATH=$GOPATH/bin:$GOROOT/bin:$HOME/.local/bin:$PATH
```

for Apple Silicon based macs

```bash
# Golang environment variables
export GOROOT=$(brew --prefix go)/libexec
export GOPATH=$HOME/go
export PATH=$GOPATH/bin:$GOROOT/bin:$HOME/.local/bin:$PATH
```

### Setup

Now run the following command

```bash
# Run the setup to set up your directories and keys
fabric --setup
```

If everything works you are good to go.

### Add aliases for all patterns

In order to add aliases for all your patterns and use them directly as commands ie. `summarize` instead of `fabric --pattern summarize`
You can add the following to your `.zshrc` or `.bashrc` file.

```bash
# Loop through all files in the ~/.config/fabric/patterns directory
for pattern_file in $HOME/.config/fabric/patterns/*; do
    # Get the base name of the file (i.e., remove the directory path)
    pattern_name=$(basename &quot;$pattern_file&quot;)

    # Create an alias in the form: alias pattern_name=&quot;fabric --pattern pattern_name&quot;
    alias_command=&quot;alias $pattern_name=&#039;fabric --pattern $pattern_name&#039;&quot;

    # Evaluate the alias command to add it to the current shell
    eval &quot;$alias_command&quot;
done

yt() {
    if [ &quot;$#&quot; -eq 0 ] || [ &quot;$#&quot; -gt 2 ]; then
        echo &quot;Usage: yt [-t | --timestamps] youtube-link&quot;
        echo &quot;Use the &#039;-t&#039; flag to get the transcript with timestamps.&quot;
        return 1
    fi

    transcript_flag=&quot;--transcript&quot;
    if [ &quot;$1&quot; = &quot;-t&quot; ] || [ &quot;$1&quot; = &quot;--timestamps&quot; ]; then
        transcript_flag=&quot;--transcript-with-timestamps&quot;
        shift
    fi
    local video_link=&quot;$1&quot;
    fabric -y &quot;$video_link&quot; $transcript_flag
}
```

You can add the below code for the equivalent aliases inside PowerShell by running `notepad $PROFILE` inside a PowerShell window:

```powershell
# Path to the patterns directory
$patternsPath = Join-Path $HOME &quot;.config/fabric/patterns&quot;
foreach ($patternDir in Get-ChildItem -Path $patternsPath -Directory) {
    $patternName = $patternDir.Name

    # Dynamically define a function for each pattern
    $functionDefinition = @&quot;
function $patternName {
    [CmdletBinding()]
    param(
        [Parameter(ValueFromPipeline = `$true)]
        [string] `$InputObject,

        [Parameter(ValueFromRemainingArguments = `$true)]
        [String[]] `$patternArgs
    )

    begin {
        # Initialize an array to collect pipeline input
        `$collector = @()
    }

    process {
        # Collect pipeline input objects
        if (`$InputObject) {
            `$collector += `$InputObject
        }
    }

    end {
        # Join all pipeline input into a single string, separated by newlines
        `$pipelineContent = `$collector -join &quot;`n&quot;

        # If there&#039;s pipeline input, include it in the call to fabric
        if (`$pipelineContent) {
            `$pipelineContent | fabric --pattern $patternName `$patternArgs
        } else {
            # No pipeline input; just call fabric with the additional args
            fabric --pattern $patternName `$patternArgs
        }
    }
}
&quot;@
    # Add the function to the current session
    Invoke-Expression $functionDefinition
}

# Define the &#039;yt&#039; function as well
function yt {
    [CmdletBinding()]
    param(
        [Parameter()]
        [Alias(&quot;timestamps&quot;)]
        [switch]$t,

        [Parameter(Position = 0, ValueFromPipeline = $true)]
        [string]$videoLink
    )

    begin {
        $transcriptFlag = &quot;--transcript&quot;
        if ($t) {
            $transcriptFlag = &quot;--transcript-with-timestamps&quot;
        }
    }

    process {
        if (-not $videoLink) {
            Write-Error &quot;Usage: yt [-t | --timestamps] youtube-link&quot;
            return
        }
    }

    end {
        if ($videoLink) {
            # Execute and allow output to flow through the pipeline
            fabric -y $videoLink $transcriptFlag
        }
    }
}
```

This also creates a `yt` alias that allows you to use `yt https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4b0iet22VIk` to get transcripts, comments, and metadata.

#### Save your files in markdown using aliases

If in addition to the above aliases you would like to have the option to save the output to your favorite markdown note vault like Obsidian then instead of the above add the following to your `.zshrc` or `.bashrc` file:

```bash
# Define the base directory for Obsidian notes
obsidian_base=&quot;/path/to/obsidian&quot;

# Loop through all files in the ~/.config/fabric/patterns directory
for pattern_file in ~/.config/fabric/patterns/*; do
    # Get the base name of the file (i.e., remove the directory path)
    pattern_name=$(basename &quot;$pattern_file&quot;)

    # Remove any existing alias with the same name
    unalias &quot;$pattern_name&quot; 2&gt;/dev/null

    # Define a function dynamically for each pattern
    eval &quot;
    $pattern_name() {
        local title=\$1
        local date_stamp=\$(date +&#039;%Y-%m-%d&#039;)
        local output_path=\&quot;\$obsidian_base/\${date_stamp}-\${title}.md\&quot;

        # Check if a title was provided
        if [ -n \&quot;\$title\&quot; ]; then
            # If a title is provided, use the output path
            fabric --pattern \&quot;$pattern_name\&quot; -o \&quot;\$output_path\&quot;
        else
            # If no title is provided, use --stream
            fabric --pattern \&quot;$pattern_name\&quot; --stream
        fi
    }
    &quot;
done
```

This will allow you to use the patterns as aliases like in the above for example `summarize` instead of `fabric --pattern summarize --stream`, however if you pass in an extra argument like this `summarize &quot;my_article_title&quot;` your output will be saved in the destination that you set in `obsidian_base=&quot;/path/to/obsidian&quot;` in the following format `YYYY-MM-DD-my_article_title.md` where the date gets autogenerated for you.
You can tweak the date format by tweaking the `date_stamp` format.

### Migration

If you have the Legacy (Python) version installed and want to migrate to the Go version, here&#039;s how you do it. It&#039;s basically two steps: 1) uninstall the Python version, and 2) install the Go version.

```bash
# Uninstall Legacy Fabric
pipx uninstall fabric

# Clear any old Fabric aliases
(check your .bashrc, .zshrc, etc.)
# Install the Go version
go install github.com/danielmiessler/fabric@latest
# Run setup for the new version. Important because things have changed
fabric --setup
```

Then [set your environmental variables](#environment-variables) as shown above.

### Upgrading

The great thing about Go is that it&#039;s super easy to upgrade. Just run the same command you used to install it in the first place and you&#039;ll always get the latest version.

```bash
go install github.com/danielmiessler/fabric@latest
```

### Shell Completions

Fabric provides shell completion scripts for Zsh, Bash, and Fish
shells, making it easier to use the CLI by providing tab completion
for commands and options.

#### Zsh Completion

To enable Zsh completion:

```bash
# Copy the completion file to a directory in your $fpath
mkdir -p ~/.zsh/completions
cp completions/_fabric ~/.zsh/completions/

# Add the directory to fpath in your .zshrc before compinit
echo &#039;fpath=(~/.zsh/completions $fpath)&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.zshrc
echo &#039;autoload -Uz compinit &amp;&amp; compinit&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.zshrc
```

#### Bash Completion

To enable Bash completion:

```bash
# Source the completion script in your .bashrc
echo &#039;source /path/to/fabric/completions/fabric.bash&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc

# Or copy to the system-wide bash completion directory
sudo cp completions/fabric.bash /etc/bash_completion.d/
```

#### Fish Completion

To enable Fish completion:

```bash
# Copy the completion file to the fish completions directory
mkdir -p ~/.config/fish/completions
cp completions/fabric.fish ~/.config/fish/completions/
```

## Usage

Once you have it all set up, here&#039;s how to use it.

```bash
fabric -h
```

```plaintext

Usage:
  fabric [OPTIONS]

Application Options:
  -p, --pattern=                    Choose a pattern from the available patterns
  -v, --variable=                   Values for pattern variables, e.g. -v=#role:expert -v=#points:30
  -C, --context=                    Choose a context from the available contexts
      --session=                    Choose a session from the available sessions
  -a, --attachment=                 Attachment path or URL (e.g. for OpenAI image recognition messages)
  -S, --setup                       Run setup for all reconfigurable parts of fabric
  -t, --temperature=                Set temperature (default: 0.7)
  -T, --topp=                       Set top P (default: 0.9)
  -s, --stream                      Stream
  -P, --presencepenalty=            Set presence penalty (default: 0.0)
  -r, --raw                         Use the defaults of the model without sending chat options (like temperature etc.) and use the user role instead of the system role for patterns.
  -F, --frequencypenalty=           Set frequency penalty (default: 0.0)
  -l, --listpatterns                List all patterns
  -L, --listmodels                  List all available models
  -x, --listcontexts                List all contexts
  -X, --listsessions                List all sessions
  -U, --updatepatterns              Update patterns
  -c, --copy                        Copy to clipboard
  -m, --model=                      Choose model
      --modelContextLength=         Model context length (only affects ollama)
  -o, --output=                     Output to file
      --output-session              Output the entire session (also a temporary one) to the output file
  -n, --latest=                     Number of latest patterns to list (default: 0)
  -d, --changeDefaultModel          Change default model
  -y, --youtube=                    YouTube video or play list &quot;URL&quot; to grab transcript, comments from it and send to chat or print it put to the console and store it in the output file
      --playlist                    Prefer playlist over video if both ids are present in the URL
      --transcript                  Grab transcript from YouTube video and send to chat (it is used per default).
      --transcript-with-timestamps  Grab transcript from YouTube video with timestamps and send to chat
      --comments                    Grab comments from YouTube video and send to chat
      --metadata                    Output video metadata
  -g, --language=                   Specify the Language Code for the chat, e.g. -g=en -g=zh
  -u, --scrape_url=                 Scrape website URL to markdown using Jina AI
  -q, --scrape_question=            Search question using Jina AI
  -e, --seed=                       Seed to be used for LMM generation
  -w, --wipecontext=                Wipe context
  -W, --wipesession=                Wipe session
      --printcontext=               Print context
      --printsession=               Print session
      --readability                 Convert HTML input into a clean, readable view
      --input-has-vars              Apply variables to user input
      --dry-run                     Show what would be sent to the model without actually sending it
      --serve                       Serve the Fabric Rest API
      --serveOllama                 Serve the Fabric Rest API with ollama endpoints
      --address=                    The address to bind the REST API (default: :8080)
      --api-key=                    API key used to secure server routes
      --config=                     Path to YAML config file
      --version                     Print current version
      --listextensions              List all registered extensions
      --addextension=               Register a new extension fro

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[louislam/uptime-kuma]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A fancy self-hosted monitoring tool]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma">louislam/uptime-kuma</a></h1>
            <p>A fancy self-hosted monitoring tool</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 71,244</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,293</p>
            <p>Stars today: 45 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./public/icon.svg&quot; width=&quot;128&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

# Uptime Kuma

Uptime Kuma is an easy-to-use self-hosted monitoring tool.

&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/louislam/uptime-kuma?style=flat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/v/louislam/uptime-kuma/latest?label=docker%20image%20ver.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/louislam/uptime-kuma&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://opencollective.com/uptime-kuma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://opencollective.com/uptime-kuma/total/badge.svg?label=Open%20Collective%20Backers&amp;color=brightgreen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
[![GitHub Sponsors](https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/louislam?label=GitHub%20Sponsors)](https://github.com/sponsors/louislam) &lt;a href=&quot;https://weblate.kuma.pet/projects/uptime-kuma/uptime-kuma/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://weblate.kuma.pet/widgets/uptime-kuma/-/svg-badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Translation status&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1336778/212262296-e6205815-ad62-488c-83ec-a5b0d0689f7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

## 🥔 Live Demo

Try it!

Demo Server (Location: Frankfurt - Germany): https://demo.kuma.pet/start-demo

It is a temporary live demo, all data will be deleted after 10 minutes. Sponsored by [Uptime Kuma Sponsors](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma#%EF%B8%8F-sponsors).

## ⭐ Features

- Monitoring uptime for HTTP(s) / TCP / HTTP(s) Keyword / HTTP(s) Json Query / Ping / DNS Record / Push / Steam Game Server / Docker Containers
- Fancy, Reactive, Fast UI/UX
- Notifications via Telegram, Discord, Gotify, Slack, Pushover, Email (SMTP), and [90+ notification services, click here for the full list](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/tree/master/src/components/notifications)
- 20-second intervals
- [Multi Languages](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/tree/master/src/lang)
- Multiple status pages
- Map status pages to specific domains
- Ping chart
- Certificate info
- Proxy support
- 2FA support

## 🔧 How to Install

### 🐳 Docker

```bash
docker run -d --restart=always -p 3001:3001 -v uptime-kuma:/app/data --name uptime-kuma louislam/uptime-kuma:1
```

Uptime Kuma is now running on &lt;http://0.0.0.0:3001&gt;.

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; File Systems like **NFS** (Network File System) are **NOT** supported. Please map to a local directory or volume.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; If you want to limit exposure to localhost (without exposing port for other users or to use a [reverse proxy](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/wiki/Reverse-Proxy)), you can expose the port like this:
&gt; 
&gt; ```bash
&gt; docker run -d --restart=always -p 127.0.0.1:3001:3001 -v uptime-kuma:/app/data --name uptime-kuma louislam/uptime-kuma:1
&gt; ```

### 💪🏻 Non-Docker

Requirements:

- Platform
  - ✅ Major Linux distros such as Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS, Fedora and ArchLinux etc.
  - ✅ Windows 10 (x64), Windows Server 2012 R2 (x64) or higher
  - ❌ FreeBSD / OpenBSD / NetBSD
  - ❌ Replit / Heroku
- [Node.js](https://nodejs.org/en/download/) 18 / 20.4
- [npm](https://docs.npmjs.com/cli/) 9
- [Git](https://git-scm.com/downloads)
- [pm2](https://pm2.keymetrics.io/) - For running Uptime Kuma in the background

```bash
git clone https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma.git
cd uptime-kuma
npm run setup

# Option 1. Try it
node server/server.js

# (Recommended) Option 2. Run in the background using PM2
# Install PM2 if you don&#039;t have it:
npm install pm2 -g &amp;&amp; pm2 install pm2-logrotate

# Start Server
pm2 start server/server.js --name uptime-kuma
```

Uptime Kuma is now running on http://localhost:3001

More useful PM2 Commands

```bash
# If you want to see the current console output
pm2 monit

# If you want to add it to startup
pm2 save &amp;&amp; pm2 startup
```

### Advanced Installation

If you need more options or need to browse via a reverse proxy, please read:

https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/wiki/%F0%9F%94%A7-How-to-Install

## 🆙 How to Update

Please read:

https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/wiki/%F0%9F%86%99-How-to-Update

## 🆕 What&#039;s Next?

I will assign requests/issues to the next milestone.

https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/milestones

## ❤️ Sponsors

Thank you so much! (GitHub Sponsors will be updated manually. OpenCollective sponsors will be updated automatically, the list will be cached by GitHub though. It may need some time to be updated)

&lt;img src=&quot;https://uptime.kuma.pet/sponsors?v=6&quot; alt /&gt;

## 🖼 More Screenshots

Light Mode:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://uptime.kuma.pet/img/light.jpg&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

Status Page:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1336778/134628766-a3fe0981-0926-4285-ab46-891a21c3e4cb.png&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

Settings Page:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://louislam.net/uptimekuma/2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

Telegram Notification Sample:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://louislam.net/uptimekuma/3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

## Motivation

- I was looking for a self-hosted monitoring tool like &quot;Uptime Robot&quot;, but it is hard to find a suitable one. One of the closest ones is statping. Unfortunately, it is not stable and no longer maintained.
- Wanted to build a fancy UI.
- Learn Vue 3 and vite.js.
- Show the power of Bootstrap 5.
- Try to use WebSocket with SPA instead of a REST API.
- Deploy my first Docker image to Docker Hub.

If you love this project, please consider giving it a ⭐.

## 🗣️ Discussion / Ask for Help

⚠️ For any general or technical questions, please don&#039;t send me an email, as I am unable to provide support in that manner. I will not respond if you ask questions there.

I recommend using Google, GitHub Issues, or Uptime Kuma&#039;s subreddit for finding answers to your question. If you cannot find the information you need, feel free to ask:

- [GitHub Issues](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/issues)
- [Subreddit (r/UptimeKuma)](https://www.reddit.com/r/UptimeKuma/)

My Reddit account: [u/louislamlam](https://reddit.com/u/louislamlam)
You can mention me if you ask a question on the subreddit.

## Contributions

### Create Pull Requests

We DO NOT accept all types of pull requests and do not want to waste your time. Please be sure that you have read and follow pull request rules:
[CONTRIBUTING.md#can-i-create-a-pull-request-for-uptime-kuma](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md#can-i-create-a-pull-request-for-uptime-kuma)

### Test Pull Requests

There are a lot of pull requests right now, but I don&#039;t have time to test them all.

If you want to help, you can check this:
https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/wiki/Test-Pull-Requests

### Test Beta Version

Check out the latest beta release here: https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/releases

### Bug Reports / Feature Requests

If you want to report a bug or request a new feature, feel free to open a [new issue](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/issues).

### Translations

If you want to translate Uptime Kuma into your language, please visit [Weblate Readme](https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kuma/blob/master/src/lang/README.md).

### Spelling &amp; Grammar

Feel free to correct the grammar in the documentation or code.
My mother language is not English and my grammar is not that great.


</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[USB Army Knife – the ultimate close access tool for penetration testers and red teamers.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife">i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife</a></h1>
            <p>USB Army Knife – the ultimate close access tool for penetration testers and red teamers.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,655</p>
            <p>Forks: 155</p>
            <p>Stars today: 49 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;License&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/mashape/apistatus.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
[![PlatformIO CI](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/actions/workflows/main.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/actions/workflows/main.yml)
[![.NET](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/actions/workflows/dotnet.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/actions/workflows/dotnet.yml)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=therealshodan&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/therealshodan?style=social&amp;logo=twitter&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
[![ko-fi](https://ko-fi.com/img/githubbutton_sm.svg)](https://ko-fi.com/O5O8145AVW)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/therealshodan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.buymeacoffee.com/buttons/default-orange.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Me A Coffee&quot; height=&quot;41&quot; width=&quot;174&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

# USB Army Knife

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Introducing the USB Army Knife – the ultimate tool for penetration testers and red teamers.
    &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/images/t-dongle-s3-side.png&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Compact and versatile, this device packs a punch with its extensive capabilities, including USB HID attacks, mass storage emulation, network device impersonation and WiFi/Bluetooth exploits (thanks to our forked version of ESP32 Marauder).

Complete control over how and when your payloads are run. Plug in and execute, leave behind and trigger over WiFi, run on a timer or build a Hollywood-esq UI. Manage and deploy your attacks effortlessly using just a phone using a user-friendly Bootstrap web interface.

Want more? Deploy the agent and execute commands even when the machine is locked. Working over the serial interface egress is incredibly hard to detect. You can even view the victims screen over the devices&#039; dedicated WiFi connection.

Equip yourself with the USB Army Knife and elevate your local access toolkit to the next level.

## Testimonials

*&quot;Your device is evil. You are doing evil.&quot;* - Mr. Peoples via X

## Intro
There is a problem with physical access/USB attacks today. On their own, each attack doesn&#039;t provide enough of a solution to meet most objectives.
* USB keyboard attacks (Ducky, HID&amp;Run) require a logged on machine and even the best tools don’t provide a solution to this.
* Networking attacks (poison tap and alike) might get you a password hash but often require something complex hanging out of an Ethernet port to get this back for offline cracking.
* When you get on a box, what options do you still have for exfiltrating data when anything that opens a socket is getting sent to VT.

What was needed is a physical access platform that enables a suitable rogue to take the best bits of each attack and workaround their respective problems with another attack. Ideally this platform would be so cheap and covert that losing one wouldn&#039;t be an issue.

This is why I decided to create the USB Army Knife. 
* Want to become a USB Ethernet adapter PCAP the interface and egress it over WiFI? USB Army Knife.
* Want to wrap your attacks in custom UI or just show a Hollywood interface when your attack has worked? USB Army Knife
* Want a covert storage device? USB Army Knife
* Want to deauth everyone on the WiFi, PCAP the renegotiation and email this to yourself when the machine has been left unlocked for offline cracking? USB Army Knife
* Want your attack to destroy itself when it’s been found? USB Army Knife
* What to connect to other bits of hardware, motion sensors and alike? USB Army Knife.
* Want to view what’s on the victim&#039;s screen over WiFi? USB Army Knife.
* Want to record what your victim is saying? USB Army Knife.

## Video
[This video shows how the ultimate rick roll works](./examples/rickroll/)

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f373e18e-5cad-4871-9f2a-17523fa33398

[This video shows how the USB PCAP functionality and has a brief peak at the web interface](./examples/usb_ethernet_pcap/)

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/0d5b1485-b808-46c6-aaf7-7cf016088b8f

[This video shows how to pull the victims machine once the agent has been installed](./examples/vnc/) 

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3c866d29-ef26-4eaf-943b-1206b8c40101

## Features
This project implements a variety of attacks based around an easily concealable USB/WiFi/BT dongle. The attacks include sending BadUSB (USB HID commands using DuckyScript), appearing as mass storage devices, appearing as USB network devices, and performing WiFi and Bluetooth attacks with ESP32 Marauder. Attacks are deployed using a Ducky-like language you probably already know and love. This language has been agumented with a raft of custom commands and even the entire ESP32 Marauder capability (improved). Attacks include:

- **USB HID Attacks**: Send custom HID commands using DuckyScript, supports BadUSB &amp; USB HID and run style attacks. Supports multiple keyboard layouts/languages.
- **Mass Storage Device**: Emulate a USB mass storage device (USB drive and CDROM).
- **USB Network Device**: Appear as a USB network device.
- **WiFi and Bluetooth Attacks**: Utilize ESP32 Marauder for WiFi and Bluetooth attacks. Include EvilAP, Deauth and pcap.
- **Hot Mic**: Plug in a USB device and stream audio over WiFi

## Examples

| Name      | Description   |
| ------------- | ------------- |
| [Covert Storage](./examples/covertstorage/) | Example showing how to masquerade as two different USB mass storage devices. The first time the device is plugged in the devices appears with the full contents of the micro SD card. In all subsequence attempts a different &#039;benign&#039; drive appears. |
| [Progress Bar](./examples/progressbar/) | Images are displayed on the devices LCD screen showing a progress bar. Great for those Hollywood style attacks or if you want a visual indicator to show an attack has deployed. |
| [Ultimate RickRoll](./examples/rickroll/) | Inject keystrokes to display the famous rickroll video but also uses ESP32 Marauder to blast the lyrics over WiFi. |
| [USB Ethernet PCAP](./examples/usb_ethernet_pcap/) | Turns the device into a USB network adapter and collects a PCAP of the first few seconds of network traffic. |
| [Deploy the serial agent](./examples/install_agent_and_run_command/) | Deploys the agent if it isn&#039;t already installed and sends commands over the serial port. Command output can be seen in the web interface|
| [Pull the screen](./examples/vnc/) | Deploys the agent, the agent includes a tiny VNC server. Now the screen can be viewed via the web interface|
| [Simple UI](./examples/simple_ui/) | A simple yet powerful UI to select scripts/images and run these using the hardware button. Shows how you can build complex UI interactions simply.  |
| [Stream Mic audio over WiFi](./examples/hotmic/) | The M5Stack AtomS3U has a microphone that you can stream over WiFi.  |
| [Instantly crash Linux boxes](./examples/linux_panic/) | Deploy a bad filesystem which cause Linux machines which automount to panic. |
| [Evil USB CDROM/NIC](./examples/malicious_ethernet_adapter/) | Pretend to be a USB NICs which requires a driver from a CDROM device that appears when you plug the NIC in. |
| [Use different keyboard layouts](./examples/multiple_keyboard_layouts/) | Automatically support different keyboard layouts without rewriting your payloads |

## Supported Hardware

| Hardware     | Supported      | Purchase Links |
| ------------ | -------------- | -------------- |
| **LilyGo T-Dongle S3**  (Recommended)![screenshot](./docs/images/t-dongle-s3.png) | The LilyGo T-Dongle S3 is a USB pen drive shaped ESP32-S3 development board. It features a colour LCD screen, physical button, hidden/covert micro SD card adapter (inside the USB-A connector) as well as a SPI adapter. It has 16MB of flash. It is based on the ESP32-S3 chipset which enables it to host a WiFi station as well as support a range of WiFi and Bluetooth attacks. *It is incredibly cheap!* There are two versions of this device with and without the screen. Only the version with the screen has been tested.  | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_DCMq0ZX)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon UK](https://amzn.to/3YuNCg3)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon US](https://amzn.to/4f4AqUk)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[eBay UK](https://ebay.us/3TJVed)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **Waveshare ESP32-S3 1.47inch** ![screenshot](./docs/images/waveshare-147.png) | This device is similar in design, size and features to the LilyGo T-Dongle S3 and uses the same chipset. It is clearly a dev board as it doesn&#039;t come with a case and has exposed circuitry on the underside. Where this device betters the T-Dongle S3 is that it has a very large high quality screen and 8MB of additional RAM. | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_DmlJI3x)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[eBay UK](https://ebay.us/E4gFr5])&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **M5Stack AtomS3U** ![screenshot](./docs/images/m5stack-atoms3u.png) | This is an ESP32-S3 development board with two external interface at the rear. It doesn&#039;t feature a screen or an SD card, but does have an LED and a button. Instead of an SD card the flash memory is used to store files. Unusually it also contains a digital microphone and IR LED that are not currently supported. To put the device in boot mode hold RESET (the button on the side of the device) until a green LED comes on. | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_EIAUNXX)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **ESP32 Udisk** ![screenshot](./docs/images/esp32-udisk.png) | The most basic device that can run the USB Army Knife code is a ESP32-S2 chip connected to a USB port. Often you can find these sold in a very similar enclosures to the T-Dongle S3 and tend to advertised on sites like AliExpress as Playstation 4 jailbreaks under the name &#039;USB Dongle Udisk for P4&#039;. These devices lack RAM, a screen, SD card, Bluetooth, LEDs and a good hardware button. Instead of an SD card, flash memory is used to store tiny files. These devices are incredibly cheap and are often good at running HID+WiFi payloads (like the rick roll). **Warning** They are too underpowered to run the webserver. When buying these **beware** that they can often be confused with a very similar looking device that includes a CH343P chipset and no reset button. **Make sure the device you buy has a button that can be pushed with a paperclip.** Ensure you flash this device with the Generic-ESP32-S2 configuration.  | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_Dn5wXe5)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon UK](https://amzn.to/3Y4hrCE)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon US](https://amzn.to/4h98Jf4)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[eBay UK](https://ebay.us/AVZcK0)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **ESP32 Key** ![screenshot](./docs/images/esp32-key.png) | Very similar to the ESP32 UDisk (please see that description for a list of things it can&#039;t do) this is an ESP32-S2 on a circuit board. It is probably the cheapest device that can just about run USB Army Knife and has a price point to match. You&#039;ll need to hold down the button when you plug it in to get the device into flashing mode. Ensure you flash this device with the Generic-ESP32-S2 configuration. | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_EyliW13)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **Waveshare-ESP32-GEEK** ![screenshot](./docs/images/esp32-geek.png) | ESP32-GEEK is a development board designed by Waveshare. It has USB-A, 1.14-inch LCD screen, an SD card and has external ports (SWD, UART and I2C), it doesn&#039;t have an LED. Hold down the button when you plug it in to get the device into flashing mode. This device has some SD card issues (compatibility and low speed). You may need to use 8GB partitions and try a few card brands to find something compatible (I found a Kingston 64gb card with a 9GB partition worked YMMV). | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_EJsjVAc)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon UK](https://amzn.to/41hLVnn)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon US](https://amzn.to/3QnV9rW)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
| **Waveshare-RP2040-GEEK** ![screenshot](./docs/images/rp2040-geek.jpg) | RP2040-GEEK is a development board designed by Waveshare. It has USB-A, 1.14-inch LCD screen, an SD card and has external ports (SWD, UART and I2C). **This board does not run the ESP32 chipset. USB ethernet (NCM) mode are whole disk SD usage are both currently unsupported. ESP32 Maurader cannot work on this device!** On Windows you may also need to set this device to use a WinUSB driver using [Zadig](https://zadig.akeo.ie/). Hold down the button when you plug it in to get the device into flashing mode. | &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;[AliExpress](https://s.click.aliexpress.com/e/_EvdfVGH)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon UK](https://amzn.to/3YZvD1f)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;[Amazon US](https://amzn.to/3YY4Ouy)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

## Getting Started
powershell

### Installation

There are two options for getting the USB Army Knife firmware onto your device:
* [Flashing pre-built firmware using your web browser (easiest route)]([https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/wiki/Installation#using-a-web-browser](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/wiki/Installation#flashing-with-a-web-browser))
* [Building and flashing the source using Visual Studio Code (more powerful)]([https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/wiki/Installation#using-visual-studio-code](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/wiki/Installation#flashing-with-visual-studio-code-and-platformio))

### Usage

1. Connect the USB dongle to your computer.
1. Connect to the WiFi access point (iPhone14) with the password of &#039;password&#039;
1. Access the web interface (http://4.3.2.1:8080) by navigating to the URL with your browser.
1. Ensure the web interface has correctly loaded. You should see thr currently running status and uptime. If not refresh the page.
1. Use the web interface to create and manage your attacks using DuckyScript.

*ESP-S2 based devices have WiFi support but do not have a web interface. Attacks are managed via DuckyScript files.*
*RP2040 devices do not have ESP32 Maurader capability*

## How to get help
* Questions about DuckyScript?
  * [DuckyScript quick reference](https://docs.hak5.org/hak5-usb-rubber-ducky/duckyscript-tm-quick-reference)
  * [The USB Army Knife command reference](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/wiki) 
* Problem getting started?
  * Check out the examples
  * [The discussions pages](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/discussions)
* Found a bug?
  * [Create an issue](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife/issues)

## Future plans

### USB Host Mode / Mobile device support
There is no reason the USB Army Knife can&#039;t also operate in USB host mode. That is the same mode a computer works in. In this way the USB Army Knife can issue commands as if it was a computer. With most smart phones supporting PTP (picture transfer protocol) this means you could in theory plug in a USB Army Knife (with a USB adapter) into a phone and have it pull the photos off.

[Espressif have documentation for USB host mode](https://docs.espressif.com/projects/esp-idf/en/latest/esp32s3/api-reference/peripherals/usb_host.html) and also [example code](https://github.com/espressif/esp-idf/tree/master/examples/peripherals/usb/host). They do not have an example for the PTP protocol.
You can collect a PCAP of your phone using PTP using [USB PCAP](https://desowin.org/usbpcap/) there is even a WireShark [dissector](https://wiki.wireshark.org/USB-PTP)

## Contributing

Contributions are welcome! Please fork the repository and submit a pull request.

## Contact

If you have any questions or suggestions, feel free to reach out to us:

- Raise an issue on the repository: [GitHub Repository](https://github.com/i-am-shodan/usb-army-knife)
- Connect with us on Twitter: [@therealshodan](https://twitter.com/therealshodan)

## License

This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the LICENSE file for details.

## Acknowledgments

- Inspired by various BadUSB projects and the ESP32 Marauder project.

## Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#i-am-shodan/USBArmyKnife&amp;Date)

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Web application generating interactive and highly customizable maps]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator">Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator</a></h1>
            <p>Web application generating interactive and highly customizable maps</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,986</p>
            <p>Forks: 746</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Fantasy Map Generator

Azgaar&#039;s _Fantasy Map Generator_ is a free web application that helps fantasy writers, game masters, and cartographers create and edit fantasy maps.

Link: [azgaar.github.io/Fantasy-Map-Generator](https://azgaar.github.io/Fantasy-Map-Generator).

Refer to the [project wiki](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/wiki) for guidance. The current progress is tracked in [Trello](https://trello.com/b/7x832DG4/fantasy-map-generator). Some details are covered in my old blog [_Fantasy Maps for fun and glory_](https://azgaar.wordpress.com).

[![preview](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/9502eae9-92e0-4d0d-9f17-a2ba4a565c01)](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/11a42446-4bd5-4526-9cb1-3ef97c868992)

[![preview](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/e751a9e5-7986-4638-b8a9-362395ef7583)](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/e751a9e5-7986-4638-b8a9-362395ef7583)

[![preview](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/b0d0efde-a0d1-4e80-8818-ea3dd83c2323)](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/assets/26469650/b0d0efde-a0d1-4e80-8818-ea3dd83c2323)

Join our [Discord server](https://discordapp.com/invite/X7E84HU) and [Reddit community](https://www.reddit.com/r/FantasyMapGenerator) to share your creations, discuss the Generator, suggest ideas and get the most recent updates.

Contact me via [email](mailto:azgaar.fmg@yandex.com) if you have non-public suggestions. For bug reports please use [GitHub issues](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/issues) or _#fmg-bugs_ channel on Discord. If you are facing performance issues, please read [the tips](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/wiki/Tips#performance-tips).

Pull requests are highly welcomed. The codebase is messy and requires re-design. I will appreciate if you start with minor changes. Check out the [data model](https://github.com/Azgaar/Fantasy-Map-Generator/wiki/Data-model) before contributing.

You can support the project on [Patreon](https://www.patreon.com/azgaar).

_Inspiration:_

- Martin O&#039;Leary&#039;s [_Generating fantasy maps_](https://mewo2.com/notes/terrain)

- Amit Patel&#039;s [_Polygonal Map Generation for Games_](http://www-cs-students.stanford.edu/~amitp/game-programming/polygon-map-generation)

- Scott Turner&#039;s [_Here Dragons Abound_](https://heredragonsabound.blogspot.com)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[bluewave-labs/Checkmate]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Checkmate is an open-source, self-hosted tool designed to track and monitor server hardware, uptime, response times, and incidents in real-time with beautiful visualizations. Don't be shy, join here: https://discord.com/invite/NAb6H3UTjK :)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate">bluewave-labs/Checkmate</a></h1>
            <p>Checkmate is an open-source, self-hosted tool designed to track and monitor server hardware, uptime, response times, and incidents in real-time with beautiful visualizations. Don't be shy, join here: https://discord.com/invite/NAb6H3UTjK :)</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,017</p>
            <p>Forks: 386</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=center&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/12443&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/12443&quot; alt=&quot;bluewave-labs%2Fcheckmate | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
![](https://img.shields.io/github/license/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/repo-size/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/top/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/issues/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
![](https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr/bluewave-labs/checkmate)
[![OpenSSF Best Practices](https://www.bestpractices.dev/projects/9901/badge)](https://www.bestpractices.dev/projects/9901)
[![Ask DeepWiki](https://deepwiki.com/badge.svg)](https://deepwiki.com/bluewave-labs/checkmate)

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bluewavelabs.ca&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Checkmate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An open source uptime and infrastructure monitoring application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img width=&quot;1660&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b748f36d-a271-4965-ad0a-18bf153bbee7&quot; /&gt;

This repository contains both the frontend and the backend of Checkmate, an open-source, self-hosted monitoring tool for tracking server hardware, uptime, response times, and incidents in real-time with beautiful visualizations. Checkmate regularly checks whether a server/website is accessible and performs optimally, providing real-time alerts and reports on the monitored services&#039; availability, downtime, and response time.

Checkmate also has an agent, called [Capture](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/capture), to retrieve data from remote servers. While Capture is not required to run Checkmate, it provides additional insights about your servers&#039; CPU, RAM, disk, and temperature status.

Checkmate has been stress-tested with 1000+ active monitors without any particular issues or performance bottlenecks.

**If you would like to sponsor a feature, [see this link](https://checkmate.so/sponsored-features).**

## 📚 Table of contents

- [📦 Demo](#-demo)  
- [🔗 User&#039;s guide](#-users-guide)  
- [🛠️ Installation](#️-installation)  
- [🏁 Translations](#-translations)  
- [🚀 Performance](#-performance)  
- [💚 Questions &amp; Ideas](#-questions--ideas)  
- [🧩 Features](#-features)  
- [🏗️ Screenshots](#-screenshots)  
- [🏗️ Tech stack](#-tech-stack)  
- [🔗 A few links](#a-few-links)  
- [🤝 Contributing](#-contributing)  
- [💰 Our sponsors](#-our-sponsors)


## 📦 Demo

You can see the latest build of [Checkmate](https://checkmate-demo.bluewavelabs.ca/) in action. The username is uptimedemo@demo.com and the password is Demouser1! (just a note that we update the demo server from time to time, so if it doesn&#039;t work for you, please ping us on the Discussions channel).

## 🔗 User&#039;s guide

Usage instructions can be found [here](https://docs.checkmate.so/checkmate-2.1). It&#039;s still WIP and some of the information there might be outdated as we continuously add features weekly. Rest assured, we are doing our best! :)

## 🛠️ Installation

See installation instructions in [Checkmate documentation portal](https://docs.checkmate.so/checkmate-2.1/users-guide/quickstart). Alternatively, you can also use [Coolify](https://coolify.io/) or [Elestio](https://elest.io/open-source/checkmate) for a one-click Docker deployment. If you would like to monitor your server infrastructure, you&#039;ll need [Capture agent](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/capture). Capture repository also contains the installation instructions.

## 🏁 Translations

If you would like to use Checkmate in your language, please [go to this page](https://poeditor.com/join/project/lRUoGZFCsJ) and register for the language you would like to translate Checkmate to. 

## 🚀 Performance

Thanks to extensive optimizations, Checkmate operates with an exceptionally small memory footprint, requiring minimal memory and CPU resources. Here’s the memory usage of a Node.js instance running on a server that monitors 323 servers every minute:

![image](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/37e04a75-d83a-488f-b25c-025511b492c9)

You can see the memory footprint of MongoDB and Redis on the same server (398Mb and 15Mb) for the same amount of servers:

![image](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3b469e85-e675-4040-a162-3f24c1afc751)

## 💚 Questions &amp; Ideas

If you have any questions, suggestions or comments, please use our [Discord channel](https://discord.gg/NAb6H3UTjK). We&#039;ve also launched our [Discussions](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/bluewave-uptime/discussions) page! Feel free to ask questions or share your ideas—we&#039;d love to hear from you!

## 🧩 Features

- Completely open source, deployable on your servers or home devices (e.g Raspberry Pi 4 or 5)
- Website monitoring
- Page speed monitoring
- Infrastructure monitoring (memory, disk usage, CPU performance etc) - requires [Capture](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/capture)
- Docker monitoring
- Ping monitoring
- SSL monitoring
- Port monitoring
- Incidents at a glance
- Status pages
- E-mail, Webhooks, Discord, Telegram, Slack notifications
- Scheduled maintenance
- JSON query monitoring
- Support for multiple languages

**Short term roadmap:** ([Milestone 2.2](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate/milestone/8))

- Better notifications
- Network monitoring
- ..and a few more features

## 🏗️ Screenshots

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img width=&quot;1628&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2eff6464-0738-4a32-9312-26e1e8e86275&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;1656&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/616c3563-c2a7-4ee4-af6c-7e6068955d1a&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1652&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7912d7cf-0d0e-4f26-aa5c-2ad7170b5c99&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img width=&quot;1652&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/08c2c6ac-3a2f-44d1-a229-d1746a3f9d16&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;



## 🏗️ Tech stack

- [ReactJs](https://react.dev/)
- [MUI (React framework)](https://mui.com/)
- [Node.js](https://nodejs.org/en)
- [MongoDB](https://mongodb.com)
- [Recharts](https://recharts.org)
- Lots of other open source components!

## A few links

- If you would like to support us, please consider giving it a ⭐ and click on &quot;watch&quot;.
- Have a question or suggestion for the roadmap/featureset? Check our [Discord channel](https://discord.gg/NAb6H3UTjK) or [Discussions](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/checkmate/discussions) forum.
- Need a ping when there&#039;s a new release? Use [Newreleases](https://newreleases.io/), a free service to track releases.
- Watch a Checkmate [installation and usage video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GfFOc0xHIwY)

## 🤝 Contributing

We are [Alex](http://github.com/ajhollid) (team lead), [Vishnu](http://github.com/vishnusn77), [Mohadeseh](http://github.com/mohicody), [Gorkem](http://github.com/gorkem-bwl/), [Owaise](http://github.com/Owaiseimdad), [Aryaman](https://github.com/Br0wnHammer) and [Mert](https://github.com/mertssmnoglu) helping individuals and businesses monitor their infra and servers.

We pride ourselves on building strong connections with contributors at every level. Despite being a young project, Checkmate has already earned 6000+ stars and attracted 80+ contributors from around the globe.

Our repo is starred by employees from **Google, Microsoft, Intel, Cisco, Tencent, Electronic Arts, ByteDance, JP Morgan Chase, Deloitte, Accenture, Foxconn, Broadcom, China Telecom, Barclays, Capgemini, Wipro, Cloudflare, Dassault Systèmes and NEC**, so don’t hold back — jump in, contribute and learn with us!

Here&#039;s how you can contribute:

0. Star this repo :)
1. Check [Contributor&#039;s guideline](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate/blob/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md). First timers are encouraged to check `good-first-issue` tag.
2. Check [project structure](https://docs.checkmate.so/checkmate-2.1/developers-guide/general-project-structure) and [high level overview](https://bluewavelabs.gitbook.io/checkmate/developers-guide/high-level-overview).
3. Read a detailed structure of [Checkmate](https://deepwiki.com/bluewave-labs/Checkmate) if you would like to deep dive into the architecture.
4. Open an issue if you believe you&#039;ve encountered a bug.
5. Check for good-first-issue&#039;s if you are a newcomer.
6. Make a pull request to add new features/make quality-of-life improvements/fix bugs.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bluewave-labs/checkmate/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=bluewave-labs/checkmate&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=bluewave-labs/checkmate&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#bluewave-labs/bluewave-uptime&amp;Date)

## 💰 Our sponsors

Thanks to [Gitbook](https://gitbook.io/) for giving us a free tier for their documentation platform, and [Poeditor](https://poeditor.com/) providing us a free account to use their i18n services. If you would like to sponsor Checkmate, please send an email to hello@bluewavelabs.ca

If you would like to sponsor a feature, [see this page](https://checkmate.so/sponsored-features).

Also check other developer and contributor-friendly projects of BlueWave:

- [VerifyWise](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/verifywise), the first open source AI governance platform.
- [DataRoom](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/bluewave-dataroom), an secure file sharing application, aka dataroom.
- [Guidefox](https://github.com/bluewave-labs/guidefox), an application that helps new users learn how to use your product via hints, tours, popups and banners.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4ian/GDevelop]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🎮 Open-source, cross-platform 2D/3D/multiplayer game engine designed for everyone.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop">4ian/GDevelop</a></h1>
            <p>🎮 Open-source, cross-platform 2D/3D/multiplayer game engine designed for everyone.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,927</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,011</p>
            <p>Stars today: 26 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![GDevelop logo](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20banner.png &quot;GDevelop logo&quot;)

GDevelop is a **full-featured, no-code, open-source** game development software. You can build **2D, 3D and multiplayer games** for mobile (iOS, Android), desktop and the web. GDevelop is fast and easy to use: the game logic is built up using an intuitive and powerful event-based system and reusable behaviors.

![The GDevelop editor when editing a game level](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20screenshot.png &quot;The GDevelop editor when editing a game level&quot;)

## Getting started

| ❔ I want to...                                   | 🚀 What to do                                                                                                                                                     |
| ------------------------------------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| 🎮 Use GDevelop to make games                     | Go to [GDevelop homepage](https://gdevelop.io) to download the app!                                                                                               |
| ⚙️ Create/improve an extension                    | Read about [creating an extension](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/extensions/create), with no-code or code.                                                   |
| 🧑‍💻 Contribute to the editor or game engine        | Follow this [README](newIDE/README.md).                                                                                                                           |
| 👾 Create or sell a game template                 | Submit a [free example or a paid template on the Asset Store](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/community/guide-for-submitting-an-example/).                     |
| 🎨 Share or sell an asset pack                    | Submit a [free or paid asset pack on the Asset Store](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/community/sell-asset-pack-store).                                        |
| 🌐 Help translate GDevelop                        | Go on the [GDevelop project on Crowdin](https://crowdin.com/project/gdevelop) or translate [in-app tutorials](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-tutorials). |
| 👥 Get online game services or commercial support | See offers for [professionals, teams or individual creators](https://gdevelop.io/pricing).                                                                        |

&gt; Are you interested in contributing to GDevelop for the first time? Take a look at the list of **[good first issues](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22%F0%9F%91%8Cgood+first+issue%22)**, **[good first contributions](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/discussions/categories/good-first-contribution)** or the **[&quot;🏐 not too hard&quot; cards](https://trello.com/b/qf0lM7k8/gdevelop-roadmap?menu=filter&amp;filter=label:Not%20too%20hard%20%E2%9A%BD%EF%B8%8F)** on the Roadmap.

## Games made with GDevelop

- Find GDevelop games on [gd.games](https://gd.games), the gaming platform for games powered by GDevelop.
- See the [showcase of games](https://gdevelop.io/games) created with GDevelop and published on Steam, iOS (App Store), Android (Google Play), Itch.io, Newgrounds, CrazyGames, Poki...
  - Suggest your game to be [added to the showcase here](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfjiOnkbODuPifSGuzxYY61vB5kyMWdTZSSqkJsv3H6ePRTQA/viewform).

[![Some games made with GDevelop](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20games.png &quot;Some games made with GDevelop&quot;)](https://gdevelop.io/games)

## Technical architecture

GDevelop is composed of an **editor**, a **game engine**, an **ecosystem** of extensions as well as **online services** and commercial support.

| Directory     | ℹ️ Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |
| ------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| `Core`        | Core classes, describing the structure of a game and tools to implement the IDE and work with GDevelop games.                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| `GDJS`        | The game engine, written in TypeScript, using PixiJS and Three.js for 2D and 3D rendering (WebGL), powering all GDevelop games.                                                                                                                                                                          |
| `GDevelop.js` | Bindings of `Core`, `GDJS` and `Extensions` to JavaScript (with WebAssembly), used by the IDE.                                                                                                                                                                                                           |
| `newIDE`      | The game editor, written in JavaScript with React, Electron, PixiJS and Three.js.js.                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |
| `Extensions`  | Built-in extensions for the game engine, providing objects, behaviors and new features. For example, this includes the physics engines running in WebAssembly (Box2D or Jolt Physics for 3D). All the [community extensions are on this repository](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-extensions). |

To learn more about GDevelop Architecture, read the [architecture overview here](Core/GDevelop-Architecture-Overview.md).

Pre-generated documentation of the game engine is [available here](https://docs.gdevelop.io).

Status of the tests and builds: [![macOS and Linux build status](https://circleci.com/gh/4ian/GDevelop.svg?style=shield)](https://app.circleci.com/pipelines/github/4ian/GDevelop) [![Fast tests status](https://gdevelop.semaphoreci.com/badges/GDevelop/branches/master.svg?style=shields)](https://gdevelop.semaphoreci.com/projects/GDevelop) [![Windows Build status](https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/84uhtdox47xp422x/branch/master?svg=true)](https://ci.appveyor.com/project/4ian/gdevelop/branch/master) [![https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg)](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation)

## Links

### Community

- [GDevelop forums](https://forum.gdevelop.io) and [Discord chat](https://discord.gg/gdevelop).
- [GDevelop homepage](https://gdevelop.io).
- [GDevelop wiki (documentation)](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/start).
- Help translate GDevelop in your language: [GDevelop project on Crowdin](https://crowdin.com/project/gdevelop).
- Open-source [extensions](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-extensions), [examples](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-examples), [tutorials](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-tutorials) are on GitHub.

### Development Roadmap

- [GDevelop Roadmap on Trello.com](https://trello.com/b/qf0lM7k8/gdevelop-roadmap), for a global view of the features that could be added. Please vote and comment here for new features/requests.
- [GitHub issue page](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/issues), for technical issues and bugs.
- [Github discussions](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/discussions) to talk about new features and ideas.

## License

- The Core library, the native and HTML5 game engines, the IDE, and all extensions (respectively `Core`, `GDJS`, `newIDE` and `Extensions` folders) are under the **MIT license**.
- The name, GDevelop, and its logo are the exclusive property of Florian Rival.

Games exported with GDevelop are based on the GDevelop game engine (see `Core` and `GDJS` folders): this engine is distributed under the MIT license so that you can **distribute, sell or do anything** with the games you created with GDevelop. In particular, you are not forced to make your game open-source.

[node.js]: https://nodejs.org

## Star History

Help us spread the word about GDevelop by starring the repository on GitHub!

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=4ian/gdevelop&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#4ian/gdevelop&amp;Date)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhiskeySockets/Baileys]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/WhiskeySockets/Baileys</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/WhiskeySockets/Baileys</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lightweight full-featured typescript/javascript WhatsApp Web API]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/WhiskeySockets/Baileys">WhiskeySockets/Baileys</a></h1>
            <p>Lightweight full-featured typescript/javascript WhatsApp Web API</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,909</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,967</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baileys logo&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/WhiskeySockets/Baileys/refs/heads/master/Media/logo.png&quot; height=&quot;75&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;

![NPM Downloads](https://img.shields.io/npm/dw/%40whiskeysockets%2Fbaileys?label=npm&amp;color=%23CB3837)
![GitHub code size in bytes](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/code-size/whiskeysockets/baileys)
![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/725839806084546610?label=discord&amp;color=%235865F2)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;Baileys is a WebSockets-based TypeScript library for interacting with the WhatsApp Web API.&lt;/div&gt;

# Important Note
This is a temporally README, the new guide is at development and will be fully released when it&#039;s finished.

New Guide: https://baileys.wiki

# Sponsor
If you&#039;d like to financially support this project, you can do so by supporting the current maintainer [here](https://purpshell.dev/sponsor).

# Disclaimer
This project is not affiliated, associated, authorized, endorsed by, or in any way officially connected with WhatsApp or any of its subsidiaries or its affiliates.
The official WhatsApp website can be found at whatsapp.com. &quot;WhatsApp&quot; as well as related names, marks, emblems and images are registered trademarks of their respective owners.

The maintainers of Baileys do not in any way condone the use of this application in practices that violate the Terms of Service of WhatsApp. The maintainers of this application call upon the personal responsibility of its users to use this application in a fair way, as it is intended to be used.
Use at your own discretion. Do not spam people with this. We discourage any stalkerware, bulk or automated messaging usage.

##

- Baileys does not require Selenium or any other browser to be interface with WhatsApp Web, it does so directly using a **WebSocket**. 
- Not running Selenium or Chromium saves you like **half a gig** of ram :/ 
- Baileys supports interacting with the multi-device &amp; web versions of WhatsApp.
- Thank you to [@pokearaujo](https://github.com/pokearaujo/multidevice) for writing his observations on the workings of WhatsApp Multi-Device. Also, thank you to [@Sigalor](https://github.com/sigalor/whatsapp-web-reveng) for writing his observations on the workings of WhatsApp Web and thanks to [@Rhymen](https://github.com/Rhymen/go-whatsapp/) for the __go__ implementation.

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; The original repository had to be removed by the original author - we now continue development in this repository here.
This is the only official repository and is maintained by the community.
&gt; **Join the Discord [here](https://discord.gg/WeJM5FP9GG)**
 
## Example

Do check out &amp; run [example.ts](Example/example.ts) to see an example usage of the library.
The script covers most common use cases.
To run the example script, download or clone the repo and then type the following in a terminal:
1. ``` cd path/to/Baileys ```
2. ``` yarn ```
3. ``` yarn example ```

## Install

Use the stable version:
```
yarn add @whiskeysockets/baileys
```

Use the edge version (no guarantee of stability, but latest fixes + features)
```
yarn add github:WhiskeySockets/Baileys
```

Then import your code using:
```ts 
import makeWASocket from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;
```

# Links

- [Discord](https://discord.gg/WeJM5FP9GG)
- [Docs](https://guide.whiskeysockets.io/)

# Index

- [Connecting Account](#connecting-account)
    - [Connect with QR-CODE](#starting-socket-with-qr-code)
    - [Connect with Pairing Code](#starting-socket-with-pairing-code)
    - [Receive Full History](#receive-full-history)
- [Important Notes About Socket Config](#important-notes-about-socket-config)
    - [Caching Group Metadata (Recommended)](#caching-group-metadata-recommended)
    - [Improve Retry System &amp; Decrypt Poll Votes](#improve-retry-system--decrypt-poll-votes)
    - [Receive Notifications in Whatsapp App](#receive-notifications-in-whatsapp-app)

- [Save Auth Info](#saving--restoring-sessions)
- [Handling Events](#handling-events)
    - [Example to Start](#example-to-start)
    - [Decrypt Poll Votes](#decrypt-poll-votes)
    - [Summary of Events on First Connection](#summary-of-events-on-first-connection)
- [Implementing a Data Store](#implementing-a-data-store)
- [Whatsapp IDs Explain](#whatsapp-ids-explain)
- [Utility Functions](#utility-functions)
- [Sending Messages](#sending-messages)
    - [Non-Media Messages](#non-media-messages)
        - [Text Message](#text-message)
        - [Quote Message](#quote-message-works-with-all-types)
        - [Mention User](#mention-user-works-with-most-types)
        - [Forward Messages](#forward-messages)
        - [Location Message](#location-message)
        - [Contact Message](#contact-message)
        - [Reaction Message](#reaction-message)
        - [Pin Message](#pin-message)
        - [Poll Message](#poll-message)
    - [Sending with Link Preview](#sending-messages-with-link-previews)
    - [Media Messages](#media-messages)
        - [Gif Message](#gif-message)
        - [Video Message](#video-message)
        - [Audio Message](#audio-message)
        - [Image Message](#image-message)
        - [ViewOnce Message](#view-once-message)
- [Modify Messages](#modify-messages)
    - [Delete Messages (for everyone)](#deleting-messages-for-everyone)
    - [Edit Messages](#editing-messages)
- [Manipulating Media Messages](#manipulating-media-messages)
    - [Thumbnail in Media Messages](#thumbnail-in-media-messages)
    - [Downloading Media Messages](#downloading-media-messages)
    - [Re-upload Media Message to Whatsapp](#re-upload-media-message-to-whatsapp)
- [Reject Call](#reject-call)
- [Send States in Chat](#send-states-in-chat)
    - [Reading Messages](#reading-messages)
    - [Update Presence](#update-presence)
- [Modifying Chats](#modifying-chats)
    - [Archive a Chat](#archive-a-chat)
    - [Mute/Unmute a Chat](#muteunmute-a-chat)
    - [Mark a Chat Read/Unread](#mark-a-chat-readunread)
    - [Delete a Message for Me](#delete-a-message-for-me)
    - [Delete a Chat](#delete-a-chat)
    - [Star/Unstar a Message](#starunstar-a-message)
    - [Disappearing Messages](#disappearing-messages)
- [User Querys](#user-querys)
    - [Check If ID Exists in Whatsapp](#check-if-id-exists-in-whatsapp)
    - [Query Chat History (groups too)](#query-chat-history-groups-too)
    - [Fetch Status](#fetch-status)
    - [Fetch Profile Picture (groups too)](#fetch-profile-picture-groups-too)
    - [Fetch Bussines Profile (such as description or category)](#fetch-bussines-profile-such-as-description-or-category)
    - [Fetch Someone&#039;s Presence (if they&#039;re typing or online)](#fetch-someones-presence-if-theyre-typing-or-online)
- [Change Profile](#change-profile)
    - [Change Profile Status](#change-profile-status)
    - [Change Profile Name](#change-profile-name)
    - [Change Display Picture (groups too)](#change-display-picture-groups-too)
    - [Remove display picture (groups too)](#remove-display-picture-groups-too)
- [Groups](#groups)
    - [Create a Group](#create-a-group)
    - [Add/Remove or Demote/Promote](#addremove-or-demotepromote)
    - [Change Subject (name)](#change-subject-name)
    - [Change Description](#change-description)
    - [Change Settings](#change-settings)
    - [Leave a Group](#leave-a-group)
    - [Get Invite Code](#get-invite-code)
    - [Revoke Invite Code](#revoke-invite-code)
    - [Join Using Invitation Code](#join-using-invitation-code)
    - [Get Group Info by Invite Code](#get-group-info-by-invite-code)
    - [Query Metadata (participants, name, description...)](#query-metadata-participants-name-description)
    - [Join using groupInviteMessage](#join-using-groupinvitemessage)
    - [Get Request Join List](#get-request-join-list)
    - [Approve/Reject Request Join](#approvereject-request-join)
    - [Get All Participating Groups Metadata](#get-all-participating-groups-metadata)
    - [Toggle Ephemeral](#toggle-ephemeral)
    - [Change Add Mode](#change-add-mode)
- [Privacy](#privacy)
    - [Block/Unblock User](#blockunblock-user)
    - [Get Privacy Settings](#get-privacy-settings)
    - [Get BlockList](#get-blocklist)
    - [Update LastSeen Privacy](#update-lastseen-privacy)
    - [Update Online Privacy](#update-online-privacy)
    - [Update Profile Picture Privacy](#update-profile-picture-privacy)
    - [Update Status Privacy](#update-status-privacy)
    - [Update Read Receipts Privacy](#update-read-receipts-privacy)
    - [Update Groups Add Privacy](#update-groups-add-privacy)
    - [Update Default Disappearing Mode](#update-default-disappearing-mode)
- [Broadcast Lists &amp; Stories](#broadcast-lists--stories)
    - [Send Broadcast &amp; Stories](#send-broadcast--stories)
    - [Query a Broadcast List&#039;s Recipients &amp; Name](#query-a-broadcast-lists-recipients--name)
- [Writing Custom Functionality](#writing-custom-functionality)
    - [Enabling Debug Level in Baileys Logs](#enabling-debug-level-in-baileys-logs)
    - [How Whatsapp Communicate With Us](#how-whatsapp-communicate-with-us)
    - [Register a Callback for Websocket Events](#register-a-callback-for-websocket-events)

## Connecting Account

WhatsApp provides a multi-device API that allows Baileys to be authenticated as a second WhatsApp client by scanning a **QR code** or **Pairing Code** with WhatsApp on your phone.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; **[Here](#example-to-start) is a simple example of event handling**

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; **You can see all supported socket configs [here](https://baileys.whiskeysockets.io/types/SocketConfig.html) (Recommended)**

### Starting socket with **QR-CODE**

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; You can customize browser name if you connect with **QR-CODE**, with `Browser` constant, we have some browsers config, **see [here](https://baileys.whiskeysockets.io/types/BrowsersMap.html)**

```ts
import makeWASocket from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;

const sock = makeWASocket({
    // can provide additional config here
    browser: Browsers.ubuntu(&#039;My App&#039;),
    printQRInTerminal: true
})
```

If the connection is successful, you will see a QR code printed on your terminal screen, scan it with WhatsApp on your phone and you&#039;ll be logged in!

### Starting socket with **Pairing Code**


&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; Pairing Code isn&#039;t Mobile API, it&#039;s a method to connect Whatsapp Web without QR-CODE, you can connect only with one device, see [here](https://faq.whatsapp.com/1324084875126592/?cms_platform=web)

The phone number can&#039;t have `+` or `()` or `-`, only numbers, you must provide country code

```ts
import makeWASocket from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;

const sock = makeWASocket({
    // can provide additional config here
    printQRInTerminal: false //need to be false
})

if (!sock.authState.creds.registered) {
    const number = &#039;XXXXXXXXXXX&#039;
    const code = await sock.requestPairingCode(number)
    console.log(code)
}
```

### Receive Full History

1. Set `syncFullHistory` as `true`
2. Baileys, by default, use chrome browser config
    - If you&#039;d like to emulate a desktop connection (and receive more message history), this browser setting to your Socket config:

```ts
const sock = makeWASocket({
    ...otherOpts,
    // can use Windows, Ubuntu here too
    browser: Browsers.macOS(&#039;Desktop&#039;),
    syncFullHistory: true
})
```

## Important Notes About Socket Config

### Caching Group Metadata (Recommended)
- If you use baileys for groups, we recommend you to set `cachedGroupMetadata` in socket config, you need to implement a cache like this:

    ```ts
    const groupCache = new NodeCache({stdTTL: 5 * 60, useClones: false})

    const sock = makeWASocket({
        cachedGroupMetadata: async (jid) =&gt; groupCache.get(jid)
    })

    sock.ev.on(&#039;groups.update&#039;, async ([event]) =&gt; {
        const metadata = await sock.groupMetadata(event.id)
        groupCache.set(event.id, metadata)
    })

    sock.ev.on(&#039;group-participants.update&#039;, async (event) =&gt; {
        const metadata = await sock.groupMetadata(event.id)
        groupCache.set(event.id, metadata)
    })
    ```

### Improve Retry System &amp; Decrypt Poll Votes
- If you want to improve sending message, retrying when error occurs and decrypt poll votes, you need to have a store and set `getMessage` config in socket like this:
    ```ts
    const sock = makeWASocket({
        getMessage: async (key) =&gt; await getMessageFromStore(key)
    })
    ```

### Receive Notifications in Whatsapp App
- If you want to receive notifications in whatsapp app, set `markOnlineOnConnect` to `false`
    ```ts
    const sock = makeWASocket({
        markOnlineOnConnect: false
    })
    ```
## Saving &amp; Restoring Sessions

You obviously don&#039;t want to keep scanning the QR code every time you want to connect. 

So, you can load the credentials to log back in:
```ts
import makeWASocket, { useMultiFileAuthState } from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;

const { state, saveCreds } = await useMultiFileAuthState(&#039;auth_info_baileys&#039;)

// will use the given state to connect
// so if valid credentials are available -- it&#039;ll connect without QR
const sock = makeWASocket({ auth: state })

// this will be called as soon as the credentials are updated
sock.ev.on(&#039;creds.update&#039;, saveCreds)
```

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; `useMultiFileAuthState` is a utility function to help save the auth state in a single folder, this function serves as a good guide to help write auth &amp; key states for SQL/no-SQL databases, which I would recommend in any production grade system.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; When a message is received/sent, due to signal sessions needing updating, the auth keys (`authState.keys`) will update. Whenever that happens, you must save the updated keys (`authState.keys.set()` is called). Not doing so will prevent your messages from reaching the recipient &amp; cause other unexpected consequences. The `useMultiFileAuthState` function automatically takes care of that, but for any other serious implementation -- you will need to be very careful with the key state management.

## Handling Events

- Baileys uses the EventEmitter syntax for events. 
They&#039;re all nicely typed up, so you shouldn&#039;t have any issues with an Intellisense editor like VS Code.

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; **The events are [these](https://baileys.whiskeysockets.io/types/BaileysEventMap.html)**, it&#039;s important you see all events

You can listen to these events like this:
```ts
const sock = makeWASocket()
sock.ev.on(&#039;messages.upsert&#039;, ({ messages }) =&gt; {
    console.log(&#039;got messages&#039;, messages)
})
```

### Example to Start

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; This example includes basic auth storage too

```ts
import makeWASocket, { DisconnectReason, useMultiFileAuthState } from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;
import { Boom } from &#039;@hapi/boom&#039;

async function connectToWhatsApp () {
    const { state, saveCreds } = await useMultiFileAuthState(&#039;auth_info_baileys&#039;)
    const sock = makeWASocket({
        // can provide additional config here
        auth: state,
        printQRInTerminal: true
    })
    sock.ev.on(&#039;connection.update&#039;, (update) =&gt; {
        const { connection, lastDisconnect } = update
        if(connection === &#039;close&#039;) {
            const shouldReconnect = (lastDisconnect.error as Boom)?.output?.statusCode !== DisconnectReason.loggedOut
            console.log(&#039;connection closed due to &#039;, lastDisconnect.error, &#039;, reconnecting &#039;, shouldReconnect)
            // reconnect if not logged out
            if(shouldReconnect) {
                connectToWhatsApp()
            }
        } else if(connection === &#039;open&#039;) {
            console.log(&#039;opened connection&#039;)
        }
    })
    sock.ev.on(&#039;messages.upsert&#039;, event =&gt; {
        for (const m of event.messages) {
            console.log(JSON.stringify(m, undefined, 2))

            console.log(&#039;replying to&#039;, m.key.remoteJid)
            await sock.sendMessage(m.key.remoteJid!, { text: &#039;Hello Word&#039; })
        }
    })

    // to storage creds (session info) when it updates
    sock.ev.on(&#039;creds.update&#039;, saveCreds)
}
// run in main file
connectToWhatsApp()
```

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; In `messages.upsert` it&#039;s recommended to use a loop like `for (const message of event.messages)` to handle all messages in array

### Decrypt Poll Votes

- By default poll votes are encrypted and handled in `messages.update`
- That&#039;s a simple example
```ts
sock.ev.on(&#039;messages.update&#039;, event =&gt; {
    for(const { key, update } of event) {
        if(update.pollUpdates) {
            const pollCreation = await getMessage(key)
            if(pollCreation) {
                console.log(
                    &#039;got poll update, aggregation: &#039;,
                    getAggregateVotesInPollMessage({
                        message: pollCreation,
                        pollUpdates: update.pollUpdates,
                    })
                )
            }
        }
    }
})
```

- `getMessage` is a [store](#implementing-a-data-store) implementation (in your end)

### Summary of Events on First Connection

1. When you connect first time, `connection.update` will be fired requesting you to restart sock
2. Then, history messages will be received in `messaging.history-set`

## Implementing a Data Store

- Baileys does not come with a defacto storage for chats, contacts, or messages. However, a simple in-memory implementation has been provided. The store listens for chat updates, new messages, message updates, etc., to always have an up-to-date version of the data.

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; I highly recommend building your own data store, as storing someone&#039;s entire chat history in memory is a terrible waste of RAM.

It can be used as follows:

```ts
import makeWASocket, { makeInMemoryStore } from &#039;@whiskeysockets/baileys&#039;
// the store maintains the data of the WA connection in memory
// can be written out to a file &amp; read from it
const store = makeInMemoryStore({ })
// can be read from a file
store.readFromFile(&#039;./baileys_store.json&#039;)
// saves the state to a file every 10s
setInterval(() =&gt; {
    store.writeToFile(&#039;./baileys_store.json&#039;)
}, 10_000)

const sock = makeWASocket({ })
// will listen from this socket
// the store can listen from a new socket once the current socket outlives its lifetime
store.bind(sock.ev)

sock.ev.on(&#039;chats.upsert&#039;, () =&gt; {
    // can use &#039;store.chats&#039; however you want, even after the socket dies out
    // &#039;chats&#039; =&gt; a KeyedDB instance
    console.log(&#039;got chats&#039;, store.chats.all())
})

sock.ev.on(&#039;contacts.upsert&#039;, () =&gt; {
    console.log(&#039;got contacts&#039;, Object.values(store.contacts))
})

```

The store also provides some simple functions such as `loadMessages` that utilize the store to speed up data retrieval.

## Whatsapp IDs Explain

- `id` is the WhatsApp ID, called `jid` too, of the person or group you&#039;re sending the message to. 
    - It must be in the format ```[country code][phone number]@s.whatsapp.net```
	    - Example for people: ```+19999999999@s.whatsapp.net```. 
	    - For groups, it must be in the format ``` 123456789-123345@g.us ```. 
    - For broadcast lists, it&#039;s `[timestamp of creation]@broadcast`.
    - For stories, the ID is `status@broadcast`.

## Utility Functions

- `getContentType`, returns the content type for any message
- `getDevice`, returns the device from message
- `makeCacheableSignalKeyStore`, make auth store more fast
- `downloadContentFromMessage`, download content from any message

## Sending Messages

- Send all types of messages with a single function
    - **[Here](https://baileys.whiskeysockets.io/types/AnyMessageContent.html) you can see all message contents supported, like text message**
    - **[Here](https://baileys.whiskeysockets.io/types/MiscMessageGenerationOptions.html) you can see all options supported, like quote message**

    ```ts
    const jid: string
    const content: AnyMessageContent
    const options: MiscMessageGenerationOptions

    sock.sendMessage(jid, content, options)
    ```

### Non-Media Messages

#### Text Message
```ts
await sock.sendMessage(jid, { text: &#039;hello word&#039; })
```

#### Quote Message (works with all types)
```ts
await sock.sendMessage(jid, { text: &#039;hello word&#039; }, { quoted: message })
```

#### Mention User 

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[zotero/zotero]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/zotero/zotero</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/zotero/zotero</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Zotero is a free, easy-to-use tool to help you collect, organize, annotate, cite, and share your research sources.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/zotero/zotero">zotero/zotero</a></h1>
            <p>Zotero is a free, easy-to-use tool to help you collect, organize, annotate, cite, and share your research sources.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,867</p>
            <p>Forks: 848</p>
            <p>Stars today: 46 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>Zotero
======
[![CI](https://github.com/zotero/zotero/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/zotero/zotero/actions/workflows/ci.yml)

[Zotero](https://www.zotero.org/) is a free, easy-to-use tool to help you collect, organize, cite, and share your research sources.

Please post feature requests or bug reports to the [Zotero Forums](https://forums.zotero.org/). If you&#039;re having trouble with Zotero, see [Getting Help](https://www.zotero.org/support/getting_help).

For more information on how to use this source code, see the [Zotero documentation](https://www.zotero.org/support/dev/source_code).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[badges/shields]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/badges/shields</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/badges/shields</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Concise, consistent, and legible badges in SVG and raster format]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/badges/shields">badges/shields</a></h1>
            <p>Concise, consistent, and legible badges in SVG and raster format</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 25,057</p>
            <p>Forks: 5,544</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/badges/shields/master/readme-logo.svg?sanitize=true&quot;
        height=&quot;130&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://shields.io/community#backers&quot; alt=&quot;Backers on Open Collective&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/opencollective/backers/shields&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://shields.io/community#sponsors&quot; alt=&quot;Sponsors on Open Collective&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/opencollective/sponsors/shields&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/badges/shields/pulse&quot; alt=&quot;Activity&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/badges/shields&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/badges/shields/discussions&quot; alt=&quot;Discussions&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/discussions/badges/shields&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/badges/shields/actions/workflows/daily-tests.yml&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/badges/shields/daily-tests.yml?label=daily%20tests&quot;
            alt=&quot;Daily Tests Status&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://coveralls.io/github/badges/shields&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/coveralls/github/badges/shields&quot;
            alt=&quot;Code Coverage&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/HjJCwm5&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/308323056592486420?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&quot;
            alt=&quot;Chat on Discord&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

This is home to [Shields.io][shields.io], a service for concise, consistent,
and legible badges in SVG and raster format, which can easily be included in
GitHub readmes or any other web page. The service supports dozens of
continuous integration services, package registries, distributions, app
stores, social networks, code coverage services, and code analysis services.
Every month it serves over 1.6 billion images and is used by some of the
world&#039;s most popular open-source projects, [VS Code][vscode], [Vue.js][vue]
and [Bootstrap][bootstrap] to name a few.

[vscode]: https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode
[vue]: https://github.com/vuejs/vue
[bootstrap]: https://github.com/twbs/bootstrap

This repo hosts:

- The [Shields.io][shields.io] frontend and server code
- An [NPM library for generating badges][badge-maker]
  - [documentation][badge-maker-docs]
  - [changelog][badge-maker-changelog]
- The [badge design specification][badge-spec]

[shields.io]: https://shields.io/
[badge-maker]: https://www.npmjs.com/package/badge-maker
[badge-spec]: https://github.com/badges/shields/tree/master/spec
[badge-maker-docs]: https://github.com/badges/shields/tree/master/badge-maker/README.md
[badge-maker-changelog]: https://github.com/badges/shields/tree/master/badge-maker/CHANGELOG.md

## Examples

- code coverage percentage: ![coverage](https://img.shields.io/badge/coverage-80%25-yellowgreen)
- stable release version: ![version](https://img.shields.io/badge/version-1.2.3-blue)
- package manager release: ![gem](https://img.shields.io/badge/gem-2.2.0-blue)
- status of third-party dependencies: ![dependencies](https://img.shields.io/badge/dependencies-out%20of%20date-orange)
- static code analysis grade: ![codacy](https://img.shields.io/badge/codacy-B-green)
- [SemVer](https://semver.org/) version observance: ![semver](https://img.shields.io/badge/semver-2.0.0-blue)
- amount of [Liberapay](https://liberapay.com/) donations per week: ![receives](https://img.shields.io/badge/receives-2.00%20USD%2Fweek-yellow)
- Python package downloads: ![downloads](https://img.shields.io/badge/downloads-13k%2Fmonth-brightgreen)
- Chrome Web Store extension rating: ![rating](https://img.shields.io/badge/rating-★★★★☆-brightgreen)
- Uptime Robot uptime percentage: ![uptime](https://img.shields.io/badge/uptime-100%25-brightgreen)

[Make your own badges!][custom badges]
(Quick example: `https://img.shields.io/badge/left-right-f39f37`)

[custom badges]: https://img.shields.io/badges/static-badge

### Quickstart

Browse a [complete list of badges][shields.io] and locate a particular badge by using the search bar or by browsing the categories. Click on the badge to fill in required data elements for that badge type (like your username or repo) and optionally customize (label, colors etc.). And it&#039;s ready for use!

Use the button at the bottom to copy your badge url or snippet, which can then be added to places like your GitHub readme files or other web pages.

## Contributing

Shields is a community project. We invite your participation through issues
and pull requests! You can peruse the [contributing guidelines][contributing].

When adding or changing a service [please add tests][service-tests].

This project has quite a backlog of suggestions! If you&#039;re new to the project,
maybe you&#039;d like to open a pull request to address one of them.

You can read a [tutorial on how to add a badge][tutorial].

[![GitHub issues by-label](https://img.shields.io/github/issues/badges/shields/good%20first%20issue)](https://github.com/badges/shields/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22good+first+issue%22)

If you intend on reporting or contributing a fix related to security vulnerabilities, please first refer to our [security policy][security].

[service-tests]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/doc/service-tests.md
[tutorial]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/doc/TUTORIAL.md
[contributing]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md
[security]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/SECURITY.md

## Development

[![Open in GitHub Codespaces](https://github.com/codespaces/badge.svg)](https://codespaces.new/badges/shields?quickstart=1)

1. Install Node 22. You can use the [package manager][] of your choice.
2. Clone this repository.
3. Run `npm ci` to install the dependencies.
4. Run `npm start` to start the badge server and the frontend dev server.
5. Open `http://localhost:3000/` to view the frontend.

When server source files change, the badge server should automatically restart
itself (using [nodemon][]). When the frontend files change, the frontend dev
server (`docusaurus start`) should also automatically reload. However the badge
definitions are built only before the server first starts. To regenerate those,
either run `npm run prestart` or manually restart the server.

To debug a badge from the command line, run `npm run badge -- /npm/v/nock`.
It also works with full URLs like
`npm run badge -- https://img.shields.io/npm/v/nock`.

Use `npm run debug:server` to start server in debug mode.
[This recipe][nodemon debug] shows how to debug Node.js application in [VS Code][].

Shields has experimental support for [Gitpod][gitpod], a pre-configured development
environment that runs in your browser. To use Gitpod, click the button below and
sign in with GitHub. Gitpod also offers a browser add-on, though it is not required.
Please report any Gitpod bugs, questions, or suggestions in issue
[#2772](https://github.com/badges/shields/issues/2772).

[![Edit with Gitpod](https://gitpod.io/button/open-in-gitpod.svg)](https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/badges/shields)

[Snapshot tests][] ensure we don&#039;t inadvertently make changes that affect the
SVG or JSON output. When deliberately changing the output, run
`SNAPSHOT_DRY=1 npm run test:package` to preview changes to the saved
snapshots, and `SNAPSHOT_UPDATE=1 npm run test:package` to update them.

The server can be configured to use [Sentry][] ([configuration][sentry configuration]) and [Prometheus][] ([configuration][prometheus configuration]).

Our [full test suite][full test suite] as well as [code coverage][code coverage] are run on a daily basis.

[package manager]: https://nodejs.org/en/download/package-manager/
[gitpod]: https://www.gitpod.io/
[snapshot tests]: https://glebbahmutov.com/blog/snapshot-testing/
[prometheus]: https://prometheus.io/
[prometheus configuration]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/doc/self-hosting.md#prometheus
[sentry]: https://sentry.io/
[sentry configuration]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/doc/self-hosting.md#sentry
[nodemon]: https://nodemon.io/
[nodemon debug]: https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode-recipes/tree/master/nodemon
[vs code]: https://code.visualstudio.com/
[full test suite]: https://github.com/badges/shields/actions/workflows/daily-tests.yml
[code coverage]: https://coveralls.io/github/badges/shields

## Hosting your own server

There is documentation about [hosting your own server][self-hosting].

[self-hosting]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/doc/self-hosting.md

## Related projects

[![Awesome](https://awesome.re/badge.svg)](https://awesome.re)

Status badges are used widely across open-source and private software projects.
Academics have studied the &quot;signal&quot; badges provide about software project
quality. There are many existing libraries for rendering these badges, and
alternatives to the hosted Shields badge service. [awesome-badges][] is a
curated collection of such resources.
[Contributions][contributing to awesome-badges] may be considered there.
(The presence of a project in that collection should not be interpreted as an endorsement nor promotion from the Shields project)

[awesome-badges]: https://github.com/badges/awesome-badges
[contributing to awesome-badges]: https://github.com/badges/awesome-badges/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md

## History

b.adge.me was the original website for this service. Heroku back then had a
thing which made it hard to use a toplevel domain with it, hence the odd
domain. It used code developed in 2013 from a library called
[gh-badges][old-gh-badges], both developed by [Thaddée Tyl][espadrine].
The project merged with shields.io by making it use the b.adge.me code
and closed b.adge.me.

The original badge specification was developed in 2013 by
[Olivier Lacan][olivierlacan]. It was inspired by the Travis CI and similar
badges (there were a lot fewer, back then). In 2014 Thaddée Tyl redesigned
it with help from a Travis CI employee and convinced everyone to switch to
it. The old design is what today is called the plastic style; the new one
is the flat style.

You can read more about [the project&#039;s inception][thread],
[the motivation of the SVG badge specification][motivation], and
[the specification itself][spec].

[olivierlacan]: https://github.com/olivierlacan
[espadrine]: https://github.com/espadrine
[old-gh-badges]: https://github.com/badges/gh-badges
[motivation]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/spec/motivation.md
[spec]: https://github.com/badges/shields/blob/master/spec/SPECIFICATION.md
[thread]: https://github.com/h5bp/lazyweb-requests/issues/150

## Project leaders

Maintainers:

- [calebcartwright](https://github.com/calebcartwright)
- [chris48s](https://github.com/chris48s)
- [jNullj](https://github.com/jnullj)
- [paulmelnikow](https://github.com/paulmelnikow)
- [PyvesB](https://github.com/PyvesB)

Alumni:

- [Daniel15](https://github.com/Daniel15)
- [espadrine](https://github.com/espadrine)
- [olivierlacan](https://github.com/olivierlacan)
- [platan](https://github.com/platan)
- [RedSparr0w](https://github.com/RedSparr0w)

## License

All assets and code are under the [CC0 LICENSE](LICENSE) and in the public
domain unless specified otherwise.

## Community

Thanks to the people and companies who donate money, services or time to keep the project running. [https://shields.io/community](https://shields.io/community)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Join a time-traveling adventure where you meet history’s legends while learning Generative AI technologies! ✨]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript">microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript</a></h1>
            <p>Join a time-traveling adventure where you meet history’s legends while learning Generative AI technologies! ✨</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 744</p>
            <p>Forks: 468</p>
            <p>Stars today: 8 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;  

&lt;img src=&quot;/docs/images/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;128&quot; /&gt;

# Generative AI for beginners with JavaScript

[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-blue?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript/blob/main/LICENSE)
[![Watch the video series](https://img.shields.io/badge/Videos-d95652.svg?style=flat-square&amp;logo=youtube)](https://aka.ms/genai-js)
[![PRs Welcome](https://img.shields.io/badge/PRs-welcome-brightgreen.svg?style=flat-square)](http://makeapullrequest.com)

[![Azure AI Discord](https://dcbadge.limes.pink/api/server/kzRShWzttr)](https://discord.gg/kzRShWzttr)

[![Azure AI Foundry Developer Forum](https://img.shields.io/badge/GitHub-Azure_AI_Foundry_Developer_Forum-blue?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github&amp;color=000000&amp;logoColor=fff)](https://aka.ms/foundry/forum)

⭐ If you like this repo, star it on GitHub — it helps a lot!

[Getting Started](#getting-started) • [Lessons](#lessons) • [Keep Learning](#keep-learning)

&lt;/div&gt;

Ready to integrate Generative AI into your JavaScript apps? 

This course throws you into a *time-traveling adventure*—meet history’s legends with a fun twist, while learning Generative AI technologies ✨
 
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]  
&gt; Open-source vibes! Reuse, tweak, and share this content freely.
 
![Character App Sneak Peek](/docs/images/background.png)
 
## NEW - MCP lessons just added

- Learn how to [build and test out your first server](/lessons/07-mcp/README.md)
- Improve your MCP client by [integrating an LLM](/lessons/08-mcp-advanced/README.md)


## Call for help - help us translate !

Help us translate this course. Each lesson in `lessons/` folder has a `translations/` directory. Add your translation file like so `README.&lt;language code&gt;.md`, for example *README.es.md*.  - Thank You.


## Step into history with AI magic! 
 
Dive into an immersive learning experience powered by Generative AI:  
- **Learn about Generative AI technologies**. If you&#039;ve wanted to understand Generative AI and the potential for your applications, you&#039;re in the right place!
 
- **Epic Time-Travel Stories**.
Dive into a fun tale, chatting with icons like Leonardo da Vinci, Ada Lovelace, or Montezuma in every lesson.
 
- **Companion App**. Interact with historical figures using Generative AI technologies ([see our Responsible AI disclaimer](#responsible-ai-disclaimer)).

  ![Interact with History through conversation](/docs/images/character-chat.png) 

  Check the [_app_](/app/README.md) directory to run the [app locally](/docs/setup/README.md#option-2--running-the-app-locally) or use [GitHub Codespaces](/docs/setup/README.md) to run it online.

- **Accessibility FTW**. Read it, hear it—audio tags bring it to life.
 
&gt; “It’s like a comic book with code!” — Happy User
 
## Getting started
 
Throughout this course you&#039;ll find many code examples and exercises, so we encourage you to run and experiment with the code in your own copy of this repository:
 
1. Select the **Fork** button in the upper right-hand corner of the repository or select this button:
   [![Fork](https://img.shields.io/badge/Fork-Repository-blue?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript/fork)
 
2. Click the **Code** button in your forked repository, go to the **Codespaces** tab, and then choose **Create codespace**.

   This will create a preconfigured online environment for you. You&#039;ll then be able to use [GitHub Models](https://github.com/marketplace/models) to run the code examples and interact with AI models for free, without any additional setup.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; While GitHub Codespaces provides a quick and easy starting point you can also run the code samples [locally](/docs/setup/README.md#option-2--running-the-app-locally).
&gt;
&gt; Learn more about [GitHub Codespaces and GitHub Models concepts here](/docs/setup/README.md).  

### Lesson description

📦 Each lesson includes:

- A **written lesson** with an assignment and quiz.
- A short **video** to help further your learning.
- **Solutions** for each assignment and quiz.
- **Characters** you can interact with using our [companion app](/app/README.md), demonstrating Generative AI.

## Lessons

🗃️ Table of contents

| # | Lesson Link  | Description |
| ---- | ----------- | ----------- |
| 1 | [Introduction to Generative AI and LLMs for JavaScript Developers](/lessons/01-intro-to-genai/README.md) | Understand Generative AI and LLM fundamentals, their applications and limits in JavaScript, and how to use AI to enhance user experiences. |
| 2 | [Build your first AI app](/lessons/02-first-ai-app/README.md) | Set up your development environment, write a basic app, and understand system prompts. |
| 3 | [Prompt engineering](/lessons/03-prompt-engineering/README.md) | Learn Prompt engineering fundamentals, techniques, and meta-prompts for better AI outcomes. |
| 4 | [Structured output](/lessons/04-structured-output/README.md) | Learn structured output, how to extract data from prompts, and present it in various formats, such as JSON, for easier consumption. |
| 5 | [Retrieval augmented generation (RAG)](/lessons/05-rag/README.md) | Learn the basics of RAG, how to integrate external data, and how to leverage it for more relevant, accurate AI responses. |
| 6 | [Tool calling/Function calling](/lessons/06-tool-calling/README.md) | Learn how to give your LLM extra capbilities, bring your own functions  |
| 7 | [MCP, Model Context Protocol ](/lessons/07-mcp/README.md) | Teaches how to get started with MCP to standardize how to expose prompts, resources and tools  |
| 8 | [Enhancing MCP Clients with Large Language Models](/lessons/08-mcp-advanced/README.md) | Learn how to improve your MCP app by improving clients with LLM and more  |

New lessons will be added to the course over time, so stay tuned!

## Keep learning

🙌 After completing this course, you can continue learning by exploring our additional resources.

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;🎬Video Series&lt;/summary&gt;

| # | Session | Description | Slides | Demo | Script | Video |
|---|---------|-------------|--------|------|--------|-------|
| 0 | Series introduction | Introduces the series and its content. | [pptx](/videos/slides/00-intro.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/00-intro.pdf) | - | [Script](/videos/sessions/00-intro.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vLYtDgs_zx8&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=1) |
| 1 | What you need to know about LLMs | Explores what LLMs are, how they&#039;re trained, how they work and their limits. | [pptx](/videos/slides/01-llms.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/01-llms.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/01-llms/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/01-llms.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQ_2OjNZ9aA&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=2)  |
| 2 | Essential prompt engineering techniques | Practical prompt engineering techniques to get the best out of AI models. | [pptx](/videos/slides/02-prompt-engineering.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/02-prompt-engineering.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/02-prompt-engineering/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/02-prompt-engineering.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gQ6TlyxBmWs&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=3)  |
| 3 | Improve AI accuracy and reliability with RAG | Introduces Retrieval-Augmented Generation, to use AI with your own data. | [pptx](/videos/slides/03-rag.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/03-rag.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/03-rag/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/03-rag.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xkFOmx5yxIA&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=4) |
| 4 | Speed up your AI development with LangChain.js | Covers LangChain.js framework core concepts, and how to use it to accelerate AI developments. | [pptx](/videos/slides/04-langchainjs.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/04-langchainjs.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/04-langchainjs/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/04-langchainjs.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=02IDU8eCX8o&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=5) |
| 5 | Run AI models on your local machine with Ollama | Shows how to integrate local AI models into your development workflow. | [pptx](/videos/slides/05-local-models.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/05-local-models.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/05-local-models/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/05-local-models.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dLfNnoPv4AQ&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=6) |
| 6 | Get started with AI for free using Phi-3 | Experiments with Ollama and Phi-3 model directly from your browser. | [pptx](/videos/slides/06-playground.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/06-playground.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/06-playground/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/06-playground.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ds32MS9SHzU&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=7) |
| 7 | Introduction to Azure AI Foundry | Kickstart your journey with Azure AI Foundry. | [pptx](/videos/slides/07-ai-foundry.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/07-ai-foundry.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/07-ai-foundry/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/07-ai-foundry.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Mo-VOGk8ng&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=8) |
| 8 | Building Generative AI Apps with Azure Cosmos DB | Build generative AI apps with Azure Cosmos DB and vector search. | [pptx](/videos/slides/08-cosmos-db.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/08-cosmos-db.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/08-cosmos-db/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/08-cosmos-db.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-GQyaLbeqxQ&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=9)  |
| 9 | Azure tools &amp; services for hosting and storing AI apps | Build, deploy, and scale AI applications using Azure tools. | [pptx](/videos/slides/09-azure-tools.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/09-azure-tools.pdf) | - | [Script](/videos/sessions/09-azure-tools.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WB6Fpzhwyug&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=10) |
| 10 | Streaming Generative AI output with the AI Chat Protocol | Integrate streaming easily into your apps with the AI Chat Protocol. | [pptx](/videos/slides/10-chat-protocol.pptx) / [pdf](/videos/slides/pdf/10-chat-protocol.pdf) | [Demo](/videos/demos/10-chat-protocol/) | [Script](/videos/sessions/10-chat-protocol.md) | [📺](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzDCW-6hMtU&amp;list=PLlrxD0HtieHi5ZpsHULPLxm839IrhmeDk&amp;index=11) |

To see the full page of resources, go to this [video overview page](/videos/README.md).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;🎒 Other Courses&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Generative AI for Beginners](https://aka.ms/genai-beginners)
- [Generative AI for Beginners .NET](https://github.com/microsoft/Generative-AI-for-beginners-dotnet)
- [Generative AI with JavaScript](https://github.com/microsoft/generative-ai-with-javascript)
- [AI for Beginners](https://aka.ms/ai-beginners)
- [AI Agents for Beginners - A Course](https://github.com/microsoft/ai-agents-for-beginners)
- [Data Science for Beginners](https://aka.ms/datascience-beginners)
- [ML for Beginners](https://aka.ms/ml-beginners)
- [Cybersecurity for Beginners](https://github.com/microsoft/Security-101) 
- [Web Dev for Beginners](https://aka.ms/webdev-beginners)
- [IoT for Beginners](https://aka.ms/iot-beginners)
- [XR Development for Beginners](https://github.com/microsoft/xr-development-for-beginners)
- [Mastering GitHub Copilot for Paired Programming](https://github.com/microsoft/Mastering-GitHub-Copilot-for-Paired-Programming)
- [Mastering GitHub Copilot for C#/.NET Developers](https://github.com/microsoft/mastering-github-copilot-for-dotnet-csharp-developers)
- [Choose Your Own Copilot Adventure](https://github.com/microsoft/CopilotAdventures)
&lt;/details&gt;

You&#039;ll also find additional resources in the form of [tutorials, code samples and more](/docs/additional-resources.md).

## Responsible AI Disclaimer

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; DISCLAIMER: This repository contains fictional content generated by AI. The historical characters depicted here are generating responses thanks to generative AI, which is based on training data. Any responses generated by these characters do not represent their actual views or quotes. This content is intended solely for entertainment purposes. [Microsoft Responsible AI principles here](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ai/principles-and-approach/)


## Interact with community

[![Azure AI Discord](https://dcbadge.limes.pink/api/server/kzRShWzttr)](https://discord.gg/kzRShWzttr)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[prettier/prettier]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/prettier/prettier</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/prettier/prettier</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Prettier is an opinionated code formatter.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/prettier/prettier">prettier/prettier</a></h1>
            <p>Prettier is an opinionated code formatter.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 50,626</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,520</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Prettier Banner](https://unpkg.com/prettier-logo@1.0.3/images/prettier-banner-light.svg)](https://prettier.io)

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Opinionated Code Formatter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;
    JavaScript
    · TypeScript
    · Flow
    · JSX
    · JSON
  &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;
    CSS
    · SCSS
    · Less
  &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;
    HTML
    · Vue
    · Angular
  &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;
    GraphQL
    · Markdown
    · YAML
  &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://prettier.io/docs/plugins&quot;&gt;
      Your favorite language?
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier/actions?query=branch%3Amain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;CI Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/check-runs/prettier/prettier/main?style=flat-square&amp;label=CI&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io/gh/prettier/prettier&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Coverage Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/codecov/c/github/prettier/prettier.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/acdlite/status/974390255393505280&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Blazing Fast&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/speed-blazing%20%F0%9F%94%A5-brightgreen.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/prettier&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;npm version&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/prettier.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/prettier&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;weekly downloads from npm&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dw/prettier.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prettier/prettier#badge&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;code style: prettier&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/code_style-prettier-ff69b4.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/intent/follow?screen_name=PrettierCode&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Follow Prettier on X&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/%40PrettierCode-9f9f9f?style=flat-square&amp;logo=x&amp;labelColor=555&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Intro

Prettier is an opinionated code formatter. It enforces a consistent style by parsing your code and re-printing it with its own rules that take the maximum line length into account, wrapping code when necessary.

### Input

&lt;!-- prettier-ignore --&gt;
```js
foo(reallyLongArg(), omgSoManyParameters(), IShouldRefactorThis(), isThereSeriouslyAnotherOne());
```

### Output

```js
foo(
  reallyLongArg(),
  omgSoManyParameters(),
  IShouldRefactorThis(),
  isThereSeriouslyAnotherOne(),
);
```

Prettier can be run [in your editor](https://prettier.io/docs/editors) on-save, in a [pre-commit hook](https://prettier.io/docs/precommit), or in [CI environments](https://prettier.io/docs/cli#list-different) to ensure your codebase has a consistent style without devs ever having to post a nit-picky comment on a code review ever again!

---

**[Documentation](https://prettier.io/docs/)**

[Install](https://prettier.io/docs/install) ·
[Options](https://prettier.io/docs/options) ·
[CLI](https://prettier.io/docs/cli) ·
[API](https://prettier.io/docs/api)

**[Playground](https://prettier.io/playground/)**

---

## Badge

Show the world you&#039;re using _Prettier_ → [![code style: prettier](https://img.shields.io/badge/code_style-prettier-ff69b4.svg?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/prettier/prettier)

```md
[![code style: prettier](https://img.shields.io/badge/code_style-prettier-ff69b4.svg?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/prettier/prettier)
```

## Contributing

See [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[prebid/Prebid.js]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:04:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Setup and manage header bidding advertising partners without writing code or confusing line items. Prebid.js is open source and free.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js">prebid/Prebid.js</a></h1>
            <p>Setup and manage header bidding advertising partners without writing code or confusing line items. Prebid.js is open source and free.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,449</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,192</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Build Status](https://circleci.com/gh/prebid/Prebid.js.svg?style=svg)](https://circleci.com/gh/prebid/Prebid.js)
[![Percentage of issues still open](http://isitmaintained.com/badge/open/prebid/Prebid.js.svg)](https://isitmaintained.com/project/prebid/Prebid.js &quot;Percentage of issues still open&quot;)
[![Coverage Status](https://coveralls.io/repos/github/prebid/Prebid.js/badge.svg)](https://coveralls.io/github/prebid/Prebid.js)

# Prebid.js

&gt; A free and open source library for publishers to quickly implement header bidding.

This README is for developers who want to contribute to Prebid.js.
Additional documentation can be found at [the Prebid.js documentation homepage](https://docs.prebid.org/prebid/prebidjs.html).
Working examples can be found in [the developer docs](https://prebid.org/dev-docs/getting-started.html).

Prebid.js is open source software that is offered for free as a convenience. While it is designed to help companies address legal requirements associated with header bidding, we cannot and do not warrant that your use of Prebid.js will satisfy legal requirements. You are solely responsible for ensuring that your use of Prebid.js complies with all applicable laws.  We strongly encourage you to obtain legal advice when using Prebid.js to ensure your implementation complies with all laws where you operate.

**Table of Contents**

- [Usage](#Usage)
- [Install](#Install)
- [Build](#Build)
- [Run](#Run)
- [Contribute](#Contribute)

&lt;a name=&quot;Usage&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Usage (as a npm dependency)

*Note:* Requires Prebid.js v1.38.0+

Prebid.js depends on Babel and some Babel Plugins in order to run correctly in the browser.  Here are some examples for
configuring webpack to work with Prebid.js.

With Babel 7:
```javascript
// webpack.conf.js
let path = require(&#039;path&#039;);
module.exports = {
  mode: &#039;production&#039;,
  module: {
    rules: [

      // this rule can be excluded if you don&#039;t require babel-loader for your other application files
      {
        test: /\.m?js$/,
        exclude: /node_modules/,
        use: {
          loader: &#039;babel-loader&#039;,
        }
      },

      // this separate rule is required to make sure that the Prebid.js files are babel-ified.  this rule will
      // override the regular exclusion from above (for being inside node_modules).
      {
        test: /.js$/,
        include: new RegExp(`\\${path.sep}prebid\\.js`),
        use: {
          loader: &#039;babel-loader&#039;,
          // presets and plugins for Prebid.js must be manually specified separate from your other babel rule.
          // this can be accomplished by requiring prebid&#039;s .babelrc.js file (requires Babel 7 and Node v8.9.0+)
          // as of Prebid 6, babelrc.js only targets modern browsers. One can change the targets and build for
          // older browsers if they prefer, but integration tests on ie11 were removed in Prebid.js 6.0
          options: require(&#039;prebid.js/.babelrc.js&#039;)
        }
      }
    ]
  }
}
```

Or for Babel 6:
```javascript
            // you must manually install and specify the presets and plugins yourself
            options: {
              plugins: [
                &quot;transform-object-assign&quot;, // required (for IE support) and &quot;babel-plugin-transform-object-assign&quot;
                                           // must be installed as part of your package.
                require(&#039;prebid.js/plugins/pbjsGlobals.js&#039;) // required!
              ],
              presets: [
                [&quot;env&quot;, {                 // you can use other presets if you wish.
                  &quot;targets&quot;: {            // this example is using &quot;babel-presets-env&quot;, which must be installed if you
                    &quot;browsers&quot;: [         // follow this example.
                      ... // your browser targets. they should probably match the targets you&#039;re using for the rest
                          // of your application
                    ]
                  }
                }]
              ]
            }
```

Then you can use Prebid.js as any other npm dependency

```javascript
import pbjs from &#039;prebid.js&#039;;
import &#039;prebid.js/modules/rubiconBidAdapter&#039;; // imported modules will register themselves automatically with prebid
import &#039;prebid.js/modules/appnexusBidAdapter&#039;;
pbjs.processQueue();  // required to process existing pbjs.queue blocks and setup any further pbjs.queue execution

pbjs.requestBids({
  ...
})

```



&lt;a name=&quot;Install&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Install



    $ git clone https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js.git
    $ cd Prebid.js
    $ npm ci

*Note:* You need to have `NodeJS` 12.16.1 or greater installed.

*Note:* In the 1.24.0 release of Prebid.js we have transitioned to using gulp 4.0 from using gulp 3.9.1.  To comply with gulp&#039;s recommended setup for 4.0, you&#039;ll need to have `gulp-cli` installed globally prior to running the general `npm ci`.  This shouldn&#039;t impact any other projects you may work on that use an earlier version of gulp in its setup.

If you have a previous version of `gulp` installed globally, you&#039;ll need to remove it before installing `gulp-cli`.  You can check if this is installed by running `gulp -v` and seeing the version that&#039;s listed in the `CLI` field of the output.  If you have the `gulp` package installed globally, it&#039;s likely the same version that you&#039;ll see in the `Local` field.  If you already have `gulp-cli` installed, it should be a lower major version (it&#039;s at version `2.0.1` at the time of the transition).

To remove the old package, you can use the command: `npm rm gulp -g`

Once setup, run the following command to globally install the `gulp-cli` package: `npm install gulp-cli -g`


&lt;a name=&quot;Build&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Build for Development

To build the project on your local machine we recommend, running:

    $ gulp serve-and-test --file &lt;spec_file.js&gt;

This will run testing but not linting. A web server will start at `http://localhost:9999` serving from the project root and generates the following files:

+ `./build/dev/prebid.js` - Full source code for dev and debug
+ `./build/dev/prebid.js.map` - Source map for dev and debug
+ `./build/dev/prebid-core.js`
+ `./build/dev/prebid-core.js.map`


Development may be a bit slower but if you prefer linting and additional watch files you can also still run just:

    $ gulp serve


### Build Optimization

The standard build output contains all the available modules from within the `modules` folder.  Note, however that there are bid adapters which support multiple bidders through aliases, so if you don&#039;t see a file in modules for a bid adapter, you may need to grep the repository to find the name of the module you need to include.

You might want to exclude some/most of them from the final bundle.  To make sure the build only includes the modules you want, you can specify the modules to be included with the `--modules` CLI argument.

For example, when running the serve command: `gulp serve --modules=openxBidAdapter,rubiconBidAdapter,sovrnBidAdapter`

Building with just these adapters will result in a smaller bundle which should allow your pages to load faster.

**Build standalone prebid.js**

- Clone the repo, run `npm ci`
- Then run the build:

        $ gulp build --modules=openxBidAdapter,rubiconBidAdapter,sovrnBidAdapter

Alternatively, a `.json` file can be specified that contains a list of modules you would like to include.

    $ gulp build --modules=modules.json

With `modules.json` containing the following
```json modules.json
[
  &quot;openxBidAdapter&quot;,
  &quot;rubiconBidAdapter&quot;,
  &quot;sovrnBidAdapter&quot;
]
```

**Build prebid.js using npm for bundling**

In case you&#039;d like to explicitly show that your project uses `prebid.js` and want a reproducible build, consider adding it as an `npm` dependency.

- Add `prebid.js` as a `npm` dependency of your project: `npm install prebid.js`
- Run the `prebid.js` build under the `node_modules/prebid.js/` folder

        $ gulp build --modules=path/to/your/list-of-modules.json

Most likely your custom `prebid.js` will only change when there&#039;s:

- A change in your list of modules
- A new release of `prebid.js`

Having said that, you are probably safe to check your custom bundle into your project.  You can also generate it in your build process.

**Build once, bundle multiple times**

If you need to generate multiple distinct bundles from the same Prebid version, you can reuse a single build with:

```
gulp build
gulp bundle --tag one --modules=one.json
gulp bundle --tag two --modules=two.json
```

This generates slightly larger files, but has the advantage of being much faster to run (after the initial `gulp build`). It&#039;s also the method used by [the Prebid.org download page](https://docs.prebid.org/download.html).

&lt;a name=&quot;Run&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

### Excluding particular features from the build

Since version 7.2.0, you may instruct the build to exclude code for some features - for example, if you don&#039;t need support for native ads:

```
gulp build --disable NATIVE --modules=openxBidAdapter,rubiconBidAdapter,sovrnBidAdapter # substitute your module list
```

Or, if you are consuming Prebid through npm, with the `disableFeatures` option in your Prebid rule:

```javascript
  {
    test: /.js$/,
    include: new RegExp(`\\${path.sep}prebid\\.js`),
    use: {
      loader: &#039;babel-loader&#039;,
      options: require(&#039;prebid.js/babelConfig.js&#039;)({disableFeatures: [&#039;NATIVE&#039;]})
    }
  }
```

Features that can be disabled this way are:

 - `VIDEO` - support for video bids;
 - `NATIVE` - support for native bids;
 - `UID2_CSTG` - support for UID2 client side token generation (see [Unified ID 2.0](https://docs.prebid.org/dev-docs/modules/userid-submodules/unified2.html))
 - `GREEDY` - disables the use blocking, &quot;greedy&quot; promises within Prebid (see below).    

#### Greedy promises

By default, Prebid attempts to hold control of the main thread when possible, using a [custom implementation of `Promise`](https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js/blob/master/libraries/greedy/greedyPromise.js) that does not submit callbacks to the scheduler once the promise is resolved (running them immediately instead).
Disabling this behavior instructs Prebid to use the standard `window.Promise` instead; this has the effect of breaking up task execution, making them slower overall but giving the browser more chances to run other tasks in between, which can improve UX.         

You may also override the `Promise` constructor used by Prebid through `pbjs.Promise`, for example:

```javascript
var pbjs = pbjs || {};
pbjs.Promise = myCustomPromiseConstructor;
```

## Unminified code

You can get a version of the code that&#039;s unminified for debugging with `build-bundle-dev`:

```bash
gulp build-bundle-dev --modules=bidderA,module1,...
```

The results will be in build/dev/prebid.js.

## ES5 Output Support

For compatibility with older parsers or environments that require ES5 syntax, you can generate ES5-compatible output using the `--ES5` flag:

```bash
gulp build-bundle-dev --modules=bidderA,module1,... --ES5
```

This will:
- Transpile all code to ES5 syntax using CommonJS modules
- Target browsers: IE11+, Chrome 50+, Firefox 50+, Safari 10+
- Ensure compatibility with older JavaScript parsers

**Note:** Without the `--ES5` flag, the build will use modern ES6+ syntax by default for better performance and smaller bundle sizes.

## Test locally

To lint the code:

```bash
gulp lint
```

To lint and only show errors

```bash
gulp lint --no-lint-warnings
```

To run the unit tests:

```bash
gulp test
```

To run the unit tests for a particular file (example for pubmaticBidAdapter_spec.js):
```bash
gulp test --file &quot;test/spec/modules/pubmaticBidAdapter_spec.js&quot; --nolint
```

To generate and view the code coverage reports:

```bash
gulp test-coverage
gulp view-coverage
```

Local end-to-end testing can be done with:

```bash
gulp e2e-test --local
```

For Prebid.org members with access to BrowserStack, additional end-to-end testing can be done with:

```bash
gulp e2e-test --host=test.localhost
```

To run these tests, the following items are required:
- setup an alias of localhost in your `hosts` file (eg `127.0.0.1  test.localhost`); note - you can use any alias.  Use this alias in the command-line argument above.
- access to [BrowserStack](https://www.browserstack.com/) account.  Assign the following variables in your bash_profile:
```bash
export BROWSERSTACK_USERNAME=&#039;YourUserNameHere&#039;
export BROWSERSTACK_ACCESS_KEY=&#039;YourAccessKeyHere&#039;
```
You can get these BrowserStack values from your profile page.

For development:

```javascript
(function() {
    var d = document, pbs = d.createElement(&#039;script&#039;), pro = d.location.protocol;
    pbs.type = &#039;text/javascript&#039;;
    pbs.src = ((pro === &#039;https:&#039;) ? &#039;https&#039; : &#039;http&#039;) + &#039;./build/dev/prebid.js&#039;;
    var target = document.getElementsByTagName(&#039;head&#039;)[0];
    target.insertBefore(pbs, target.firstChild);
})();
```

For deployment:

```javascript
(function() {
    var d = document, pbs = d.createElement(&#039;script&#039;), pro = d.location.protocol;
    pbs.type = &#039;text/javascript&#039;;
    pbs.src = ((pro === &#039;https:&#039;) ? &#039;https&#039; : &#039;http&#039;) + &#039;./build/dist/prebid.js&#039;;
    var target = document.getElementsByTagName(&#039;head&#039;)[0];
    target.insertBefore(pbs, target.firstChild);
})();
```

Build and run the project locally with:

```bash
gulp serve
```

This runs `lint` and `test`, then starts a web server at `http://localhost:9999` serving from the project root.
Navigate to your example implementation to test, and if your `prebid.js` file is sourced from the `./build/dev`
directory you will have sourcemaps available in your browser&#039;s developer tools.

To run the example file, go to:

+ `http://localhost:9999/integrationExamples/gpt/hello_world.html`

As you make code changes, the bundles will be rebuilt and the page reloaded automatically.

&lt;a name=&quot;Contribute&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Contribute

Many SSPs, bidders, and publishers have contributed to this project. [Hundreds of bidders](https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js/tree/master/modules) are supported by Prebid.js.

For guidelines, see [Contributing](./CONTRIBUTING.md).

Our PR review process can be found [here](https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js/tree/master/PR_REVIEW.md).

### Add a Bidder Adapter

To add a bidder adapter module, see the instructions in [How to add a bidder adapter](https://docs.prebid.org/dev-docs/bidder-adaptor.html).

### Code Quality

Code quality is defined by `.eslintrc` and errors are reported in the terminal.

If you are contributing code, you should [configure your editor](http://eslint.org/docs/user-guide/integrations#editors) with the provided `.eslintrc` settings.

### Unit Testing with Karma

        $ gulp test --watch --browsers=chrome

This will run tests and keep the Karma test browser open. If your `prebid.js` file is sourced from the `./build/dev` directory you will also have sourcemaps available when using your browser&#039;s developer tools.

+ To access the Karma debug page, go to `http://localhost:9876/debug.html`

+ For test results, see the console

+ To set breakpoints in source code, see the developer tools

Detailed code coverage reporting can be generated explicitly with

        $ gulp test --coverage

The results will be in

        ./build/coverage

*Note*: Starting in June 2016, all pull requests to Prebid.js need to include tests with greater than 80% code coverage before they can be merged.  For more information, see [#421](https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js/issues/421).

For instructions on writing tests for Prebid.js, see [Testing Prebid.js](https://prebid.org/dev-docs/testing-prebid.html).

### Supported Browsers

Prebid.js is supported on IE11 and modern browsers until 5.x. 6.x+ transpiles to target &gt;0.25%; not Opera Mini; not IE11.

### Governance
Review our governance model [here](https://github.com/prebid/Prebid.js/tree/master/governance.md).
### END
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[lodash/lodash]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/lodash/lodash</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/lodash/lodash</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A modern JavaScript utility library delivering modularity, performance, & extras.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/lodash/lodash">lodash/lodash</a></h1>
            <p>A modern JavaScript utility library delivering modularity, performance, & extras.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 60,691</p>
            <p>Forks: 7,060</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># lodash v4.17.21

[Site](https://lodash.com/) |
[Docs](https://lodash.com/docs) |
[FP Guide](https://github.com/lodash/lodash/wiki/FP-Guide) |
[Contributing](https://github.com/lodash/lodash/blob/master/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md) |
[Wiki](https://github.com/lodash/lodash/wiki &quot;Changelog, Roadmap, etc.&quot;) |
[Code of Conduct](https://js.foundation/conduct/) |
[Twitter](https://twitter.com/bestiejs) |
[Chat](https://gitter.im/lodash/lodash)

The [Lodash](https://lodash.com/) library exported as a [UMD](https://github.com/umdjs/umd) module.

Generated using [lodash-cli](https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash-cli):
```shell
$ npm run build
$ lodash -o ./dist/lodash.js
$ lodash core -o ./dist/lodash.core.js
```

## Download

 * [Core build](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lodash/lodash/4.17.21/dist/lodash.core.js) ([~4 kB gzipped](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lodash/lodash/4.17.21/dist/lodash.core.min.js))
 * [Full build](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lodash/lodash/4.17.21/dist/lodash.js) ([~24 kB gzipped](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lodash/lodash/4.17.21/dist/lodash.min.js))
 * [CDN copies](https://www.jsdelivr.com/projects/lodash)

Lodash is released under the [MIT license](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lodash/lodash/4.17.21/LICENSE) &amp; supports modern environments.&lt;br&gt;
Review the [build differences](https://github.com/lodash/lodash/wiki/build-differences) &amp; pick one that’s right for you.

## Installation

In a browser:
```html
&lt;script src=&quot;lodash.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
```

Using npm:
```shell
$ npm i -g npm
$ npm i --save lodash
```

In Node.js:
```js
// Load the full build.
var _ = require(&#039;lodash&#039;);
// Load the core build.
var _ = require(&#039;lodash/core&#039;);
// Load the FP build for immutable auto-curried iteratee-first data-last methods.
var fp = require(&#039;lodash/fp&#039;);

// Load method categories.
var array = require(&#039;lodash/array&#039;);
var object = require(&#039;lodash/fp/object&#039;);

// Cherry-pick methods for smaller browserify/rollup/webpack bundles.
var at = require(&#039;lodash/at&#039;);
var curryN = require(&#039;lodash/fp/curryN&#039;);
```

**Note:**&lt;br&gt;
Install [n_](https://www.npmjs.com/package/n_) for Lodash use in the Node.js &lt; 6 REPL.

## Why Lodash?

Lodash makes JavaScript easier by taking the hassle out of working with arrays,&lt;br&gt;
numbers, objects, strings, etc. Lodash’s modular methods are great for:

 * Iterating arrays, objects, &amp; strings
 * Manipulating &amp; testing values
 * Creating composite functions

## Module Formats

Lodash is available in a [variety of builds](https://lodash.com/custom-builds) &amp; module formats.

 * [lodash](https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash) &amp; [per method packages](https://www.npmjs.com/browse/keyword/lodash-modularized)
 * [lodash-es](https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash-es), [babel-plugin-lodash](https://www.npmjs.com/package/babel-plugin-lodash), &amp; [lodash-webpack-plugin](https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash-webpack-plugin)
 * [lodash/fp](https://github.com/lodash/lodash/tree/npm/fp)
 * [lodash-amd](https://www.npmjs.com/package/lodash-amd)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>