<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for javascript - JavaScript Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for javascript.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SkyworkAI/DeepResearchAgent]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/SkyworkAI/DeepResearchAgent</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/SkyworkAI/DeepResearchAgent</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[DeepResearchAgent is a hierarchical multi-agent system designed not only for deep research tasks but also for general-purpose task solving. The framework leverages a top-level planning agent to coordinate multiple specialized lower-level agents, enabling automated task decomposition and efficient execution across diverse and complex domains.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/SkyworkAI/DeepResearchAgent">SkyworkAI/DeepResearchAgent</a></h1>
            <p>DeepResearchAgent is a hierarchical multi-agent system designed not only for deep research tasks but also for general-purpose task solving. The framework leverages a top-level planning agent to coordinate multiple specialized lower-level agents, enabling automated task decomposition and efficient execution across diverse and complex domains.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,324</p>
            <p>Forks: 322</p>
            <p>Stars today: 63 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># DeepResearchAgent

[![Website](https://img.shields.io/badge/🌐-Website-blue?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github)](https://skyworkai.github.io/DeepResearchAgent/)
[![Paper](https://img.shields.io/badge/📄-arXiv%20Paper-red?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=arxiv)](https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12508)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-green?style=for-the-badge)](LICENSE)

English | [简体中文](README_CN.md) | [🌐 **Website**](https://skyworkai.github.io/DeepResearchAgent/)

## Introduction
image.png
DeepResearchAgent is a hierarchical multi-agent system designed not only for deep research tasks but also for general-purpose task solving. The framework leverages a top-level planning agent to coordinate multiple specialized lower-level agents, enabling automated task decomposition and efficient execution across diverse and complex domains.

&gt; 🌐 **Check out our interactive website**: [https://skyworkai.github.io/DeepResearchAgent/](https://skyworkai.github.io/DeepResearchAgent/) - Explore the architecture, view experiments, and learn more about our research!

## Architecture

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/architecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;Architecture&quot; width=&quot;700&quot;/&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

The system adopts a two-layer structure:

### 1. Top-Level Planning Agent

* Responsible for understanding, decomposing, and planning the overall workflow for a given task.
* Breaks down tasks into manageable sub-tasks and assigns them to appropriate lower-level agents.
* Dynamically coordinates the collaboration among agents to ensure smooth task completion.

### 2. Specialized Lower-Level Agents

* **Deep Analyzer**

  * Performs in-depth analysis of input information, extracting key insights and potential requirements.
  * Supports analysis of various data types, including text and structured data.
* **Deep Researcher**

  * Conducts thorough research on specified topics or questions, retrieving and synthesizing high-quality information.
  * Capable of generating research reports or knowledge summaries automatically.
* **Browser Use**

  * Automates browser operations, supporting web search, information extraction, and data collection tasks.
  * Assists the Deep Researcher in acquiring up-to-date information from the internet.
  
* **MCP Manager Agent**
  * Manages and orchestrates Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools and services.
  * Enables dynamic tool discovery, registration, and execution through MCP standards.
  * Supports both local and remote MCP tool integration for enhanced agent capabilities.

* **General Tool Calling Agent**
  * Provides a general-purpose interface for invoking various tools and APIs.
  * Supports function calling, allowing the agent to execute specific tasks or retrieve information from external services.

## Features

- Hierarchical agent collaboration for complex and dynamic task scenarios
- Extensible agent system, allowing easy integration of additional specialized agents
- Automated information analysis, research, and web interaction capabilities
- Secure Python code execution environment for tools, featuring configurable import controls, restricted built-ins, attribute access limitations, and resource limits. (See [PythonInterpreterTool Sandboxing](./docs/python_interpreter_sandbox.md) for details).
- Support for asynchronous operations, enabling efficient handling of multiple tasks and agents
- Support for local and remote model inference, including OpenAI, Anthropic, Google LLMs, and local Qwen models via vLLM
- Support for image and video generation tools based on the Imagen and Veo3 models, respectively

Image and Video Examples:
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/cat_yarn_playful_reference.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image Example&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/cat_playing_with_yarn_video.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Video Example&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Updates
* **2025.08.04**: Add the support for loading mcp tools from the local json file.
* **2025.07.08**: Add the video generator tool, which can generate a video based on the input text and/or image. The video generator tool is based on the Veo3 model.
* **2025.07.08**: Add the image generator tool, which can generate images based on the input text. The image generator tool is based on the Imagen model.
* **2025.07.07**: Due to the limited flexibility of TOML configuration files, we have switched to using the config format supported by mmengine.
* **2025.06.20**: Add the support for the mcp (Both the local mcp and remote mcp).
* **2025.06.17**: Update technical report https://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.12508.
* **2025.06.01**: Update the browser-use to 0.1.48.
* **2025.05.30**: Convert the sub agent to a function call. Planning agent can now be gpt-4.1 or gemini-2.5-pro.
* **2025.05.27**: Support OpenAI, Anthropic, Google LLMs, and local Qwen models (via vLLM, see details in [Usage](#usage)).

## TODO List

* [x] Asynchronous feature completed
* [x] Image Generator Tool completed
* [x] Video Generator Tool completed
* [x] MCP in progress
* [x] Load local MCP tools from JSON file completed
* [ ] AI4Research Agent to be developed
* [ ] Novel Writing Agent to be developed

## Installation

### Prepare Environment

```bash
# poetry install environment
conda create -n dra python=3.11
conda activate dra
make install

# (Optional) You can also use requirements.txt
conda create -n dra python=3.11
conda activate dra
make install-requirements

# playwright install if needed
pip install playwright
playwright install chromium --with-deps --no-shell
```

### Set Up `.env`

Please refer to the `.env.template` file and create a `.env` file in the root directory of the project. This file is used to configure API keys and other environment variables.

Refer to the following instructions to obtain the necessary google gemini-2.5-pro API key and set it in the `.env` file:

* [https://aistudio.google.com/app/apikey](https://aistudio.google.com/app/apikey)
* [https://cloud.google.com/docs/authentication/application-default-credentials?hl=zh-cn](https://cloud.google.com/docs/authentication/application-default-credentials?hl=zh-cn)

```bash
brew install --cask google-cloud-sdk
gcloud init
gcloud auth application-default login
```

## Usage

### Main Example
A simple example to demonstrate the usage of the DeepResearchAgent framework.
```bash
python main.py
```

### Run Single Agent Example
A simple example to demonstrate the usage of a single agent, such as a general tool calling agent.
```bash
python examples/run_general.py
```

### RUN GAIA Evaluation Example

```bash
# Download GAIA
mkdir data &amp;&amp; cd data
git clone https://huggingface.co/datasets/gaia-benchmark/GAIA

# Run
python examples/run_gaia.py
```

## Experiments

We evaluated our agent on both GAIA validation and test sets, achieving state-of-the-art performance. Our system demonstrates superior performance across all difficulty levels.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/gaia_test.png&quot; alt=&quot;GAIA Test Results&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/assets/gaia_validation.png&quot; alt=&quot;GAIA Validation Results&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

With the integration of the Computer Use and MCP Manager Agent, which now enables pixel-level control of the browser, our system demonstrates remarkable evolutionary capabilities. The agents can dynamically acquire and enhance their abilities through learning and adaptation, leading to significantly improved performance. The latest results show:
- **Test Set**: 83.39 (average), with 93.55 on Level 1, 83.02 on Level 2, and 65.31 on Level 3
- **Validation Set**: 82.4 (average), with 92.5 on Level 1, 83.7 on Level 2, and 57.7 on Level 3

## Questions

### 1. About Qwen Models

Our framework now supports:

* qwen2.5-7b-instruct
* qwen2.5-14b-instruct
* qwen2.5-32b-instruct

Update your config:

```toml
model_id = &quot;qwen2.5-7b-instruct&quot;
```

### 2. Browser Use

If problems occur, reinstall:

```bash
pip install &quot;browser-use[memory]&quot;==0.1.48
pip install playwright
playwright install chromium --with-deps --no-shell
```

### 3. Sub-Agent Calling

Function-calling is now supported natively by GPT-4.1 / Gemini 2.5 Pro. Claude-3.7-Sonnet is also recommended.

### 4. Use vllm for local models
We provide huggingface as a shortcut to the local model. Also provide vllm as a way to start services so that parallel acceleration can be provided.

#### Step 1: Launch the vLLM Inference Service

```bash
nohup bash -c &#039;CUDA_VISIBLE_DEVICES=0,1 python -m vllm.entrypoints.openai.api_server \
  --model /input0/Qwen3-32B \
  --served-model-name Qwen \
  --host 0.0.0.0 \
  --port 8000 \
  --max-num-seqs 16 \
  --enable-auto-tool-choice \
  --tool-call-parser hermes \
  --tensor_parallel_size 2&#039; &gt; vllm_qwen.log 2&gt;&amp;1 &amp;
```

Update `.env`:

```bash
QWEN_API_BASE=http://localhost:8000/v1
QWEN_API_KEY=&quot;abc&quot;
```

#### Step 2: Launch the Agent Service

```bash
python main.py
```

Example command:

```bash
Use deep_researcher_agent to search the latest papers on the topic of &#039;AI Agent&#039; and then summarize it.
```

## Acknowledgement

DeepResearchAgent is primarily inspired by the architecture of smolagents. The following improvements have been made:
- The codebase of smolagents has been modularized for better structure and organization.
- The original synchronous framework has been refactored into an asynchronous one.
- The multi-agent setup process has been optimized to make it more user-friendly and efficient.

We would like to express our gratitude to the following open source projects, which have greatly contributed to the development of this work:
- [smolagents](https://github.com/huggingface/smolagents) - A lightweight agent framework.
- [OpenManus](https://github.com/mannaandpoem/OpenManus) - An asynchronous agent framework.
- [browser-use](https://github.com/browser-use/browser-use) - An AI-powered browser automation tool.
- [crawl4ai](https://github.com/unclecode/crawl4ai) - A web crawling library for AI applications.
- [markitdown](https://github.com/microsoft/markitdown) - A tool for converting files to Markdown format.

We sincerely appreciate the efforts of all contributors and maintainers of these projects for their commitment to advancing AI technologies and making them available to the wider community.

## Contribution

Contributions and suggestions are welcome! Feel free to open issues or submit pull requests.

## Cite

```bibtex
@misc{zhang2025agentorchestrahierarchicalmultiagentframework,
      title={AgentOrchestra: A Hierarchical Multi-Agent Framework for General-Purpose Task Solving}, 
      author={Wentao Zhang, Liang Zeng, Yuzhen Xiao, Yongcong Li, Ce Cui, Yilei Zhao, Rui Hu, Yang Liu, Yahui Zhou, Bo An},
      year={2025},
      eprint={2506.12508},
      archivePrefix={arXiv},
      primaryClass={cs.AI},
      url={https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12508}, 
}
```

---

### 🇨🇳 中文版说明文档

如果你更习惯阅读中文说明文档，请查阅 [README_CN.md](./README_CN.md)。
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[asgeirtj/system_prompts_leaks]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/asgeirtj/system_prompts_leaks</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/asgeirtj/system_prompts_leaks</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Collection of extracted System Prompts from popular chatbots like ChatGPT, Claude & Gemini]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/asgeirtj/system_prompts_leaks">asgeirtj/system_prompts_leaks</a></h1>
            <p>Collection of extracted System Prompts from popular chatbots like ChatGPT, Claude & Gemini</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,599</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,237</p>
            <p>Stars today: 142 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[arkime/arkime]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/arkime/arkime</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/arkime/arkime</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Arkime is an open source, large scale, full packet capturing, indexing, and database system.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/arkime/arkime">arkime/arkime</a></h1>
            <p>Arkime is an open source, large scale, full packet capturing, indexing, and database system.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,047</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,111</p>
            <p>Stars today: 164 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![OpenSSF Best Practices](https://www.bestpractices.dev/projects/7997/badge)](https://www.bestpractices.dev/projects/7997)
[![GitHub tag (with filter)](https://img.shields.io/github/v/tag/arkime/arkime?label=download&amp;color=a800fc)](https://arkime.com/#download)
[![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache_2.0-D22128)](https://github.com/arkime/arkime/blob/main/LICENSE)
[![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on_Slack-ECB22E?logo=slack)](https://slackinvite.arkime.com/)
[![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/follow_us-on_LinkedIn-0077B5?logo=linkedin)](https://www.linkedin.com/company/arkime)


# Arkime
&gt; Arkime is a large scale, open-source network analysis and packet capture system.

![banner](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/arkime/arkime/main/assets/Arkime_Logo_FullGradientBlack@3x.png)

Arkime augments your current security infrastructure to store and index network traffic in standard PCAP format, providing fast, indexed access. An intuitive and simple web interface is provided for PCAP browsing, searching, and exporting. Arkime exposes APIs which allow for PCAP data and JSON formatted session data to be downloaded and consumed directly. Arkime stores and exports all packets in standard PCAP format, allowing you to also use your favorite PCAP ingesting tools, such as wireshark, during your analysis workflow.

Arkime is built to be deployed across many systems and can scale to handle tens of gigabits/sec of traffic. PCAP retention is based on available sensor disk space. Metadata retention is based on the Elasticsearch cluster scale. Both can be increased at anytime and are under your complete control.

[Learn more on arkime.com](https://arkime.com)

## Table of Contents

- [Background](#background)
- [Installation](#installation)
- [Configuration](#configuration)
- [Usage](#usage)
- [Security](#security)
- [API](#api)
- [Contribute](#contribute)
- [License](#license)

## Background

Arkime, previously named Moloch, was created to replace commercial full packet systems at AOL in 2012. By having complete control of hardware and costs, we found we could deploy full packet capture across all our networks for the same cost as just one network using a commercial tool, with larger retention.

The Arkime system is comprised of 3 main components:
* **capture** - A threaded C application that monitors network traffic, writes PCAP formatted files to local disk, parses the captured packets, and sends metadata (SPI data) to OpenSearch/Elasticsearch.
* **viewer** - A [node.js](http://nodejs.org/) application that runs per capture machine. It handles the web interface and transfer of packets to the browser.
* **[OpenSearch](https://opensearch.org/downloads.html)/[Elasticsearch](https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/current/getting-started.html)** - The search database technology powering Arkime.

We also provide several optional applications:
* **cont3xt** - An application that provides a structured approach to gathering contextual intelligence in support of technical investigations.
* **esProxy** - A proxy that provides extra security between capture and OpenSearch/Elasticsearch.
* **Parliament** - An application that monitors and is a front door to multiple Arkime clusters.
* **wiseService** - An application that integrates threat intelligence into the session metadata.


Arkime offers a user-friendly web interface for exploring network data. The Sessions page provides a comprehensive overview, listing individual sessions that can be expanded to view metadata and packet details.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/arkime/arkimeweb/blob/main/assets/sessions.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;


The SPI View page offers a detailed breakdown of data, displaying all unique values for each field recognized by Arkime

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/arkime/arkimeweb/blob/main/assets/spiview.png&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;

## Installation

Most users should use the prebuilt binaries available on our [Downloads page](https://arkime.com/downloads) and follow the [simple install instructions](https://arkime.com/install). We also provide containers see the [Docker instructions](https://arkime.com/docker) for the best tag to use.

For advanced users, you can build Arkime yourself:
* Make sure `node` is in your path, currently main supports Node version 20.x
* `git clone https://github.com/arkime/arkime` - latest version on github
* Find your OS in `.github/workflow/versions` for the easybutton options to use
* `./easybutton-build.sh [easybutton options] --install` - build and install Arkime
* `make config` - performs an initial Arkime configuration
* Refer to the [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md) file for information about how to get involved

## Configuration

Most of the system configuration is located in the `/opt/arkime/etc/config.ini` file.  The variables are documented on our [Settings page](https://arkime.com/settings).

## Usage

Once Arkime is running, point your browser to http://localhost:8005 to access the web interface.  **Click on the Owl to reach the Arkime help page.**

## Security

Access to Arkime is protected by using HTTPS with digest passwords or by using an authentication providing web server proxy. All PCAPs are stored on the sensors and are only accessed using the Arkime interface or API. Arkime is not meant to replace an IDS but instead work alongside them to store and index all the network traffic in standard PCAP format, providing fast access.


* Arkime can be configured to use OpenSearch/Elasticsearch user auth or API keys.

* Arkime machines should be locked down, however they need to talk to each other (port 8005), to the elasticsearch machines (ports 9200-920x), and the web interface needs to be open (port 8005).

* Arkime ``viewer`` should be configured to use TLS.

  - It&#039;s easiest to use a single certificate with multiple DNs or a wildcard.
  - Make sure you protect the cert on the filesystem with proper file permissions.
  - Edit certFile and keyFile settings in ``/opt/arkime/etc/config.ini.ini`` to enable.

* For large deployments it is possible to set up a Arkime ``viewer`` on a central machine that doesn&#039;t capture any data, instead the machine gateways all UI requests.

  - Using a reverse proxy (Caddy, Apache, ...) can handle the authentication and pass the username on to Arkime, this is how we deploy it.

* A shared password stored in the Arkime configuration file is used to encrypt password hashes AND for inter-Arkime communication.

  - Make sure you protect the config file on the filesystem with proper file permissions.
  - Encrypted password hashes are used so a new password hash can not be inserted into OpenSearch/Elasticsearch directly in case it hasn&#039;t been secured.

## API

You can learn more about the Arkime API on our [API page](https://arkime.com/api).


## Contribute

Please refer to the [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md) file for information about how to get involved. We welcome issues, feature requests, pull requests, and documentation updates in GitHub.  For questions about using and troubleshooting Arkime please use the Slack channels.

## Maintainers

The best way to reach us is on Slack.  Please request an invitation to join the Arkime Slack workspace [here](https://slackinvite.arkime.com).

## License

This project is licensed under the terms of the Apache 2.0 open source license. Please refer to [LICENSE](LICENSE) for the full terms.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[axios/axios]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/axios/axios</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/axios/axios</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Promise based HTTP client for the browser and node.js]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/axios/axios">axios/axios</a></h1>
            <p>Promise based HTTP client for the browser and node.js</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 107,624</p>
            <p>Forks: 11,198</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># axios

[![npm version](https://img.shields.io/npm/v/axios.svg?style=flat-square)](https://www.npmjs.org/package/axios)
[![CDNJS](https://img.shields.io/cdnjs/v/axios.svg?style=flat-square)](https://cdnjs.com/libraries/axios)
![Build status](https://github.com/axios/axios/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg)
[![Gitpod Ready-to-Code](https://img.shields.io/badge/Gitpod-Ready--to--Code-blue?logo=gitpod)](https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/axios/axios) 
[![code coverage](https://img.shields.io/coveralls/mzabriskie/axios.svg?style=flat-square)](https://coveralls.io/r/mzabriskie/axios)
[![install size](https://packagephobia.now.sh/badge?p=axios)](https://packagephobia.now.sh/result?p=axios)
[![npm downloads](https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/axios.svg?style=flat-square)](https://npm-stat.com/charts.html?package=axios)
[![gitter chat](https://img.shields.io/gitter/room/mzabriskie/axios.svg?style=flat-square)](https://gitter.im/mzabriskie/axios)
[![code helpers](https://www.codetriage.com/axios/axios/badges/users.svg)](https://www.codetriage.com/axios/axios)
[![Known Vulnerabilities](https://snyk.io/test/npm/axios/badge.svg)](https://snyk.io/test/npm/axios)
![npm bundle size](https://img.shields.io/bundlephobia/minzip/axios)

Promise based HTTP client for the browser and node.js

&gt; New axios docs website: [click here](https://axios-http.com/)

## Table of Contents

  - [Features](#features)
  - [Browser Support](#browser-support)
  - [Installing](#installing)
  - [Example](#example)
  - [Axios API](#axios-api)
  - [Request method aliases](#request-method-aliases)
  - [Concurrency 👎](#concurrency-deprecated)
  - [Creating an instance](#creating-an-instance)
  - [Instance methods](#instance-methods)
  - [Request Config](#request-config)
  - [Response Schema](#response-schema)
  - [Config Defaults](#config-defaults)
    - [Global axios defaults](#global-axios-defaults)
    - [Custom instance defaults](#custom-instance-defaults)
    - [Config order of precedence](#config-order-of-precedence)
  - [Interceptors](#interceptors)
    - [Multiple Interceptors](#multiple-interceptors)
  - [Handling Errors](#handling-errors)
  - [Cancellation](#cancellation)
    - [AbortController](#abortcontroller)
    - [CancelToken 👎](#canceltoken-deprecated)
  - [Using application/x-www-form-urlencoded format](#using-applicationx-www-form-urlencoded-format)
    - [URLSearchParams](#urlsearchparams)
    - [Query string](#query-string-older-browsers)
    - [🆕 Automatic serialization](#-automatic-serialization-to-urlsearchparams)        
  - [Using multipart/form-data format](#using-multipartform-data-format)    
    - [FormData](#formdata)
    - [🆕 Automatic serialization](#-automatic-serialization-to-formdata) 
  - [Files Posting](#files-posting)
  - [HTML Form Posting](#html-form-posting-browser)
  - [Semver](#semver)
  - [Promises](#promises)
  - [TypeScript](#typescript)
  - [Resources](#resources)
  - [Credits](#credits)
  - [License](#license)

## Features

- Make [XMLHttpRequests](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/XMLHttpRequest) from the browser
- Make [http](https://nodejs.org/api/http.html) requests from node.js
- Supports the [Promise](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Promise) API
- Intercept request and response
- Transform request and response data
- Cancel requests
- Automatic transforms for JSON data
- 🆕 Automatic data object serialization to `multipart/form-data` and `x-www-form-urlencoded` body encodings
- Client side support for protecting against [XSRF](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_request_forgery)

## Browser Support

![Chrome](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/main/src/chrome/chrome_48x48.png) | ![Firefox](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/main/src/firefox/firefox_48x48.png) | ![Safari](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/main/src/safari/safari_48x48.png) | ![Opera](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/main/src/opera/opera_48x48.png) | ![Edge](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/main/src/edge/edge_48x48.png) | ![IE](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alrra/browser-logos/master/src/archive/internet-explorer_9-11/internet-explorer_9-11_48x48.png) |
--- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
Latest ✔ | Latest ✔ | Latest ✔ | Latest ✔ | Latest ✔ | 11 ✔ |

[![Browser Matrix](https://saucelabs.com/open_sauce/build_matrix/axios.svg)](https://saucelabs.com/u/axios)

## Installing

Using npm:

```bash
$ npm install axios
```

Using bower:

```bash
$ bower install axios
```

Using yarn:

```bash
$ yarn add axios
```

Using pnpm:

```bash
$ pnpm add axios
```

Using jsDelivr CDN:

```html
&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/axios/dist/axios.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
```

Using unpkg CDN:

```html
&lt;script src=&quot;https://unpkg.com/axios/dist/axios.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
```

## Example

### note: CommonJS usage
In order to gain the TypeScript typings (for intellisense / autocomplete) while using CommonJS imports with `require()` use the following approach:

```js
const axios = require(&#039;axios&#039;).default;

// axios.&lt;method&gt; will now provide autocomplete and parameter typings
```

Performing a `GET` request

```js
const axios = require(&#039;axios&#039;).default;

// Make a request for a user with a given ID
axios.get(&#039;/user?ID=12345&#039;)
  .then(function (response) {
    // handle success
    console.log(response);
  })
  .catch(function (error) {
    // handle error
    console.log(error);
  })
  .then(function () {
    // always executed
  });

// Optionally the request above could also be done as
axios.get(&#039;/user&#039;, {
    params: {
      ID: 12345
    }
  })
  .then(function (response) {
    console.log(response);
  })
  .catch(function (error) {
    console.log(error);
  })
  .then(function () {
    // always executed
  });  

// Want to use async/await? Add the `async` keyword to your outer function/method.
async function getUser() {
  try {
    const response = await axios.get(&#039;/user?ID=12345&#039;);
    console.log(response);
  } catch (error) {
    console.error(error);
  }
}
```

&gt; **NOTE:** `async/await` is part of ECMAScript 2017 and is not supported in Internet
&gt; Explorer and older browsers, so use with caution.

Performing a `POST` request

```js
axios.post(&#039;/user&#039;, {
    firstName: &#039;Fred&#039;,
    lastName: &#039;Flintstone&#039;
  })
  .then(function (response) {
    console.log(response);
  })
  .catch(function (error) {
    console.log(error);
  });
```

Performing multiple concurrent requests

```js
function getUserAccount() {
  return axios.get(&#039;/user/12345&#039;);
}

function getUserPermissions() {
  return axios.get(&#039;/user/12345/permissions&#039;);
}

Promise.all([getUserAccount(), getUserPermissions()])
  .then(function (results) {
    const acct = results[0];
    const perm = results[1];
  });
```

## axios API

Requests can be made by passing the relevant config to `axios`.

##### axios(config)

```js
// Send a POST request
axios({
  method: &#039;post&#039;,
  url: &#039;/user/12345&#039;,
  data: {
    firstName: &#039;Fred&#039;,
    lastName: &#039;Flintstone&#039;
  }
});
```

```js
// GET request for remote image in node.js
axios({
  method: &#039;get&#039;,
  url: &#039;https://bit.ly/2mTM3nY&#039;,
  responseType: &#039;stream&#039;
})
  .then(function (response) {
    response.data.pipe(fs.createWriteStream(&#039;ada_lovelace.jpg&#039;))
  });
```

##### axios(url[, config])

```js
// Send a GET request (default method)
axios(&#039;/user/12345&#039;);
```

### Request method aliases

For convenience, aliases have been provided for all common request methods.

##### axios.request(config)
##### axios.get(url[, config])
##### axios.delete(url[, config])
##### axios.head(url[, config])
##### axios.options(url[, config])
##### axios.post(url[, data[, config]])
##### axios.put(url[, data[, config]])
##### axios.patch(url[, data[, config]])

###### NOTE
When using the alias methods `url`, `method`, and `data` properties don&#039;t need to be specified in config.

### Concurrency (Deprecated)
Please use `Promise.all` to replace the below functions.

Helper functions for dealing with concurrent requests.

axios.all(iterable)
axios.spread(callback)

### Creating an instance

You can create a new instance of axios with a custom config.

##### axios.create([config])

```js
const instance = axios.create({
  baseURL: &#039;https://some-domain.com/api/&#039;,
  timeout: 1000,
  headers: {&#039;X-Custom-Header&#039;: &#039;foobar&#039;}
});
```

### Instance methods

The available instance methods are listed below. The specified config will be merged with the instance config.

##### axios#request(config)
##### axios#get(url[, config])
##### axios#delete(url[, config])
##### axios#head(url[, config])
##### axios#options(url[, config])
##### axios#post(url[, data[, config]])
##### axios#put(url[, data[, config]])
##### axios#patch(url[, data[, config]])
##### axios#getUri([config])

## Request Config

These are the available config options for making requests. Only the `url` is required. Requests will default to `GET` if `method` is not specified.

```js
{
  // `url` is the server URL that will be used for the request
  url: &#039;/user&#039;,

  // `method` is the request method to be used when making the request
  method: &#039;get&#039;, // default

  // `baseURL` will be prepended to `url` unless `url` is absolute.
  // It can be convenient to set `baseURL` for an instance of axios to pass relative URLs
  // to methods of that instance.
  baseURL: &#039;https://some-domain.com/api/&#039;,

  // `transformRequest` allows changes to the request data before it is sent to the server
  // This is only applicable for request methods &#039;PUT&#039;, &#039;POST&#039;, &#039;PATCH&#039; and &#039;DELETE&#039;
  // The last function in the array must return a string or an instance of Buffer, ArrayBuffer,
  // FormData or Stream
  // You may modify the headers object.
  transformRequest: [function (data, headers) {
    // Do whatever you want to transform the data

    return data;
  }],

  // `transformResponse` allows changes to the response data to be made before
  // it is passed to then/catch
  transformResponse: [function (data) {
    // Do whatever you want to transform the data

    return data;
  }],

  // `headers` are custom headers to be sent
  headers: {&#039;X-Requested-With&#039;: &#039;XMLHttpRequest&#039;},

  // `params` are the URL parameters to be sent with the request
  // Must be a plain object or a URLSearchParams object
  params: {
    ID: 12345
  },

  // `paramsSerializer` is an optional config in charge of serializing `params`
  paramsSerializer: {
    indexes: null // array indexes format (null - no brackets, false - empty brackets, true - brackets with indexes)
  },

  // `data` is the data to be sent as the request body
  // Only applicable for request methods &#039;PUT&#039;, &#039;POST&#039;, &#039;DELETE , and &#039;PATCH&#039;
  // When no `transformRequest` is set, must be of one of the following types:
  // - string, plain object, ArrayBuffer, ArrayBufferView, URLSearchParams
  // - Browser only: FormData, File, Blob
  // - Node only: Stream, Buffer
  data: {
    firstName: &#039;Fred&#039;
  },
  
  // syntax alternative to send data into the body
  // method post
  // only the value is sent, not the key
  data: &#039;Country=Brasil&amp;City=Belo Horizonte&#039;,

  // `timeout` specifies the number of milliseconds before the request times out.
  // If the request takes longer than `timeout`, the request will be aborted.
  timeout: 1000, // default is `0` (no timeout)

  // `withCredentials` indicates whether or not cross-site Access-Control requests
  // should be made using credentials
  withCredentials: false, // default

  // `adapter` allows custom handling of requests which makes testing easier.
  // Return a promise and supply a valid response (see lib/adapters/README.md).
  adapter: function (config) {
    /* ... */
  },

  // `auth` indicates that HTTP Basic auth should be used, and supplies credentials.
  // This will set an `Authorization` header, overwriting any existing
  // `Authorization` custom headers you have set using `headers`.
  // Please note that only HTTP Basic auth is configurable through this parameter.
  // For Bearer tokens and such, use `Authorization` custom headers instead.
  auth: {
    username: &#039;janedoe&#039;,
    password: &#039;s00pers3cret&#039;
  },

  // `responseType` indicates the type of data that the server will respond with
  // options are: &#039;arraybuffer&#039;, &#039;document&#039;, &#039;json&#039;, &#039;text&#039;, &#039;stream&#039;
  //   browser only: &#039;blob&#039;
  responseType: &#039;json&#039;, // default

  // `responseEncoding` indicates encoding to use for decoding responses (Node.js only)
  // Note: Ignored for `responseType` of &#039;stream&#039; or client-side requests
  responseEncoding: &#039;utf8&#039;, // default

  // `xsrfCookieName` is the name of the cookie to use as a value for xsrf token
  xsrfCookieName: &#039;XSRF-TOKEN&#039;, // default

  // `xsrfHeaderName` is the name of the http header that carries the xsrf token value
  xsrfHeaderName: &#039;X-XSRF-TOKEN&#039;, // default

  // `onUploadProgress` allows handling of progress events for uploads
  // browser only
  onUploadProgress: function (progressEvent) {
    // Do whatever you want with the native progress event
  },

  // `onDownloadProgress` allows handling of progress events for downloads
  // browser only
  onDownloadProgress: function (progressEvent) {
    // Do whatever you want with the native progress event
  },

  // `maxContentLength` defines the max size of the http response content in bytes allowed in node.js
  maxContentLength: 2000,

  // `maxBodyLength` (Node only option) defines the max size of the http request content in bytes allowed
  maxBodyLength: 2000,

  // `validateStatus` defines whether to resolve or reject the promise for a given
  // HTTP response status code. If `validateStatus` returns `true` (or is set to `null`
  // or `undefined`), the promise will be resolved; otherwise, the promise will be
  // rejected.
  validateStatus: function (status) {
    return status &gt;= 200 &amp;&amp; status &lt; 300; // default
  },

  // `maxRedirects` defines the maximum number of redirects to follow in node.js.
  // If set to 0, no redirects will be followed.
  maxRedirects: 21, // default

  // `beforeRedirect` defines a function that will be called before redirect.
  // Use this to adjust the request options upon redirecting,
  // to inspect the latest response headers,
  // or to cancel the request by throwing an error
  // If maxRedirects is set to 0, `beforeRedirect` is not used.
  beforeRedirect: (options, { headers }) =&gt; {
    if (options.hostname === &quot;example.com&quot;) {
      options.auth = &quot;user:password&quot;;
    }
  },

  // `socketPath` defines a UNIX Socket to be used in node.js.
  // e.g. &#039;/var/run/docker.sock&#039; to send requests to the docker daemon.
  // Only either `socketPath` or `proxy` can be specified.
  // If both are specified, `socketPath` is used.
  socketPath: null, // default

  // `httpAgent` and `httpsAgent` define a custom agent to be used when performing http
  // and https requests, respectively, in node.js. This allows options to be added like
  // `keepAlive` that are not enabled by default.
  httpAgent: new http.Agent({ keepAlive: true }),
  httpsAgent: new https.Agent({ keepAlive: true }),

  // `proxy` defines the hostname, port, and protocol of the proxy server.
  // You can also define your proxy using the conventional `http_proxy` and
  // `https_proxy` environment variables. If you are using environment variables
  // for your proxy configuration, you can also define a `no_proxy` environment
  // variable as a comma-separated list of domains that should not be proxied.
  // Use `false` to disable proxies, ignoring environment variables.
  // `auth` indicates that HTTP Basic auth should be used to connect to the proxy, and
  // supplies credentials.
  // This will set an `Proxy-Authorization` header, overwriting any existing
  // `Proxy-Authorization` custom headers you have set using `headers`.
  // If the proxy server uses HTTPS, then you must set the protocol to `https`. 
  proxy: {
    protocol: &#039;https&#039;,
    host: &#039;127.0.0.1&#039;,
    port: 9000,
    auth: {
      username: &#039;mikeymike&#039;,
      password: &#039;rapunz3l&#039;
    }
  },

  // `cancelToken` specifies a cancel token that can be used to cancel the request
  // (see Cancellation section below for details)
  cancelToken: new CancelToken(function (cancel) {
  }),

  // an alternative way to cancel Axios requests using AbortController
  signal: new AbortController().signal,

  // `decompress` indicates whether or not the response body should be decompressed 
  // automatically. If set to `true` will also remove the &#039;content-encoding&#039; header 
  // from the responses objects of all decompressed responses
  // - Node only (XHR cannot turn off decompression)
  decompress: true // default

  // `insecureHTTPParser` boolean.
  // Indicates where to use an insecure HTTP parser that accepts invalid HTTP headers.
  // This may allow interoperability with non-conformant HTTP implementations.
  // Using the insecure parser should be avoided.
  // see options https://nodejs.org/dist/latest-v12.x/docs/api/http.html#http_http_request_url_options_callback
  // see also https://nodejs.org/en/blog/vulnerability/february-2020-security-releases/#strict-http-header-parsing-none
  insecureHTTPParser: undefined // default

  // transitional options for backward compatibility that may be removed in the newer versions
  transitional: {
    // silent JSON parsing mode
    // `true`  - ignore JSON parsing errors and set response.data to null if parsing failed (old behaviour)
    // `false` - throw SyntaxError if JSON parsing failed (Note: responseType must be set to &#039;json&#039;)
    silentJSONParsing: true, // default value for the current Axios version

    // try to parse the response string as JSON even if `responseType` is not &#039;json&#039;
    forcedJSONParsing: true,
    
    // throw ETIMEDOUT error instead of generic ECONNABORTED on request timeouts
    clarifyTimeoutError: false,
  },

  env: {
    // The FormData class to be used to automatically serialize the payload into a FormData object
    FormData: window?.FormData || global?.FormData
  },

  formSerializer: {
      visitor: (value, key, path, helpers)=&gt; {}; // custom visitor funaction to serrialize form values
      dots: boolean; // use dots instead of brackets format
      metaTokens: boolean; // keep special endings like {} in parameter key 
      indexes: boolean; // array indexes format null - no brackets, false - empty brackets, true - brackets with indexes
  }
}
```

## Response Schema

The response for a request contains the following information.

```js
{
  // `data` is the response that was provided by the server
  data: {},

  // `status` is the HTTP status code from the server response
  status: 200,

  // `statusText` is the HTTP status message from the server response
  statusText: &#039;OK&#039;,

  // `headers` the HTTP headers that the server responded with
  // All header names are lowercase and can be accessed using the bracket notation.
  // Example: `response.headers[&#039;content-type&#039;]`
  headers: {},

  // `config` is the config that was provided to `axios` for the request
  config: {},

  // `request` is the request that generated this response
  // It is the last ClientRequest instance in node.js (in redirects)
  // and an XMLHttpRequest instance in the browser
  request: {}
}
```

When using `then`, you will receive the response as follows:

```js
axios.get(&#039;/user/12345&#039;)
  .then(function (response) {
    console.log(response.data);
    console.log(response.status);
    console.log(response.statusText);
    console.log(response.headers);
    console.log(response.config);
  });
```

When using `catch`, or passing a [rejection callback](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/Promise/then) as second parameter of `then`, the response will be available through the `error` object as explained in the [Handling Errors](#handling-errors) section.

## Config Defaults

You can specify config defaults that will be applied to every request.

### Global axios defaults

```js
axios.defaults.bas

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WebKit/WebKit]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/WebKit/WebKit</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/WebKit/WebKit</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Home of the WebKit project, the browser engine used by Safari, Mail, App Store and many other applications on macOS, iOS and Linux.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/WebKit/WebKit">WebKit/WebKit</a></h1>
            <p>Home of the WebKit project, the browser engine used by Safari, Mail, App Store and many other applications on macOS, iOS and Linux.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,004</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,667</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[vercel/next.js]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/vercel/next.js</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/vercel/next.js</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The React Framework]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/vercel/next.js">vercel/next.js</a></h1>
            <p>The React Framework</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 134,485</p>
            <p>Forks: 29,332</p>
            <p>Stars today: 42 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[👩‍💻👨‍💻 Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks and development tools. They include everything you should know in one single file.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets">LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets</a></h1>
            <p>👩‍💻👨‍💻 Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks and development tools. They include everything you should know in one single file.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 44,260</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,587</p>
            <p>Stars today: 15 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![AWESOME CHEATSHEETS LOGO](_design/cover_github@2x.png)](https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets/)

[![Awesome](https://awesome.re/badge.svg)](https://awesome.re) [![GitHub license](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg)](https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/blob/master/LICENSE)

**WEBSITE DIRECTORY**: [Available here](https://lecoupa.github.io/awesome-cheatsheets/).

&gt; 📚 Awesome cheatsheets for popular programming languages, frameworks and development tools. They include everything you should know in one single file.

## 🤔 Why Awesome-Cheatsheets?

I usually make a cheat sheet when I want to improve my skills in a programming language, a framework or a development tool. [I started doing these kinds of things a long time ago on Gist](https://gist.github.com/LeCoupa). To better keep track of the history and to let people contribute, I re-organized all of them into this single repository. Most of the content is coming from official documentation and some books I have read.

Feel free to take a look. You might learn new things. They have been designed to provide a quick way to assess your knowledge and to save you time.

## 📚 Table of Contents

### 📃 Languages

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;View cheatsheets&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Command line interface

- [Bash](languages/bash.sh)

#### Imperative

- [C](languages/C.txt)
- [C#](languages/C%23.txt)
- [Go](languages/golang.md)
- [Java](languages/java.md)
- [PHP](languages/php.php)
- [Python](languages/python.md)

#### Functional

- [JavaScript](languages/javascript.js)

&lt;/details&gt;

### 📦 Backend

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;View cheatsheets&lt;/summary&gt;

#### PHP

- [Laravel](backend/laravel.php)

#### Python

- [Django](backend/django.py)

#### Javascript

- [Adonis.js](backend/adonis.js)
- [Express.js](backend/express.js)
- [Feathers.js](backend/feathers.js)
- [Moleculer](backend/moleculer.js)
- [Node.js](backend/node.js)
- [Sails.js](backend/sails.js)
  &lt;/details&gt;

### 🌐 Frontend

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;View cheatsheets&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Basics

- [HTML5](frontend/html5.html)
- [CSS3](frontend/css3.css)

#### Frameworks

- [React.js](frontend/react.js)
- [Vue.js](frontend/vue.js)
- [Tailwind.css](frontend/tailwind.css)
- [Ember.js](frontend/ember.js)
- [Angular (2+)](frontend/angular.js)
- [AngularJS](frontend/angularjs.js)
  &lt;/details&gt;

### 🗃️ Databases

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;View cheatsheets&lt;/summary&gt;

#### SQL

- [MySQL](databases/mysql.sh)

#### NoSQL

- [Redis](databases/redis.sh)
  &lt;/details&gt;

### 🔧 Tools

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;View cheatsheets&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Development

- [cURL](tools/curl.sh)
- [Drush](tools/drush.sh)
- [Elasticsearch](tools/elasticsearch.js)
- [Emmet](tools/emmet.md)
- [Git](tools/git.sh)
- [Puppeteer](tools/puppeteer.js)
- [Sublime Text](tools/sublime_text.md)
- [VIM](tools/vim.txt)
- [Visual Studio Code](tools/vscode.md)
- [Xcode](tools/xcode.txt)

#### Infrastructure

- [AWS CLI](tools/aws.sh)
- [Docker](tools/docker.sh)
- [Heroku CLI](tools/heroku.sh)
- [Kubernetes](tools/kubernetes.md)
- [Nanobox Boxfile](tools/nanobox_boxfile.yml)
- [Nanobox CLI](tools/nanobox_cli.sh)
- [Nginx](tools/nginx.sh)
- [PM2](tools/pm2.sh)
- [Ubuntu](tools/ubuntu.sh)
- [Firebase CLI](tools/firebase_cli.md)
  &lt;/details&gt;

## 🙌🏼 How to Contribute?

You are more than welcome to contribute and build your own cheat sheet for your favorite programming language, framework or development tool. Just submit changes via pull request and I will review them before merging.

## 👩‍💻👨‍💻 Our valuable Contributors

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=LeCoupa/awesome-cheatsheets&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[jgraph/drawio-desktop]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Official electron build of draw.io]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop">jgraph/drawio-desktop</a></h1>
            <p>Official electron build of draw.io</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 56,788</p>
            <p>Forks: 5,416</p>
            <p>Stars today: 13 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>About
----- 

**drawio-desktop** is a diagramming desktop app based on [Electron](https://electronjs.org/) that wraps the [core draw.io editor](https://github.com/jgraph/drawio).

Download built binaries from the [releases section](https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop/releases).

**Can I use this app for free?** Yes, under the apache 2.0 license. If you don&#039;t change the code and accept it is provided &quot;as-is&quot;, you can use it for any purpose.

Security
--------

draw.io Desktop is designed to be completely isolated from the Internet, apart from the update process. This checks github.com at startup for a newer version and downloads it from an AWS S3 bucket owned by Github. All JavaScript files are self-contained, the Content Security Policy forbids running remotely loaded JavaScript.

No diagram data is ever sent externally, nor do we send any analytics about app usage externally. There is a Content Security Policy in place on the web part of the interface to ensure external transmission cannot happen, even by accident.

Security and isolating the app are the primarily objectives of draw.io desktop. If you ask for anything that involves external connections enabled in the app by default, the answer will be no.

Support
-------

Support is provided on a reasonable business constraints basis, but without anything contractually binding. All support is provided via this repo. There is no private ticketing support for non-paying users.

Purchasing draw.io for Confluence or Jira does not entitle you to commercial support for draw.io desktop.

Developing
----------

**draw.io** is a git submodule of **drawio-desktop**. To get both you need to clone recursively:

`git clone --recursive https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop.git`

To run this:
1. `npm install` (in the root directory of this repo)
2. [internal use only] export DRAWIO_ENV=dev if you want to develop/debug in dev mode.
3. `npm start` _in the root directory of this repo_ runs the app. For debugging, use `npm start --enable-logging`.

Note: If a symlink is used to refer to drawio repo (instead of the submodule), then symlink the `node_modules` directory inside `drawio/src/main/webapp` also.

To release:
1. Update the draw.io sub-module and push the change. Add version tag before pushing to origin.
2. Wait for the builds to complete (https://travis-ci.org/jgraph/drawio-desktop and https://ci.appveyor.com/project/davidjgraph/drawio-desktop)
3. Go to https://github.com/jgraph/drawio-desktop/releases, edit the preview release.
4. Download the windows exe and windows portable, sign them using `signtool sign /a /tr http://rfc3161timestamp.globalsign.com/advanced /td SHA256 c:/path/to/your/file.exe`
5. Re-upload signed file as `draw.io-windows-installer-x.y.z.exe` and `draw.io-windows-no-installer-x.y.z.exe`
6. Add release notes
7. Publish release

*Note*: In Windows release, when using both x64 and is32 as arch, the result is one big file with both archs. This is why we split them.

Local Storage and Session Storage is stored in the AppData folder:

- macOS: `~/Library/Application Support/draw.io`
- Windows: `C:\Users\&lt;USER-NAME&gt;\AppData\Roaming\draw.io\`

Not open-contribution
---------------------

draw.io is closed to contributions (unless a maintainer permits it, which is extremely rare).

The level of complexity of this project means that even simple changes 
can break a _lot_ of other moving parts. The amount of testing required 
is far more than it first seems. If we were to receive a PR, we&#039;d have 
to basically throw it away and write it how we want it to be implemented.

We are grateful for community involvement, bug reports, &amp; feature requests. We do
not wish to come off as anything but welcoming, however, we&#039;ve
made the decision to keep this project closed to contributions for 
the long term viability of the project.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[open-webui/open-webui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/open-webui/open-webui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/open-webui/open-webui</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[User-friendly AI Interface (Supports Ollama, OpenAI API, ...)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/open-webui/open-webui">open-webui/open-webui</a></h1>
            <p>User-friendly AI Interface (Supports Ollama, OpenAI API, ...)</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 110,087</p>
            <p>Forks: 15,097</p>
            <p>Stars today: 115 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Open WebUI 👋

![GitHub stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/open-webui/open-webui?style=social)
![GitHub forks](https://img.shields.io/github/forks/open-webui/open-webui?style=social)
![GitHub watchers](https://img.shields.io/github/watchers/open-webui/open-webui?style=social)
![GitHub repo size](https://img.shields.io/github/repo-size/open-webui/open-webui)
![GitHub language count](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/count/open-webui/open-webui)
![GitHub top language](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/top/open-webui/open-webui)
![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/open-webui/open-webui?color=red)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Open_WebUI-blue?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/5rJgQTnV4s)
[![](https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=Sponsor&amp;message=%E2%9D%A4&amp;logo=GitHub&amp;color=%23fe8e86)](https://github.com/sponsors/tjbck)

**Open WebUI is an [extensible](https://docs.openwebui.com/features/plugin/), feature-rich, and user-friendly self-hosted AI platform designed to operate entirely offline.** It supports various LLM runners like **Ollama** and **OpenAI-compatible APIs**, with **built-in inference engine** for RAG, making it a **powerful AI deployment solution**.

Passionate about open-source AI? [Join our team →](https://careers.openwebui.com/)

![Open WebUI Demo](./demo.gif)

&gt; [!TIP]  
&gt; **Looking for an [Enterprise Plan](https://docs.openwebui.com/enterprise)?** – **[Speak with Our Sales Team Today!](mailto:sales@openwebui.com)**
&gt;
&gt; Get **enhanced capabilities**, including **custom theming and branding**, **Service Level Agreement (SLA) support**, **Long-Term Support (LTS) versions**, and **more!**

For more information, be sure to check out our [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/).

## Key Features of Open WebUI ⭐

- 🚀 **Effortless Setup**: Install seamlessly using Docker or Kubernetes (kubectl, kustomize or helm) for a hassle-free experience with support for both `:ollama` and `:cuda` tagged images.

- 🤝 **Ollama/OpenAI API Integration**: Effortlessly integrate OpenAI-compatible APIs for versatile conversations alongside Ollama models. Customize the OpenAI API URL to link with **LMStudio, GroqCloud, Mistral, OpenRouter, and more**.

- 🛡️ **Granular Permissions and User Groups**: By allowing administrators to create detailed user roles and permissions, we ensure a secure user environment. This granularity not only enhances security but also allows for customized user experiences, fostering a sense of ownership and responsibility amongst users.

- 🔄 **SCIM 2.0 Support**: Enterprise-grade user and group provisioning through SCIM 2.0 protocol, enabling seamless integration with identity providers like Okta, Azure AD, and Google Workspace for automated user lifecycle management.

- 📱 **Responsive Design**: Enjoy a seamless experience across Desktop PC, Laptop, and Mobile devices.

- 📱 **Progressive Web App (PWA) for Mobile**: Enjoy a native app-like experience on your mobile device with our PWA, providing offline access on localhost and a seamless user interface.

- ✒️🔢 **Full Markdown and LaTeX Support**: Elevate your LLM experience with comprehensive Markdown and LaTeX capabilities for enriched interaction.

- 🎤📹 **Hands-Free Voice/Video Call**: Experience seamless communication with integrated hands-free voice and video call features, allowing for a more dynamic and interactive chat environment.

- 🛠️ **Model Builder**: Easily create Ollama models via the Web UI. Create and add custom characters/agents, customize chat elements, and import models effortlessly through [Open WebUI Community](https://openwebui.com/) integration.

- 🐍 **Native Python Function Calling Tool**: Enhance your LLMs with built-in code editor support in the tools workspace. Bring Your Own Function (BYOF) by simply adding your pure Python functions, enabling seamless integration with LLMs.

- 📚 **Local RAG Integration**: Dive into the future of chat interactions with groundbreaking Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) support. This feature seamlessly integrates document interactions into your chat experience. You can load documents directly into the chat or add files to your document library, effortlessly accessing them using the `#` command before a query.

- 🔍 **Web Search for RAG**: Perform web searches using providers like `SearXNG`, `Google PSE`, `Brave Search`, `serpstack`, `serper`, `Serply`, `DuckDuckGo`, `TavilySearch`, `SearchApi` and `Bing` and inject the results directly into your chat experience.

- 🌐 **Web Browsing Capability**: Seamlessly integrate websites into your chat experience using the `#` command followed by a URL. This feature allows you to incorporate web content directly into your conversations, enhancing the richness and depth of your interactions.

- 🎨 **Image Generation Integration**: Seamlessly incorporate image generation capabilities using options such as AUTOMATIC1111 API or ComfyUI (local), and OpenAI&#039;s DALL-E (external), enriching your chat experience with dynamic visual content.

- ⚙️ **Many Models Conversations**: Effortlessly engage with various models simultaneously, harnessing their unique strengths for optimal responses. Enhance your experience by leveraging a diverse set of models in parallel.

- 🔐 **Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)**: Ensure secure access with restricted permissions; only authorized individuals can access your Ollama, and exclusive model creation/pulling rights are reserved for administrators.

- 🌐🌍 **Multilingual Support**: Experience Open WebUI in your preferred language with our internationalization (i18n) support. Join us in expanding our supported languages! We&#039;re actively seeking contributors!

- 🧩 **Pipelines, Open WebUI Plugin Support**: Seamlessly integrate custom logic and Python libraries into Open WebUI using [Pipelines Plugin Framework](https://github.com/open-webui/pipelines). Launch your Pipelines instance, set the OpenAI URL to the Pipelines URL, and explore endless possibilities. [Examples](https://github.com/open-webui/pipelines/tree/main/examples) include **Function Calling**, User **Rate Limiting** to control access, **Usage Monitoring** with tools like Langfuse, **Live Translation with LibreTranslate** for multilingual support, **Toxic Message Filtering** and much more.

- 🌟 **Continuous Updates**: We are committed to improving Open WebUI with regular updates, fixes, and new features.

Want to learn more about Open WebUI&#039;s features? Check out our [Open WebUI documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/features) for a comprehensive overview!

## Sponsors 🙌

#### Emerald

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://n8n.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.openwebui.com/sponsors/logos/n8n.png&quot; alt=&quot;n8n&quot; style=&quot;width: 8rem; height: 8rem; border-radius: .75rem;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://n8n.io/&quot;&gt;n8n&lt;/a&gt; • Does your interface have a backend yet?&lt;br&gt;Try &lt;a href=&quot;https://n8n.io/&quot;&gt;n8n&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt; --&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailscale.com/blog/self-host-a-local-ai-stack/?utm_source=OpenWebUI&amp;utm_medium=paid-ad-placement&amp;utm_campaign=OpenWebUI-Docs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.openwebui.com/sponsors/logos/tailscale.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tailscale&quot; style=&quot;width: 8rem; height: 8rem; border-radius: .75rem;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailscale.com/blog/self-host-a-local-ai-stack/?utm_source=OpenWebUI&amp;utm_medium=paid-ad-placement&amp;utm_campaign=OpenWebUI-Docs&quot;&gt;Tailscale&lt;/a&gt; • Connect self-hosted AI to any device with Tailscale
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
   &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://warp.dev/open-webui&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.openwebui.com/sponsors/logos/warp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Warp&quot; style=&quot;width: 8rem; height: 8rem; border-radius: .75rem;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://warp.dev/open-webui&quot;&gt;Warp&lt;/a&gt; • The intelligent terminal for developers
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

---

We are incredibly grateful for the generous support of our sponsors. Their contributions help us to maintain and improve our project, ensuring we can continue to deliver quality work to our community. Thank you!

## How to Install 🚀

### Installation via Python pip 🐍

Open WebUI can be installed using pip, the Python package installer. Before proceeding, ensure you&#039;re using **Python 3.11** to avoid compatibility issues.

1. **Install Open WebUI**:
   Open your terminal and run the following command to install Open WebUI:

   ```bash
   pip install open-webui
   ```

2. **Running Open WebUI**:
   After installation, you can start Open WebUI by executing:

   ```bash
   open-webui serve
   ```

This will start the Open WebUI server, which you can access at [http://localhost:8080](http://localhost:8080)

### Quick Start with Docker 🐳

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; Please note that for certain Docker environments, additional configurations might be needed. If you encounter any connection issues, our detailed guide on [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/) is ready to assist you.

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; When using Docker to install Open WebUI, make sure to include the `-v open-webui:/app/backend/data` in your Docker command. This step is crucial as it ensures your database is properly mounted and prevents any loss of data.

&gt; [!TIP]  
&gt; If you wish to utilize Open WebUI with Ollama included or CUDA acceleration, we recommend utilizing our official images tagged with either `:cuda` or `:ollama`. To enable CUDA, you must install the [Nvidia CUDA container toolkit](https://docs.nvidia.com/dgx/nvidia-container-runtime-upgrade/) on your Linux/WSL system.

### Installation with Default Configuration

- **If Ollama is on your computer**, use this command:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 --add-host=host.docker.internal:host-gateway -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:main
  ```

- **If Ollama is on a Different Server**, use this command:

  To connect to Ollama on another server, change the `OLLAMA_BASE_URL` to the server&#039;s URL:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 -e OLLAMA_BASE_URL=https://example.com -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:main
  ```

- **To run Open WebUI with Nvidia GPU support**, use this command:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 --gpus all --add-host=host.docker.internal:host-gateway -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:cuda
  ```

### Installation for OpenAI API Usage Only

- **If you&#039;re only using OpenAI API**, use this command:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 -e OPENAI_API_KEY=your_secret_key -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:main
  ```

### Installing Open WebUI with Bundled Ollama Support

This installation method uses a single container image that bundles Open WebUI with Ollama, allowing for a streamlined setup via a single command. Choose the appropriate command based on your hardware setup:

- **With GPU Support**:
  Utilize GPU resources by running the following command:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 --gpus=all -v ollama:/root/.ollama -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:ollama
  ```

- **For CPU Only**:
  If you&#039;re not using a GPU, use this command instead:

  ```bash
  docker run -d -p 3000:8080 -v ollama:/root/.ollama -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:ollama
  ```

Both commands facilitate a built-in, hassle-free installation of both Open WebUI and Ollama, ensuring that you can get everything up and running swiftly.

After installation, you can access Open WebUI at [http://localhost:3000](http://localhost:3000). Enjoy! 😄

### Other Installation Methods

We offer various installation alternatives, including non-Docker native installation methods, Docker Compose, Kustomize, and Helm. Visit our [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/getting-started/) or join our [Discord community](https://discord.gg/5rJgQTnV4s) for comprehensive guidance.

Look at the [Local Development Guide](https://docs.openwebui.com/getting-started/advanced-topics/development) for instructions on setting up a local development environment.

### Troubleshooting

Encountering connection issues? Our [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/troubleshooting/) has got you covered. For further assistance and to join our vibrant community, visit the [Open WebUI Discord](https://discord.gg/5rJgQTnV4s).

#### Open WebUI: Server Connection Error

If you&#039;re experiencing connection issues, it’s often due to the WebUI docker container not being able to reach the Ollama server at 127.0.0.1:11434 (host.docker.internal:11434) inside the container . Use the `--network=host` flag in your docker command to resolve this. Note that the port changes from 3000 to 8080, resulting in the link: `http://localhost:8080`.

**Example Docker Command**:

```bash
docker run -d --network=host -v open-webui:/app/backend/data -e OLLAMA_BASE_URL=http://127.0.0.1:11434 --name open-webui --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:main
```

### Keeping Your Docker Installation Up-to-Date

In case you want to update your local Docker installation to the latest version, you can do it with [Watchtower](https://containrrr.dev/watchtower/):

```bash
docker run --rm --volume /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock containrrr/watchtower --run-once open-webui
```

In the last part of the command, replace `open-webui` with your container name if it is different.

Check our Updating Guide available in our [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/getting-started/updating).

### Using the Dev Branch 🌙

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; The `:dev` branch contains the latest unstable features and changes. Use it at your own risk as it may have bugs or incomplete features.

If you want to try out the latest bleeding-edge features and are okay with occasional instability, you can use the `:dev` tag like this:

```bash
docker run -d -p 3000:8080 -v open-webui:/app/backend/data --name open-webui --add-host=host.docker.internal:host-gateway --restart always ghcr.io/open-webui/open-webui:dev
```

### Offline Mode

If you are running Open WebUI in an offline environment, you can set the `HF_HUB_OFFLINE` environment variable to `1` to prevent attempts to download models from the internet.

```bash
export HF_HUB_OFFLINE=1
```

## What&#039;s Next? 🌟

Discover upcoming features on our roadmap in the [Open WebUI Documentation](https://docs.openwebui.com/roadmap/).

## License 📜

This project is licensed under the [Open WebUI License](LICENSE), a revised BSD-3-Clause license. You receive all the same rights as the classic BSD-3 license: you can use, modify, and distribute the software, including in proprietary and commercial products, with minimal restrictions. The only additional requirement is to preserve the &quot;Open WebUI&quot; branding, as detailed in the LICENSE file. For full terms, see the [LICENSE](LICENSE) document. 📄

## Support 💬

If you have any questions, suggestions, or need assistance, please open an issue or join our
[Open WebUI Discord community](https://discord.gg/5rJgQTnV4s) to connect with us! 🤝

## Star History

&lt;a href=&quot;https://star-history.com/#open-webui/open-webui&amp;Date&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=open-webui/open-webui&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=open-webui/open-webui&amp;type=Date&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Star History Chart&quot; src=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=open-webui/open-webui&amp;type=Date&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

---

Created by [Timothy Jaeryang Baek](https://github.com/tjbck) - Let&#039;s make Open WebUI even more amazing together! 💪
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WebGoat/WebGoat]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[WebGoat is a deliberately insecure application]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat">WebGoat/WebGoat</a></h1>
            <p>WebGoat is a deliberately insecure application</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,749</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,698</p>
            <p>Stars today: 4 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># WebGoat: A deliberately insecure Web Application

[![Build](https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?branch=develop)](https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/actions/workflows/build.yml)
[![java-jdk](https://img.shields.io/badge/java%20jdk-23-green.svg)](https://jdk.java.net/)
[![OWASP Labs](https://img.shields.io/badge/OWASP-Lab%20project-f7b73c.svg)](https://owasp.org/projects/)
[![GitHub release](https://img.shields.io/github/release/WebGoat/WebGoat.svg)](https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/releases/latest)
[![Gitter](https://badges.gitter.im/OWASPWebGoat/community.svg)](https://gitter.im/OWASPWebGoat/community?utm_source=badge&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge)
[![Discussions](https://img.shields.io/github/discussions/WebGoat/WebGoat)](https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/discussions)
[![Conventional Commits](https://img.shields.io/badge/Conventional%20Commits-1.0.0-%23FE5196?logo=conventionalcommits&amp;logoColor=white)](https://conventionalcommits.org)

# Introduction

WebGoat is a deliberately insecure web application maintained by [OWASP](http://www.owasp.org/) designed to teach web
application security lessons.

This program is a demonstration of common server-side application flaws. The
exercises are intended to be used by people to learn about application security and
penetration testing techniques.

**WARNING 1:** *While running this program your machine will be extremely
vulnerable to attack. You should disconnect from the Internet while using
this program.*  WebGoat&#039;s default configuration binds to localhost to minimize
the exposure.

**WARNING 2:** *This program is for educational purposes only. If you attempt
these techniques without authorization, you are very likely to get caught. If
you are caught engaging in unauthorized hacking, most companies will fire you.
Claiming that you were doing security research will not work as that is the
first thing that all hackers claim.*

![WebGoat](docs/images/webgoat.png)

# Installation instructions:

For more details check [the Contribution guide](/CONTRIBUTING.md)

## 1. Run using Docker

Already have a browser and ZAP and/or Burp installed on your machine in this case you can run the WebGoat image directly using Docker.

Every release is also published on [DockerHub](https://hub.docker.com/r/webgoat/webgoat).

```shell
docker run -it -p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 -p 127.0.0.1:9090:9090 webgoat/webgoat
```

For some lessons you need the container run in the same timezone. For this you can set the TZ environment variable.
E.g.

```shell
docker run -it -p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 -p 127.0.0.1:9090:9090 -e TZ=America/Boise webgoat/webgoat
```

If you want to use OWASP ZAP or another proxy, you can no longer use 127.0.0.1 or localhost. but
you can use custom host entries. For example:

```shell
127.0.0.1 www.webgoat.local www.webwolf.local
```

Then you can run the container with:

```shell
docker run -it -p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 -p 127.0.0.1:9090:9090 -e WEBGOAT_HOST=www.webgoat.local -e WEBWOLF_HOST=www.webwolf.local -e TZ=America/Boise webgoat/webgoat
```

Then visit http://www.webgoat.local:8080/WebGoat/ and http://www.webwolf.local:9090/WebWolf/

## 2. Run using Docker with complete Linux Desktop

Instead of installing tools locally we have a complete Docker image based on running a desktop in your browser. This way you only have to run a Docker image which will give you the best user experience.

```shell
docker run -p 127.0.0.1:3000:3000 webgoat/webgoat-desktop
```

## 3. Standalone

Download the latest WebGoat release from [https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/releases](https://github.com/WebGoat/WebGoat/releases)

```shell
export TZ=Europe/Amsterdam # or your timezone
java -Dfile.encoding=UTF-8 -jar webgoat-2023.8.jar
```

Click the link in the log to start WebGoat.

### 3.1 Running on a different port

If for some reason you want to run WebGoat on a different port, you can do so by adding the following parameter:

```shell
java -jar webgoat-2023.8.jar --webgoat.port=8001 --webwolf.port=8002
```

For a full overview of all the parameters you can use, please check the [WebGoat properties file](webgoat-container/src/main/resources/application-{webgoat, webwolf}.properties).

## 4. Run from the sources

### Prerequisites:

* Java 23
* Your favorite IDE
* Git, or Git support in your IDE

Open a command shell/window:

```Shell
git clone git@github.com:WebGoat/WebGoat.git
```

Now let&#039;s start by compiling the project.

```Shell
cd WebGoat
git checkout &lt;&lt;branch_name&gt;&gt;
# On Linux/Mac:
./mvnw clean install

# On Windows:
./mvnw.cmd clean install

# Using docker or podman, you can than build the container locally
docker build -f Dockerfile . -t webgoat/webgoat
```

Now we are ready to run the project. WebGoat is using Spring Boot.

```Shell
# On Linux/Mac:
./mvnw spring-boot:run
# On Windows:
./mvnw.cmd spring-boot:run

```

... you should be running WebGoat on http://localhost:8080/WebGoat momentarily.

Note: The above link will redirect you to login page if you are not logged in. LogIn/Create account to proceed.

To change the IP address add the following variable to the `WebGoat/webgoat-container/src/main/resources/application.properties` file:

```
server.address=x.x.x.x
```

## 4. Run with custom menu

For specialist only. There is a way to set up WebGoat with a personalized menu. You can leave out some menu categories or individual lessons by setting certain environment variables.

For instance running as a jar on a Linux/macOS it will look like this:

```Shell
export TZ=Europe/Amsterdam # or your timezone
export EXCLUDE_CATEGORIES=&quot;CLIENT_SIDE,GENERAL,CHALLENGE&quot;
export EXCLUDE_LESSONS=&quot;SqlInjectionAdvanced,SqlInjectionMitigations&quot;
java -jar target/webgoat-2023.8-SNAPSHOT.jar
```

Or in a docker run it would (once this version is pushed into docker hub) look like this:

```Shell
docker run -d -p 127.0.0.1:8080:8080 -p 127.0.0.1:9090:9090 -e EXCLUDE_CATEGORIES=&quot;CLIENT_SIDE,GENERAL,CHALLENGE&quot; -e EXCLUDE_LESSONS=&quot;SqlInjectionAdvanced,SqlInjectionMitigations&quot; webgoat/webgoat
```

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UseInterstellar/Interstellar]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[One of the most popular modern web proxies with blazing fast speeds and a variety of games.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar">UseInterstellar/Interstellar</a></h1>
            <p>One of the most popular modern web proxies with blazing fast speeds and a variety of games.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,655</p>
            <p>Forks: 19,801</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar/main/.github/branding/in.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Serving over 15 million users since 2022.&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Interstellar is a web proxy with a Clean and Sleek UI and easy to use menus. Our goal is to provide the best user experience to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

![inpreview](https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar/assets/89202835/2669efed-5186-4932-83c4-725acae60bd2)

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; If you fork this project, consider giving it a star in the original repository!

**Join Our [Discord Community](https://discord.gg/interstellar) for support, more links, and an active community!**

## Features

- About:Blank Cloaking
- Tab Cloaking
- Wide collection of apps &amp; games
- Clean, Easy to use UI
- Inspect Element
- Various Themes
- Password Protection (Optional)
- Built-in Tab System
- Now.gg Support
- Fast Speeds
- Geforce NOW Support

## Deployment

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; You **cannot** deploy to static web hosts, including Netlify, Cloudflare Pages, and GitHub Pages.

### Password Protection

1. Go to the `config.js` file and set `challenge` to **true**. Then, set the environment variable as follows:
2. For PNPM: Run either `config=true pnpm start` or `$env:config=true; pnpm start`, depending on your server.
3. For Bun: Run either `config=true bun start` or `$env:config=true; bun start` if you prefer Bun.
4. For NPM: Run either `config=true npm start` or `$env:config=true; npm start` if you prefer NPM.


### Server Deployment

You must run these commands on your server:

```bash
git clone https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar
cd Interstellar
```

#### Ad-Free Deployment

```bash
git clone --branch Ad-Free https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar
cd Interstellar
```

Next depending on your package manager, run one of the following commands:

#### Bun

If you are using Bun, run the following commands:

```bash
bun i
bun start
```

#### pnpm

If you are using pnpm, run the following commands:

```bash
pnpm i
pnpm start
```

#### npm

If you are using npm, run the following commands:

```bash
npm i
npm run start
```

### Updating

```bash
cd Interstellar
git pull --force --allow-unrelated-histories # This may overwrite your local changes
```

&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://heroku.com/deploy/?template=https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Deploy to Heroku&quot; src=&quot;https://binbashbanana.github.io/deploy-buttons/buttons/remade/heroku.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://app.koyeb.com/deploy?type=git&amp;repository=github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Deploy to Koyeb&quot; src=&quot;https://binbashbanana.github.io/deploy-buttons/buttons/remade/koyeb.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

### Deployment Alternatives

For more deployment options, join our [Discord Server](https://discord.gg/interstellar) for various ways to deploy Interstellar.
This includes methods of deploying to Render/OnRender.

#### What happened to Replit Deployment?

As of January 1st, 2024, Replit is [no longer free](https://blog.replit.com/hosting-changes). Try GitHub Codespaces instead.

### GitHub Codespaces

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; If you&#039;re setting the port below 1023, then you must run `sudo PORT=1023`

1. Create a GitHub account if you haven&#039;t already.
2. Click &quot;Code&quot; (green button) and then &quot;Create Codespace on main.&quot;
3. In the terminal at the bottom, paste `pnpm i &amp;&amp; pnpm start`.
4. Respond to the application popup by clicking &quot;Make public.&quot;
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; Make sure you click the &quot;Make public.&quot; button, or the proxy won&#039;t function properly.&lt;br&gt;
&gt; If you get a Range Error, go back and make sure you clicked Make public!
5. Access the deployed website from the ports tab.
6. For subsequent uses in the same codespace, just run `pnpm start`

### Solution for if there is no popup.

1. Run `pnpm i`, and before `pnpm start`, prepend `PORT=8080`, replacing 8080 with another port. For example, `PORT=6969 pnpm start`.
2. If this does not work then you can prepend `$env:PORT=8080;`, replacing 8080 with another port. For example, `$env:PORT=6969; pnpm start`
3. Go to the ports tab, Click Forward A Port, And type the port number.
4. Right-click Visibility and set Port Visibility to Public.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; We are committed to making Interstellar easy and personalized however, as of now we need your support in making it ad-free. Consider keeping ads so Interstellar can run freely or contribute by being a supporter.

## Report Issues

If you encounter problems, open an issue on GitHub, and we&#039;ll address it promptly.

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; If you&#039;re having trouble, don&#039;t hesitate to reach out to us on [Discord](https://discord.gg/interstellar) for personalized support.

# Credits

A huge thanks goes out to all of the people who have contributed to Interstellar.

[![Contributors](https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=UseInterstellar/Interstellar)](https://github.com/UseInterstellar/Interstellar/graphs/contributors)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[overleaf/overleaf]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A web-based collaborative LaTeX editor]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf">overleaf/overleaf</a></h1>
            <p>A web-based collaborative LaTeX editor</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,526</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,713</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;doc/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overleaf&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;An open-source online real-time collaborative LaTeX editor.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf/wiki&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/for/enterprises&quot;&gt;Server Pro&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#contributing&quot;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchi.mp/overleaf.com/community-edition-and-server-pro&quot;&gt;Mailing List&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;doc/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of a project being edited in Overleaf Community Edition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Figure 1: A screenshot of a project being edited in Overleaf Community Edition.
&lt;/p&gt;

## Community Edition

[Overleaf](https://www.overleaf.com) is an open-source online real-time collaborative LaTeX editor. We run a hosted version at [www.overleaf.com](https://www.overleaf.com), but you can also run your own local version, and contribute to the development of Overleaf.

&gt; [!CAUTION]
&gt; Overleaf Community Edition is intended for use in environments where **all** users are trusted. Community Edition is **not** appropriate for scenarios where isolation of users is required due to Sandbox Compiles not being available. When not using Sandboxed Compiles, users have full read and write access to the `sharelatex` container resources (filesystem, network, environment variables) when running LaTeX compiles.

For more information on Sandbox Compiles check out our [documentation](https://docs.overleaf.com/on-premises/configuration/overleaf-toolkit/server-pro-only-configuration/sandboxed-compiles).

## Enterprise

If you want help installing and maintaining Overleaf in your lab or workplace, we offer an officially supported version called [Overleaf Server Pro](https://www.overleaf.com/for/enterprises). It also includes more features for security (SSO with LDAP or SAML), administration and collaboration (e.g. tracked changes). [Find out more!](https://www.overleaf.com/for/enterprises)

## Keeping up to date

Sign up to the [mailing list](https://mailchi.mp/overleaf.com/community-edition-and-server-pro) to get updates on Overleaf releases and development.

## Installation

We have detailed installation instructions in the [Overleaf Toolkit](https://github.com/overleaf/toolkit/).

## Upgrading

If you are upgrading from a previous version of Overleaf, please see the [Release Notes section on the Wiki](https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf/wiki#release-notes) for all of the versions between your current version and the version you are upgrading to.

## Overleaf Docker Image

This repo contains two dockerfiles, [`Dockerfile-base`](server-ce/Dockerfile-base), which builds the
`sharelatex/sharelatex-base` image, and [`Dockerfile`](server-ce/Dockerfile) which builds the
`sharelatex/sharelatex` (or &quot;community&quot;) image.

The Base image generally contains the basic dependencies like `wget`, plus `texlive`.
We split this out because it&#039;s a pretty heavy set of
dependencies, and it&#039;s nice to not have to rebuild all of that every time.

The `sharelatex/sharelatex` image extends the base image and adds the actual Overleaf code
and services.

Use `make build-base` and `make build-community` from `server-ce/` to build these images.

We use the [Phusion base-image](https://github.com/phusion/baseimage-docker)
(which is extended by our `base` image) to provide us with a VM-like container
in which to run the Overleaf services. Baseimage uses the `runit` service
manager to manage services, and we add our init-scripts from the `server-ce/runit`
folder.


## Contributing

Please see the [CONTRIBUTING](CONTRIBUTING.md) file for information on contributing to the development of Overleaf.

## Authors

[The Overleaf Team](https://www.overleaf.com/about)

## License

The code in this repository is released under the GNU AFFERO GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE, version 3. A copy can be found in the [`LICENSE`](LICENSE) file.

Copyright (c) Overleaf, 2014-2025.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[danielmiessler/Fabric]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/danielmiessler/Fabric</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/danielmiessler/Fabric</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. It provides a modular system for solving specific problems using a crowdsourced set of AI prompts that can be used anywhere.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/danielmiessler/Fabric">danielmiessler/Fabric</a></h1>
            <p>Fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. It provides a modular system for solving specific problems using a crowdsourced set of AI prompts that can be used anywhere.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 33,488</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,423</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.warp.dev/fabric&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
        &lt;sup&gt;Special thanks to:&lt;/sup&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Warp sponsorship&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/warpdotdev/brand-assets/refs/heads/main/Github/Sponsor/Warp-Github-LG-02.png&quot;&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;h&gt;Warp, built for coding with multiple AI agents&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;sup&gt;Available for macOS, Linux and Windows&lt;/sup&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/images/fabric-logo-gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;fabriclogo&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;

# `fabric`

![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/mission-human_flourishing_via_AI_augmentation-purple)
&lt;br /&gt;
![GitHub top language](https://img.shields.io/github/languages/top/danielmiessler/fabric)
![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/danielmiessler/fabric)
[![License: MIT](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-green.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT)
[![Ask DeepWiki](https://deepwiki.com/badge.svg)](https://deepwiki.com/danielmiessler/fabric)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;fabric&lt;/code&gt; is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

![Screenshot of fabric](./docs/images/fabric-summarize.png)

&lt;/div&gt;

[Updates](#updates) •
[What and Why](#what-and-why) •
[Philosophy](#philosophy) •
[Installation](#installation) •
[Usage](#usage) •
[Examples](#examples) •
[Just Use the Patterns](#just-use-the-patterns) •
[Custom Patterns](#custom-patterns) •
[Helper Apps](#helper-apps) •
[Meta](#meta)

![Screenshot of fabric](./docs/images/fabric-summarize.png)

&lt;/div&gt;

## What and why

Since the start of modern AI in late 2022 we&#039;ve seen an **_extraordinary_** number of AI applications for accomplishing tasks. There are thousands of websites, chat-bots, mobile apps, and other interfaces for using all the different AI out there.

It&#039;s all really exciting and powerful, but _it&#039;s not easy to integrate this functionality into our lives._

&lt;div class=&quot;align center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;In other words, AI doesn&#039;t have a capabilities problem—it has an &lt;em&gt;integration&lt;/em&gt; problem.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

**Fabric was created to address this by creating and organizing the fundamental units of AI—the prompts themselves!**

Fabric organizes prompts by real-world task, allowing people to create, collect, and organize their most important AI solutions in a single place for use in their favorite tools. And if you&#039;re command-line focused, you can use Fabric itself as the interface!

## Updates

Dear Users,

We&#039;ve been doing so many exciting things here at Fabric, I wanted to give a quick summary here to give you a sense of our development velocity!

Below are the **new features and capabilities** we&#039;ve added (newest first):

### Recent Major Features

- [v1.4.311](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.311) (Sep 13, 2025) — **More internationalization support**: Adds de (German), fa (Persian / Farsi), fr (French), it (Italian),
  ja (Japanese), pt (Portuguese), zh (Chinese)
- [v1.4.309](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.309) (Sep 9, 2025) — **Comprehensive internationalization support**: Includes English and Spanish locale files.
- [v1.4.303](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.303) (Aug 29, 2025) — **New Binary Releases**: Linux ARM and Windows ARM targets. You can run Fabric on the Raspberry PI and on your Windows Surface!
- [v1.4.294](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.294) (Aug 20, 2025) — **Venice AI Support**: Added the Venice AI provider. Venice is a Privacy-First, Open-Source AI provider. See their [&quot;About Venice&quot;](https://docs.venice.ai/overview/about-venice) page for details.
- [v1.4.291](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.291) (Aug 18, 2025) — **Speech To Text**: Add OpenAI speech-to-text support with `--transcribe-file`, `--transcribe-model`, and `--split-media-file` flags.
- [v1.4.287](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.287) (Aug 16, 2025) — **AI Reasoning**: Add Thinking to Gemini models and introduce `readme_updates` python script
- [v1.4.286](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.286) (Aug 14, 2025) — **AI Reasoning**: Introduce Thinking Config Across Anthropic and OpenAI Providers
- [v1.4.285](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.285) (Aug 13, 2025) — **Extended Context**: Enable One Million Token Context Beta Feature for Sonnet-4
- [v1.4.284](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.284) (Aug 12, 2025) — **Easy Shell Completions Setup**: Introduce One-Liner Curl Install for Completions
- [v1.4.283](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.283) (Aug 12, 2025) — **Model Management**: Add Vendor Selection Support for Models
- [v1.4.282](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.282) (Aug 11, 2025) — **Enhanced Shell Completions**: Enhanced Shell Completions for Fabric CLI Binaries
- [v1.4.281](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.281) (Aug 11, 2025) — **Gemini Search Tool**: Add Web Search Tool Support for Gemini Models
- [v1.4.278](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.278) (Aug 9, 2025) — **Enhance YouTube Transcripts**: Enhance YouTube Support with Custom yt-dlp Arguments
- [v1.4.277](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.277) (Aug 8, 2025) — **Desktop Notifications**: Add cross-platform desktop notifications to Fabric CLI
- [v1.4.274](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.274) (Aug 7, 2025) — **Claude 4.1 Added**: Add Support for Claude Opus 4.1 Model
- [v1.4.271](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.271) (Jul 28, 2025) — **AI Summarized Release Notes**: Enable AI summary updates for GitHub releases
- [v1.4.268](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.268) (Jul 26, 2025) — **Gemini TTS Voice Selection**: add Gemini TTS voice selection and listing functionality
- [v1.4.267](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.267) (Jul 26, 2025) — **Text-to-Speech**: Update Gemini Plugin to New SDK with TTS Support
- [v1.4.258](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.258) (Jul 17, 2025) — **Onboarding Improved**: Add startup check to initialize config and .env file automatically
- [v1.4.257](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.257) (Jul 17, 2025) — **OpenAI Routing Control**: Introduce CLI Flag to Disable OpenAI Responses API
- [v1.4.252](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.252) (Jul 16, 2025) — **Hide Thinking Block**: Optional Hiding of Model Thinking Process with Configurable Tags
- [v1.4.246](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.246) (Jul 14, 2025) — **Automatic ChangeLog Updates**: Add AI-powered changelog generation with high-performance Go tool and comprehensive caching
- [v1.4.245](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.245) (Jul 11, 2025) — **Together AI**: Together AI Support with OpenAI Fallback Mechanism Added
- [v1.4.232](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.232) (Jul 6, 2025) — **Add Custom**: Add Custom Patterns Directory Support
- [v1.4.231](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.231) (Jul 5, 2025) — **OAuth Auto-Auth**: OAuth Authentication Support for Anthropic (Use your Max Subscription)
- [v1.4.230](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.230) (Jul 5, 2025) — **Model Management**: Add advanced image generation parameters for OpenAI models with four new CLI flags
- [v1.4.227](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.227) (Jul 4, 2025) — **Add Image**: Add Image Generation Support to Fabric
- [v1.4.226](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.226) (Jul 4, 2025) — **Web Search**: OpenAI Plugin Now Supports Web Search Functionality
- [v1.4.225](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.225) (Jul 4, 2025) — **Web Search**: Runtime Web Search Control via Command-Line `--search` Flag
- [v1.4.224](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.224) (Jul 1, 2025) — **Add code_review**: Add code_review pattern and updates in Pattern_Descriptions
- [v1.4.222](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.222) (Jul 1, 2025) — **OpenAI Plugin**: OpenAI Plugin Migrates to New Responses API
- [v1.4.218](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.218) (Jun 27, 2025) — **Model Management**: Add Support for OpenAI Search and Research Model Variants
- [v1.4.217](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.217) (Jun 26, 2025) — **New YouTube**: New YouTube Transcript Endpoint Added to REST API
- [v1.4.212](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.212) (Jun 23, 2025) — **Add Langdock**: Add Langdock AI and enhance generic OpenAI compatible support
- [v1.4.211](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.211) (Jun 19, 2025) — **REST API**: REST API and Web UI Now Support Dynamic Pattern Variables
- [v1.4.210](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.210) (Jun 18, 2025) — **Add Citations**: Add Citation Support to Perplexity Response
- [v1.4.208](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.208) (Jun 17, 2025) — **Add Perplexity**: Add Perplexity AI Provider with Token Limits Support
- [v1.4.203](https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/tag/v1.4.203) (Jun 14, 2025) — **Add Amazon Bedrock**: Add support for Amazon Bedrock

These features represent our commitment to making Fabric the most powerful and flexible AI augmentation framework available!

## Intro videos

Keep in mind that many of these were recorded when Fabric was Python-based, so remember to use the current [install instructions](#installation) below.

- [Network Chuck](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbDyjIIGaxQ)
- [David Bombal](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vF-MQmVxnCs)
- [My Own Intro to the Tool](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPEyyigh10g)
- [More Fabric YouTube Videos](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=fabric+ai)

## Navigation

- [`fabric`](#fabric)
  - [What and why](#what-and-why)
  - [Updates](#updates)
    - [Recent Major Features](#recent-major-features)
  - [Intro videos](#intro-videos)
  - [Navigation](#navigation)
  - [Changelog](#changelog)
  - [Philosophy](#philosophy)
    - [Breaking problems into components](#breaking-problems-into-components)
    - [Too many prompts](#too-many-prompts)
  - [Installation](#installation)
    - [One-Line Install (Recommended)](#one-line-install-recommended)
    - [Manual Binary Downloads](#manual-binary-downloads)
    - [Using package managers](#using-package-managers)
      - [macOS (Homebrew)](#macos-homebrew)
      - [Arch Linux (AUR)](#arch-linux-aur)
      - [Windows](#windows)
    - [From Source](#from-source)
    - [Docker](#docker)
    - [Environment Variables](#environment-variables)
    - [Setup](#setup)
    - [Per-Pattern Model Mapping](#per-pattern-model-mapping)
    - [Add aliases for all patterns](#add-aliases-for-all-patterns)
      - [Save your files in markdown using aliases](#save-your-files-in-markdown-using-aliases)
    - [Migration](#migration)
    - [Upgrading](#upgrading)
    - [Shell Completions](#shell-completions)
      - [Quick install (no clone required)](#quick-install-no-clone-required)
      - [Zsh Completion](#zsh-completion)
      - [Bash Completion](#bash-completion)
      - [Fish Completion](#fish-completion)
  - [Usage](#usage)
    - [Debug Levels](#debug-levels)
  - [Our approach to prompting](#our-approach-to-prompting)
  - [Examples](#examples)
  - [Just use the Patterns](#just-use-the-patterns)
    - [Prompt Strategies](#prompt-strategies)
  - [Custom Patterns](#custom-patterns)
    - [Setting Up Custom Patterns](#setting-up-custom-patterns)
    - [Using Custom Patterns](#using-custom-patterns)
    - [How It Works](#how-it-works)
  - [Helper Apps](#helper-apps)
    - [`to_pdf`](#to_pdf)
    - [`to_pdf` Installation](#to_pdf-installation)
    - [`code_helper`](#code_helper)
  - [pbpaste](#pbpaste)
  - [Web Interface](#web-interface)
    - [Installing](#installing)
    - [Streamlit UI](#streamlit-ui)
      - [Clipboard Support](#clipboard-support)
  - [Meta](#meta)
    - [Primary contributors](#primary-contributors)
    - [Contributors](#contributors)

&lt;br /&gt;

## Changelog

Fabric is evolving rapidly.

Stay current with the latest features by reviewing the [CHANGELOG](./CHANGELOG.md) for all recent changes.

## Philosophy

&gt; AI isn&#039;t a thing; it&#039;s a _magnifier_ of a thing. And that thing is **human creativity**.

We believe the purpose of technology is to help humans flourish, so when we talk about AI we start with the **human** problems we want to solve.

### Breaking problems into components

Our approach is to break problems into individual pieces (see below) and then apply AI to them one at a time. See below for some examples.

&lt;img width=&quot;2078&quot; alt=&quot;augmented_challenges&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/assets/50654/31997394-85a9-40c2-879b-b347e4701f06&quot;&gt;

### Too many prompts

Prompts are good for this, but the biggest challenge I faced in 2023——which still exists today—is **the sheer number of AI prompts out there**. We all have prompts that are useful, but it&#039;s hard to discover new ones, know if they are good or not, _and manage different versions of the ones we like_.

One of `fabric`&#039;s primary features is helping people collect and integrate prompts, which we call _Patterns_, into various parts of their lives.

Fabric has Patterns for all sorts of life and work activities, including:

- Extracting the most interesting parts of YouTube videos and podcasts
- Writing an essay in your own voice with just an idea as an input
- Summarizing opaque academic papers
- Creating perfectly matched AI art prompts for a piece of writing
- Rating the quality of content to see if you want to read/watch the whole thing
- Getting summaries of long, boring content
- Explaining code to you
- Turning bad documentation into usable documentation
- Creating social media posts from any content input
- And a million more…

## Installation

### One-Line Install (Recommended)

**Unix/Linux/macOS:**

```bash
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/danielmiessler/fabric/main/scripts/installer/install.sh | bash
```

**Windows PowerShell:**

```powershell
iwr -useb https://raw.githubusercontent.com/danielmiessler/fabric/main/scripts/installer/install.ps1 | iex
```

&gt; See [scripts/installer/README.md](./scripts/installer/README.md) for custom installation options and troubleshooting.

### Manual Binary Downloads

The latest release binary archives and their expected SHA256 hashes can be found at &lt;https://github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/releases/latest&gt;

### Using package managers

**NOTE:** using Homebrew or the Arch Linux package managers makes `fabric` available as `fabric-ai`, so add
the following alias to your shell startup files to account for this:

```bash
alias fabric=&#039;fabric-ai&#039;
```

#### macOS (Homebrew)

`brew install fabric-ai`

#### Arch Linux (AUR)

`yay -S fabric-ai`

#### Windows

Use the official Microsoft supported `Winget` tool:

`winget install danielmiessler.Fabric`

### From Source

To install Fabric, [make sure Go is installed](https://go.dev/doc/install), and then run the following command.

```bash
# Install Fabric directly from the repo
go install github.com/danielmiessler/fabric/cmd/fabric@latest
```

### Docker

Run Fabric using pre-built Docker images:

```bash
# Use latest image from Docker Hub
docker run --rm -it kayvan/fabric:latest --version

# Use specific version from GHCR
docker run --rm -it ghcr.io/ksylvan/fabric:v1.4.305 --version

# Run setup (first time)
mkdir -p $HOME/.fabric-config
docker run --rm -it -v $HOME/.fabric-config:/root/.config/fabric kayvan/fabric:latest --setup

# Use Fabric with your patterns
docker run --rm -it -v $HOME/.fabric-config:/root/.config/fabric kayvan/fabric:latest -p summarize

# Run the REST API server
docker run --rm -it -p 8080:8080 -v $HOME/.fabric-config:/root/.config/fabric kayvan/fabric:latest --serve
```

**Images available at:**

- Docker Hub: [kayvan/fabric](https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/kayvan/fabric/general)
- GHCR: [ksylvan/fabric](https://github.com/ksylvan/fabric/pkgs/container/fabric)

See [scripts/docker/README.md](./scripts/docker/README.md) for building custom images and advanced configuration.

### Environment Variables

You may need to set some environment variables in your `~/.bashrc` on linux or `~/.zshrc` file on mac to be able to run the `fabric` command. Here is an example of what you can add:

For Intel based macs or linux

```bash
# Golang environment variables
export GOROOT=/usr/local/go
export GOPATH=$HOME/go

# Update PATH to include GOPATH and GOROOT binaries
export PATH=$GOPATH/bin:$GOROOT/bin:$HOME/.local/bin:$PATH
```

for Apple Silicon based macs

```bash
# Golang environment variables
export GOROOT=$(brew --prefix go)/libexec
export GOPATH=$HOME/go
export PATH=$GOPATH/bin:$GOROOT/bin:$HOME/.local/bin:$PATH
```

### Setup

Now run the following command

```bash
# Run the setup to set up your directories and keys
fabric --setup
```

If everything works you are good to go.

### Per-Pattern Model Mapping

 You can configure specific models for individual patterns using environment variables
 like `FABRIC_MODEL_PATTERN_NAME=vendor|model`

 This makes it easy to maintain these per-pattern model mappings in your shell startup files.

### Add aliases for all patterns

In order to add aliases for all your patterns and use them directly as commands, for example, `summarize` instead of `fabric --pattern summarize`
You can add the following to your `.zshrc` or `.bashrc` file. You
can also optionally set the `FABRIC_ALIAS_PREFIX` environment variable
before, if you&#039;d prefer all the fabric aliases to start with the same prefix.

```bash
# Loop through all files in the ~/.config/fabric/patterns directory
for pattern_file in $HOME/.config/fabric/patterns/*; do
    # Get the base name of the file (i.e., remove the directory path)
    pattern_name=&quot;$(basename &quot;$pattern_file&quot;)&quot;
    alias_name=&quot;${FABRIC_ALIAS_PREFIX:-}${pattern_name}&quot;

    # Create an alias in the form: alias pattern_name=&quot;fabric --pattern pattern_name&quot;
    alias_command=&quot;alias $alias_name=&#039;fabric --pattern $pattern_name&#039;&quot;

    # Evaluate the alias command to add it to the current shell
    eval &quot;$alias_command&quot;
done

yt() {
    if [ &quot;$#&quot; -eq 0 ] || [ &quot;$#&quot; -gt 2 ]; then
        echo &quot;Usage: yt [-t | --timestamps] youtube-link&quot;
        echo &quot;Use the &#039;-t&#039; flag to get the transcript with timestamps.&quot;
        return 1
    fi

    transcript_flag=&quot;--transcript&quot;
    if [ &quot;$1&quot; = &quot;-t&quot; ] || [ &quot;$1&quot; = &quot;--timestamps&quot; ]; then
        transcript_flag=&quot;--transcript-with-timestamps&quot;
        shift
    fi
    local video_link=&quot;$1&quot;
    fabric -y &quot;$video_link&quot; $transcript_flag
}
```

You can add the below code for the equivalent aliases inside PowerShell by running `notepad $PROFILE` inside a PowerShell window:

```powershell
# Path to the patterns directory
$patternsPath = Join-Path $HOME &quot;.config/fabric/patterns&quot;
foreach ($patternDir in Get-ChildItem -Path $patternsPath -Directory) {
    # Prepend FABRIC_ALIAS_PREFIX if set; otherwise use empty string
    $prefix = $env:FABRIC_ALIAS_PREFIX ?? &#039;&#039;
    $patternName = &quot;$($patternDir.Name)&quot;
    $aliasName = &quot;$prefix$patternName&quot;
    # Dynamically define a function for each pattern
    $functionDefinition = @&quot;
function $aliasName {
    [CmdletBinding()]
    param(
        [Parameter(ValueFromPipeline = `$true)]
        [string] `$InputObject,

        [Parameter(ValueFromRemainingArguments = `$true)]
        [String[]] `$patternArgs
    )

    begin {
        # Initialize an array to collect pipeline input
        `$collector = @()
    }

    process {
        # Coll

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[upstash/context7]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/upstash/context7</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/upstash/context7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Context7 MCP Server -- Up-to-date code documentation for LLMs and AI code editors]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/upstash/context7">upstash/context7</a></h1>
            <p>Context7 MCP Server -- Up-to-date code documentation for LLMs and AI code editors</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 30,436</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,519</p>
            <p>Stars today: 130 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![Cover](public/cover.png)

# Context7 MCP - Up-to-date Code Docs For Any Prompt

[![Website](https://img.shields.io/badge/Website-context7.com-blue)](https://context7.com) [![smithery badge](https://smithery.ai/badge/@upstash/context7-mcp)](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp) [![NPM Version](https://img.shields.io/npm/v/%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp?color=red)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@upstash/context7-mcp) [![MIT licensed](https://img.shields.io/npm/l/%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp)](./LICENSE)

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/en/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL21jcC5jb250ZXh0Ny5jb20vbWNwIn0%3D) [&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Install%20in%20VS%20Code-0098FF?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=visualstudiocode&amp;logoColor=white&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)

[![繁體中文](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-繁體中文-yellow)](./docs/README.zh-TW.md) [![简体中文](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-简体中文-yellow)](./docs/README.zh-CN.md) [![日本語](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-日本語-b7003a)](./docs/README.ja.md) [![한국어 문서](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-한국어-green)](./docs/README.ko.md) [![Documentación en Español](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Español-orange)](./docs/README.es.md) [![Documentation en Français](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Français-blue)](./docs/README.fr.md) [![Documentação em Português (Brasil)](&lt;https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Português%20(Brasil)-purple&gt;)](./docs/README.pt-BR.md) [![Documentazione in italiano](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Italian-red)](./docs/README.it.md) [![Dokumentasi Bahasa Indonesia](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Bahasa%20Indonesia-pink)](./docs/README.id-ID.md) [![Dokumentation auf Deutsch](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Deutsch-darkgreen)](./docs/README.de.md) [![Документация на русском языке](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Русский-darkblue)](./docs/README.ru.md) [![Українська документація](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Українська-lightblue)](./docs/README.uk.md) [![Türkçe Doküman](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Türkçe-blue)](./docs/README.tr.md) [![Arabic Documentation](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Arabic-white)](./docs/README.ar.md) [![Tiếng Việt](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-Tiếng%20Việt-red)](./docs/README.vi.md)

## ❌ Without Context7

LLMs rely on outdated or generic information about the libraries you use. You get:

- ❌ Code examples are outdated and based on year-old training data
- ❌ Hallucinated APIs that don&#039;t even exist
- ❌ Generic answers for old package versions

## ✅ With Context7

Context7 MCP pulls up-to-date, version-specific documentation and code examples straight from the source — and places them directly into your prompt.

Add `use context7` to your prompt in Cursor:

```txt
Create a Next.js middleware that checks for a valid JWT in cookies and redirects unauthenticated users to `/login`. use context7
```

```txt
Configure a Cloudflare Worker script to cache JSON API responses for five minutes. use context7
```

Context7 fetches up-to-date code examples and documentation right into your LLM&#039;s context.

- 1️⃣ Write your prompt naturally
- 2️⃣ Tell the LLM to `use context7`
- 3️⃣ Get working code answers

No tab-switching, no hallucinated APIs that don&#039;t exist, no outdated code generation.

## 📚 Adding Projects

Check out our [project addition guide](./docs/adding-projects.md) to learn how to add (or update) your favorite libraries to Context7.

## 🛠️ Installation

### Requirements

- Node.js &gt;= v18.0.0
- Cursor, Claude Code, VSCode, Windsurf or another MCP Client
- Context7 API Key (Optional for higher rate limits) (Get yours by creating an account at [context7.com/dashboard](https://context7.com/dashboard))

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; **SSE Protocol Deprecation Notice**
&gt;
&gt; The Server-Sent Events (SSE) transport protocol is deprecated and its endpoint will be removed in upcoming releases. Please use HTTP or stdio transport methods instead.

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Installing via Smithery&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

To install Context7 MCP Server for any client automatically via [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp):

```bash
npx -y @smithery/cli@latest install @upstash/context7-mcp --client &lt;CLIENT_NAME&gt; --key &lt;YOUR_SMITHERY_KEY&gt;
```

You can find your Smithery key in the [Smithery.ai webpage](https://smithery.ai/server/@upstash/context7-mcp).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Cursor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Go to: `Settings` -&gt; `Cursor Settings` -&gt; `MCP` -&gt; `Add new global MCP server`

Pasting the following configuration into your Cursor `~/.cursor/mcp.json` file is the recommended approach. You may also install in a specific project by creating `.cursor/mcp.json` in your project folder. See [Cursor MCP docs](https://docs.cursor.com/context/model-context-protocol) for more info.

&gt; Since Cursor 1.0, you can click the install button below for instant one-click installation.

#### Cursor Remote Server Connection

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/en/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL21jcC5jb250ZXh0Ny5jb20vbWNwIn0%3D)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

#### Cursor Local Server Connection

[![Install MCP Server](https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg)](https://cursor.com/en/install-mcp?name=context7&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoibnB4IC15IEB1cHN0YXNoL2NvbnRleHQ3LW1jcCJ9)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Claude Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Run this command. See [Claude Code MCP docs](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/claude-code/mcp) for more info.

#### Claude Code Remote Server Connection

```sh
claude mcp add --transport http context7 https://mcp.context7.com/mcp --header &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY: YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
```

#### Claude Code Local Server Connection

```sh
claude mcp add context7 -- npx -y @upstash/context7-mcp --api-key YOUR_API_KEY
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Windsurf&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Windsurf MCP config file. See [Windsurf MCP docs](https://docs.windsurf.com/windsurf/cascade/mcp) for more info.

#### Windsurf Remote Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;serverUrl&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

#### Windsurf Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in VS Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

[&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-VS_Code?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Context7%20MCP&amp;color=0098FF&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)
[&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code Insiders (npx)&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code_Insiders-VS_Code_Insiders?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Context7%20MCP&amp;color=24bfa5&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode-insiders%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22context7%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22-y%22%2C%22%40upstash%2Fcontext7-mcp%40latest%22%5D%7D)

Add this to your VS Code MCP config file. See [VS Code MCP docs](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/copilot/chat/mcp-servers) for more info.

#### VS Code Remote Server Connection

```json
&quot;mcp&quot;: {
  &quot;servers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

#### VS Code Local Server Connection

```json
&quot;mcp&quot;: {
  &quot;servers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;stdio&quot;,
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Install in Cline&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/summary&gt;

You can easily install Context7 through the [Cline MCP Server Marketplace](https://cline.bot/mcp-marketplace) by following these instructions:

1. Open **Cline**.
2. Click the hamburger menu icon (☰) to enter the **MCP Servers** section.
3. Use the search bar within the **Marketplace** tab to find _Context7_.
4. Click the **Install** button.

Or you can directly edit MCP servers configuration:

1. Open **Cline**.
2. Click the hamburger menu icon (☰) to enter the **MCP Servers** section.
3. Choose **Remote Servers** tab.
4. Click the **Edit Configuration** button.
5. Add context7 to `mcpServers`:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;streamableHttp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;Authorization&quot;: &quot;Bearer YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Zed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

It can be installed via [Zed Extensions](https://zed.dev/extensions?query=Context7) or you can add this to your Zed `settings.json`. See [Zed Context Server docs](https://zed.dev/docs/assistant/context-servers) for more info.

```json
{
  &quot;context_servers&quot;: {
    &quot;Context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: {
        &quot;path&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
        &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
      },
      &quot;settings&quot;: {}
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Augment Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

To configure Context7 MCP in Augment Code, you can use either the graphical interface or manual configuration.

### **A. Using the Augment Code UI**

1. Click the hamburger menu.
2. Select **Settings**.
3. Navigate to the **Tools** section.
4. Click the **+ Add MCP** button.
5. Enter the following command:

   ```
   npx -y @upstash/context7-mcp@latest
   ```

6. Name the MCP: **Context7**.
7. Click the **Add** button.

Once the MCP server is added, you can start using Context7&#039;s up-to-date code documentation features directly within Augment Code.

---

### **B. Manual Configuration**

1. Press Cmd/Ctrl Shift P or go to the hamburger menu in the Augment panel
2. Select Edit Settings
3. Under Advanced, click Edit in settings.json
4. Add the server configuration to the `mcpServers` array in the `augment.advanced` object

```json
&quot;augment.advanced&quot;: {
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;name&quot;: &quot;context7&quot;,
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  ]
}
```

Once the MCP server is added, restart your editor. If you receive any errors, check the syntax to make sure closing brackets or commas are not missing.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Roo Code&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Roo Code MCP configuration file. See [Roo Code MCP docs](https://docs.roocode.com/features/mcp/using-mcp-in-roo) for more info.

#### Roo Code Remote Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;streamable-http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### Roo Code Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Gemini CLI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Gemini CLI Configuration](https://google-gemini.github.io/gemini-cli/docs/tools/mcp-server.html) for details.

1.  Open the Gemini CLI settings file. The location is `~/.gemini/settings.json` (where `~` is your home directory).
2.  Add the following to the `mcpServers` object in your `settings.json` file:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;httpUrl&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;,
        &quot;Accept&quot;: &quot;application/json, text/event-stream&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

Or, for a local server:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

If the `mcpServers` object does not exist, create it.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Claude Desktop&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Remote Server Connection

Open Claude Desktop and navigate to Settings &gt; Connectors &gt; Add Custom Connector. Enter the name as `Context7` and the remote MCP server URL as `https://mcp.context7.com/mcp`.

#### Local Server Connection

Open Claude Desktop developer settings and edit your `claude_desktop_config.json` file to add the following configuration. See [Claude Desktop MCP docs](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/quickstart/user) for more info.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Opencode&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Opencode configuration file. See [Opencode MCP docs](https://opencode.ai/docs/mcp-servers) for more info.

#### Opencode Remote Server Connection

```json
&quot;mcp&quot;: {
  &quot;context7&quot;: {
    &quot;type&quot;: &quot;remote&quot;,
    &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;,
    &quot;headers&quot;: {
      &quot;CONTEXT7_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
    },
    &quot;enabled&quot;: true
  }
}
```

#### Opencode Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcp&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;local&quot;,
      &quot;command&quot;: [&quot;npx&quot;, &quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;],
      &quot;enabled&quot;: true
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in OpenAI Codex&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [OpenAI Codex](https://github.com/openai/codex) for more information.

Add the following configuration to your OpenAI Codex MCP server settings:

```toml
[mcp_servers.context7]
args = [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
command = &quot;npx&quot;
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in JetBrains AI Assistant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [JetBrains AI Assistant Documentation](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/ai-assistant/configure-an-mcp-server.html) for more details.

1. In JetBrains IDEs, go to `Settings` -&gt; `Tools` -&gt; `AI Assistant` -&gt; `Model Context Protocol (MCP)`
2. Click `+ Add`.
3. Click on `Command` in the top-left corner of the dialog and select the As JSON option from the list
4. Add this configuration and click `OK`

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

5. Click `Apply` to save changes.
6. The same way context7 could be added for JetBrains Junie in `Settings` -&gt; `Tools` -&gt; `Junie` -&gt; `MCP Settings`

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
  
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Kiro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Kiro Model Context Protocol Documentation](https://kiro.dev/docs/mcp/configuration/) for details.

1. Navigate `Kiro` &gt; `MCP Servers`
2. Add a new MCP server by clicking the `+ Add` button.
3. Paste the configuration given below:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;Context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {},
      &quot;disabled&quot;: false,
      &quot;autoApprove&quot;: []
    }
  }
}
```

4. Click `Save` to apply the changes.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Trae&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Use the Add manually feature and fill in the JSON configuration information for that MCP server.
For more details, visit the [Trae documentation](https://docs.trae.ai/ide/model-context-protocol?_lang=en).

#### Trae Remote Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.context7.com/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

#### Trae Local Server Connection

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Using Bun or Deno&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Use these alternatives to run the local Context7 MCP server with other runtimes. These examples work for any client that supports launching a local MCP server via command + args.

#### Bun

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;bunx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

#### Deno

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;deno&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;run&quot;,
        &quot;--allow-env=NO_DEPRECATION,TRACE_DEPRECATION&quot;,
        &quot;--allow-net&quot;,
        &quot;npm:@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;
      ]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Using Docker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

If you prefer to run the MCP server in a Docker container:

1. **Build the Docker Image:**

   First, create a `Dockerfile` in the project root (or anywhere you prefer):

   &lt;details&gt;
   &lt;summary&gt;Click to see Dockerfile content&lt;/summary&gt;

   ```Dockerfile
   FROM node:18-alpine

   WORKDIR /app

   # Install the latest version globally
   RUN npm install -g @upstash/context7-mcp

   # Expose default port if needed (optional, depends on MCP client interaction)
   # EXPOSE 3000

   # Default command to run the server
   CMD [&quot;context7-mcp&quot;]
   ```

   &lt;/details&gt;

   Then, build the image using a tag (e.g., `context7-mcp`). **Make sure Docker Desktop (or the Docker daemon) is running.** Run the following command in the same directory where you saved the `Dockerfile`:

   ```bash
   docker build -t context7-mcp .
   ```

2. **Configure Your MCP Client:**

   Update your MCP client&#039;s configuration to use the Docker command.

   _Example for a cline_mcp_settings.json:_

   ```json
   {
     &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
       &quot;Сontext7&quot;: {
         &quot;autoApprove&quot;: [],
         &quot;disabled&quot;: false,
         &quot;timeout&quot;: 60,
         &quot;command&quot;: &quot;docker&quot;,
         &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;run&quot;, &quot;-i&quot;, &quot;--rm&quot;, &quot;context7-mcp&quot;],
         &quot;transportType&quot;: &quot;stdio&quot;
       }
     }
   }
   ```

   _Note: This is an example configuration. Please refer to the specific examples for your MCP client (like Cursor, VS Code, etc.) earlier in this README to adapt the structure (e.g., `mcpServers` vs `servers`). Also, ensure the image name in `args` matches the tag used during the `docker build` command._

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install Using the Desktop Extension&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the [context7.mcpb](mcpb/context7.mcpb) file under the mcpb folder and add it to your client. For more information, please check out [MCP bundles docs](https://github.com/anthropics/mcpb#mcp-bundles-mcpb).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Windows&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

The configuration on Windows is slightly different compared to Linux or macOS (_`Cline` is used in the example_). The same principle applies to other editors; refer to the configuration of `command` and `args`.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;github.com/upstash/context7-mcp&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;cmd&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;/c&quot;, &quot;npx&quot;, &quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;],
      &quot;disabled&quot;: false,
      &quot;autoApprove&quot;: []
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Amazon Q Developer CLI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

Add this to your Amazon Q Developer CLI configuration file. See [Amazon Q Developer CLI docs](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-mcp-configuration.html) for more details.

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;context7&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@upstash/context7-mcp&quot;, &quot;--api-key&quot;, &quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Install in Warp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

See [Warp Model Context Protocol Documentation](https://docs.warp.dev/knowledge-and-collaboration/

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foundry376/Mailspring]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[💌 A beautiful, fast and fully open source mail client for Mac, Windows and Linux.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring">Foundry376/Mailspring</a></h1>
            <p>💌 A beautiful, fast and fully open source mail client for Mac, Windows and Linux.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,691</p>
            <p>Forks: 944</p>
            <p>Stars today: 19 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># 💌 Mailspring

[![Travis Status](https://api.travis-ci.com/Foundry376/Mailspring.svg?branch=master)](https://travis-ci.com/github/Foundry376/Mailspring)
[![AppVeyor Status](https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/iuuuy6d65u3x6bj6?svg=true)](https://ci.appveyor.com/project/Foundry376/Mailspring)

**Mailspring is a new version of Nylas Mail maintained by one of the original authors. It&#039;s faster, leaner, and shipping today!** It replaces the JavaScript sync code in Nylas Mail with a new C++ sync engine based on [Mailcore2](https://github.com/MailCore/mailcore2). It uses roughly half the RAM and CPU of Nylas Mail and idles with almost zero &quot;CPU Wakes&quot;, which translates to great battery life. It also has an entirely revamped composer and other great new features.

Mailspring&#039;s UI is open source (GPLv3) and written in TypeScript with [Electron](https://github.com/atom/electron) and [React](https://facebook.github.io/react/) - it&#039;s built on a plugin architecture and was designed to be easy to extend. Check out [CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md) to get started!

Mailspring&#039;s sync engine is spawned by the Electron application and runs locally on your computer. [It is open source (GPLv3) and written in C++ and C.](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring-Sync) For convenience, however, when you set up your development environment, Mailspring uses the latest version of the sync engine we&#039;ve shipped for your platform so you don&#039;t need to pull sources or install its compile-time dependencies.

![Mailspring Screenshot](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring/raw/master/screenshots/hero_graphic_mac%402x.png)

## Features

Mailspring comes packed with powerful features like Unified Inbox, Snooze, Send
Later, Mail Rules, Templates and more. Mailspring Pro, which you can unlock
with a monthly subscription, adds even more features for people who send a ton
of email: link tracking, read receipts, mailbox analytics, contact and company
profiles. **All of these features run in the client - Mailspring does not send
your email credentials to the cloud.** For a full list of features, check out
[getmailspring.com](https://getmailspring.com/).

## Download Mailspring

You can download compiled versions of Mailspring for Windows, Mac OS X, and
Linux (deb, rpm and snap) from
[https://getmailspring.com/download](https://getmailspring.com/download).

## Getting Help

You can find community-based help and discussion with other Mailspring users on our
[Discourse community](https://community.getmailspring.com/).

## Contributing

Mailspring is entirely open-source. Pull requests and contributions are
welcome! There are three ways to contribute: building a plugin, building a
theme, and submitting pull requests to the project itself. When you&#039;re getting
started, you may want to join our
[Discourse](https://community.getmailspring.com/) so you can ask questions and
learn from other people doing development.

[![Contributor Covenant](https://img.shields.io/badge/Contributor%20Covenant-v2.0%20adopted-ff69b4.svg)](CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md)

### Running Mailspring from Source

To install all dependencies and run Mailspring from its source code,
run the following commands from the root directory of the Mailspring repository:

```
export npm_config_arch=x64 # If you are on an M1 / Apple Silicon Mac
npm install
npm start
```

You can attach command line parameters by separating them using a double hyphen:

```
npm start -- --help
```

### Building Mailspring

To build Mailspring, you need to run the following command from the root directory
of the Mailspring repository:

```
npm run-script build
```

### Building A Plugin

Plugins lie at the heart of Mailspring and give it its powerful features.
Building your own plugins allows you to integrate the app with other tools,
experiment with new workflows, and more. Follow the [Getting Started
guide](https://Foundry376.github.io/Mailspring/) to write your first plugin in
five minutes.

- To create your own theme, check out the
  [Mailspring-Theme-Starter](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring-Theme-Starter).

- To create your own plugin, check out the
  [Mailspring-Plugin-Starter](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring-Plugin-Starter).

A plugin &quot;store&quot; like the Chrome Web Store is coming soon, and will make it
easy for other users to discover plugins you create. (Right now, users need to
&quot;sideload&quot; the plugins into the app by downloading them and copying them into
place.)

You can share and browse Mailspring Plugins, and discuss plugin development
with other developers, on our
[Discourse](https://community.getmailspring.com/).

### Building a Theme

The Mailspring user interface is styled using CSS, which means it&#039;s easy to
modify and extend. Mailspring comes stock with a few beautiful themes, and
there are many more which have been built by community developers. To start
creating a theme, [clone the theme starter](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring-Theme-Starter)!

If you are updating an existing Nylas theme for Mailspring here is a
[step by step tutorial](https://community.getmailspring.com/t/updating-an-n1-nylas-mail-theme-for-mailspring/195).
Notice: as part of the update process you will probably need to [import mailspring base variables](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring/issues/326#issuecomment-343757775).

You can share and browse Mailspring Themes, and discuss theme development with other developers, on our [Discourse](https://community.getmailspring.com/).

### Localizing / Translating

Mailspring (1.5.0 and above) supports localization. If you&#039;re a fluent speaker of
another language, we&#039;d love your help improving translations. Check out the
[LOCALIZATION](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring/blob/master/LOCALIZATION.md)
guide for more information. You can discuss localization and translation with
other developers on our [Discourse](https://community.getmailspring.com/).

### Contributing to Mailspring Core

Pull requests are always welcome - check out
[CONTRIBUTING](https://github.com/Foundry376/Mailspring/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md)
for more information about setting up the development environment, running
tests locally, and submitting pull requests.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaflet/Leaflet]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🍃 JavaScript library for mobile-friendly interactive maps 🇺🇦]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet">Leaflet/Leaflet</a></h1>
            <p>🍃 JavaScript library for mobile-friendly interactive maps 🇺🇦</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 43,627</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,003</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>Leaflet was created 14 years ago by [Volodymyr Agafonkin](https://agafonkin.com), a Ukrainian citizen living in Kyiv.

Russian bombs are now falling over Volodymyr&#039;s hometown. His family, his friends, his neighbours, thousands and thousands of absolutely wonderful people, are either seeking refuge or fighting for their lives.

Russian soldiers have already killed tens of thousands of civilians, including women and children, and are committing mass war crimes like gang rapes, executions, looting, and targeted bombings of civilian shelters and places of cultural significance. The death toll keeps rising, and Ukraine needs your help.

As Volodymyr [expressed a few days before the invasion](https://twitter.com/LeafletJS/status/1496051256409919489):

&gt; If you want to help, educate yourself and others on the Russian threat, follow reputable journalists, demand severe Russian sanctions and Ukrainian support from your leaders, protest the war, reach out to Ukrainian friends, donate to Ukrainian charities. Just don&#039;t be silent.

Ukrainians recommend the [Come Back Alive](https://savelife.in.ua/en/) charity. For other options, see [StandWithUkraine](https://stand-with-ukraine.pp.ua).

If an appeal to humanity doesn&#039;t work for you, I&#039;ll appeal to your egoism: the future of Ukrainian citizens is the future of Leaflet.

It is chilling to see Leaflet being used for [documenting Russia&#039;s war crimes](https://ukraine.bellingcat.com/), [factual reporting of the war](https://liveuamap.com/) and for coordination of humanitarian efforts across Europe. We commend these uses of Leaflet.

If you support the actions of the Russian government (even after reading all this), do everyone else a favour and [carry some seeds in your pocket](https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2022/feb/25/ukrainian-woman-sunflower-seeds-russian-soldiers-video).

Yours truly,&lt;br&gt;
Leaflet maintainers.

---

&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; src=&quot;https://rawgit.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/main/src/images/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Leaflet&quot; /&gt;

Leaflet is the leading open-source JavaScript library for **building powerful interactive maps**.

Weighing just about 42 KB of gzipped JS plus 4 KB of gzipped CSS code, it has all the mapping [features][] most developers ever need.

Leaflet is designed with *simplicity*, *performance* and *usability* in mind.
It works efficiently across all major desktop and mobile platforms out of the box,
taking advantage of modern browser features while being accessible on older ones too.
It can be extended with a huge amount of [plugins][],
has a beautiful, easy to use and [well-documented][] API
and a simple, readable [source code][] that is a joy to [contribute][] to.

For more info, docs and tutorials, check out the [official website][].&lt;br&gt;
For **Leaflet downloads** (including the built main version), check out the [download page][].

We&#039;re happy to meet new contributors.
If you want to **get involved** with Leaflet development, check out the [contribution guide][contribute].
Let&#039;s make the best mapping library that will ever exist,
and push the limits of what&#039;s possible with online maps!

[![CI](https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/actions/workflows/main.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/actions/workflows/main.yml)

 [contributors]: https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/graphs/contributors
 [features]: http://leafletjs.com/#features
 [plugins]: http://leafletjs.com/plugins.html
 [well-documented]: http://leafletjs.com/reference.html &quot;Leaflet API reference&quot;
 [source code]: https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet &quot;Leaflet GitHub repository&quot;
 [hosted on GitHub]: http://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet
 [contribute]: https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md &quot;A guide to contributing to Leaflet&quot;
 [official website]: http://leafletjs.com
 [download page]: http://leafletjs.com/download.html

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[egonSchiele/grokking_algorithms]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/egonSchiele/grokking_algorithms</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/egonSchiele/grokking_algorithms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Code for the book Grokking Algorithms (https://www.amazon.com/dp/1633438538)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/egonSchiele/grokking_algorithms">egonSchiele/grokking_algorithms</a></h1>
            <p>Code for the book Grokking Algorithms (https://www.amazon.com/dp/1633438538)</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 12,805</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,006</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Grokking Algorithms

This is the code in my book [Grokking Algorithms](https://www.manning.com/bhargava).

Check out [Python Tutor](http://pythontutor.com/), a great website that guides you through Python code line by line.

## Errata

[Here&#039;s the errata page](http://adit.io/errata.html).

## Images

This repository contains every image in Grokking Algorithms in high resolution. These images are available for non-commercial use. If you use an image, please add &quot;copyright Manning Publications, drawn by adit.io&quot;. You are welcome to use these images in any non-commercial materials (i.e. teaching materials, presentations, etc.)

## Contributing

Thanks for wanting to contribute to this repo!

If you have found a mistake in the book or have a question, please email me as that will be the best way to get a response. My email is listed on my website, adit.io.
If you would like to make a change, please go ahead and open a PR with your suggested change. I am quicker at responding to those than I am to issues.

It takes me a long time to respond to PRs. It&#039;s something I&#039;m trying to get better at, but I apologize in advance for how long it will take. I will eventually get to it.

The contributions that are most useful are:
- fixing errors in existing code
- adding examples to new languages
- modernizing code as the language evolves
- making code easier to read.

I&#039;m less likely to merge code that involves stylistic changes, and I&#039;m very unlikely to merge PRs that add complex optimizations, as the main purpose of this repo is to have easy to read examples that help people understand concepts.

Thanks for contributing and I hope you&#039;re enjoying the book!</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[plankanban/planka]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/plankanban/planka</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/plankanban/planka</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[PLANKA is the kanban-style project mastering tool for everyone.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/plankanban/planka">plankanban/planka</a></h1>
            <p>PLANKA is the kanban-style project mastering tool for everyone.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,629</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,072</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># PLANKA

**Project mastering driven by fun**

![Version](https://img.shields.io/github/package-json/v/plankanban/planka?style=flat-square) [![Docker Pulls](https://img.shields.io/badge/docker_pulls-6M%2B-%23066da5?style=flat-square&amp;color=red)](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/pkgs/container/planka) [![Contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/plankanban/planka?style=flat-square&amp;color=blue)](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/graphs/contributors) [![Chat](https://img.shields.io/discord/1041440072953765979?style=flat-square&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/WqqYNd7Jvt)

![Demo](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plankanban/planka/master/assets/demo.gif)

[**Client demo**](https://plankanban.github.io/planka) (without server features).

&gt; ⚠️ The demo GIF and client demo are based on **v1** and will be updated soon.

## Key Features

- **Collaborative Kanban Boards**: Create projects, boards, lists, cards, and manage tasks with an intuitive drag-and-drop interface
- **Real-Time Updates**: Instant syncing across all users, no refresh needed
- **Rich Markdown Support**: Write beautifully formatted card descriptions with a powerful markdown editor
- **Flexible Notifications**: Get alerts through 100+ providers, fully customizable to your workflow
- **Seamless Authentication**: Single sign-on with OpenID Connect integration
- **Multilingual &amp; Easy to Translate**: Full internationalization support for a global audience

## How to Deploy

PLANKA is easy to install using multiple methods - learn more in the [installation guide](https://docs.planka.cloud/docs/welcome/).

For configuration and environment settings, see the [configuration section](https://docs.planka.cloud/docs/category/configuration/).

## Contact

Interested in a hosted version of PLANKA? Email us at [github@planka.group](mailto:github@planka.group).

For any security issues, please do not create a public issue on GitHub - instead, report it privately by emailing [security@planka.group](mailto:security@planka.group).

**Note:** We do NOT offer any public support via email, please use GitHub.

**Join our community:** Get help, share ideas, or contribute on our [Discord server](https://discord.gg/WqqYNd7Jvt).

## License

PLANKA is [fair-code](https://faircode.io) distributed under the [Fair Use License](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/blob/master/LICENSES/PLANKA%20Community%20License%20EN.md) and [PLANKA Pro/Enterprise License](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/blob/master/LICENSES/PLANKA%20Commercial%20License%20EN.md).

- **Source Available**: The source code is always visible
- **Self-Hostable**: Deploy and host it anywhere
- **Extensible**: Customize with your own functionality
- **Enterprise Licenses**: Available for additional features and support

For more details, check the [License Guide](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/blob/master/LICENSES/PLANKA%20License%20Guide%20EN.md).

## Contributing

Found a bug or have a feature request? Check out our [Contributing Guide](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md) to get started.

For setting up the project locally, see the [development section](https://docs.planka.cloud/docs/category/development/).

**Thanks to all our contributors!**

[![Contributors](https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=plankanban/planka)](https://github.com/plankanban/planka/graphs/contributors)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4ian/GDevelop]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🎮 Open-source, cross-platform 2D/3D/multiplayer game engine designed for everyone.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop">4ian/GDevelop</a></h1>
            <p>🎮 Open-source, cross-platform 2D/3D/multiplayer game engine designed for everyone.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,461</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,077</p>
            <p>Stars today: 31 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![GDevelop logo](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20banner.png &quot;GDevelop logo&quot;)

GDevelop is a **full-featured, no-code, open-source** game development software. You can build **2D, 3D and multiplayer games** for mobile (iOS, Android), desktop and the web. GDevelop is fast and easy to use: the game logic is built up using an intuitive and powerful event-based system and reusable behaviors.

![The GDevelop editor when editing a game level](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20screenshot.png &quot;The GDevelop editor when editing a game level&quot;)

## Getting started

| ❔ I want to...                                   | 🚀 What to do                                                                                                                                                     |
| ------------------------------------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| 🎮 Use GDevelop to make games                     | Go to [GDevelop homepage](https://gdevelop.io) to download the app!                                                                                               |
| ⚙️ Create/improve an extension                    | Read about [creating an extension](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/extensions/create), with no-code or code.                                                   |
| 🧑‍💻 Contribute to the editor or game engine        | Follow this [README](newIDE/README.md).                                                                                                                           |
| 👾 Create or sell a game template                 | Submit a [free example or a paid template on the Asset Store](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/community/guide-for-submitting-an-example/).                     |
| 🎨 Share or sell an asset pack                    | Submit a [free or paid asset pack on the Asset Store](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/community/sell-asset-pack-store).                                        |
| 🌐 Help translate GDevelop                        | Go on the [GDevelop project on Crowdin](https://crowdin.com/project/gdevelop) or translate [in-app tutorials](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-tutorials). |
| 👥 Get online game services or commercial support | See offers for [professionals, teams or individual creators](https://gdevelop.io/pricing).                                                                        |

&gt; Are you interested in contributing to GDevelop for the first time? Take a look at the list of **[good first issues](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22%F0%9F%91%8Cgood+first+issue%22)**, **[good first contributions](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/discussions/categories/good-first-contribution)** or the **[&quot;🏐 not too hard&quot; cards](https://trello.com/b/qf0lM7k8/gdevelop-roadmap?menu=filter&amp;filter=label:Not%20too%20hard%20%E2%9A%BD%EF%B8%8F)** on the Roadmap.

## Games made with GDevelop

- Find GDevelop games on [gd.games](https://gd.games), the gaming platform for games powered by GDevelop.
- See the [showcase of games](https://gdevelop.io/games) created with GDevelop and published on Steam, iOS (App Store), Android (Google Play), Itch.io, Newgrounds, CrazyGames, Poki...
  - Suggest your game to be [added to the showcase here](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfjiOnkbODuPifSGuzxYY61vB5kyMWdTZSSqkJsv3H6ePRTQA/viewform).

[![Some games made with GDevelop](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/4ian/GDevelop/master/newIDE/GDevelop%20games.png &quot;Some games made with GDevelop&quot;)](https://gdevelop.io/games)

## Technical architecture

GDevelop is composed of an **editor**, a **game engine**, an **ecosystem** of extensions as well as **online services** and commercial support.

| Directory     | ℹ️ Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |
| ------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| `Core`        | Core classes, describing the structure of a game and tools to implement the IDE and work with GDevelop games.                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| `GDJS`        | The game engine, written in TypeScript, using PixiJS and Three.js for 2D and 3D rendering (WebGL), powering all GDevelop games.                                                                                                                                                                          |
| `GDevelop.js` | Bindings of `Core`, `GDJS` and `Extensions` to JavaScript (with WebAssembly), used by the IDE.                                                                                                                                                                                                           |
| `newIDE`      | The game editor, written in JavaScript with React, Electron, PixiJS and Three.js.js.                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |
| `Extensions`  | Built-in extensions for the game engine, providing objects, behaviors and new features. For example, this includes the physics engines running in WebAssembly (Box2D or Jolt Physics for 3D). All the [community extensions are on this repository](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-extensions). |

To learn more about GDevelop Architecture, read the [architecture overview here](Core/GDevelop-Architecture-Overview.md).

Pre-generated documentation of the game engine is [available here](https://docs.gdevelop.io).

Status of the tests and builds: [![macOS and Linux build status](https://circleci.com/gh/4ian/GDevelop.svg?style=shield)](https://app.circleci.com/pipelines/github/4ian/GDevelop) [![Fast tests status](https://gdevelop.semaphoreci.com/badges/GDevelop/branches/master.svg?style=shields)](https://gdevelop.semaphoreci.com/projects/GDevelop) [![Windows Build status](https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/84uhtdox47xp422x/branch/master?svg=true)](https://ci.appveyor.com/project/4ian/gdevelop/branch/master) [![https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg)](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation)

## Links

### Community

- [GDevelop forums](https://forum.gdevelop.io) and [Discord chat](https://discord.gg/gdevelop).
- [GDevelop homepage](https://gdevelop.io).
- [GDevelop wiki (documentation)](https://wiki.gdevelop.io/gdevelop5/start).
- Help translate GDevelop in your language: [GDevelop project on Crowdin](https://crowdin.com/project/gdevelop).
- Open-source [extensions](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-extensions), [examples](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-examples), [tutorials](https://github.com/GDevelopApp/GDevelop-tutorials) are on GitHub.

### Development Roadmap

- [GDevelop Roadmap on Trello.com](https://trello.com/b/qf0lM7k8/gdevelop-roadmap), for a global view of the features that could be added. Please vote and comment here for new features/requests.
- [GitHub issue page](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/issues), for technical issues and bugs.
- [Github discussions](https://github.com/4ian/GDevelop/discussions) to talk about new features and ideas.

## License

- The Core library, the native and HTML5 game engines, the IDE, and all extensions (respectively `Core`, `GDJS`, `newIDE` and `Extensions` folders) are under the **MIT license**.
- The name, GDevelop, and its logo are the exclusive property of Florian Rival.

Games exported with GDevelop are based on the GDevelop game engine (see `Core` and `GDJS` folders): this engine is distributed under the MIT license so that you can **distribute, sell or do anything** with the games you created with GDevelop. In particular, you are not forced to make your game open-source.

[node.js]: https://nodejs.org

## Star History

Help us spread the word about GDevelop by starring the repository on GitHub!

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=4ian/gdevelop&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#4ian/gdevelop&amp;Date)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[swagger-api/swagger-ui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Swagger UI is a collection of HTML, JavaScript, and CSS assets that dynamically generate beautiful documentation from a Swagger-compliant API.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui">swagger-api/swagger-ui</a></h1>
            <p>Swagger UI is a collection of HTML, JavaScript, and CSS assets that dynamically generate beautiful documentation from a Swagger-compliant API.</p>
            <p>Language: JavaScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 28,142</p>
            <p>Forks: 9,201</p>
            <p>Stars today: 4 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swagger-api/swagger.io/wordpress/images/assets/SWU-logo-clr.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;

[![NPM version](https://badge.fury.io/js/swagger-ui.svg)](http://badge.fury.io/js/swagger-ui)
[![Build Status](https://jenkins.swagger.io/view/OSS%20-%20JavaScript/job/oss-swagger-ui-master/badge/icon?subject=jenkins%20build)](https://jenkins.swagger.io/view/OSS%20-%20JavaScript/job/oss-swagger-ui-master/)
[![npm audit](https://jenkins.swagger.io/buildStatus/icon?job=oss-swagger-ui-security-audit&amp;subject=npm%20audit)](https://jenkins.swagger.io/job/oss-swagger-ui-security-audit/lastBuild/console)
[![total GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors-anon/swagger-api/swagger-ui.svg)](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/graphs/contributors)

[![monthly npm installs](https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/swagger-ui.svg?label=npm%20downloads)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui)
![docker registry](https://img.shields.io/badge/docker-docker.swagger.io%2Fswaggerapi%2Fswagger--ui-blue)
![monthly packagist installs](https://img.shields.io/packagist/dm/swagger-api/swagger-ui.svg?label=packagist%20installs)
[![gzip size](https://img.shields.io/bundlephobia/minzip/swagger-ui.svg?label=gzip%20size)](https://bundlephobia.com/package/swagger-ui)

## Introduction
[Swagger UI](https://swagger.io/tools/swagger-ui/) allows anyone — be it your development team or your end consumers — to visualize and interact with the API’s resources without having any of the implementation logic in place. It’s automatically generated from your OpenAPI (formerly known as Swagger) Specification, with the visual documentation making it easy for back end implementation and client side consumption.

## General
**👉🏼 Want to score an easy open-source contribution?** Check out our [Good first issue](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22Good+first+issue%22) label.

**🕰️ Looking for the older version of Swagger UI?** Refer to the [*2.x* branch](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/2.x).


This repository publishes three different NPM modules:

* [swagger-ui](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui) is a traditional npm module intended for use in single-page applications that are capable of resolving dependencies (via Webpack, Browserify, etc.).
* [swagger-ui-dist](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui-dist) is a dependency-free module that includes everything you need to serve Swagger UI in a server-side project, or a single-page application that can&#039;t resolve npm module dependencies.
* [swagger-ui-react](https://www.npmjs.com/package/swagger-ui-react) is Swagger UI packaged as a React component for use in React applications.

We strongly suggest that you use `swagger-ui` instead of `swagger-ui-dist` if you&#039;re building a single-page application, since `swagger-ui-dist` is significantly larger.

If you are looking for plain ol&#039; HTML/JS/CSS, [download the latest release](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/releases/latest) and copy the contents of the `/dist` folder to your server.


## Compatibility
The OpenAPI Specification has undergone 5 revisions since initial creation in 2010.  Compatibility between Swagger UI and the OpenAPI Specification is as follows:

| Swagger UI Version | Release Date | OpenAPI Spec compatibility                           | Notes                                                                 |
|--------------------|--------------|------------------------------------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------|
| 5.19.0             | 2025-02-17   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3, 3.0.4, 3.1.0, 3.1.1 | [tag v5.19.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v5.19.0) |
| 5.0.0              | 2023-06-12   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3, 3.1.0               | [tag v5.0.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v5.0.0)   |
| 4.0.0              | 2021-11-03   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3                      | [tag v4.0.0](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v4.0.0)   |
| 3.18.3             | 2018-08-03   | 2.0, 3.0.0, 3.0.1, 3.0.2, 3.0.3                      | [tag v3.18.3](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v3.18.3) |
| 3.0.21             | 2017-07-26   | 2.0                                                  | [tag v3.0.21](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v3.0.21) |
| 2.2.10             | 2017-01-04   | 1.1, 1.2, 2.0                                        | [tag v2.2.10](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.2.10) |
| 2.1.5              | 2016-07-20   | 1.1, 1.2, 2.0                                        | [tag v2.1.5](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.1.5)   |
| 2.0.24             | 2014-09-12   | 1.1, 1.2                                             | [tag v2.0.24](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v2.0.24) |
| 1.0.13             | 2013-03-08   | 1.1, 1.2                                             | [tag v1.0.13](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v1.0.13) |
| 1.0.1              | 2011-10-11   | 1.0, 1.1                                             | [tag v1.0.1](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/tree/v1.0.1)   |

## Anonymized analytics

SwaggerUI uses [Scarf](https://scarf.sh/) to collect [anonymized installation analytics](https://github.com/scarf-sh/scarf-js?tab=readme-ov-file#as-a-user-of-a-package-using-scarf-js-what-information-does-scarf-js-send-about-me). These analytics help support the maintainers of this library and ONLY run during installation. To [opt out](https://github.com/scarf-sh/scarf-js?tab=readme-ov-file#as-a-user-of-a-package-using-scarf-js-how-can-i-opt-out-of-analytics), you can set the `scarfSettings.enabled` field to `false` in your project&#039;s `package.json`:

```
// package.json
{
  // ...
  &quot;scarfSettings&quot;: {
    &quot;enabled&quot;: false
  }
  // ...
}
```

Alternatively, you can set the environment variable `SCARF_ANALYTICS` to `false` as part of the environment that installs your npm packages, e.g., `SCARF_ANALYTICS=false npm install`.

## Documentation

#### Usage
- [Installation](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/installation.md)
- [Configuration](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/configuration.md)
- [CORS](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/cors.md)
- [OAuth2](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/oauth2.md)
- [Deep Linking](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/deep-linking.md)
- [Limitations](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/limitations.md)
- [Version detection](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/usage/version-detection.md)

#### Customization
- [Overview](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/overview.md)
- [Plugin API](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/plugin-api.md)
- [Custom layout](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/customization/custom-layout.md)

#### Development
- [Setting up](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/development/setting-up.md)
- [Scripts](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/HEAD/docs/development/scripts.md)

#### Contributing
- [Contributing](https://github.com/swagger-api/.github/blob/HEAD/CONTRIBUTING.md)

##### Integration Tests

You will need JDK of version 7 or higher as instructed here
https://nightwatchjs.org/guide/getting-started/installation.html#install-selenium-server

Integration tests can be run locally with `npm run e2e` - be sure you aren&#039;t running a dev server when testing!

### Browser support
Swagger UI works in the latest versions of Chrome, Safari, Firefox, and Edge.

### Known Issues

To help with the migration, here are the currently known issues with 3.X. This list will update regularly, and will not include features that were not implemented in previous versions.

- Only part of the parameters previously supported are available.
- The JSON Form Editor is not implemented.
- Support for `collectionFormat` is partial.
- l10n (translations) is not implemented.
- Relative path support for external files is not implemented.

## Security contact

Please disclose any security-related issues or vulnerabilities by emailing [security@swagger.io](mailto:security@swagger.io), instead of using the public issue tracker.

## License

SwaggerUI is licensed under [Apache 2.0 license](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/master/LICENSE).
SwaggerUI comes with an explicit [NOTICE](https://github.com/swagger-api/swagger-ui/blob/master/NOTICE) file
containing additional legal notices and information.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>JavaScript</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>