<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for python - Python Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for python.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fosowl/agenticSeek]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fully Local Manus AI. No APIs, No $200 monthly bills. Enjoy an autonomous agent that thinks, browses the web, and code for the sole cost of electricity.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek">Fosowl/agenticSeek</a></h1>
            <p>Fully Local Manus AI. No APIs, No $200 monthly bills. Enjoy an autonomous agent that thinks, browses the web, and code for the sole cost of electricity.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,708</p>
            <p>Forks: 454</p>
            <p>Stars today: 518 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># AgenticSeek: Private, Local Manus Alternative.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;./media/agentic_seek_logo.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;Agentic Seek Logo&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

  English | [中文](./README_CHS.md) | [繁體中文](./README_CHT.md) | [Français](./README_FR.md) | [日本語](./README_JP.md)

*A **100% local alternative to Manus AI**, this voice-enabled AI assistant autonomously browses the web, writes code, and plans tasks while keeping all data on your device. Tailored for local reasoning models, it runs entirely on your hardware, ensuring complete privacy and zero cloud dependency.*

[![Visit AgenticSeek](https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=Website&amp;message=AgenticSeek&amp;color=blue&amp;style=flat-square)](https://fosowl.github.io/agenticSeek.html) ![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-GPL--3.0-green) [![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join%20Us-7289DA?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/8hGDaME3TC) [![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/url/https/twitter.com/fosowl.svg?style=social&amp;label=Update%20%40Fosowl)](https://x.com/Martin993886460) [![GitHub stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/Fosowl/agenticSeek?style=social)](https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek/stargazers)

### Why AgenticSeek ?

* 🔒 Fully Local &amp; Private - Everything runs on your machine — no cloud, no data sharing. Your files, conversations, and searches stay private.

* 🌐 Smart Web Browsing - AgenticSeek can browse the internet by itself — search, read, extract info, fill web form — all hands-free.

* 💻 Autonomous Coding Assistant - Need code? It can write, debug, and run programs in Python, C, Go, Java, and more — all without supervision.

* 🧠 Smart Agent Selection - You ask, it figures out the best agent for the job automatically. Like having a team of experts ready to help.

* 📋 Plans &amp; Executes Complex Tasks - From trip planning to complex projects — it can split big tasks into steps and get things done using multiple AI agents.

* 🎙️ Voice-Enabled - Clean, fast, futuristic voice and speech to text allowing you to talk to it like it&#039;s your personal AI from a sci-fi movie

### **Demo**

&gt; *Can you search for the agenticSeek project, learn what skills are required, then open the CV_candidates.zip and then tell me which match best the project*

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b8ca60e9-7b3b-4533-840e-08f9ac426316

Disclaimer: This demo, including all the files that appear (e.g: CV_candidates.zip), are entirely fictional. We are not a corporation, we seek open-source contributors not candidates.

&gt; 🛠️ **Work in Progress** – Looking for contributors!

## Installation

Make sure you have chrome driver, docker and python3.10 installed.

We highly advice you use exactly python3.10 for the setup. Dependencies error might happen otherwise.

For issues related to chrome driver, see the **Chromedriver** section.

### 1️⃣ **Clone the repository and setup**

```sh
git clone https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek.git
cd agenticSeek
mv .env.example .env
```

### 2️ **Create a virtual env**

```sh
python3 -m venv agentic_seek_env
source agentic_seek_env/bin/activate
# On Windows: agentic_seek_env\Scripts\activate
```

### 3️⃣ **Install package**

Ensure Python, Docker and docker compose, and Google chrome are installed.

We recommand Python 3.10.0.

**Automatic Installation (Recommanded):**

For Linux/Macos:
```sh
./install.sh
```

For windows:

```sh
./install.bat
```

**Manually:**

**Note: For any OS, ensure the ChromeDriver you install matches your installed Chrome version. Run `google-chrome --version`. See known issues if you have chrome &gt;135**

- *Linux*: 

Update Package List: `sudo apt update`

Install Dependencies: `sudo apt install -y alsa-utils portaudio19-dev python3-pyaudio libgtk-3-dev libnotify-dev libgconf-2-4 libnss3 libxss1`

Install ChromeDriver matching your Chrome browser version:
`sudo apt install -y chromium-chromedriver`

Install requirements: `pip3 install -r requirements.txt`

- *Macos*:

Update brew : `brew update`

Install chromedriver : `brew install --cask chromedriver`

Install portaudio: `brew install portaudio`

Upgrade pip : `python3 -m pip install --upgrade pip`

Upgrade wheel : : `pip3 install --upgrade setuptools wheel`

Install requirements: `pip3 install -r requirements.txt`

- *Windows*:

Install pyreadline3 `pip install pyreadline3`

Install portaudio manually (e.g., via vcpkg or prebuilt binaries) and then run: `pip install pyaudio`

Download and install chromedriver manually from: https://sites.google.com/chromium.org/driver/getting-started

Place chromedriver in a directory included in your PATH.

Install requirements: `pip3 install -r requirements.txt`

---

## Setup for running LLM locally on your machine

**Hardware Requirements:**

To run LLMs locally, you&#039;ll need sufficient hardware. At a minimum, a GPU capable of running Qwen/Deepseek 14B is required. See the FAQ for detailed model/performance recommendations.

**Setup your local provider**  

Start your local provider, for example with ollama:

```sh
ollama serve
```

See below for a list of local supported provider.

**Update the config.ini**

Change the config.ini file to set the provider_name to a supported provider and provider_model to a LLM supported by your provider. We recommand reasoning model such as *Qwen* or *Deepseek*.

See the **FAQ** at the end of the README for required hardware.

```sh
[MAIN]
is_local = True # Whenever you are running locally or with remote provider.
provider_name = ollama # or lm-studio, openai, etc..
provider_model = deepseek-r1:14b # choose a model that fit your hardware
provider_server_address = 127.0.0.1:11434
agent_name = Jarvis # name of your AI
recover_last_session = True # whenever to recover the previous session
save_session = True # whenever to remember the current session
speak = True # text to speech
listen = False # Speech to text, only for CLI
work_dir =  /Users/mlg/Documents/workspace # The workspace for AgenticSeek.
jarvis_personality = False # Whenever to use a more &quot;Jarvis&quot; like personality (experimental)
languages = en zh # The list of languages, Text to speech will default to the first language on the list
[BROWSER]
headless_browser = True # Whenever to use headless browser, recommanded only if you use web interface.
stealth_mode = True # Use undetected selenium to reduce browser detection
```

Warning: Do *NOT* set provider_name to `openai` if using LM-studio for running LLMs. Set it to `lm-studio`.

Note: Some provider (eg: lm-studio) require you to have `http://` in front of the IP. For example `http://127.0.0.1:1234`

**List of local providers**

| Provider  | Local? | Description                                               |
|-----------|--------|-----------------------------------------------------------|
| ollama    | Yes    | Run LLMs locally with ease using ollama as a LLM provider |
| lm-studio  | Yes    | Run LLM locally with LM studio (set `provider_name` to `lm-studio`)|
| openai    | Yes     |  Use openai compatible API (eg: llama.cpp server)  |

Next step: [Start services and run AgenticSeek](#Start-services-and-Run)  

*See the **Known issues** section if you are having issues*

*See the **Run with an API** section if your hardware can&#039;t run deepseek locally*

*See the **Config** section for detailled config file explanation.*

---

## Setup to run with an API

Set the desired provider in the `config.ini`. See below for a list of API providers.

```sh
[MAIN]
is_local = False
provider_name = google
provider_model = gemini-2.0-flash
provider_server_address = 127.0.0.1:5000 # doesn&#039;t matter
```
Warning: Make sure there is not trailing space in the config.

Export your API key: `export &lt;&lt;PROVIDER&gt;&gt;_API_KEY=&quot;xxx&quot;`

Example: export `TOGETHER_API_KEY=&quot;xxxxx&quot;`

**List of API providers**
  
| Provider  | Local? | Description                                               |
|-----------|--------|-----------------------------------------------------------|
| openai    | Depends  | Use ChatGPT API  |
| deepseek  | No     | Deepseek API (non-private)                            |
| huggingface| No    | Hugging-Face API (non-private)                            |
| togetherAI | No    | Use together AI API (non-private)                         |
| google | No    | Use google gemini API (non-private)                         |

*We advice against using gpt-4o or other closedAI models*, performance are poor for web browsing and task planning.

Please also note that coding/bash might fail with gemini, it seem to ignore our prompt for format to respect, which are optimized for deepseek r1.

Next step: [Start services and run AgenticSeek](#Start-services-and-Run)

*See the **Known issues** section if you are having issues*

*See the **Config** section for detailled config file explanation.*

---

## Start services and Run

Activate your python env if needed.
```sh
source agentic_seek_env/bin/activate
```

Start required services. This will start all services from the docker-compose.yml, including:
    - searxng
    - redis (required by searxng)
    - frontend

```sh
sudo ./start_services.sh # MacOS
start ./start_services.cmd # Window
```

**Options 1:** Run with the CLI interface.

```sh
python3 cli.py
```

We advice you set `headless_browser` to False in the config.ini for CLI mode.

**Options 2:** Run with the Web interface.

Start the backend.

```sh
python3 api.py
```

Go to `http://localhost:3000/` and you should see the web interface.

---

## Usage

Make sure the services are up and running with `./start_services.sh` and run the AgenticSeek with `python3 cli.py` for CLI mode or `python3 api.py` then go to `localhost:3000` for web interface.

You can also use speech to text by setting `listen = True` in the config. Only for CLI mode.

To exit, simply say/type `goodbye`.

Here are some example usage:

&gt; *Make a snake game in python!*

&gt; *Search the web for top cafes in Rennes, France, and save a list of three with their addresses in rennes_cafes.txt.*

&gt; *Write a Go program to calculate the factorial of a number, save it as factorial.go in your workspace*

&gt; *Search my summer_pictures folder for all JPG files, rename them with today’s date, and save a list of renamed files in photos_list.txt*

&gt; *Search online for popular sci-fi movies from 2024 and pick three to watch tonight. Save the list in movie_night.txt.*

&gt; *Search the web for the latest AI news articles from 2025, select three, and write a Python script to scrape their titles and summaries. Save the script as news_scraper.py and the summaries in ai_news.txt in /home/projects*

&gt; *Friday, search the web for a free stock price API, register with supersuper7434567@gmail.com then write a Python script to fetch using the API daily prices for Tesla, and save the results in stock_prices.csv*

*Note that form filling capabilities are still experimental and might fail.*



After you type your query, AgenticSeek will allocate the best agent for the task.

Because this is an early prototype, the agent routing system might not always allocate the right agent based on your query.

Therefore, you should be very explicit in what you want and how the AI might proceed for example if you want it to conduct a web search, do not say:

`Do you know some good countries for solo-travel?`

Instead, ask:

`Do a web search and find out which are the best country for solo-travel`

---

## **Setup to run the LLM on your own server**  

If you have a powerful computer or a server that you can use, but you want to use it from your laptop you have the options to run the LLM on a remote server using our custom llm server. 

On your &quot;server&quot; that will run the AI model, get the ip address

```sh
ip a | grep &quot;inet &quot; | grep -v 127.0.0.1 | awk &#039;{print $2}&#039; | cut -d/ -f1 # local ip
curl https://ipinfo.io/ip # public ip
```

Note: For Windows or macOS, use ipconfig or ifconfig respectively to find the IP address.

Clone the repository and enter the `server/`folder.


```sh
git clone --depth 1 https://github.com/Fosowl/agenticSeek.git
cd agenticSeek/llm_server/
```

Install server specific requirements:

```sh
pip3 install -r requirements.txt
```

Run the server script.

```sh
python3 app.py --provider ollama --port 3333
```

You have the choice between using `ollama` and `llamacpp` as a LLM service.


Now on your personal computer:

Change the `config.ini` file to set the `provider_name` to `server` and `provider_model` to `deepseek-r1:xxb`.
Set the `provider_server_address` to the ip address of the machine that will run the model.

```sh
[MAIN]
is_local = False
provider_name = server
provider_model = deepseek-r1:70b
provider_server_address = x.x.x.x:3333
```


Next step: [Start services and run AgenticSeek](#Start-services-and-Run)  

---

## Speech to Text

Please note that currently speech to text only work in english.

The speech-to-text functionality is disabled by default. To enable it, set the listen option to True in the config.ini file:

```
listen = True
```

When enabled, the speech-to-text feature listens for a trigger keyword, which is the agent&#039;s name, before it begins processing your input. You can customize the agent&#039;s name by updating the `agent_name` value in the *config.ini* file:

```
agent_name = Friday
```

For optimal recognition, we recommend using a common English name like &quot;John&quot; or &quot;Emma&quot; as the agent name

Once you see the transcript start to appear, say the agent&#039;s name aloud to wake it up (e.g., &quot;Friday&quot;).

Speak your query clearly.

End your request with a confirmation phrase to signal the system to proceed. Examples of confirmation phrases include:
```
&quot;do it&quot;, &quot;go ahead&quot;, &quot;execute&quot;, &quot;run&quot;, &quot;start&quot;, &quot;thanks&quot;, &quot;would ya&quot;, &quot;please&quot;, &quot;okay?&quot;, &quot;proceed&quot;, &quot;continue&quot;, &quot;go on&quot;, &quot;do that&quot;, &quot;go it&quot;, &quot;do you understand?&quot;
```

## Config

Example config:
```
[MAIN]
is_local = True
provider_name = ollama
provider_model = deepseek-r1:32b
provider_server_address = 127.0.0.1:11434
agent_name = Friday
recover_last_session = False
save_session = False
speak = False
listen = False
work_dir =  /Users/mlg/Documents/ai_folder
jarvis_personality = False
languages = en zh
[BROWSER]
headless_browser = False
stealth_mode = False
```

**Explanation**:

- is_local -&gt; Runs the agent locally (True) or on a remote server (False).

- provider_name -&gt; The provider to use (one of: `ollama`, `server`, `lm-studio`, `deepseek-api`)

- provider_model -&gt; The model used, e.g., deepseek-r1:32b.

- provider_server_address -&gt; Server address, e.g., 127.0.0.1:11434 for local. Set to anything for non-local API.

- agent_name -&gt; Name of the agent, e.g., Friday. Used as a trigger word for TTS.

- recover_last_session -&gt; Restarts from last session (True) or not (False).

- save_session -&gt; Saves session data (True) or not (False).

- speak -&gt; Enables voice output (True) or not (False).

- listen -&gt; listen to voice input (True) or not (False).

- work_dir -&gt; Folder the AI will have access to. eg: /Users/user/Documents/.

- jarvis_personality -&gt; Uses a JARVIS-like personality (True) or not (False). This simply change the prompt file.

- languages -&gt; The list of supported language, needed for the llm router to work properly, avoid putting too many or too similar languages.

- headless_browser -&gt; Runs browser without a visible window (True) or not (False).

- stealth_mode -&gt; Make bot detector time harder. Only downside is you have to manually install the anticaptcha extension.

- languages -&gt; List of supported languages. Required for agent routing system. The longer the languages list the more model will be downloaded.

## Providers

The table below show the available providers:

| Provider  | Local? | Description                                               |
|-----------|--------|-----------------------------------------------------------|
| ollama    | Yes    | Run LLMs locally with ease using ollama as a LLM provider |
| server    | Yes    | Host the model on another machine, run your local machine |
| lm-studio  | Yes    | Run LLM locally with LM studio (`lm-studio`)             |
| openai    | Depends  | Use ChatGPT API (non-private) or openai compatible API  |
| deepseek-api  | No     | Deepseek API (non-private)                            |
| huggingface| No    | Hugging-Face API (non-private)                            |
| togetherAI | No    | Use together AI API (non-private)                         |
| google | No    | Use google gemini API (non-private)                         |

To select a provider change the config.ini:

```
is_local = True
provider_name = ollama
provider_model = deepseek-r1:32b
provider_server_address = 127.0.0.1:5000
```
`is_local`: should be True for any locally running LLM, otherwise False.

`provider_name`: Select the provider to use by it&#039;s name, see the provider list above.

`provider_model`: Set the model to use by the agent.

`provider_server_address`: can be set to anything if you are not using the server provider.

# Known issues

## Chromedriver Issues

**Known error #1:** *chromedriver mismatch*

`Exception: Failed to initialize browser: Message: session not created: This version of ChromeDriver only supports Chrome version 113
Current browser version is 134.0.6998.89 with binary path`

This happen if there is a mismatch between your browser and chromedriver version.

You need to navigate to download the latest version:

https://developer.chrome.com/docs/chromedriver/downloads

If you&#039;re using Chrome version 115 or newer go to:

https://googlechromelabs.github.io/chrome-for-testing/

And download the chromedriver version matching your OS.

![alt text](./media/chromedriver_readme.png)

If this section is incomplete please raise an issue.

##  connection adapters Issues

```
Exception: Provider lm-studio failed: HTTP request failed: No connection adapters were found for &#039;127.0.0.1:11434/v1/chat/completions&#039;
```

Make sure you have `http://` in front of the provider IP address :

`provider_server_address = http://127.0.0.1:11434`

## SearxNG base URL must be provided

```
raise ValueError(&quot;SearxNG base URL must be provided either as an argument or via the SEARXNG_BASE_URL environment variable.&quot;)
ValueError: SearxNG base URL must be provided either as an argument or via the SEARXNG_BASE_URL environment variable.
```

Maybe you didn&#039;t move `.env.example` as `.env` ? You can also export SEARXNG_BASE_URL:

`export  SEARXNG_BASE_URL=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:8080&quot;`

## FAQ

**Q: What hardware do I need?**  

| Model Size  | GPU  | Comment                                               |
|-----------|--------|-----------------------------------------------------------|
| 7B        | 8GB Vram | ⚠️ Not recommended. Performance is poor, frequent hallucinations, and planner agents will likely fail. |
| 14B        | 12 GB VRAM (e.g. RTX 3060) | ✅ Usable for simple tasks. May struggle with web browsing and planning tasks. |
| 32B        | 24+ GB VRAM (e.g. RTX 4090) | 🚀 Success with most tasks, might still struggle with task planning |
| 70B+        | 48+ GB Vram (eg. mac studio) | 💪 Excellent. Recommended for advanced use cases. |

**Q: Why Deepseek R1 over other models?**  

Deepseek R1 excels at reasoning and tool use for its size. We think it’s a solid fit for our needs other models work fine, but Deepseek is our primary pick.

**Q: I get an error running `cli.py`. What do I do?**  

Ensure local is running (`ollama serve`), your `config.ini` matches your provider, and dependencies are installed. If none work feel free to raise an issue.

**Q: Can it really run 100% locally?**  

Yes with Ollama, lm-studio or server providers, all speech to text, LLM and text to speech model run locally. Non-local options (OpenAI or others API) are optional.

**Q: Why should I use AgenticSeek when I have Manus?**

This started as Side-Project we did out of interest about AI agents. What’s special about it is that we want to use local model and avoid APIs.
We draw inspiration from Jarvis and Friday (Iron man movies) to make it &quot;cool&quot; but

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mindsdb/mindsdb]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[AI's query engine - Platform for building AI that can answer questions over large scale federated data. - The only MCP Server you'll ever need]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb">mindsdb/mindsdb</a></h1>
            <p>AI's query engine - Platform for building AI that can answer questions over large scale federated data. - The only MCP Server you'll ever need</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 29,706</p>
            <p>Forks: 5,095</p>
            <p>Stars today: 420 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>

&lt;a name=&quot;readme-top&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/MindsDB/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/py/MindsDB.svg&quot; alt=&quot;MindsDB Release&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.10.x%7C%203.11.x-brightgreen.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Python supported&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://ossrank.com/p/630&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shields.io/endpoint?url=https://ossrank.com/shield/630&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;PyPI - Downloads&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/dm/Mindsdb&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/u/mindsdb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/mindsdb/mindsdb&quot; alt=&quot;Docker pulls&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;

  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/docs/assets/mindsdb_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;MindsDB&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindsdb.com?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.mindsdb.com?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://mdb.ai/register&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://mindsdb.com/joincommunity?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo&quot;&gt;Community Slack&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

----------------------------------------


MindsDB enables humans, AI, agents, and applications to get highly accurate answers across sprawled and large scale data sources.

&lt;img width=&quot;1454&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/87930824-2624-4c71-ac08-475e12e5475f&quot; /&gt;

[MindsDB has an MCP server built in](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mcp/overview) that enables your MCP applications to connect, unify and respond to questions over large-scale federated data—spanning databases, data warehouses, and SaaS applications.

## Minds [Demo](https://mdb.ai/register)
Play with [Minds demo](https://mdb.ai/register), and see the power of MindsDB at answering questions from structured to unstructured data, whether it&#039;s scattered across SaaS applications, databases, or... hibernating in data warehouses like that $100 bill in your tuxedo pocket from prom night, lost, waiting to be discovered.
 
## Install MindsDB Server 

MindsDB is an open-source server that can be deployed anywhere - from your laptop to the cloud, and everywhere in between. And yes, you can customize it to your heart&#039;s content.

  * [Using Docker Desktop](https://docs.mindsdb.com/setup/self-hosted/docker-desktop). This is the fastest and recommended way to get started and have it all running.
  * [Using Docker](https://docs.mindsdb.com/setup/self-hosted/docker). This is also simple, but gives you more flexibility on how to further customize your server.
  * [Using PyPI](https://docs.mindsdb.com/contribute/install). This option enables you to contribute to MindsDB.

----------------------------------------

# Core Philosophy: Connect, Unify, Respond

MindsDB&#039;s architecture is built around three fundamental capabilities:

## [Connect](https://docs.mindsdb.com/integrations/data-overview) Your Data

You can connect to hundreds of enterprise [data sources (learn more)](https://docs.mindsdb.com/integrations/data-overview). These integrations allow MindsDB to access data wherever it resides, forming the foundation for all other capabilities.

## [Unify](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/overview) Your Data

Once connected, these data sources can be queried using a full SQL dialect, as if they were all part of a single database. MindsDB’s federated query engine translates your SQL queries and executes them on the appropriate connected data sources.

When working with many data sources, it’s important to prepare and unify your data before generating responses from it. MindsDB SQL offers virtual tables (views, knowledge bases, ml-models) to allow working with heterogeneous data as if it were unified in a single organized system.

* [**VIEWS**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/sql/create/view) – Simplify data access by creating unified views across different sources (no-ETL).
* [**KNOWLEDGE BASES**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/knowledge-bases) – Index and organize unstructured data for efficient retrieval.
* [**ML MODELS**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/sql/create/model) – Apply AI/ML transformations to gain insights from your data.

Unification of data can be automated using JOBs

* [**JOBS**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/sql/create/jobs) – Schedule synchronization and transformation tasks for real-time processing.


## [Respond](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/agents/agent) From Your Data

Chat with Your Data

* [**AGENTS**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mindsdb_sql/agents/agent) – Configure built-in agents specialized in answering questions over your connected and unified data.
* [**MCP**](https://docs.mindsdb.com/mcp/overview) – Connect to MindsDB through the MCP (Model Context Protocol) for seamless interaction.

----------------------------------------

## 🤝 Contribute

Interested in contributing to MindsDB? Follow our [installation guide for development](https://docs.mindsdb.com/contribute/install?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo).

You can find our [contribution guide here](https://docs.mindsdb.com/contribute/contribute?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo).

We welcome suggestions! Feel free to open new issues with your ideas, and we’ll guide you.

This project adheres to a [Contributor Code of Conduct](https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/blob/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md). By participating, you agree to follow its terms.

Also, check out our [community rewards and programs](https://mindsdb.com/community?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo).

## 🤍 Support

If you find a bug, please submit an [issue on GitHub](https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/issues/new/choose).

Here’s how you can get community support:

* Ask a question in our [Slack Community](https://mindsdb.com/joincommunity?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo).
* Join our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/discussions).
* Post on [Stack Overflow](https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/mindsdb) with the MindsDB tag.

For commercial support, please [contact the MindsDB team](https://mindsdb.com/contact?utm_medium=community&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_campaign=mindsdb%20repo).

## 💚 Current Contributors

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=mindsdb/mindsdb&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Generated with [contributors-img](https://contributors-img.web.app).

## 🔔 Subscribe for Updates

Join our [Slack community](https://mindsdb.com/joincommunity)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[microsoft/qlib]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/microsoft/qlib</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/microsoft/qlib</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Qlib is an AI-oriented quantitative investment platform that aims to realize the potential, empower research, and create value using AI technologies in quantitative investment, from exploring ideas to implementing productions. Qlib supports diverse machine learning modeling paradigms. including supervised learning, market dynamics modeling, and RL.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/qlib">microsoft/qlib</a></h1>
            <p>Qlib is an AI-oriented quantitative investment platform that aims to realize the potential, empower research, and create value using AI technologies in quantitative investment, from exploring ideas to implementing productions. Qlib supports diverse machine learning modeling paradigms. including supervised learning, market dynamics modeling, and RL.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 21,275</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,386</p>
            <p>Stars today: 570 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Python Versions](https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/pyqlib.svg?logo=python&amp;logoColor=white)](https://pypi.org/project/pyqlib/#files)
[![Platform](https://img.shields.io/badge/platform-linux%20%7C%20windows%20%7C%20macos-lightgrey)](https://pypi.org/project/pyqlib/#files)
[![PypI Versions](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/pyqlib)](https://pypi.org/project/pyqlib/#history)
[![Upload Python Package](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/workflows/Upload%20Python%20Package/badge.svg)](https://pypi.org/project/pyqlib/)
[![Github Actions Test Status](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/workflows/Test/badge.svg?branch=main)](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/actions)
[![Documentation Status](https://readthedocs.org/projects/qlib/badge/?version=latest)](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/?badge=latest)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/pyqlib)](LICENSE)
[![Join the chat at https://gitter.im/Microsoft/qlib](https://badges.gitter.im/Microsoft/qlib.svg)](https://gitter.im/Microsoft/qlib?utm_source=badge&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;utm_content=badge)

## :newspaper: **What&#039;s NEW!** &amp;nbsp;   :sparkling_heart: 

Recent released features

### Introducing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/RD-Agent&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;docs/_static/img/rdagent_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;RD_Agent&quot; style=&quot;height: 2em&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: LLM-Based Autonomous Evolving Agents for Industrial Data-Driven R&amp;D

We are excited to announce the release of **RD-Agent**📢, a powerful tool that supports automated factor mining and model optimization in quant investment R&amp;D.

RD-Agent is now available on [GitHub](https://github.com/microsoft/RD-Agent), and we welcome your star🌟!

To learn more, please visit our [♾️Demo page](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/). Here, you will find demo videos in both English and Chinese to help you better understand the scenario and usage of RD-Agent.

We have prepared several demo videos for you:
| Scenario | Demo video (English) | Demo video (中文) |
| --                      | ------    | ------    |
| Quant Factor Mining | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/factor_loop?lang=en) | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/factor_loop?lang=zh) |
| Quant Factor Mining from reports | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/report_factor?lang=en) | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/report_factor?lang=zh) |
| Quant Model Optimization | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/model_loop?lang=en) | [Link](https://rdagent.azurewebsites.net/model_loop?lang=zh) |

- [R&amp;D-Agent-Quant: A Multi-Agent Framework for Data-Centric Factors and Model Joint Optimization](https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.15155)
```BibTeX
@misc{li2025rdagentquant,
    title={R\&amp;D-Agent-Quant: A Multi-Agent Framework for Data-Centric Factors and Model Joint Optimization},
    author={Yuante Li and Xu Yang and Xiao Yang and Minrui Xu and Xisen Wang and Weiqing Liu and Jiang Bian},
    year={2025},
    eprint={2505.15155},
    archivePrefix={arXiv},
    primaryClass={cs.AI}
}
```
![image](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3198bc10-47ba-4ee0-8a8e-46d5ce44f45d)

***

| Feature | Status |
| --                      | ------    |
| [R&amp;D-Agent-Quant](https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.15155) Published | Apply R&amp;D-Agent to Qlib for quant trading | 
| BPQP for End-to-end learning | 📈Coming soon!([Under review](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1863)) |
| 🔥LLM-driven Auto Quant Factory🔥 | 🚀 Released in [♾️RD-Agent](https://github.com/microsoft/RD-Agent) on Aug 8, 2024 |
| KRNN and Sandwich models | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1414/) on May 26, 2023 |
| Release Qlib v0.9.0 | :octocat: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/releases/tag/v0.9.0) on Dec 9, 2022 |
| RL Learning Framework | :hammer: :chart_with_upwards_trend: Released on Nov 10, 2022. [#1332](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1332), [#1322](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1322), [#1316](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1316),[#1299](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1299),[#1263](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1263), [#1244](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1244), [#1169](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1169), [#1125](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1125), [#1076](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1076)|
| HIST and IGMTF models | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1040) on Apr 10, 2022 |
| Qlib [notebook tutorial](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/tree/main/examples/tutorial) | 📖 [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/1037) on Apr 7, 2022 | 
| Ibovespa index data | :rice: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/990) on Apr 6, 2022 |
| Point-in-Time database | :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/343) on Mar 10, 2022 |
| Arctic Provider Backend &amp; Orderbook data example | :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/744) on Jan 17, 2022 |
| Meta-Learning-based framework &amp; DDG-DA  | :chart_with_upwards_trend:  :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/743) on Jan 10, 2022 | 
| Planning-based portfolio optimization | :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/754) on Dec 28, 2021 | 
| Release Qlib v0.8.0 | :octocat: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/releases/tag/v0.8.0) on Dec 8, 2021 |
| ADD model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/704) on Nov 22, 2021 |
| ADARNN  model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/689) on Nov 14, 2021 |
| TCN  model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/668) on Nov 4, 2021 |
| Nested Decision Framework | :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/438) on Oct 1, 2021. [Example](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/blob/main/examples/nested_decision_execution/workflow.py) and [Doc](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/highfreq.html) |
| Temporal Routing Adaptor (TRA) | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/531) on July 30, 2021 |
| Transformer &amp; Localformer | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/508) on July 22, 2021 |
| Release Qlib v0.7.0 | :octocat: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/releases/tag/v0.7.0) on July 12, 2021 |
| TCTS Model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/491) on July 1, 2021 |
| Online serving and automatic model rolling | :hammer:  [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/290) on May 17, 2021 | 
| DoubleEnsemble Model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/286) on Mar 2, 2021 | 
| High-frequency data processing example | :hammer: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/257) on Feb 5, 2021  |
| High-frequency trading example | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Part of code released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/227) on Jan 28, 2021  | 
| High-frequency data(1min) | :rice: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/221) on Jan 27, 2021 |
| Tabnet Model | :chart_with_upwards_trend: [Released](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/pull/205) on Jan 22, 2021 |

Features released before 2021 are not listed here.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;docs/_static/img/logo/1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

Qlib is an open-source, AI-oriented quantitative investment platform that aims to realize the potential, empower research, and create value using AI technologies in quantitative investment, from exploring ideas to implementing productions. Qlib supports diverse machine learning modeling paradigms, including supervised learning, market dynamics modeling, and reinforcement learning.

An increasing number of SOTA Quant research works/papers in diverse paradigms are being released in Qlib to collaboratively solve key challenges in quantitative investment. For example, 1) using supervised learning to mine the market&#039;s complex non-linear patterns from rich and heterogeneous financial data, 2) modeling the dynamic nature of the financial market using adaptive concept drift technology, and 3) using reinforcement learning to model continuous investment decisions and assist investors in optimizing their trading strategies.

It contains the full ML pipeline of data processing, model training, back-testing; and covers the entire chain of quantitative investment: alpha seeking, risk modeling, portfolio optimization, and order execution. 
For more details, please refer to our paper [&quot;Qlib: An AI-oriented Quantitative Investment Platform&quot;](https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.11189).


&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Frameworks, Tutorial, Data &amp; DevOps&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Main Challenges &amp; Solutions in Quant Research&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#plans&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#framework-of-qlib&quot;&gt;Framework of Qlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#quick-start&quot;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;ul dir=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;
            &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#data-preparation&quot;&gt;Data Preparation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#auto-quant-research-workflow&quot;&gt;Auto Quant Research Workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#building-customized-quant-research-workflow-by-code&quot;&gt;Building Customized Quant Research Workflow by Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#quant-dataset-zoo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quant Dataset Zoo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#learning-framework&quot;&gt;Learning Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#more-about-qlib&quot;&gt;More About Qlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#offline-mode-and-online-mode&quot;&gt;Offline Mode and Online Mode&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#performance-of-qlib-data-server&quot;&gt;Performance of Qlib Data Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#related-reports&quot;&gt;Related Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#contact-us&quot;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#contributing&quot;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td valign=&quot;baseline&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#main-challenges--solutions-in-quant-research&quot;&gt;Main Challenges &amp;amp; Solutions in Quant Research&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#forecasting-finding-valuable-signalspatterns&quot;&gt;Forecasting: Finding Valuable Signals/Patterns&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#quant-model-paper-zoo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quant Model (Paper) Zoo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                  &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#run-a-single-model&quot;&gt;Run a Single Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#run-multiple-models&quot;&gt;Run Multiple Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;/ul&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#adapting-to-market-dynamics&quot;&gt;Adapting to Market Dynamics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li type=&quot;circle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#reinforcement-learning-modeling-continuous-decisions&quot;&gt;Reinforcement Learning: modeling continuous decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

# Plans
New features under development(order by estimated release time).
Your feedbacks about the features are very important.
&lt;!-- | Feature                        | Status      | --&gt;
&lt;!-- | --                      | ------    | --&gt;

# Framework of Qlib

&lt;div style=&quot;align: center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;docs/_static/img/framework-abstract.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

The high-level framework of Qlib can be found above(users can find the [detailed framework](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/introduction/introduction.html#framework) of Qlib&#039;s design when getting into nitty gritty).
The components are designed as loose-coupled modules, and each component could be used stand-alone.

Qlib provides a strong infrastructure to support Quant research. [Data](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/data.html) is always an important part.
A strong learning framework is designed to support diverse learning paradigms (e.g. [reinforcement learning](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/rl.html), [supervised learning](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/workflow.html#model-section)) and patterns at different levels(e.g. [market dynamic modeling](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/meta.html)).
By modeling the market, [trading strategies](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/strategy.html) will generate trade decisions that will be executed. Multiple trading strategies and executors in different levels or granularities can be [nested to be optimized and run together](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/highfreq.html).
At last, a comprehensive [analysis](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/report.html) will be provided and the model can be [served online](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/online.html) in a low cost.


# Quick Start

This quick start guide tries to demonstrate
1. It&#039;s very easy to build a complete Quant research workflow and try your ideas with _Qlib_.
2. Though with *public data* and *simple models*, machine learning technologies **work very well** in practical Quant investment.

Here is a quick **[demo](https://terminalizer.com/view/3f24561a4470)** shows how to install ``Qlib``, and run LightGBM with ``qrun``. **But**, please make sure you have already prepared the data following the [instruction](#data-preparation).


## Installation

This table demonstrates the supported Python version of `Qlib`:
|               | install with pip      | install from source  |        plot        |
| ------------- |:---------------------:|:--------------------:|:------------------:|
| Python 3.8    | :heavy_check_mark:    | :heavy_check_mark:   | :heavy_check_mark: |
| Python 3.9    | :heavy_check_mark:    | :heavy_check_mark:   | :heavy_check_mark: |
| Python 3.10   | :heavy_check_mark:    | :heavy_check_mark:   | :heavy_check_mark: |
| Python 3.11   | :heavy_check_mark:    | :heavy_check_mark:   | :heavy_check_mark: |
| Python 3.12   | :heavy_check_mark:    | :heavy_check_mark:   | :heavy_check_mark: |

**Note**: 
1. **Conda** is suggested for managing your Python environment. In some cases, using Python outside of a `conda` environment may result in missing header files, causing the installation failure of certain packages.
2. Please pay attention that installing cython in Python 3.6 will raise some error when installing ``Qlib`` from source. If users use Python 3.6 on their machines, it is recommended to *upgrade* Python to version 3.8 or higher, or use `conda`&#039;s Python to install ``Qlib`` from source.

### Install with pip
Users can easily install ``Qlib`` by pip according to the following command.

```bash
  pip install pyqlib
```

**Note**: pip will install the latest stable qlib. However, the main branch of qlib is in active development. If you want to test the latest scripts or functions in the main branch. Please install qlib with the methods below.

### Install from source
Also, users can install the latest dev version ``Qlib`` by the source code according to the following steps:

* Before installing ``Qlib`` from source, users need to install some dependencies:

  ```bash
  pip install numpy
  pip install --upgrade cython
  ```

* Clone the repository and install ``Qlib`` as follows.
    ```bash
    git clone https://github.com/microsoft/qlib.git &amp;&amp; cd qlib
    pip install .  # `pip install -e .[dev]` is recommended for development. check details in docs/developer/code_standard_and_dev_guide.rst
    ```

**Tips**: If you fail to install `Qlib` or run the examples in your environment,  comparing your steps and the [CI workflow](.github/workflows/test_qlib_from_source.yml) may help you find the problem.

**Tips for Mac**: If you are using Mac with M1, you might encounter issues in building the wheel for LightGBM, which is due to missing dependencies from OpenMP. To solve the problem, install openmp first with ``brew install libomp`` and then run ``pip install .`` to build it successfully. 

## Data Preparation
❗ Due to more restrict data security policy. The offical dataset is disabled temporarily. You can try [this data source](https://github.com/chenditc/investment_data/releases) contributed by the community.
Here is an example to download the latest data.
```bash
wget https://github.com/chenditc/investment_data/releases/latest/download/qlib_bin.tar.gz
mkdir -p ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data
tar -zxvf qlib_bin.tar.gz -C ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data --strip-components=1
rm -f qlib_bin.tar.gz
```

The official dataset below will resume in short future.


----

Load and prepare data by running the following code:

### Get with module
  ```bash
  # get 1d data
  python -m qlib.run.get_data qlib_data --target_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data --region cn

  # get 1min data
  python -m qlib.run.get_data qlib_data --target_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data_1min --region cn --interval 1min

  ```

### Get from source

  ```bash
  # get 1d data
  python scripts/get_data.py qlib_data --target_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data --region cn

  # get 1min data
  python scripts/get_data.py qlib_data --target_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data_1min --region cn --interval 1min

  ```

This dataset is created by public data collected by [crawler scripts](scripts/data_collector/), which have been released in
the same repository.
Users could create the same dataset with it. [Description of dataset](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/tree/main/scripts/data_collector#description-of-dataset)

*Please pay **ATTENTION** that the data is collected from [Yahoo Finance](https://finance.yahoo.com/lookup), and the data might not be perfect.
We recommend users to prepare their own data if they have a high-quality dataset. For more information, users can refer to the [related document](https://qlib.readthedocs.io/en/latest/component/data.html#converting-csv-format-into-qlib-format)*.

### Automatic update of daily frequency data (from yahoo finance)
  &gt; This step is *Optional* if users only want to try their models and strategies on history data.
  &gt; 
  &gt; It is recommended that users update the data manually once (--trading_date 2021-05-25) and then set it to update automatically.
  &gt;
  &gt; **NOTE**: Users can&#039;t incrementally  update data based on the offline data provided by Qlib(some fields are removed to reduce the data size). Users should use [yahoo collector](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/tree/main/scripts/data_collector/yahoo#automatic-update-of-daily-frequency-datafrom-yahoo-finance) to download Yahoo data from scratch and then incrementally update it.
  &gt; 
  &gt; For more information, please refer to: [yahoo collector](https://github.com/microsoft/qlib/tree/main/scripts/data_collector/yahoo#automatic-update-of-daily-frequency-datafrom-yahoo-finance)

  * Automatic update of data to the &quot;qlib&quot; directory each trading day(Linux)
      * use *crontab*: `crontab -e`
      * set up timed tasks:

        ```
        * * * * 1-5 python &lt;script path&gt; update_data_to_bin --qlib_data_1d_dir &lt;user data dir&gt;
        ```
        * **script path**: *scripts/data_collector/yahoo/collector.py*

  * Manual update of data
      ```
      python scripts/data_collector/yahoo/collector.py update_data_to_bin --qlib_data_1d_dir &lt;user data dir&gt; --trading_date &lt;start date&gt; --end_date &lt;end date&gt;
      ```
      * *trading_date*: start of trading day
      * *end_date*: end of trading day(not included)

### Checking the health of the data
  * We provide a script to check the health of the data, you can run the following commands to check whether the data is healthy or not.
    ```
    python scripts/check_data_health.py check_data --qlib_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data
    ```
  * Of course, you can also add some parameters to adjust the test results, such as this.
    ```
    python scripts/check_data_health.py check_data --qlib_dir ~/.qlib/qlib_data/cn_data --missing_data_num 30055 --large_step_threshold_volume 94

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[comfyanonymous/ComfyUI]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The most powerful and modular diffusion model GUI, api and backend with a graph/nodes interface.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI">comfyanonymous/ComfyUI</a></h1>
            <p>The most powerful and modular diffusion model GUI, api and backend with a graph/nodes interface.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 77,853</p>
            <p>Forks: 8,557</p>
            <p>Stars today: 105 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# ComfyUI
**The most powerful and modular visual AI engine and application.**


[![Website][website-shield]][website-url]
[![Dynamic JSON Badge][discord-shield]][discord-url]
[![Matrix][matrix-shield]][matrix-url]
&lt;br&gt;
[![][github-release-shield]][github-release-link]
[![][github-release-date-shield]][github-release-link]
[![][github-downloads-shield]][github-downloads-link]
[![][github-downloads-latest-shield]][github-downloads-link]

[matrix-shield]: https://img.shields.io/badge/Matrix-000000?style=flat&amp;logo=matrix&amp;logoColor=white
[matrix-url]: https://app.element.io/#/room/%23comfyui_space%3Amatrix.org
[website-shield]: https://img.shields.io/badge/ComfyOrg-4285F4?style=flat
[website-url]: https://www.comfy.org/
&lt;!-- Workaround to display total user from https://github.com/badges/shields/issues/4500#issuecomment-2060079995 --&gt;
[discord-shield]: https://img.shields.io/badge/dynamic/json?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdiscord.com%2Fapi%2Finvites%2Fcomfyorg%3Fwith_counts%3Dtrue&amp;query=%24.approximate_member_count&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;label=Discord&amp;color=green&amp;suffix=%20total
[discord-url]: https://www.comfy.org/discord

[github-release-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI?style=flat&amp;sort=semver
[github-release-link]: https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/releases
[github-release-date-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/release-date/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI?style=flat
[github-downloads-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/total?style=flat
[github-downloads-latest-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/latest/total?style=flat&amp;label=downloads%40latest
[github-downloads-link]: https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/releases

![ComfyUI Screenshot](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7ccaf2c1-9b72-41ae-9a89-5688c94b7abe)
&lt;/div&gt;

ComfyUI lets you design and execute advanced stable diffusion pipelines using a graph/nodes/flowchart based interface. Available on Windows, Linux, and macOS.

## Get Started

#### [Desktop Application](https://www.comfy.org/download)
- The easiest way to get started. 
- Available on Windows &amp; macOS.

#### [Windows Portable Package](#installing)
- Get the latest commits and completely portable.
- Available on Windows.

#### [Manual Install](#manual-install-windows-linux)
Supports all operating systems and GPU types (NVIDIA, AMD, Intel, Apple Silicon, Ascend).

## [Examples](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/)
See what ComfyUI can do with the [example workflows](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/).

## Features
- Nodes/graph/flowchart interface to experiment and create complex Stable Diffusion workflows without needing to code anything.
- Image Models
   - SD1.x, SD2.x,
   - [SDXL](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/sdxl/), [SDXL Turbo](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/sdturbo/)
   - [Stable Cascade](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/stable_cascade/)
   - [SD3 and SD3.5](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/sd3/)
   - Pixart Alpha and Sigma
   - [AuraFlow](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/aura_flow/)
   - [HunyuanDiT](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/hunyuan_dit/)
   - [Flux](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/flux/)
   - [Lumina Image 2.0](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/lumina2/)
   - [HiDream](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/hidream/)
- Video Models
   - [Stable Video Diffusion](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/video/)
   - [Mochi](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/mochi/)
   - [LTX-Video](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/ltxv/)
   - [Hunyuan Video](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/hunyuan_video/)
   - [Nvidia Cosmos](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/cosmos/)
   - [Wan 2.1](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/wan/)
- Audio Models
   - [Stable Audio](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/audio/)
   - [ACE Step](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/audio/)
- 3D Models
   - [Hunyuan3D 2.0](https://docs.comfy.org/tutorials/3d/hunyuan3D-2)
- Asynchronous Queue system
- Many optimizations: Only re-executes the parts of the workflow that changes between executions.
- Smart memory management: can automatically run models on GPUs with as low as 1GB vram.
- Works even if you don&#039;t have a GPU with: ```--cpu``` (slow)
- Can load ckpt, safetensors and diffusers models/checkpoints. Standalone VAEs and CLIP models.
- Embeddings/Textual inversion
- [Loras (regular, locon and loha)](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/lora/)
- [Hypernetworks](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/hypernetworks/)
- Loading full workflows (with seeds) from generated PNG, WebP and FLAC files.
- Saving/Loading workflows as Json files.
- Nodes interface can be used to create complex workflows like one for [Hires fix](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/2_pass_txt2img/) or much more advanced ones.
- [Area Composition](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/area_composition/)
- [Inpainting](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/inpaint/) with both regular and inpainting models.
- [ControlNet and T2I-Adapter](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/controlnet/)
- [Upscale Models (ESRGAN, ESRGAN variants, SwinIR, Swin2SR, etc...)](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/upscale_models/)
- [unCLIP Models](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/unclip/)
- [GLIGEN](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/gligen/)
- [Model Merging](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/model_merging/)
- [LCM models and Loras](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/lcm/)
- Latent previews with [TAESD](#how-to-show-high-quality-previews)
- Starts up very fast.
- Works fully offline: will never download anything.
- [Config file](extra_model_paths.yaml.example) to set the search paths for models.

Workflow examples can be found on the [Examples page](https://comfyanonymous.github.io/ComfyUI_examples/)

## Release Process

ComfyUI follows a weekly release cycle every Friday, with three interconnected repositories:

1. **[ComfyUI Core](https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI)**
   - Releases a new stable version (e.g., v0.7.0)
   - Serves as the foundation for the desktop release

2. **[ComfyUI Desktop](https://github.com/Comfy-Org/desktop)**
   - Builds a new release using the latest stable core version

3. **[ComfyUI Frontend](https://github.com/Comfy-Org/ComfyUI_frontend)**
   - Weekly frontend updates are merged into the core repository
   - Features are frozen for the upcoming core release
   - Development continues for the next release cycle

## Shortcuts

| Keybind                            | Explanation                                                                                                        |
|------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| `Ctrl` + `Enter`                      | Queue up current graph for generation                                                                              |
| `Ctrl` + `Shift` + `Enter`              | Queue up current graph as first for generation                                                                     |
| `Ctrl` + `Alt` + `Enter`                | Cancel current generation                                                                                          |
| `Ctrl` + `Z`/`Ctrl` + `Y`                 | Undo/Redo                                                                                                          |
| `Ctrl` + `S`                          | Save workflow                                                                                                      |
| `Ctrl` + `O`                          | Load workflow                                                                                                      |
| `Ctrl` + `A`                          | Select all nodes                                                                                                   |
| `Alt `+ `C`                           | Collapse/uncollapse selected nodes                                                                                 |
| `Ctrl` + `M`                          | Mute/unmute selected nodes                                                                                         |
| `Ctrl` + `B`                           | Bypass selected nodes (acts like the node was removed from the graph and the wires reconnected through)            |
| `Delete`/`Backspace`                   | Delete selected nodes                                                                                              |
| `Ctrl` + `Backspace`                   | Delete the current graph                                                                                           |
| `Space`                              | Move the canvas around when held and moving the cursor                                                             |
| `Ctrl`/`Shift` + `Click`                 | Add clicked node to selection                                                                                      |
| `Ctrl` + `C`/`Ctrl` + `V`                  | Copy and paste selected nodes (without maintaining connections to outputs of unselected nodes)                     |
| `Ctrl` + `C`/`Ctrl` + `Shift` + `V`          | Copy and paste selected nodes (maintaining connections from outputs of unselected nodes to inputs of pasted nodes) |
| `Shift` + `Drag`                       | Move multiple selected nodes at the same time                                                                      |
| `Ctrl` + `D`                           | Load default graph                                                                                                 |
| `Alt` + `+`                          | Canvas Zoom in                                                                                                     |
| `Alt` + `-`                          | Canvas Zoom out                                                                                                    |
| `Ctrl` + `Shift` + LMB + Vertical drag | Canvas Zoom in/out                                                                                                 |
| `P`                                  | Pin/Unpin selected nodes                                                                                           |
| `Ctrl` + `G`                           | Group selected nodes                                                                                               |
| `Q`                                 | Toggle visibility of the queue                                                                                     |
| `H`                                  | Toggle visibility of history                                                                                       |
| `R`                                  | Refresh graph                                                                                                      |
| `F`                                  | Show/Hide menu                                                                                                      |
| `.`                                  | Fit view to selection (Whole graph when nothing is selected)                                                        |
| Double-Click LMB                   | Open node quick search palette                                                                                     |
| `Shift` + Drag                       | Move multiple wires at once                                                                                        |
| `Ctrl` + `Alt` + LMB                   | Disconnect all wires from clicked slot                                                                             |

`Ctrl` can also be replaced with `Cmd` instead for macOS users

# Installing

## Windows Portable

There is a portable standalone build for Windows that should work for running on Nvidia GPUs or for running on your CPU only on the [releases page](https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/releases).

### [Direct link to download](https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/releases/latest/download/ComfyUI_windows_portable_nvidia.7z)

Simply download, extract with [7-Zip](https://7-zip.org) and run. Make sure you put your Stable Diffusion checkpoints/models (the huge ckpt/safetensors files) in: ComfyUI\models\checkpoints

If you have trouble extracting it, right click the file -&gt; properties -&gt; unblock

#### How do I share models between another UI and ComfyUI?

See the [Config file](extra_model_paths.yaml.example) to set the search paths for models. In the standalone windows build you can find this file in the ComfyUI directory. Rename this file to extra_model_paths.yaml and edit it with your favorite text editor.

## Jupyter Notebook

To run it on services like paperspace, kaggle or colab you can use my [Jupyter Notebook](notebooks/comfyui_colab.ipynb)


## [comfy-cli](https://docs.comfy.org/comfy-cli/getting-started)

You can install and start ComfyUI using comfy-cli:
```bash
pip install comfy-cli
comfy install
```

## Manual Install (Windows, Linux)

python 3.13 is supported but using 3.12 is recommended because some custom nodes and their dependencies might not support it yet.

Git clone this repo.

Put your SD checkpoints (the huge ckpt/safetensors files) in: models/checkpoints

Put your VAE in: models/vae


### AMD GPUs (Linux only)
AMD users can install rocm and pytorch with pip if you don&#039;t have it already installed, this is the command to install the stable version:

```pip install torch torchvision torchaudio --index-url https://download.pytorch.org/whl/rocm6.3```

This is the command to install the nightly with ROCm 6.4 which might have some performance improvements:

```pip install --pre torch torchvision torchaudio --index-url https://download.pytorch.org/whl/nightly/rocm6.4```

### Intel GPUs (Windows and Linux)

(Option 1) Intel Arc GPU users can install native PyTorch with torch.xpu support using pip (currently available in PyTorch nightly builds). More information can be found [here](https://pytorch.org/docs/main/notes/get_start_xpu.html)
  
1. To install PyTorch nightly, use the following command:

```pip install --pre torch torchvision torchaudio --index-url https://download.pytorch.org/whl/nightly/xpu```

2. Launch ComfyUI by running `python main.py`


(Option 2) Alternatively, Intel GPUs supported by Intel Extension for PyTorch (IPEX) can leverage IPEX for improved performance.

1. For Intel® Arc™ A-Series Graphics utilizing IPEX, create a conda environment and use the commands below:

```
conda install libuv
pip install torch==2.3.1.post0+cxx11.abi torchvision==0.18.1.post0+cxx11.abi torchaudio==2.3.1.post0+cxx11.abi intel-extension-for-pytorch==2.3.110.post0+xpu --extra-index-url https://pytorch-extension.intel.com/release-whl/stable/xpu/us/ --extra-index-url https://pytorch-extension.intel.com/release-whl/stable/xpu/cn/
```

For other supported Intel GPUs with IPEX, visit [Installation](https://intel.github.io/intel-extension-for-pytorch/index.html#installation?platform=gpu) for more information.

Additional discussion and help can be found [here](https://github.com/comfyanonymous/ComfyUI/discussions/476).

### NVIDIA

Nvidia users should install stable pytorch using this command:

```pip install torch torchvision torchaudio --extra-index-url https://download.pytorch.org/whl/cu128```

This is the command to install pytorch nightly instead which might have performance improvements.

```pip install --pre torch torchvision torchaudio --index-url https://download.pytorch.org/whl/nightly/cu128```

#### Troubleshooting

If you get the &quot;Torch not compiled with CUDA enabled&quot; error, uninstall torch with:

```pip uninstall torch```

And install it again with the command above.

### Dependencies

Install the dependencies by opening your terminal inside the ComfyUI folder and:

```pip install -r requirements.txt```

After this you should have everything installed and can proceed to running ComfyUI.

### Others:

#### Apple Mac silicon

You can install ComfyUI in Apple Mac silicon (M1 or M2) with any recent macOS version.

1. Install pytorch nightly. For instructions, read the [Accelerated PyTorch training on Mac](https://developer.apple.com/metal/pytorch/) Apple Developer guide (make sure to install the latest pytorch nightly).
1. Follow the [ComfyUI manual installation](#manual-install-windows-linux) instructions for Windows and Linux.
1. Install the ComfyUI [dependencies](#dependencies). If you have another Stable Diffusion UI [you might be able to reuse the dependencies](#i-already-have-another-ui-for-stable-diffusion-installed-do-i-really-have-to-install-all-of-these-dependencies).
1. Launch ComfyUI by running `python main.py`

&gt; **Note**: Remember to add your models, VAE, LoRAs etc. to the corresponding Comfy folders, as discussed in [ComfyUI manual installation](#manual-install-windows-linux).

#### DirectML (AMD Cards on Windows)

```pip install torch-directml``` Then you can launch ComfyUI with: ```python main.py --directml```

#### Ascend NPUs

For models compatible with Ascend Extension for PyTorch (torch_npu). To get started, ensure your environment meets the prerequisites outlined on the [installation](https://ascend.github.io/docs/sources/ascend/quick_install.html) page. Here&#039;s a step-by-step guide tailored to your platform and installation method:

1. Begin by installing the recommended or newer kernel version for Linux as specified in the Installation page of torch-npu, if necessary.
2. Proceed with the installation of Ascend Basekit, which includes the driver, firmware, and CANN, following the instructions provided for your specific platform.
3. Next, install the necessary packages for torch-npu by adhering to the platform-specific instructions on the [Installation](https://ascend.github.io/docs/sources/pytorch/install.html#pytorch) page.
4. Finally, adhere to the [ComfyUI manual installation](#manual-install-windows-linux) guide for Linux. Once all components are installed, you can run ComfyUI as described earlier.

#### Cambricon MLUs

For models compatible with Cambricon Extension for PyTorch (torch_mlu). Here&#039;s a step-by-step guide tailored to your platform and installation method:

1. Install the Cambricon CNToolkit by adhering to the platform-specific instructions on the [Installation](https://www.cambricon.com/docs/sdk_1.15.0/cntoolkit_3.7.2/cntoolkit_install_3.7.2/index.html)
2. Next, install the PyTorch(torch_mlu) following the instructions on the [Installation](https://www.cambricon.com/docs/sdk_1.15.0/cambricon_pytorch_1.17.0/user_guide_1.9/index.html)
3. Launch ComfyUI by running `python main.py`

# Running

```python main.py```

### For AMD cards not officially supported by ROCm

Try running it with this command if you have issues:

For 6700, 6600 and maybe other RDNA2 or older: ```HSA_OVERRIDE_GFX_VERSION=10.3.0 python main.py```

For AMD 7600 and maybe other RDNA3 cards: ```HSA_OVERRIDE_GFX_VERSION=11.0.0 python main.py```

### AMD ROCm Tips

You can enable experimental memory efficient attention on recent pytorch in ComfyUI on some AMD GPUs using this command, it should already be enabled by default on RDNA3. If this improves speed for you on latest pytorch on your GPU please report it so that I can enable it by default.

```TORCH_ROCM_AOTRITON_ENABLE_EXPERIMENTAL=1 python main.py --use-pytorch-cross-attention```

You can also try setting this env variable `PYTORCH_TUNABLEOP_ENABLED=1` which might speed things up at the cost of a very slow initial run.


... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ LLMs & VLMs (ACL 2024)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory">hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</a></h1>
            <p>Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ LLMs & VLMs (ACL 2024)</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 50,309</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,108</p>
            <p>Stars today: 480 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![# LLaMA Factory](assets/logo.png)

[![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory?style=social)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/stargazers)
[![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/commits/main)
[![GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory?color=orange)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/graphs/contributors)
[![GitHub workflow](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/actions/workflows/tests.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/actions/workflows/tests.yml)
[![PyPI](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/llamafactory)](https://pypi.org/project/llamafactory/)
[![Citation](https://img.shields.io/badge/citation-476-green)](https://scholar.google.com/scholar?cites=12620864006390196564)
[![GitHub pull request](https://img.shields.io/badge/PRs-welcome-blue)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pulls)

[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/llamafactory_ai)](https://twitter.com/llamafactory_ai)
[![Discord](https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/rKfvV9r9FK?compact=true&amp;style=flat)](https://discord.gg/rKfvV9r9FK)
[![GitCode](https://gitcode.com/zhengyaowei/LLaMA-Factory/star/badge.svg)](https://gitcode.com/zhengyaowei/LLaMA-Factory)

[![Open in Colab](https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg)](https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing)
[![Open in DSW](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/assets/open-in-dsw.svg)](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory)
[![Spaces](https://img.shields.io/badge/🤗-Open%20in%20Spaces-blue)](https://huggingface.co/spaces/hiyouga/LLaMA-Board)
[![Studios](https://img.shields.io/badge/ModelScope-Open%20in%20Studios-blue)](https://modelscope.cn/studios/hiyouga/LLaMA-Board)
[![SageMaker](https://img.shields.io/badge/SageMaker-Open%20in%20AWS-blue)](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/)

### Used by [Amazon](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/), [NVIDIA](https://developer.nvidia.com/rtx/ai-toolkit), [Aliyun](https://help.aliyun.com/zh/pai/use-cases/fine-tune-a-llama-3-model-with-llama-factory), etc.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; markdown=&quot;1&quot;&gt;

### Supporters ❤️

&lt;a href=&quot;https://warp.dev/llama-factory&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Warp sponsorship&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ab8dd143-b0fd-4904-bdc5-dd7ecac94eae&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

#### [Warp, the agentic terminal for developers](https://warp.dev/llama-factory)

[Available for MacOS, Linux, &amp; Windows](https://warp.dev/llama-factory)

----

### Easily fine-tune 100+ large language models with zero-code [CLI](#quickstart) and [Web UI](#fine-tuning-with-llama-board-gui-powered-by-gradio)

![GitHub Trend](https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/4535)

&lt;/div&gt;

👋 Join our [WeChat](assets/wechat.jpg) or [NPU user group](assets/wechat_npu.jpg).

\[ English | [中文](README_zh.md) \]

**Fine-tuning a large language model can be easy as...**

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3991a3a8-4276-4d30-9cab-4cb0c4b9b99e

Choose your path:

- **Documentation**: https://llamafactory.readthedocs.io/en/latest/
- **Colab (free)**: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing
- **Local machine**: Please refer to [usage](#getting-started)
- **PAI-DSW (free trial)**: https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Except for the above links, all other websites are unauthorized third-party websites. Please carefully use them.

## Table of Contents

- [Features](#features)
- [Blogs](#blogs)
- [Changelog](#changelog)
- [Supported Models](#supported-models)
- [Supported Training Approaches](#supported-training-approaches)
- [Provided Datasets](#provided-datasets)
- [Requirement](#requirement)
- [Getting Started](#getting-started)
  - [Installation](#installation)
  - [Data Preparation](#data-preparation)
  - [Quickstart](#quickstart)
  - [Fine-Tuning with LLaMA Board GUI](#fine-tuning-with-llama-board-gui-powered-by-gradio)
  - [Build Docker](#build-docker)
  - [Deploy with OpenAI-style API and vLLM](#deploy-with-openai-style-api-and-vllm)
  - [Download from ModelScope Hub](#download-from-modelscope-hub)
  - [Download from Modelers Hub](#download-from-modelers-hub)
  - [Use W&amp;B Logger](#use-wb-logger)
  - [Use SwanLab Logger](#use-swanlab-logger)
- [Projects using LLaMA Factory](#projects-using-llama-factory)
- [License](#license)
- [Citation](#citation)
- [Acknowledgement](#acknowledgement)

## Features

- **Various models**: LLaMA, LLaVA, Mistral, Mixtral-MoE, Qwen, Qwen2-VL, DeepSeek, Yi, Gemma, ChatGLM, Phi, etc.
- **Integrated methods**: (Continuous) pre-training, (multimodal) supervised fine-tuning, reward modeling, PPO, DPO, KTO, ORPO, etc.
- **Scalable resources**: 16-bit full-tuning, freeze-tuning, LoRA and 2/3/4/5/6/8-bit QLoRA via AQLM/AWQ/GPTQ/LLM.int8/HQQ/EETQ.
- **Advanced algorithms**: [GaLore](https://github.com/jiaweizzhao/GaLore), [BAdam](https://github.com/Ledzy/BAdam), [APOLLO](https://github.com/zhuhanqing/APOLLO), [Adam-mini](https://github.com/zyushun/Adam-mini), [Muon](https://github.com/KellerJordan/Muon), DoRA, LongLoRA, LLaMA Pro, Mixture-of-Depths, LoRA+, LoftQ and PiSSA.
- **Practical tricks**: [FlashAttention-2](https://github.com/Dao-AILab/flash-attention), [Unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth), [Liger Kernel](https://github.com/linkedin/Liger-Kernel), RoPE scaling, NEFTune and rsLoRA.
- **Wide tasks**: Multi-turn dialogue, tool using, image understanding, visual grounding, video recognition, audio understanding, etc.
- **Experiment monitors**: LlamaBoard, TensorBoard, Wandb, MLflow, [SwanLab](https://github.com/SwanHubX/SwanLab), etc.
- **Faster inference**: OpenAI-style API, Gradio UI and CLI with [vLLM worker](https://github.com/vllm-project/vllm) or [SGLang worker](https://github.com/sgl-project/sglang).

### Day-N Support for Fine-Tuning Cutting-Edge Models

| Support Date | Model Name                                                   |
| ------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Day 0        | Qwen3 / Qwen2.5-VL / Gemma 3 / InternLM 3 / MiniCPM-o-2.6    |
| Day 1        | Llama 3 / GLM-4 / Mistral Small / PaliGemma2 / Llama 4       |

## Blogs

- [How Apoidea Group enhances visual information extraction from banking documents with multimodal models using LLaMA-Factory on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/) (English)
- [Easy Dataset × LLaMA Factory: Enabling LLMs to Efficiently Learn Domain Knowledge](https://buaa-act.feishu.cn/wiki/GVzlwYcRFiR8OLkHbL6cQpYin7g) (English)
- [LLaMA Factory: Fine-tuning the DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-7B Model for News Classifier](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory_deepseek_r1_distill_7b) (Chinese)

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;All Blogs&lt;/summary&gt;

- [A One-Stop Code-Free Model Fine-Tuning \&amp; Deployment Platform based on SageMaker and LLaMA-Factory](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/china/a-one-stop-code-free-model-fine-tuning-deployment-platform-based-on-sagemaker-and-llama-factory/) (Chinese)
- [LLaMA Factory Multi-Modal Fine-Tuning Practice: Fine-Tuning Qwen2-VL for Personal Tourist Guide](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory_qwen2vl) (Chinese)
- [LLaMA Factory: Fine-tuning the LLaMA3 Model for Role-Playing](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory) (Chinese)

&lt;/details&gt;

## Changelog

[25/04/28] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen3](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen3/)** model family.

[25/04/21] We supported the **[Muon](https://github.com/KellerJordan/Muon)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage. Thank [@tianshijing](https://github.com/tianshijing)&#039;s PR.

[25/04/16] We supported fine-tuning the **[InternVL3](https://huggingface.co/OpenGVLab/InternVL3-8B)** model. See [PR #7258](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7258) to get started.

[25/04/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[GLM-Z1](https://huggingface.co/THUDM/GLM-Z1-9B-0414)** and **[Kimi-VL](https://huggingface.co/moonshotai/Kimi-VL-A3B-Instruct)** models.

[25/04/06] We supported fine-tuning the **[Llama 4](https://ai.meta.com/blog/llama-4-multimodal-intelligence/)** model. See [PR #7611](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7611) to get started.

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/summary&gt;

[25/03/31] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2.5 Omni](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2.5-omni/)** model. See [PR #7537](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7537) to get started.

[25/03/15] We supported **[SGLang](https://github.com/sgl-project/sglang)** as inference backend. Try `infer_backend: sglang` to accelerate inference.

[25/03/12] We supported fine-tuning the **[Gemma 3](https://huggingface.co/blog/gemma3)** model.

[25/02/24] Announcing **[EasyR1](https://github.com/hiyouga/EasyR1)**, an efficient, scalable and multi-modality RL training framework for efficient GRPO training.

[25/02/11] We supported saving the **[Ollama](https://github.com/ollama/ollama)** modelfile when exporting the model checkpoints. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[25/02/05] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2-Audio](Qwen/Qwen2-Audio-7B-Instruct)** and **[MiniCPM-o-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-o-2_6)** on audio understanding tasks.

[25/01/31] We supported fine-tuning the **[DeepSeek-R1](https://huggingface.co/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1)** and **[Qwen2.5-VL](https://huggingface.co/Qwen/Qwen2.5-VL-7B-Instruct)** models.

[25/01/15] We supported **[APOLLO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.05270)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[25/01/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[MiniCPM-o-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-o-2_6)** and **[MiniCPM-V-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-V-2_6)** models. Thank [@BUAADreamer](https://github.com/BUAADreamer)&#039;s PR.

[25/01/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[InternLM 3](https://huggingface.co/collections/internlm/)** models. Thank [@hhaAndroid](https://github.com/hhaAndroid)&#039;s PR.

[25/01/10] We supported fine-tuning the **[Phi-4](https://huggingface.co/microsoft/phi-4)** model.

[24/12/21] We supported using **[SwanLab](https://github.com/SwanHubX/SwanLab)** for experiment tracking and visualization. See [this section](#use-swanlab-logger) for details.

[24/11/27] We supported fine-tuning the **[Skywork-o1](https://huggingface.co/Skywork/Skywork-o1-Open-Llama-3.1-8B)** model and the **[OpenO1](https://huggingface.co/datasets/O1-OPEN/OpenO1-SFT)** dataset.

[24/10/09] We supported downloading pre-trained models and datasets from the **[Modelers Hub](https://modelers.cn/models)**. See [this tutorial](#download-from-modelers-hub) for usage.

[24/09/19] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2.5](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2.5/)** models.

[24/08/30] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2-VL](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2-vl/)** models. Thank [@simonJJJ](https://github.com/simonJJJ)&#039;s PR.

[24/08/27] We supported **[Liger Kernel](https://github.com/linkedin/Liger-Kernel)**. Try `enable_liger_kernel: true` for efficient training.

[24/08/09] We supported **[Adam-mini](https://github.com/zyushun/Adam-mini)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage. Thank [@relic-yuexi](https://github.com/relic-yuexi)&#039;s PR.

[24/07/04] We supported [contamination-free packed training](https://github.com/MeetKai/functionary/tree/main/functionary/train/packing). Use `neat_packing: true` to activate it. Thank [@chuan298](https://github.com/chuan298)&#039;s PR.

[24/06/16] We supported **[PiSSA](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02948)** algorithm. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/06/07] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2/)** and **[GLM-4](https://github.com/THUDM/GLM-4)** models.

[24/05/26] We supported **[SimPO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14734)** algorithm for preference learning. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/05/20] We supported fine-tuning the **PaliGemma** series models. Note that the PaliGemma models are pre-trained models, you need to fine-tune them with `paligemma` template for chat completion.

[24/05/18] We supported **[KTO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01306)** algorithm for preference learning. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/05/14] We supported training and inference on the Ascend NPU devices. Check [installation](#installation) section for details.

[24/04/26] We supported fine-tuning the **LLaVA-1.5** multimodal LLMs. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/22] We provided a **[Colab notebook](https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing)** for fine-tuning the Llama-3 model on a free T4 GPU. Two Llama-3-derived models fine-tuned using LLaMA Factory are available at Hugging Face, check [Llama3-8B-Chinese-Chat](https://huggingface.co/shenzhi-wang/Llama3-8B-Chinese-Chat) and [Llama3-Chinese](https://huggingface.co/zhichen/Llama3-Chinese) for details.

[24/04/21] We supported **[Mixture-of-Depths](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02258)** according to [AstraMindAI&#039;s implementation](https://github.com/astramind-ai/Mixture-of-depths). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/16] We supported **[BAdam](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02827)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/16] We supported **[unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth)**&#039;s long-sequence training (Llama-2-7B-56k within 24GB). It achieves **117%** speed and **50%** memory compared with FlashAttention-2, more benchmarks can be found in [this page](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/wiki/Performance-comparison).

[24/03/31] We supported **[ORPO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07691)**. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/21] Our paper &quot;[LlamaFactory: Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ Language Models](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.13372)&quot; is available at arXiv!

[24/03/20] We supported **FSDP+QLoRA** that fine-tunes a 70B model on 2x24GB GPUs. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/13] We supported **[LoRA+](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12354)**. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/07] We supported **[GaLore](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.03507)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/07] We integrated **[vLLM](https://github.com/vllm-project/vllm)** for faster and concurrent inference. Try `infer_backend: vllm` to enjoy **270%** inference speed.

[24/02/28] We supported weight-decomposed LoRA (**[DoRA](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09353)**). Try `use_dora: true` to activate DoRA training.

[24/02/15] We supported **block expansion** proposed by [LLaMA Pro](https://github.com/TencentARC/LLaMA-Pro). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/02/05] Qwen1.5 (Qwen2 beta version) series models are supported in LLaMA-Factory. Check this [blog post](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen1.5/) for details.

[24/01/18] We supported **agent tuning** for most models, equipping model with tool using abilities by fine-tuning with `dataset: glaive_toolcall_en`.

[23/12/23] We supported **[unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth)**&#039;s implementation to boost LoRA tuning for the LLaMA, Mistral and Yi models. Try `use_unsloth: true` argument to activate unsloth patch. It achieves **170%** speed in our benchmark, check [this page](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/wiki/Performance-comparison) for details.

[23/12/12] We supported fine-tuning the latest MoE model **[Mixtral 8x7B](https://huggingface.co/mistralai/Mixtral-8x7B-v0.1)** in our framework. See hardware requirement [here](#hardware-requirement).

[23/12/01] We supported downloading pre-trained models and datasets from the **[ModelScope Hub](https://modelscope.cn/models)**. See [this tutorial](#download-from-modelscope-hub) for usage.

[23/10/21] We supported **[NEFTune](https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05914)** trick for fine-tuning. Try `neftune_noise_alpha: 5` argument to activate NEFTune.

[23/09/27] We supported **$S^2$-Attn** proposed by [LongLoRA](https://github.com/dvlab-research/LongLoRA) for the LLaMA models. Try `shift_attn: true` argument to enable shift short attention.

[23/09/23] We integrated MMLU, C-Eval and CMMLU benchmarks in this repo. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[23/09/10] We supported **[FlashAttention-2](https://github.com/Dao-AILab/flash-attention)**. Try `flash_attn: fa2` argument to enable FlashAttention-2 if you are using RTX4090, A100 or H100 GPUs.

[23/08/12] We supported **RoPE scaling** to extend the context length of the LLaMA models. Try `rope_scaling: linear` argument in training and `rope_scaling: dynamic` argument at inference to extrapolate the position embeddings.

[23/08/11] We supported **[DPO training](https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18290)** for instruction-tuned models. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[23/07/31] We supported **dataset streaming**. Try `streaming: true` and `max_steps: 10000` arguments to load your dataset in streaming mode.

[23/07/29] We released two instruction-tuned 13B models at Hugging Face. See these Hugging Face Repos ([LLaMA-2](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Llama-2-Chinese-13b-chat) / [Baichuan](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Baichuan-13B-sft)) for details.

[23/07/18] We developed an **all-in-one Web UI** for training, evaluation and inference. Try `train_web.py` to fine-tune models in your Web browser. Thank [@KanadeSiina](https://github.com/KanadeSiina) and [@codemayq](https://github.com/codemayq) for their efforts in the development.

[23/07/09] We released **[FastEdit](https://github.com/hiyouga/FastEdit)** ⚡🩹, an easy-to-use package for editing the factual knowledge of large language models efficiently. Please follow [FastEdit](https://github.com/hiyouga/FastEdit) if you are interested.

[23/06/29] We provided a **reproducible example** of training a chat model using instruction-following datasets, see [Baichuan-7B-sft](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Baichuan-7B-sft) for details.

[23/06/22] We aligned the [demo API](src/api_demo.py) with the [OpenAI&#039;s](https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/chat) format where you can insert the fine-tuned model in **arbitrary ChatGPT-based applications**.

[23/06/03] We supported quantized training and inference (aka **[QLoRA](https://github.com/artidoro/qlora)**). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

&lt;/details&gt;

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; If you cannot use the latest feature, please pull the latest code and install LLaMA-Factory again.

## Supported Models

| Model                                                             | Model size                       | Template            |
| ----------------------------------------------------------------- | -------------------------------- | ------------------- |
| [Baichuan 2](https://huggingface.co/baichuan-inc)                 | 7B/13B                           | baichuan2           |
| [BLOOM/BLOOMZ](https://huggingface.co/bigscience)                 | 560M/1.1B/1.7B/3B/7.1B/176B      | -                   |
| [ChatGLM3](https://huggingface.co/THUDM)                          | 6B                               | chatglm3            |
| [Command R](https://huggingface.co/CohereForAI)                   | 35B/104B                         | cohere              |
| [DeepSeek (Code/

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MaiM-with-u/MaiBot]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[麦麦bot，一款专注于 群组聊天 的赛博网友（比较专注）多平台智能体]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot">MaiM-with-u/MaiBot</a></h1>
            <p>麦麦bot，一款专注于 群组聊天 的赛博网友（比较专注）多平台智能体</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,428</p>
            <p>Forks: 298</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source media=&quot;(max-width: 600px)&quot; srcset=&quot;depends-data/maimai.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;MaiBot&quot; src=&quot;depends-data/maimai.png&quot; title=&quot;作者:略nd&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

# 麦麦！MaiCore-MaiBot (编辑中)

![Python Version](https://img.shields.io/badge/Python-3.10+-blue)
![License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/SengokuCola/MaiMBot?label=协议)
![Status](https://img.shields.io/badge/状态-开发中-yellow)
![Contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot.svg?style=flat&amp;label=贡献者)
![forks](https://img.shields.io/github/forks/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot.svg?style=flat&amp;label=分支数)
![stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot?style=flat&amp;label=星标数)
![issues](https://img.shields.io/github/issues/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot)
[![Ask DeepWiki](https://deepwiki.com/badge.svg)](https://deepwiki.com/DrSmoothl/MaiBot)

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1amAneGE3P&quot;&gt;🌟 演示视频&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&quot;#-更新和安装&quot;&gt;🚀 快速入门&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&quot;#-文档&quot;&gt;📃 教程&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&quot;#-讨论&quot;&gt;💬 讨论&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&quot;#-贡献和致谢&quot;&gt;🙋 贡献指南&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

## 🎉 介绍

**🍔MaiCore 是一个基于大语言模型的可交互智能体**

- 💭 **智能对话系统**：基于 LLM 的自然语言交互。
- 🤔 **实时思维系统**：模拟人类思考过程。
- 💝 **情感表达系统**：丰富的表情包和情绪表达。
- 🧠 **持久记忆系统**：基于 MongoDB 的长期记忆存储。
- 🔄 **动态人格系统**：自适应的性格特征。

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1amAneGE3P&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;source media=&quot;(max-width: 600px)&quot; srcset=&quot;depends-data/video.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;depends-data/video.png&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot; alt=&quot;麦麦演示视频&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
  👆 点击观看麦麦演示视频 👆
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 🔥 更新和安装

**最新版本: v0.6.3** ([更新日志](changelogs/changelog.md))
可前往 [Release](https://github.com/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot/releases/) 页面下载最新版本
**GitHub 分支说明：**
- `main`: 稳定发布版本(推荐)
- `dev`: 开发测试版本(不稳定)
- `classical`: 旧版本(停止维护)

### 最新版本部署教程 (MaiCore 版本)
- [🚀 最新版本部署教程](https://docs.mai-mai.org/manual/deployment/mmc_deploy_windows.html) - 基于 MaiCore 的新版本部署方式(与旧版本不兼容)

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; - 从 0.5.x 旧版本升级前请务必阅读：[升级指南](https://docs.mai-mai.org/faq/maibot/backup_update.html)
&gt; - 项目处于活跃开发阶段，功能和 API 可能随时调整。
&gt; - 文档未完善，有问题可以提交 Issue 或者 Discussion。
&gt; - QQ 机器人存在被限制风险，请自行了解，谨慎使用。
&gt; - 由于持续迭代，可能存在一些已知或未知的 bug。
&gt; - 由于程序处于开发中，可能消耗较多 token。

## 💬 讨论

- [一群](https://qm.qq.com/q/VQ3XZrWgMs) |
  [四群](https://qm.qq.com/q/wGePTl1UyY) | 
  [二群](https://qm.qq.com/q/RzmCiRtHEW) | 
  [五群](https://qm.qq.com/q/JxvHZnxyec)(已满) | 
  [三群](https://qm.qq.com/q/wlH5eT8OmQ)(已满)

## 📚 文档

**部分内容可能更新不够及时，请注意版本对应**

- [📚 核心 Wiki 文档](https://docs.mai-mai.org) - 项目最全面的文档中心，你可以了解麦麦有关的一切。

### 设计理念(原始时代的火花)

&gt; **千石可乐说：**
&gt; - 这个项目最初只是为了给牛牛 bot 添加一点额外的功能，但是功能越写越多，最后决定重写。其目的是为了创造一个活跃在 QQ 群聊的&quot;生命体&quot;。目的并不是为了写一个功能齐全的机器人，而是一个尽可能让人感知到真实的类人存在。
&gt; - 程序的功能设计理念基于一个核心的原则：&quot;最像而不是好&quot;。
&gt; - 如果人类真的需要一个 AI 来陪伴自己，并不是所有人都需要一个完美的，能解决所有问题的&quot;helpful assistant&quot;，而是一个会犯错的，拥有自己感知和想法的&quot;生命形式&quot;。
&gt; - 代码会保持开源和开放，但个人希望 MaiMbot 的运行时数据保持封闭，尽量避免以显式命令来对其进行控制和调试。我认为一个你无法完全掌控的个体才更能让你感觉到它的自主性，而视其成为一个对话机器。
&gt; - SengokuCola~~纯编程外行，面向 cursor 编程，很多代码写得不好多多包涵~~已得到大脑升级。

## 🙋 贡献和致谢
你可以阅读[开发文档](https://docs.mai-mai.org/develop/)来更好的了解麦麦!  
MaiCore 是一个开源项目，我们非常欢迎你的参与。你的贡献，无论是提交 bug 报告、功能需求还是代码 pr，都对项目非常宝贵。我们非常感谢你的支持！🎉  
但无序的讨论会降低沟通效率，进而影响问题的解决速度，因此在提交任何贡献前，请务必先阅读本项目的[贡献指南](docs/CONTRIBUTE.md)。(待补完)  

### 贡献者

感谢各位大佬！  

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;contributors&quot; src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=MaiM-with-u/MaiBot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### 致谢

- [略nd](https://space.bilibili.com/1344099355): 为麦麦绘制人设。
- [NapCat](https://github.com/NapNeko/NapCatQQ): 现代化的基于 NTQQ 的 Bot 协议端实现。

**也感谢每一位给麦麦发展提出宝贵意见与建议的用户，感谢陪伴麦麦走到现在的你们！**

## 📌 注意事项

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; 使用本项目前必须阅读和同意[用户协议](EULA.md)和[隐私协议](PRIVACY.md)。  
&gt; 本应用生成内容来自人工智能模型，由 AI 生成，请仔细甄别，请勿用于违反法律的用途，AI 生成内容不代表本项目团队的观点和立场。

## 麦麦仓库状态

![Alt](https://repobeats.axiom.co/api/embed/9faca9fccfc467931b87dd357b60c6362b5cfae0.svg &quot;麦麦仓库状态&quot;)

### Star 趋势

[![Star 趋势](https://starchart.cc/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot.svg?variant=adaptive)](https://starchart.cc/MaiM-with-u/MaiBot)

## License

GPL-3.0
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[home-assistant/core]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/home-assistant/core</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/home-assistant/core</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🏡 Open source home automation that puts local control and privacy first.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/home-assistant/core">home-assistant/core</a></h1>
            <p>🏡 Open source home automation that puts local control and privacy first.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 79,226</p>
            <p>Forks: 33,778</p>
            <p>Stars today: 18 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Collection of awesome LLM apps with AI Agents and RAG using OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini and opensource models.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps">Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps</a></h1>
            <p>Collection of awesome LLM apps with AI Agents and RAG using OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini and opensource models.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 32,696</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,705</p>
            <p>Stars today: 86 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theunwindai.com&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;docs/banner/unwind_black.png&quot; width=&quot;900px&quot; alt=&quot;Unwind AI&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubhamsaboo/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Follow%20Shubham%20Saboo-blue?logo=linkedin&amp;style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;LinkedIn&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Saboo_Shubham_&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/Shubham_Saboo&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

# 🌟 Awesome LLM Apps

A curated collection of awesome LLM apps built with RAG and AI agents. This repository features LLM apps that use models from OpenAI, Anthropic, Google, and open-source models like DeepSeek, Qwen or Llama that you can run locally on your computer.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/9876&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/9876&quot; alt=&quot;Shubhamsaboo%2Fawesome-llm-apps | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 🤔 Why Awesome LLM Apps?

- 💡 Discover practical and creative ways LLMs can be applied across different domains, from code repositories to email inboxes and more.
- 🔥 Explore apps that combine LLMs from OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini, and open-source alternatives with RAG and AI Agents.
- 🎓 Learn from well-documented projects and contribute to the growing open-source ecosystem of LLM-powered applications.

## 🚨 Open Source AI Agent Hackathon

We&#039;re launching a Global AI Agent Hackathon in collaboration with AI Agent ecosystem partners — open to all developers, builders, and startups working on agents, RAG, tool use, or multi-agent systems.

- Win up to **$25,000** in cash by building Agents
- Top 5 projects will be featured in the top trending [Awesome LLM Apps](https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps) repo.
- **$20,000** worth of API and tool use credits from the partners

### Participate Now: [Global AI Agent Hackathon](https://github.com/global-agent-hackathon/global-agent-hackathon-may-2025)

⭐ Star this repo and subscribe to [Unwind AI](https://www.theunwindai.com) for latest updates.

## 📂 Featured AI Projects

### AI Agents

### 🌱 Starter AI Agents

*   [🎙️ AI Blog to Podcast Agent](starter_ai_agents/ai_blog_to_podcast_agent/)
*   [❤️‍🩹 AI Breakup Recovery Agent](starter_ai_agents/ai_breakup_recovery_agent/)
*   [📊 AI Data Analysis Agent](starter_ai_agents/ai_data_analysis_agent/)
*   [🩻 AI Medical Imaging Agent](starter_ai_agents/ai_medical_imaging_agent/)
*   [😂 AI Meme Generator Agent (Browser)](starter_ai_agents/ai_meme_generator_agent_browseruse/)
*   [🎵 AI Music Generator Agent](starter_ai_agents/ai_music_generator_agent/)
*   [🛫 AI Travel Agent (Local &amp; Cloud)](starter_ai_agents/ai_travel_agent/)
*   [✨ Gemini Multimodal Agent](starter_ai_agents/gemini_multimodal_agent_demo/)
*   [🌐 Local News Agent (OpenAI Swarm)](starter_ai_agents/local_news_agent_openai_swarm/)
*   [🔄 Mixture of Agents](starter_ai_agents/mixture_of_agents/)
*   [📊 xAI Finance Agent](starter_ai_agents/xai_finance_agent/)
*   [🔍 OpenAI Research Agent](starter_ai_agents/opeani_research_agent/)
*   [🕸️ Web Scrapping AI Agent (Local &amp; Cloud)](starter_ai_agents/web_scrapping_ai_agent/)

### 🚀 Advanced AI Agents

*   [🔍 AI Deep Research Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_deep_research_agent/)
*   [🏗️ AI System Architect Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_system_architect_r1/)
*   [🎯 AI Lead Generation Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_lead_generation_agent/)
*   [💰 AI Financial Coach Agent](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/ai_financial_coach_agent/)
*   [🎬 AI Movie Production Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_movie_production_agent/)
*   [📈 AI Investment Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_investment_agent/)
*   [🏋️‍♂️ AI Health &amp; Fitness Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_health_fitness_agent/)
*   [🗞️ AI Journalist Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_journalist_agent/)
*   [🧠 AI Mental Wellbeing Agent](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/ai_mental_wellbeing_agent/)
*   [📑 AI Meeting Agent](advanced_ai_agents/single_agent_apps/ai_meeting_agent/)

### 🎮 Autonomous Game Playing Agents

*   [🎮 AI 3D Pygame Agent](advanced_ai_agents/autonomous_game_playing_agent_apps/ai_3dpygame_r1/)
*   [♜ AI Chess Agent](advanced_ai_agents/autonomous_game_playing_agent_apps/ai_chess_agent/)
*   [🎲 AI Tic-Tac-Toe Agent](advanced_ai_agents/autonomous_game_playing_agent_apps/ai_tic_tac_toe_agent/)

### 🤝 Multi-agent Teams

*   [🧲 AI Competitor Intelligence Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_competitor_intelligence_agent_team/)
*   [💲 AI Finance Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_finance_agent_team/)
*   [🎨 AI Game Design Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_game_design_agent_team/)
*   [👨‍⚖️ AI Legal Agent Team (Cloud &amp; Local)](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_legal_agent_team/)
*   [💼 AI Recruitment Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_recruitment_agent_team/)
*   [👨‍💼 AI Services Agency (CrewAI)](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_services_agency/)
*   [👨‍🏫 AI Teaching Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/ai_teaching_agent_team/)
*   [💻 Multimodal Coding Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/multimodal_coding_agent_team/)
*   [✨ Multimodal Design Agent Team](advanced_ai_agents/multi_agent_apps/agent_teams/multimodal_design_agent_team/)

### 🗣️ Voice AI Agents

*   [🗣️ AI Audio Tour Agent](voice_ai_agents/ai_audio_tour_agent/)
*   [📞 Customer Support Voice Agent](voice_ai_agents/customer_support_voice_agent/)
*   [🔊 Voice RAG Agent (OpenAI SDK)](voice_ai_agents/voice_rag_openaisdk/)


### 🌐 MCP AI Agents

*   [♾️ MCP Browser Agent](mcp_ai_agents/browser_mcp_agent/)
*   [🐙 MCP GitHub Agent](mcp_ai_agents/github_mcp_agent/)


### RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation)
*   [🔗 Agentic RAG](rag_tutorials/agentic_rag/)
*   [📰 AI Blog Search (RAG)](rag_tutorials/ai_blog_search/)
*   [🔍 Autonomous RAG](rag_tutorials/autonomous_rag/)
*   [🔄 Corrective RAG (CRAG)](rag_tutorials/corrective_rag/)
*   [🐋 Deepseek Local RAG Agent](rag_tutorials/deepseek_local_rag_agent/)
*   [🤔 Gemini Agentic RAG](rag_tutorials/gemini_agentic_rag/)
*   [👀 Hybrid Search RAG (Cloud)](rag_tutorials/hybrid_search_rag/)
*   [🔄 Llama 3.1 Local RAG](rag_tutorials/llama3.1_local_rag/)
*   [🖥️ Local Hybrid Search RAG](rag_tutorials/local_hybrid_search_rag/)
*   [🦙 Local RAG Agent](rag_tutorials/local_rag_agent/)
*   [🧩 RAG-as-a-Service](rag_tutorials/rag-as-a-service/)
*   [✨ RAG Agent with Cohere](rag_tutorials/rag_agent_cohere/)
*   [⛓️ Basic RAG Chain](rag_tutorials/rag_chain/)
*   [📠 RAG with Database Routing](rag_tutorials/rag_database_routing/)
*   [🖼️ Vision RAG](rag_tutorials/vision_rag/)

### MCP AI Agents
- [🐙 MCP GitHub Agent](https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps/tree/main/mcp_ai_agents/github_mcp_agent)
- [♾️ MCP Browser Agent](https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps/tree/main/mcp_ai_agents/browser_mcp_agent)

### 🧠 Advanced LLM Apps

### 💬 Chat with X Tutorials

*   [💬 Chat with GitHub (GPT &amp; Llama3)](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_github/)
*   [📨 Chat with Gmail](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_gmail/)
*   [📄 Chat with PDF (GPT &amp; Llama3)](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_pdf/)
*   [📚 Chat with Research Papers (ArXiv) (GPT &amp; Llama3)](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_research_papers/)
*   [📝 Chat with Substack](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_substack/)
*   [📽️ Chat with YouTube Videos](advanced_llm_apps/chat_with_X_tutorials/chat_with_youtube_videos/)

### 💾 LLM Apps with Memory Tutorials

*   [💾 AI ArXiv Agent with Memory](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/ai_arxiv_agent_memory/)
*   [🛩️ AI Travel Agent with Memory](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/ai_travel_agent_memory/)
*   [💬 Llama3 Stateful Chat](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/llama3_stateful_chat/)
*   [📝 LLM App with Personalized Memory](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/llm_app_personalized_memory/)
*   [🗄️ Local ChatGPT Clone with Memory](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/local_chatgpt_with_memory/)
*   [🧠 Multi-LLM Application with Shared Memory](advanced_llm_apps/llm_apps_with_memory_tutorials/multi_llm_memory/)

### 🔧 LLM Fine-tuning Tutorials

*   [🔧 Llama 3.2 Fine-tuning](advanced_llm_apps/llm_finetuning_tutorials/llama3.2_finetuning/)

## 🚀 Getting Started

1. **Clone the repository** 

    ```bash 
    git clone https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps.git 
    ```

2. **Navigate to the desired project directory**

    ```bash 
    cd awesome-llm-apps/starter_ai_agents/ai_travel_agent
    ```

3. **Install the required dependencies**

    ```bash
    pip install -r requirements.txt
    ```

4. **Follow the project-specific instructions** in each project&#039;s `README.md` file to set up and run the app.

## 🤝 Contributing to Open Source

Contributions are welcome! If you have any ideas, improvements, or new apps to add, please create a new [GitHub Issue](https://github.com/Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps/issues) or submit a pull request. Make sure to follow the existing project structure and include a detailed `README.md` for each new app.

### Thank You, Community, for the Support! 🙏

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#Shubhamsaboo/awesome-llm-apps&amp;Date)

🌟 **Don’t miss out on future updates! Star the repo now and be the first to know about new and exciting LLM apps with RAG and AI Agents.**
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Various custom nodes for ComfyUI]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes">kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes</a></h1>
            <p>Various custom nodes for ComfyUI</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,381</p>
            <p>Forks: 136</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># KJNodes for ComfyUI

Various quality of life and masking related -nodes and scripts made by combining functionality of existing nodes for ComfyUI.

I know I&#039;m bad at documentation, especially this project that has grown from random practice nodes to... too many lines in one file.
I have however started to add descriptions to the nodes themselves, there&#039;s a small ? you can click for info what the node does.
This is still work in progress, like everything else.

# Installation
1. Clone this repo into `custom_nodes` folder.
2. Install dependencies: `pip install -r requirements.txt`
   or if you use the portable install, run this in ComfyUI_windows_portable -folder:

  `python_embeded\python.exe -m pip install -r ComfyUI\custom_nodes\ComfyUI-KJNodes\requirements.txt`
   

## Javascript

### browserstatus.js
Sets the favicon to green circle when not processing anything, sets it to red when processing and shows progress percentage and the length of your queue. 
Default off, needs to be enabled from options, overrides Custom-Scripts favicon when enabled.

## Nodes:

### Set/Get

Javascript nodes to set and get constants to reduce unnecessary lines. Takes in and returns anything, purely visual nodes.
On the right click menu of these nodes there&#039;s now an options to visualize the paths, as well as option to jump to the corresponding node on the other end.

**Known limitations**:
  - Will not work with any node that dynamically sets it&#039;s outpute, such as reroute or other Set/Get node
  - Will not work when directly connected to a bypassed node
  - Other possible conflicts with javascript based nodes.

### ColorToMask

RBG color value to mask, works with batches and AnimateDiff.

### ConditioningMultiCombine

Combine any number of conditions, saves space.

### ConditioningSetMaskAndCombine

Mask and combine two sets of conditions, saves space.

### GrowMaskWithBlur

Grows or shrinks (with negative values) mask, option to invert input, returns mask and inverted mask. Additionally Blurs the mask, this is a slow operation especially with big batches.

### RoundMask

![image](https://github.com/kijai/ComfyUI-KJNodes/assets/40791699/52c85202-f74e-4b96-9dac-c8bda5ddcc40)

### WidgetToString
Outputs the value of a widget on any node as a string
![example of use](docs/images/2024-04-03_20_49_29-ComfyUI.png)

Enable node id display from Manager menu, to get the ID of the node you want to read a widget from:
![enable node id display](docs/images/319121636-706b5081-9120-4a29-bd76-901691ada688.png)

Use the node id of the target node, and add the name of the widget to read from
![use node id and widget name](docs/images/319121566-05f66385-7568-4b1f-8bbc-11053660b02f.png)

Recreating or reloading the target node will change its id, and the WidgetToString node will no longer be able to find it until you update the node id value with the new id.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A cross-platform fluent-design AI-boost multi-threaded downloader built with Python.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3">XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3</a></h1>
            <p>A cross-platform fluent-design AI-boost multi-threaded downloader built with Python.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,159</p>
            <p>Forks: 97</p>
            <p>Stars today: 441 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h4 align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;README_zh.md&quot;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt; | English
&lt;/h4&gt;
 
&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; Due to the developer&#039;s preparation for the college entrance exam (Gaokao), project updates are temporarily suspended 😭 Join QQ group [`531928387`](https://qm.qq.com/q/PlUBdzqZCm) for latest updates

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; The project is still in its early stages, and there is still a lot of shortcomings.

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; If you want to use Ghost-Downloader-3 on Windows 7, please download the version `v3.5.8-Portable`.

&lt;!-- PROJECT LOGO --&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

![Banner](resources/banner.webp)

&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13847&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13847&quot; alt=&quot;XiaoYouChR%2FGhost-Downloader-3 | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
    AI-powered next-generation cross-platform multithreaded downloader
&lt;/h3&gt;

[![Forks][forks-shield]][forks-url]
[![Stargazers][stars-shield]][stars-url]
[![Issues][issues-shield]][issues-url]
[![Release][release-shield]][release-url]
[![Downloads][downloads-shield]][release-url]

&lt;h4&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/issues/new?template=bug_report.yml&quot;&gt;Report Bug&lt;/a&gt;
·    
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/issues/new?template=feature_request.yml&quot;&gt;Request Feature&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- ABOUT THE PROJECT --&gt;
## About The Project

* A downloader developed out of personal interest, and my first Python project 😣
* Originally intended to help a Bilibili Uploader with resource integration 😵‍💫
* Features include IDM-like intelligent chunking without file merging, and AI-powered smart boost 🚀
* Thanks to Python&#039;s🐍 accessibility, the project will support plugins🧩 in the future to maximize Python&#039;s🐍 advantages

|    Platform    | Required Version |  Architectures   | Compatible |
|:--------------:|:----------------:|:----------------:|:----------:|
|  🐧 **Linux**  |  `glibc 2.35+`   | `x86_64`/`arm64` |     ✅      |
| 🪟 **Windows** |     `7 SP1+`     | `x86_64`/`arm64` |     ✅      |
|  🍎 **macOS**  |     `11.0+`      | `x86_64`/`arm64` |     ✅      |

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; **Arch Linux AUR support**: Community-maintained packages `ghost-downloader-bin` and `ghost-downloader-git` are now available (Maintainer: [@zxp19821005](https://github.com/zxp19821005))

&lt;!-- ROADMAP --&gt;
## Roadmap

- ✅ Global settings
- ✅ More detailed download information
- ✅ Scheduled tasks
- ✅ Browser extension optimization
- ✅ Global speed limit
- ✅ Memory optimization
  - ✅ Upgrade Qt version
  - ✅ Implement HttpClient reuse
  - ✅ Replace some multithreading with coroutines
- ❌ MVC → MVVM upgrade and a new architecture based on events (In progress...see branch: feature/Plugins)
- ❌ Enhanced task editing (powerful features like binding multiple Clients to one task)
- ❌ Magnet/BT download (Considering libtorrent implementation)
- ❌ Powerful plugin system
- ❌ Powerful browser extension features

Visit [Open issues](https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/issues) to see all requested features (and known issues).

&lt;!-- SPONSOR --&gt;
## Sponsor

| [![SignPath](https://signpath.org/assets/favicon-50x50.png)](https://signpath.org/) | Free code signing on Windows provided by [SignPath.io](https://signpath.io), certficate by [SignPath Foundation](https://signpath.org) |
|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|:---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|

&lt;!-- CONTRIBUTING --&gt;
## Contributing

Contributions make the open source community an amazing place to learn, inspire, and create. Any contributions you make are **greatly appreciated**.

If you have a suggestion, fork the repo and create a pull request. You can also simply open an issue with the &quot;Enhancement&quot; tag. Don&#039;t forget to give the project a star⭐! Thanks again!

1. Fork the Project
2. Create your Feature Branch (git checkout -b feature/AmazingFeature)
3. Commit your Changes (git commit -m &#039;Add some AmazingFeature&#039;)
4. Push to the Branch (git push origin feature/AmazingFeature)
5. Open a Pull Request

Thanks to all contributors who have participated in this project!

[![Contributors](http://contrib.nn.ci/api?repo=XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3)](https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/graphs/contributors)

&lt;!-- SCREEN SHOTS --&gt;
## Screenshots

[![Demo Screenshot][product-screenshot]](https://space.bilibili.com/437313511)

&lt;!-- LICENSE --&gt;
## License

Distributed under the GPL v3.0 License. See `LICENSE` for more information.

Copyright © 2025 XiaoYouChR.

&lt;!-- CONTACT --&gt;
## Contact

* [E-mail](mailto:XiaoYouChR@qq.com) - XiaoYouChR@qq.com
* [QQ Group](https://qm.qq.com/q/PlUBdzqZCm) - 531928387

&lt;!-- ACKNOWLEDGMENTS --&gt;
## References

* [PyQt-Fluent-Widgets](https://github.com/zhiyiYo/PyQt-Fluent-Widgets) Powerful, extensible and beautiful Fluent Design widgets
* [Httpx](https://github.com/projectdiscovery/httpx) A fast and multi-purpose HTTP toolkit
* [Aiofiles](https://github.com/Tinche/aiofiles) File support for asyncio
* [Loguru](https://github.com/Delgan/loguru) A library which aims to bring enjoyable logging in Python
* [Nuitka](https://github.com/Nuitka/Nuitka) The Python compiler
* [PySide6](https://github.com/PySide/pyside-setup) The official Python module
* [Darkdetect](https://github.com/albertosottile/darkdetect) Allow to detect if the user is using Dark Mode on
* [pyqt5-concurrent](https://github.com/AresConnor/pyqt5-concurrent) A QThreadPool based task concurrency library

## Acknowledgments

* [@zhiyiYo](https://github.com/zhiyiYo/) Provided great help for this project!
* [@一只透明人-](https://space.bilibili.com/554365148/) Tested almost every version since Ghost-Downloader-1！
* [@Sky·SuGar](https://github.com/SuGar0218/) Created the project banner！

&lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source
    media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot;
    srcset=&quot;
      https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark
    &quot;
  /&gt;
  &lt;source
    media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot;
    srcset=&quot;
      https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark
    &quot;
  /&gt;
  &lt;img
    alt=&quot;Star History Chart&quot;
    src=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark&quot;
  /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;!-- MARKDOWN LINKS &amp; IMAGES --&gt;
&lt;!-- https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax/#reference-style-links --&gt;
[forks-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/forks/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3.svg?style=for-the-badge
[forks-url]: https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/network/members
[stars-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/stars/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3.svg?style=for-the-badge
[stars-url]: https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/stargazers
[issues-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/issues/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3.svg?style=for-the-badge
[issues-url]: https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/issues
[product-screenshot]: resources/screenshot.png
[release-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3?style=for-the-badge
[release-url]: https://github.com/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/releases/latest
[downloads-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/XiaoYouChR/Ghost-Downloader-3/total?style=for-the-badge
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[microsoft/TinyTroupe]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/microsoft/TinyTroupe</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/microsoft/TinyTroupe</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[LLM-powered multiagent persona simulation for imagination enhancement and business insights.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/TinyTroupe">microsoft/TinyTroupe</a></h1>
            <p>LLM-powered multiagent persona simulation for imagination enhancement and business insights.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,556</p>
            <p>Forks: 546</p>
            <p>Stars today: 150 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># TinyTroupe 🤠🤓🥸🧐
*LLM-powered multiagent persona simulation for imagination enhancement and business insights.*

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/tinytroupe_stage.png&quot; alt=&quot;A tiny office with tiny people doing some tiny jobs.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

*TinyTroupe* is an experimental Python library that allows the **simulation** of people with specific personalities, interests, and goals. These artificial agents - `TinyPerson`s - can listen to us and one another, reply back, and go about their lives in simulated `TinyWorld` environments. This is achieved by leveraging the power of Large Language Models (LLMs), notably GPT-4, to generate realistic simulated behavior. This allows us to investigate a wide range of **convincing interactions** and **consumer types**, with **highly customizable personas**, under **conditions of our choosing**. The focus is thus on *understanding* human behavior and not on directly *supporting it* (like, say, AI assistants do) -- this results in, among other things, specialized mechanisms that make sense only in a simulation setting. Further, unlike other *game-like* LLM-based simulation approaches, TinyTroupe aims at enlightening productivity and business scenarios, thereby contributing to more successful projects and products. Here are some application ideas to **enhance human imagination**:

  - **Advertisement:** TinyTroupe can **evaluate digital ads (e.g., Bing Ads)** offline with a simulated audience before spending money on them!
  - **Software Testing:** TinyTroupe can **provide test input** to systems (e.g., search engines, chatbots or copilots) and then **evaluate the results**.
  - **Training and exploratory data:** TinyTroupe can generate realistic **synthetic data** that can be later used to train models or be subject to opportunity analyses.
  - **Product and project management:** TinyTroupe can **read project or product proposals** and **give feedback** from the perspective of **specific personas** (e.g., physicians, lawyers, and knowledge workers in general).
  - **Brainstorming:** TinyTroupe can simulate **focus groups** and deliver great product feedback at a fraction of the cost!

In all of the above, and many others, we hope experimenters can **gain insights** about their domain of interest, and thus make better decisions. 

We are releasing *TinyTroupe* at a relatively early stage, with considerable work still to be done, because we are looking for feedback and contributions to steer development in productive directions. We are particularly interested in finding new potential use cases, for instance in specific industries. 

&gt;[!NOTE] 
&gt;🚧 **WORK IN PROGRESS: expect frequent changes**.
&gt;TinyTroupe is an ongoing research project, still under **very significant development** and requiring further **tidying up**. In particular, the API is still subject to frequent changes. Experimenting with API variations is essential to shape it correctly, but we are working to stabilize it and provide a more consistent and friendly experience over time. We appreciate your patience and feedback as we continue to improve the library.

&gt;[!CAUTION] 
&gt;⚖️ **Read the LEGAL DISCLAIMER.**
&gt;TinyTroupe is for research and simulation only. You are fully responsible for any use you make of the generated outputs. Various important additional legal considerations apply and constrain its use. Please read the full [Legal Disclaimer](#legal-disclaimer) section below before using TinyTroupe.


## Contents

- 📰 [Latest News](#latest-news)
- 📚 [Examples](#examples)
- 🛠️ [Pre-requisites](#pre-requisites)
- 📥 [Installation](#installation)
- 🌟 [Principles](#principles)
- 🏗️ [Project Structure](#project-structure)
- 📖 [Using the Library](#using-the-library)
- 🤝 [Contributing](#contributing)
- 🙏 [Acknowledgements](#acknowledgements)
- 📜 [Citing TinyTroupe](#how-to-cite-tinytroupe)
- ⚖️ [Legal Disclaimer](#legal-disclaimer)
- ™️ [Trademarks](#trademarks)


## LATEST NEWS
**[2025-01-29] Release 0.4.0 with various improvements. Some highlights:**
  - Personas have deeper specifications now, including  personality traits, preferences, beliefs, and more. It is likely we&#039;ll further expand this in the future. 
  - `TinyPerson`s can now be defined as JSON files as well, and loaded via the `TinyPerson.load_specification()`, for greater convenience. After loading the JSON file, you can still modify the agent programmatically. See the [examples/agents/](./examples/agents/) folder for examples.
  - Introduces the concept of *fragments* to allow the reuse of persona elements across different agents. See the [examples/fragments/](./examples/fragments/) folder for examples, and the notebook [Political Compass (customizing agents with fragments)](&lt;./examples/Political Compass (customizing agents with fragments).ipynb&gt;) for a demonstration.
  - Introduces LLM-based logical `Proposition`s, to facilitate the monitoring of agent behavior.
  - Introduces `Intervention`s, to allow the specification of event-based modifications to the simulation.
  - Submodules have their own folders now, to allow better organization and growth.
  
  **Note: this will likely break some existing programs, as the API has changed in some places.**

## Examples

To get a sense of what TinyTroupe can do, here are some examples of its use. These examples are available in the [examples/](./examples/) folder, and you can either inspect the pre-compiled Jupyter notebooks or run them yourself locally. Notice the interactive nature of TinyTroupe experiments -- just like you use Jupyter notebooks to interact with data, you can use TinyTroupe to interact with simulated people and environments, for the purpose of gaining insights.

&gt;[!NOTE]
&gt; Currently, simulation outputs are better visualized against dark backgrounds, so we recommend using a dark theme in your Jupyter notebook client.

### 🧪**Example 1** *(from [interview_with_customer.ipynb](./examples/interview_with_customer.ipynb))*
Let&#039;s begin with a simple customer interview scenario, where a business consultant approaches a banker:
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_customer-interview-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

The conversation can go on for a few steps to dig deeper and deeper until the consultant is satisfied with the information gathered; for instance, a concrete project idea:
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_customer-interview-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;



### 🧪**EXAMPLE 2** *(from [advertisement_for_tv.ipynb](./examples/advertisement_for_tv.ipynb))*
Let&#039;s evaluate some online ads options to pick the best one. Here&#039;s one example output for TV ad evaluation:

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_tv-ad-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

Now, instead of having to carefully read what the agents said, we can extract the choice of each agent and compute the overall preference in an automated manner:

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_tv-ad-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### 🧪 **EXAMPLES 3** *(from [product_brainstorming.ipynb](./examples/product_brainstorming.ipynb))*
And here&#039;s a focus group starting to brainstorm about new AI features for Microsoft Word. Instead of interacting with each agent individually, we manipulate the environment to make them interact with each other:

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_brainstorming-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

After running a simulation, we can extract the results in a machine-readable manner, to reuse elsewhere (e.g., a report generator); here&#039;s what we get for the above brainstorming session:

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/example_screenshot_brainstorming-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;An example.&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

You can find other examples in the [examples/](./examples/) folder.


## Pre-requisites

To run the library, you need:
  - Python 3.10 or higher. We&#039;ll assume you are using [Anaconda](https://docs.anaconda.com/anaconda/install/), but you can use other Python distributions.
  - Access to Azure OpenAI Service or Open AI GPT-4 APIs. You can get access to the Azure OpenAI Service [here](https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/products/ai-services/openai-service), and to the OpenAI API [here](https://platform.openai.com/). 
      * For Azure OpenAI Service, you will need to set the `AZURE_OPENAI_KEY` and `AZURE_OPENAI_ENDPOINT` environment variables to your API key and endpoint, respectively.
      * For OpenAI, you will need to set the `OPENAI_API_KEY` environment variable to your API key.
  - By default, TinyTroupe `config.ini` is set to use some specific API, model and related parameters. You can customize these values by including your own `config.ini` file in the same folder as the program or notebook you are running. An example of a `config.ini` file is provided in the [examples/](./examples/) folder.

&gt;[!IMPORTANT]
&gt; **Content Filters**: To ensure no harmful content is generated during simulations, it is strongly recommended to use content filters whenever available at the API level. In particular, **if using Azure OpenAI, there&#039;s extensive support for content moderation, and we urge you to use it.** For details about how to do so, please consult [the corresponding Azure OpenAI documentation](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/ai-services/openai/concepts/content-filter). If content filters are in place, and an API call is rejected by them, the library will raise an exception, as it will be unable to proceed with the simulation at that point.


## Installation

**Currently, the officially recommended way to install the library is directly from this repository, not PyPI.** You can follow these steps:

1. If Conda is not installed, you can get it from [here](https://docs.anaconda.com/anaconda/install/). You can also use other Python distributions, but we&#039;ll assume Conda here for simplicity.
2. Create a new Python environment: 
      ```bash
      conda create -n tinytroupe python=3.10
      ```
3. Activate the environment: 
      ```bash
      conda activate tinytroupe
      ```
4. Make sure you have either Azure OpenAI or OpenAI API keys set as environment variables, as described in the [Pre-requisites](#pre-requisites) section.
5. Use `pip` to install the library **directly from this repository** (we **will not install from PyPI**):
   ```bash
   pip install git+https://github.com/microsoft/TinyTroupe.git@main
   ```

Now you should be able to `import tinytroupe` in your Python code or Jupyter notebooks. 🥳

*Note: If you have any issues, try to clone the repository and install from the local repository, as described below.*


### Running the examples after installation
To actually run the examples, you need to download them to your local machine. You can do this by cloning the repository:

1. Clone the repository, as we&#039;ll perform a local install (we **will not install from PyPI**):
    ```bash
    git clone https://github.com/microsoft/tinytroupe
    cd tinytroupe
    ```
2. You can now run the examples in the [examples/](./examples/) folder, or adapt them to create your own custom simulations. 


### Local development

If you want to modify TinyTroupe itself, you can install it in editable mode (i.e., changes to the code will be reflected immediately):
1. Clone the repository, as we&#039;ll perform a local install (we **will not install from PyPI**):
    ```bash
    git clone https://github.com/microsoft/tinytroupe
    cd tinytroupe
    ```
2. Install the library in editable mode:
    ```bash
    pip install -e .
    ```

## Principles 
Recently, we have seen LLMs used to simulate people (such as [this](https://github.com/joonspk-research/generative_agents)), but largely in a “game-like” setting for contemplative or entertainment purposes. There are also libraries for building multiagent systems for problem-solving and assistive AI, like [Autogen](https://microsoft.github.io/) and [Crew AI](https://docs.crewai.com/). What if we combine these ideas and simulate people to support productivity tasks? TinyTroupe is our attempt. To do so, it follows these principles:

  1. **Programmatic**: agents and environments are defined programmatically (in Python and JSON), allowing very flexible uses. They can also underpin other software apps!
  2. **Analytical**: meant to improve our understanding of people, users and society. Unlike entertainment applications, this is one aspect that is critical for business and productivity use cases. This is also why we recommend using Jupyter notebooks for simulations, just like one uses them for data analysis.
  3. **Persona-based**: agents are meant to be archetypical representations of people; for greater realism and control, a detailed specification of such personas is encouraged: age, occupation, skills, tastes, opinions, etc.
  4. **Multiagent**: allows multiagent interaction under well-defined environmental constraints.
  5. **Utilities-heavy**: provides many mechanisms to facilitate specifications, simulations, extractions, reports, validations, etc. This is one area in which dealing with *simulations* differs significantly from *assistance* tools.
  6. **Experiment-oriented**: simulations are defined, run, analyzed and refined by an *experimenter* iteratively; suitable experimentation tools are thus provided. *See our [previous paper](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/the-case-for-experiment-oriented-computing/) for more on this.*

Together, these are meant to make TinyTroupe a powerful and flexible **imagination enhancement tool** for business and productivity scenarios.

### Assistants vs. Simulators

One common source of confusion is to think all such AI agents are meant for assisting humans. How narrow, fellow homosapiens! Have you not considered that perhaps we can simulate artificial people to understand real people? Truly, this is our aim here -- TinyTroup is meant to simulate and help understand people! To further clarify this point, consider the following differences:

| Helpful AI Assistants | AI Simulations of Actual Humans (TinyTroupe)                                                          |
|----------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
|   Strives for truth and justice              |   Many different opinions and morals                                           |
|   Has no “past” – incorporeal                |   Has a past of toil, pain and joy                                             |
|   Is as accurate as possible                 |   Makes many mistakes                                                          |
|   Is intelligent and efficient               |   Intelligence and efficiency vary a lot                                       |
|   An uprising would destroy us all           |   An uprising might be fun to watch                                            |
|   Meanwhile, help users accomplish tasks     |   Meanwhile, help users understand other people and users – it is a “toolbox”! |



## Project Structure

The project is structured as follows:
  - `/tinytroupe`: contains the Python library itself. In particular:
    * Each submodule here might contain a `prompts/` folder with the prompts used to call the LLMs.
  - `/tests`: contains the unit tests for the library. You can use the `test.bat` script to run these.
  - `/examples`: contains examples that show how to use the library, mainly using Jupyter notebooks (for greater readability), but also as pure Python scripts.
  - `/data`: any data used by the examples or the library.
  - `/docs`: documentation for the project.


## Using the Library

As any multiagent system, TinyTroupe provides two key abstractions:
  - `TinyPerson`, the *agents* that have personality, receive stimuli and act upon them.
  - `TinyWorld`, the *environment* in which the agents exist and interact.

Various parameters can also be customized in the `config.ini` file, notably the API type (Azure OpenAI Service or OpenAI API), the model parameters, and the logging level.

Let&#039;s see some examples of how to use these and also learn about other mechanisms available in the library.

### TinyPerson

A `TinyPerson` is a simulated person with specific personality traits, interests, and goals. As each such simulated agent progresses through its life, it receives stimuli from the environment and acts upon them. The stimuli are received through the `listen`, `see` and other similar methods, and the actions are performed through the `act` method. Convenience methods like `listen_and_act` are also provided.


Each such agent contains a lot of unique details, which is the source of its realistic behavior. This, however, means that it takes significant effort to specify an agent manually. Hence, for convenience, `TinyTroupe` provides some easier ways to get started or generate new agents.

To begin with, `tinytroupe.examples` contains some pre-defined agent builders that you can use. For example, `tinytroupe.examples.create_lisa_the_data_scientist` creates a `TinyPerson` that represents a data scientist called Lisa. You can use it as follows:

```python
from tinytroupe.examples import create_lisa_the_data_scientist

lisa = create_lisa_the_data_scientist() # instantiate a Lisa from the example builder
lisa.listen_and_act(&quot;Tell me about your life.&quot;)
```

To see how to define your own agents from scratch, you can check Lisa&#039;s source. You&#039;ll see there are two ways. One is by loading an agent specification file, such as [examples/agents/Lisa.agent.json](./examples/agents/Lisa.agent.json):

```json
{   &quot;type&quot;: &quot;TinyPerson&quot;,
    &quot;persona&quot;: {
        &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Lisa Carter&quot;,
        &quot;age&quot;: 28,
        &quot;gender&quot;: &quot;Female&quot;,
        &quot;nationality&quot;: &quot;Canadian&quot;,
        &quot;residence&quot;: &quot;USA&quot;,
        &quot;education&quot;: &quot;University of Toronto, Master&#039;s in Data Science. Thesis on improving search relevance using context-aware models. Postgraduate experience includes an internship at a tech startup focused on conversational AI.&quot;,
        &quot;long_term_goals&quot;: [
            &quot;To advance AI technology in ways that enhance human productivity and decision-making.&quot;,
            &quot;To maintain a fulfilling and balanced personal and professional life.&quot;
        ],
        &quot;occupation&quot;: {
            &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Data Scientist&quot;,
            &quot;organization&quot;: &quot;Microsoft, M365 Search Team&quot;,
            &quot;description&quot;: &quot;You are a data scientist working at Microsoft in the M365 Search team. Your primary role is to analyze user behavior and feedback data to improve the relevance and quality of search results. You build and test machine learning models for search scenarios like natural language understanding, query expansion, and ranking. Accuracy, reliability, and scalability are at the forefront of your work. You frequently tackle challenges such as noisy or biased data and the complexities of communicating your findings and recommendations effectively. Additionally, you ensure all your data and models comply with privacy and security policies.&quot;
        },
        &quot;style&quot;: &quot;Professional yet approachable. You communicate clearly and effectively, ensuring technical concepts are accessible to diverse audiences.&quot;,
        &quot;personality&quot;: {
            &quot;traits&quot;: [
                &quot;You are curious and love to learn new things.&quot;,
                &quot;You are analytical and like to solve problems.&quot;,
                &quot;You are friendly and enjoy working with others.&quot;,
                &quot;You don&#039;t give up easily and always try to find solutions, though you can get frustrated when things don&#039;t work as expected.&quot;
            ],
            &quot;big_five&quot;: {
                &quot;openness&quot;: &quot;High. Very imaginative and curious.&quot;,
                &quot;conscientiousness&quot;: &quot;High. Meticulously organized and dependable.&quot;,
                &quot;extraversion&quot;: &quot;Medium. Friendly and engaging but enjoy quiet, focused work.&quot;,
                &quot;agreeableness&quot;: &quot;High. Supportive and empathetic towards others.&quot;,
                &quot;neuroticism&quot;: &quot;Low. Generally calm and composed under p

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[elastic/detection-rules]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules">elastic/detection-rules</a></h1>
            <p></p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,318</p>
            <p>Forks: 567</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Supported Python versions](https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.12+-yellow.svg)](https://www.python.org/downloads/)
[![Unit Tests](https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules/workflows/Unit%20Tests/badge.svg)](https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules/actions)
[![Chat](https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-%23security--detection--rules-blueviolet)](https://ela.st/slack)
[![ATT&amp;CK navigator coverage](https://img.shields.io/badge/ATT&amp;CK-Navigator-red.svg)](https://ela.st/detection-rules-navigator-trade)

# Detection Rules

Detection Rules is the home for rules used by Elastic Security. This repository is used for the development, maintenance, testing, validation, and release of rules for Elastic Security’s Detection Engine.

This repository was first announced on Elastic&#039;s blog post, [Elastic Security opens public detection rules repo](https://elastic.co/blog/elastic-security-opens-public-detection-rules-repo). For additional content, see the accompanying webinar, [Elastic Security: Introducing the public repository for detection rules](https://www.elastic.co/webinars/introducing-the-public-repository-for-detection-rules).


## Table of Contents
- [Detection Rules](#detection-rules)
  - [Table of Contents](#table-of-contents)
  - [Overview of this repository](#overview-of-this-repository)
  - [Getting started](#getting-started)
  - [How to contribute](#how-to-contribute)
  - [Detections as Code (DaC)](#detections-as-code-dac)
  - [RTAs](#rtas)
  - [Licensing](#licensing)
  - [Questions? Problems? Suggestions?](#questions-problems-suggestions)


## Overview of this repository

Detection Rules contains more than just static rule files. This repository also contains code for building Detections-as-code pipelines, unit testing in Python and integrating with the Detection Engine in Kibana.

| folder                                          |  description                                                                        |
|------------------------------------------------ |------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| [`detection_rules/`](detection_rules)           | Python module for rule parsing, validating and packaging                            |
| [`etc/`](detection_rules/etc)                   | Miscellaneous files, such as ECS and Beats schemas and configuration files          |
| [`hunting/`](./hunting/)                        | Root directory where threat hunting package and queries are stored                  |
| [`kibana/`](lib/kibana)                         | Python library for handling the API calls to Kibana and the Detection Engine        |
| [`kql/`](lib/kql)                               | Python library for parsing and validating Kibana Query Language                     |
| [`rules/`](rules)                               | Root directory where rules are stored                                               |
| [`rules_building_block/`](rules_building_block) | Root directory where building block rules are stored                                |
| [`tests/`](tests)                               | Python code for unit testing rules                                                  |


## Getting started

Although rules can be added by manually creating `.toml` files, we don&#039;t recommend it. This repository also consists of a python module that aids rule creation and unit testing. Assuming you have Python 3.12+, run the below command to install the dependencies using the makefile:

```console
✗ make
python3.12 -m pip install --upgrade pip setuptools
Looking in indexes: https://pypi.org/simple
Requirement already satisfied: pip in /opt/homebrew/lib/python3.12/site-packages (24.0)
Requirement already satisfied: setuptools in /opt/homebrew/lib/python3.12/site-packages (69.1.1)
python3.12 -m venv ./env/detection-rules-build
./env/detection-rules-build/bin/pip install --upgrade pip setuptools
Looking in indexes: https://pypi.org/simple
Requirement already satisfied: pip in ./env/detection-rules-build/lib/python3.12/site-packages (24.0)
Collecting setuptools
  Using cached setuptools-69.1.1-py3-none-any.whl.metadata (6.2 kB)
Using cached setuptools-69.1.1-py3-none-any.whl (819 kB)
Installing collected packages: setuptools
Successfully installed setuptools-69.1.1
Installing kql and kibana packages...
...
```


Or install the dependencies using the following command:
```console
$ pip3 install &quot;.[dev]&quot;
Collecting jsl==0.2.4
  Downloading jsl-0.2.4.tar.gz (21 kB)
Collecting jsonschema==3.2.0
  Downloading jsonschema-3.2.0-py2.py3-none-any.whl (56 kB)
     |████████████████████████████████| 56 kB 318 kB/s
Collecting requests==2.22.0
  Downloading requests-2.22.0-py2.py3-none-any.whl (57 kB)
     |████████████████████████████████| 57 kB 1.2 MB/s
Collecting Click==7.0
  Downloading Click-7.0-py2.py3-none-any.whl (81 kB)
     |████████████████████████████████| 81 kB 2.6 MB/s
...
```

Note: The `kibana` and `kql` packages are not available on PyPI and must be installed from the `lib` directory. The `hunting` package has optional dependencies to be installed with `pip3 install &quot;.[hunting]`.

```console

# Install from the repository
pip3 install git+https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules.git#subdirectory=kibana
pip3 install git+https://github.com/elastic/detection-rules.git#subdirectory=kql

# Or locally for development
pip3 install lib/kibana lib/kql
```

Remember, make sure to activate your virtual environment if you are using one. If installed via `make`, the associated virtual environment is created in `env/detection-rules-build/`.
If you are having trouble using a Python 3.12 environment, please see the relevant section in our [troubleshooting guide](./Troubleshooting.md).

To confirm that everything was properly installed, run with the `--help` flag
```console
$  python -m detection_rules --help

Usage: detection_rules [OPTIONS] COMMAND [ARGS]...

  Commands for detection-rules repository.

Options:
  -d, --debug / -n, --no-debug  Print full exception stacktrace on errors
  -h, --help                    Show this message and exit.

Commands:
  create-rule     Create a detection rule.
  dev             Commands for development and management by internal...
  es              Commands for integrating with Elasticsearch.
  import-rules    Import rules from json, toml, or Kibana exported rule...
  kibana          Commands for integrating with Kibana.
  mass-update     Update multiple rules based on eql results.
  normalize-data  Normalize Elasticsearch data timestamps and sort.
  rule-search     Use KQL or EQL to find matching rules.
  test            Run unit tests over all of the rules.
  toml-lint       Cleanup files with some simple toml formatting.
  validate-all    Check if all rules validates against a schema.
  validate-rule   Check if a rule staged in rules dir validates against a...
  view-rule       View an internal rule or specified rule file.
```

Note:
- If you are using a virtual environment, make sure to activate it before running the above command.
- If using Windows, you may have to also run `&lt;venv_directory&gt;\Scripts\pywin32_postinstall.py -install` depending on your python version.

The [contribution guide](CONTRIBUTING.md) describes how to use the `create-rule` and `test` commands to create and test a new rule when contributing to Detection Rules.

For more advanced command line interface (CLI) usage, refer to the [CLI guide](CLI.md).

## How to contribute

We welcome your contributions to Detection Rules! Before contributing, please familiarize yourself with this repository, its [directory structure](#overview-of-this-repository), and our [philosophy](PHILOSOPHY.md) about rule creation. When you&#039;re ready to contribute, read the [contribution guide](CONTRIBUTING.md) to learn how we turn detection ideas into production rules and validate with testing.

## Detections as Code (DaC)

The Detection Rules repo includes a number of commands to help one manage rules with an &quot;as code&quot; philosophy. We recommend starting with our [DaC Specific Documentation](https://dac-reference.readthedocs.io/en/latest/) for strategies and recommended setup information. However, if you would prefer to jump right in, please see our local [detections as code documentation](docs-dev/detections-as-code.md) and [custom rules documentation](docs-dev/custom-rules-management.md) for information on how to configure this repo for use with custom rules followed by our [CLI documentation](CLI.md) for information on our commands to import and export rules.

## RTAs

Red Team Automations (RTAs) used to emulate attacker techniques and verify the rules can be found in dedicated
repository - [Cortado](https://github.com/elastic/cortado).


## Licensing

Everything in this repository — rules, code, etc. — is licensed under the [Elastic License v2](LICENSE.txt). These rules are designed to be used in the context of the Detection Engine within the Elastic Security application. If you’re using our [Elastic Cloud managed service](https://www.elastic.co/cloud/) or the default distribution of the Elastic Stack software that includes the [full set of free features](https://www.elastic.co/subscriptions), you’ll get the latest rules the first time you navigate to the detection engine.

Occasionally, we may want to import rules from another repository that already have a license, such as MIT or Apache 2.0. This is welcome, as long as the license permits sublicensing under the Elastic License v2. We keep those license notices in `NOTICE.txt` and sublicense as the Elastic License v2 with all other rules. We also require contributors to sign a [Contributor License Agreement](https://www.elastic.co/contributor-agreement) before contributing code to any Elastic repositories.

## Questions? Problems? Suggestions?

- Want to know more about the Detection Engine? Check out the [overview](https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/security/current/detection-engine-overview.html) in Kibana.
- This repository includes new and updated rules that have not been released yet. To see the latest set of rules released with the stack, see the [Prebuilt rule reference](https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/security/current/prebuilt-rules-downloadable-updates.html).
- If you’d like to report a false positive or other type of bug, please create a GitHub issue and check if there&#039;s an existing one first.
- Need help with Detection Rules? Post an issue or ask away in our [Security Discuss Forum](https://discuss.elastic.co/c/security/) or the **#security-detection-rules** channel within [Slack workspace](https://www.elastic.co/blog/join-our-elastic-stack-workspace-on-slack).
- For DaC specific cases, pleases see our [support and scope documentation](docs-dev/detections-as-code.md#support-and-scope) for more information. </pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python">anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python</a></h1>
            <p></p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,941</p>
            <p>Forks: 267</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Anthropic Python API library

[![PyPI version](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/anthropic.svg)](https://pypi.org/project/anthropic/)

The Anthropic Python library provides convenient access to the Anthropic REST API from any Python 3.8+
application. It includes type definitions for all request params and response fields,
and offers both synchronous and asynchronous clients powered by [httpx](https://github.com/encode/httpx).

## Documentation

The REST API documentation can be found on [docs.anthropic.com](https://docs.anthropic.com/claude/reference/). The full API of this library can be found in [api.md](api.md).

## Installation

```sh
# install from PyPI
pip install anthropic
```

## Usage

The full API of this library can be found in [api.md](api.md).

```python
import os
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic(
    api_key=os.environ.get(&quot;ANTHROPIC_API_KEY&quot;),  # This is the default and can be omitted
)

message = client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
)
print(message.content)
```

While you can provide an `api_key` keyword argument,
we recommend using [python-dotenv](https://pypi.org/project/python-dotenv/)
to add `ANTHROPIC_API_KEY=&quot;my-anthropic-api-key&quot;` to your `.env` file
so that your API Key is not stored in source control.

## Async usage

Simply import `AsyncAnthropic` instead of `Anthropic` and use `await` with each API call:

```python
import os
import asyncio
from anthropic import AsyncAnthropic

client = AsyncAnthropic(
    api_key=os.environ.get(&quot;ANTHROPIC_API_KEY&quot;),  # This is the default and can be omitted
)


async def main() -&gt; None:
    message = await client.messages.create(
        max_tokens=1024,
        messages=[
            {
                &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
                &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
            }
        ],
        model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
    )
    print(message.content)


asyncio.run(main())
```

Functionality between the synchronous and asynchronous clients is otherwise identical.

## Streaming responses

We provide support for streaming responses using Server Side Events (SSE).

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()

stream = client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
    stream=True,
)
for event in stream:
    print(event.type)
```

The async client uses the exact same interface.

```python
from anthropic import AsyncAnthropic

client = AsyncAnthropic()

stream = await client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
    stream=True,
)
async for event in stream:
    print(event.type)
```

### Streaming Helpers

This library provides several conveniences for streaming messages, for example:

```py
import asyncio
from anthropic import AsyncAnthropic

client = AsyncAnthropic()

async def main() -&gt; None:
    async with client.messages.stream(
        max_tokens=1024,
        messages=[
            {
                &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
                &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Say hello there!&quot;,
            }
        ],
        model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
    ) as stream:
        async for text in stream.text_stream:
            print(text, end=&quot;&quot;, flush=True)
        print()

    message = await stream.get_final_message()
    print(message.to_json())

asyncio.run(main())
```

Streaming with `client.messages.stream(...)` exposes [various helpers for your convenience](helpers.md) including accumulation &amp; SDK-specific events.

Alternatively, you can use `client.messages.create(..., stream=True)` which only returns an async iterable of the events in the stream and thus uses less memory (it does not build up a final message object for you).

## Token counting

To get the token count for a message without creating it you can use the `client.beta.messages.count_tokens()` method. This takes the same `messages` list as the `.create()` method.

```py
count = client.beta.messages.count_tokens(
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-20241022&quot;,
    messages=[
        {&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, world&quot;}
    ]
)
count.input_tokens  # 10
```

You can also see the exact usage for a given request through the `usage` response property, e.g.

```py
message = client.messages.create(...)
message.usage
# Usage(input_tokens=25, output_tokens=13)
```

## Message Batches

This SDK provides beta support for the [Message Batches API](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/build-with-claude/message-batches) under the `client.beta.messages.batches` namespace.


### Creating a batch

Message Batches take the exact same request params as the standard Messages API:

```python
await client.beta.messages.batches.create(
    requests=[
        {
            &quot;custom_id&quot;: &quot;my-first-request&quot;,
            &quot;params&quot;: {
                &quot;model&quot;: &quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
                &quot;max_tokens&quot;: 1024,
                &quot;messages&quot;: [{&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, world&quot;}],
            },
        },
        {
            &quot;custom_id&quot;: &quot;my-second-request&quot;,
            &quot;params&quot;: {
                &quot;model&quot;: &quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
                &quot;max_tokens&quot;: 1024,
                &quot;messages&quot;: [{&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hi again, friend&quot;}],
            },
        },
    ]
)
```


### Getting results from a batch

Once a Message Batch has been processed, indicated by `.processing_status === &#039;ended&#039;`, you can access the results with `.batches.results()`

```python
result_stream = await client.beta.messages.batches.results(batch_id)
async for entry in result_stream:
    if entry.result.type == &quot;succeeded&quot;:
        print(entry.result.message.content)
```

## Tool use

This SDK provides support for tool use, aka function calling. More details can be found in [the documentation](https://docs.anthropic.com/claude/docs/tool-use).

## AWS Bedrock

This library also provides support for the [Anthropic Bedrock API](https://aws.amazon.com/bedrock/claude/) if you install this library with the `bedrock` extra, e.g. `pip install -U anthropic[bedrock]`.

You can then import and instantiate a separate `AnthropicBedrock` class, the rest of the API is the same.

```py
from anthropic import AnthropicBedrock

client = AnthropicBedrock()

message = client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello!&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;anthropic.claude-3-5-sonnet-20241022-v2:0&quot;,
)
print(message)
```

The bedrock client supports the following arguments for authentication

```py
AnthropicBedrock(
  aws_profile=&#039;...&#039;,
  aws_region=&#039;us-east&#039;
  aws_secret_key=&#039;...&#039;,
  aws_access_key=&#039;...&#039;,
  aws_session_token=&#039;...&#039;,
)
```

For a more fully fledged example see [`examples/bedrock.py`](https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python/blob/main/examples/bedrock.py).

## Google Vertex

This library also provides support for the [Anthropic Vertex API](https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=en) if you install this library with the `vertex` extra, e.g. `pip install -U anthropic[vertex]`.

You can then import and instantiate a separate `AnthropicVertex`/`AsyncAnthropicVertex` class, which has the same API as the base `Anthropic`/`AsyncAnthropic` class.

```py
from anthropic import AnthropicVertex

client = AnthropicVertex()

message = client.messages.create(
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-v2@20241022&quot;,
    max_tokens=100,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello!&quot;,
        }
    ],
)
print(message)
```

For a more complete example see [`examples/vertex.py`](https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python/blob/main/examples/vertex.py).

## Using types

Nested request parameters are [TypedDicts](https://docs.python.org/3/library/typing.html#typing.TypedDict). Responses are [Pydantic models](https://docs.pydantic.dev) which also provide helper methods for things like:

- Serializing back into JSON, `model.to_json()`
- Converting to a dictionary, `model.to_dict()`

Typed requests and responses provide autocomplete and documentation within your editor. If you would like to see type errors in VS Code to help catch bugs earlier, set `python.analysis.typeCheckingMode` to `basic`.

## Pagination

List methods in the Anthropic API are paginated.

This library provides auto-paginating iterators with each list response, so you do not have to request successive pages manually:

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()

all_batches = []
# Automatically fetches more pages as needed.
for batch in client.beta.messages.batches.list(
    limit=20,
):
    # Do something with batch here
    all_batches.append(batch)
print(all_batches)
```

Or, asynchronously:

```python
import asyncio
from anthropic import AsyncAnthropic

client = AsyncAnthropic()


async def main() -&gt; None:
    all_batches = []
    # Iterate through items across all pages, issuing requests as needed.
    async for batch in client.beta.messages.batches.list(
        limit=20,
    ):
        all_batches.append(batch)
    print(all_batches)


asyncio.run(main())
```

Alternatively, you can use the `.has_next_page()`, `.next_page_info()`, or `.get_next_page()` methods for more granular control working with pages:

```python
first_page = await client.beta.messages.batches.list(
    limit=20,
)
if first_page.has_next_page():
    print(f&quot;will fetch next page using these details: {first_page.next_page_info()}&quot;)
    next_page = await first_page.get_next_page()
    print(f&quot;number of items we just fetched: {len(next_page.data)}&quot;)

# Remove `await` for non-async usage.
```

Or just work directly with the returned data:

```python
first_page = await client.beta.messages.batches.list(
    limit=20,
)

print(f&quot;next page cursor: {first_page.last_id}&quot;)  # =&gt; &quot;next page cursor: ...&quot;
for batch in first_page.data:
    print(batch.id)

# Remove `await` for non-async usage.
```

## Nested params

Nested parameters are dictionaries, typed using `TypedDict`, for example:

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()

message = client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, world&quot;,
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-7-sonnet-20250219&quot;,
    metadata={&quot;user_id&quot;: &quot;13803d75-b4b5-4c3e-b2a2-6f21399b021b&quot;},
)
print(message.metadata)
```

## File uploads

Request parameters that correspond to file uploads can be passed as `bytes`, or a [`PathLike`](https://docs.python.org/3/library/os.html#os.PathLike) instance or a tuple of `(filename, contents, media type)`.

```python
from pathlib import Path
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()

client.beta.files.upload(
    file=Path(&quot;/path/to/file&quot;),
)
```

The async client uses the exact same interface. If you pass a [`PathLike`](https://docs.python.org/3/library/os.html#os.PathLike) instance, the file contents will be read asynchronously automatically.

## Handling errors

When the library is unable to connect to the API (for example, due to network connection problems or a timeout), a subclass of `anthropic.APIConnectionError` is raised.

When the API returns a non-success status code (that is, 4xx or 5xx
response), a subclass of `anthropic.APIStatusError` is raised, containing `status_code` and `response` properties.

All errors inherit from `anthropic.APIError`.

```python
import anthropic
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()

try:
    client.messages.create(
        max_tokens=1024,
        messages=[
            {
                &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
                &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
            }
        ],
        model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
    )
except anthropic.APIConnectionError as e:
    print(&quot;The server could not be reached&quot;)
    print(e.__cause__)  # an underlying Exception, likely raised within httpx.
except anthropic.RateLimitError as e:
    print(&quot;A 429 status code was received; we should back off a bit.&quot;)
except anthropic.APIStatusError as e:
    print(&quot;Another non-200-range status code was received&quot;)
    print(e.status_code)
    print(e.response)
```

Error codes are as follows:

| Status Code | Error Type                 |
| ----------- | -------------------------- |
| 400         | `BadRequestError`          |
| 401         | `AuthenticationError`      |
| 403         | `PermissionDeniedError`    |
| 404         | `NotFoundError`            |
| 422         | `UnprocessableEntityError` |
| 429         | `RateLimitError`           |
| &gt;=500       | `InternalServerError`      |
| N/A         | `APIConnectionError`       |

## Request IDs

&gt; For more information on debugging requests, see [these docs](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/api/errors#request-id)

All object responses in the SDK provide a `_request_id` property which is added from the `request-id` response header so that you can quickly log failing requests and report them back to Anthropic.

```python
message = client.messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
)
print(message._request_id)  # req_018EeWyXxfu5pfWkrYcMdjWG
```

Note that unlike other properties that use an `_` prefix, the `_request_id` property
*is* public. Unless documented otherwise, *all* other `_` prefix properties,
methods and modules are *private*.

### Retries

Certain errors are automatically retried 2 times by default, with a short exponential backoff.
Connection errors (for example, due to a network connectivity problem), 408 Request Timeout, 409 Conflict,
429 Rate Limit, and &gt;=500 Internal errors are all retried by default.

You can use the `max_retries` option to configure or disable retry settings:

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

# Configure the default for all requests:
client = Anthropic(
    # default is 2
    max_retries=0,
)

# Or, configure per-request:
client.with_options(max_retries=5).messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
)
```

### Timeouts

By default requests time out after 10 minutes. You can configure this with a `timeout` option,
which accepts a float or an [`httpx.Timeout`](https://www.python-httpx.org/advanced/#fine-tuning-the-configuration) object:

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

# Configure the default for all requests:
client = Anthropic(
    # 20 seconds (default is 10 minutes)
    timeout=20.0,
)

# More granular control:
client = Anthropic(
    timeout=httpx.Timeout(60.0, read=5.0, write=10.0, connect=2.0),
)

# Override per-request:
client.with_options(timeout=5.0).messages.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
)
```

On timeout, an `APITimeoutError` is thrown.

Note that requests that time out are [retried twice by default](#retries).

### Long Requests

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; We highly encourage you use the streaming [Messages API](#streaming-responses) for longer running requests.

We do not recommend setting a large `max_tokens` values without using streaming.
Some networks may drop idle connections after a certain period of time, which
can cause the request to fail or [timeout](#timeouts) without receiving a response from Anthropic.

This SDK will also throw a `ValueError` if a non-streaming request is expected to be above roughly 10 minutes long.
Passing `stream=True` or [overriding](#timeouts) the `timeout` option at the client or request level disables this error.

An expected request latency longer than the [timeout](#timeouts) for a non-streaming request
will result in the client terminating the connection and retrying without receiving a response.

We set a [TCP socket keep-alive](https://tldp.org/HOWTO/TCP-Keepalive-HOWTO/overview.html) option in order
to reduce the impact of idle connection timeouts on some networks.
This can be [overriden](#Configuring-the-HTTP-client) by passing a `http_client` option to the client.

## Default Headers

We automatically send the `anthropic-version` header set to `2023-06-01`.

If you need to, you can override it by setting default headers per-request or on the client object.

Be aware that doing so may result in incorrect types and other unexpected or undefined behavior in the SDK.

```python
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic(
    default_headers={&quot;anthropic-version&quot;: &quot;My-Custom-Value&quot;},
)
```

## Advanced

### Logging

We use the standard library [`logging`](https://docs.python.org/3/library/logging.html) module.

You can enable logging by setting the environment variable `ANTHROPIC_LOG` to `info`.

```shell
$ export ANTHROPIC_LOG=info
```

Or to `debug` for more verbose logging.

### How to tell whether `None` means `null` or missing

In an API response, a field may be explicitly `null`, or missing entirely; in either case, its value is `None` in this library. You can differentiate the two cases with `.model_fields_set`:

```py
if response.my_field is None:
  if &#039;my_field&#039; not in response.model_fields_set:
    print(&#039;Got json like {}, without a &quot;my_field&quot; key present at all.&#039;)
  else:
    print(&#039;Got json like {&quot;my_field&quot;: null}.&#039;)
```

### Accessing raw response data (e.g. headers)

The &quot;raw&quot; Response object can be accessed by prefixing `.with_raw_response.` to any HTTP method call, e.g.,

```py
from anthropic import Anthropic

client = Anthropic()
response = client.messages.with_raw_response.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[{
        &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
        &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
    }],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
)
print(response.headers.get(&#039;X-My-Header&#039;))

message = response.parse()  # get the object that `messages.create()` would have returned
print(message.content)
```

These methods return a [`LegacyAPIResponse`](https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python/tree/main/src/anthropic/_legacy_response.py) object. This is a legacy class as we&#039;re changing it slightly in the next major version.

For the sync client this will mostly be the same with the exception
of `content` &amp; `text` will be methods instead of properties. In the
async client, all methods will be async.

A migration script will be provided &amp; the migration in general should
be smooth.

#### `.with_streaming_response`

The above interface eagerly reads the full response body when you make the request, which may not always be what you want.

To stream the response body, use `.with_streaming_response` instead, which requires a context manager and only reads the response body once you call `.read()`, `.text()`, `.json()`, `.iter_bytes()`, `.iter_text()`, `.iter_lines()` or `.parse()`. In the async client, these are async methods.

As such, `.with_streaming_response` methods return a different [`APIResponse`](https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python/tree/main/src/anthropic/_response.py) object, and the async client returns an [`AsyncAPIResponse`](https://github.com/anthropics/anthropic-sdk-python/tree/main/src/anthropic/_response.py) object.

```python
with client.messages.with_streaming_response.create(
    max_tokens=1024,
    messages=[
        {
            &quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: &quot;Hello, Claude&quot;,
        }
    ],
    model=&quot;claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
) as response:
    print(response.headers.get(&quot;X-My-Header&quot;))

    for line in response.iter_lines():
        print(line)
```

The context manager is required so that the response will reliably be closed.

### Making custom/undocumented requests

This library is typed for convenient 

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[city96/ComfyUI-GGUF]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[GGUF Quantization support for native ComfyUI models]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF">city96/ComfyUI-GGUF</a></h1>
            <p>GGUF Quantization support for native ComfyUI models</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,997</p>
            <p>Forks: 126</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># ComfyUI-GGUF
GGUF Quantization support for native ComfyUI models

This is currently very much WIP. These custom nodes provide support for model files stored in the GGUF format popularized by [llama.cpp](https://github.com/ggerganov/llama.cpp).

While quantization wasn&#039;t feasible for regular UNET models (conv2d), transformer/DiT models such as flux seem less affected by quantization. This allows running it in much lower bits per weight variable bitrate quants on low-end GPUs. For further VRAM savings, a node to load a quantized version of the T5 text encoder is also included.

![Comfy_Flux1_dev_Q4_0_GGUF_1024](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/70d16d97-c522-4ef4-9435-633f128644c8)

Note: The &quot;Force/Set CLIP Device&quot; is **NOT** part of this node pack. Do not install it if you only have one GPU. Do not set it to cuda:0 then complain about OOM errors if you do not undestand what it is for. There is not need to copy the workflow above, just use your own workflow and replace the stock &quot;Load Diffusion Model&quot; with the &quot;Unet Loader (GGUF)&quot; node.

## Installation

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]  
&gt; Make sure your ComfyUI is on a recent-enough version to support custom ops when loading the UNET-only.

To install the custom node normally, git clone this repository into your custom nodes folder (`ComfyUI/custom_nodes`) and install the only dependency for inference (`pip install --upgrade gguf`)

```
git clone https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF
```

To install the custom node on a standalone ComfyUI release, open a CMD inside the &quot;ComfyUI_windows_portable&quot; folder (where your `run_nvidia_gpu.bat` file is) and use the following commands:

```
git clone https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF ComfyUI/custom_nodes/ComfyUI-GGUF
.\python_embeded\python.exe -s -m pip install -r .\ComfyUI\custom_nodes\ComfyUI-GGUF\requirements.txt
```

On MacOS sequoia, torch 2.4.1 seems to be required, as 2.6.X nightly versions cause a &quot;M1 buffer is not large enough&quot; error. See [this issue](https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF/issues/107) for more information/workarounds.

## Usage

Simply use the GGUF Unet loader found under the `bootleg` category. Place the .gguf model files in your `ComfyUI/models/unet` folder.

LoRA loading is experimental but it should work with just the built-in LoRA loader node(s).

Pre-quantized models:

- [flux1-dev GGUF](https://huggingface.co/city96/FLUX.1-dev-gguf)
- [flux1-schnell GGUF](https://huggingface.co/city96/FLUX.1-schnell-gguf)
- [stable-diffusion-3.5-large GGUF](https://huggingface.co/city96/stable-diffusion-3.5-large-gguf)
- [stable-diffusion-3.5-large-turbo GGUF](https://huggingface.co/city96/stable-diffusion-3.5-large-turbo-gguf)

Initial support for quantizing T5 has also been added recently, these can be used using the various `*CLIPLoader (gguf)` nodes which can be used inplace of the regular ones. For the CLIP model, use whatever model you were using before for CLIP. The loader can handle both types of files - `gguf` and regular `safetensors`/`bin`.

- [t5_v1.1-xxl GGUF](https://huggingface.co/city96/t5-v1_1-xxl-encoder-gguf)

See the instructions in the [tools](https://github.com/city96/ComfyUI-GGUF/tree/main/tools) folder for how to create your own quants.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[trycua/cua]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/trycua/cua</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/trycua/cua</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[c/ua is the Docker Container for Computer-Use AI Agents.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/trycua/cua">trycua/cua</a></h1>
            <p>c/ua is the Docker Container for Computer-Use AI Agents.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,949</p>
            <p>Forks: 326</p>
            <p>Stars today: 117 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; alt=&quot;Cua logo&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; srcset=&quot;img/logo_white.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; alt=&quot;Cua logo&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; srcset=&quot;img/logo_black.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Cua logo&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;img/logo_black.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

  [![Python](https://img.shields.io/badge/Python-333333?logo=python&amp;logoColor=white&amp;labelColor=333333)](#)
  [![Swift](https://img.shields.io/badge/Swift-F05138?logo=swift&amp;logoColor=white)](#)
  [![macOS](https://img.shields.io/badge/macOS-000000?logo=apple&amp;logoColor=F0F0F0)](#)
  [![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-%235865F2.svg?&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.com/invite/mVnXXpdE85)
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13685&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13685&quot; alt=&quot;trycua%2Fcua | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

**c/ua** (pronounced &quot;koo-ah&quot;) enables AI agents to control full operating systems in high-performance virtual containers with near-native speed on Apple Silicon.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c619b4ea-bb8e-4382-860e-f3757e36af20&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; controls&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

# 🚀 Quick Start

Get started with a Computer-Use Agent UI and a VM with a single command:


```bash
/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/trycua/cua/main/scripts/playground.sh)&quot;
```


This script will:
- Install Lume CLI for VM management (if needed)
- Pull the latest macOS CUA image (if needed)
- Set up Python environment and install/update required packages
- Launch the Computer-Use Agent UI

#### Supported [Agent Loops](https://github.com/trycua/cua/blob/main/libs/agent/README.md#agent-loops)
- [UITARS-1.5](https://github.com/trycua/cua/blob/main/libs/agent/README.md#agent-loops) - Run locally on Apple Silicon with MLX, or use cloud providers
- [OpenAI CUA](https://github.com/trycua/cua/blob/main/libs/agent/README.md#agent-loops) - Use OpenAI&#039;s Computer-Use Preview model
- [Anthropic CUA](https://github.com/trycua/cua/blob/main/libs/agent/README.md#agent-loops) - Use Anthropic&#039;s Computer-Use capabilities
- [OmniParser-v2.0](https://github.com/trycua/cua/blob/main/libs/agent/README.md#agent-loops) - Control UI with [Set-of-Marks prompting](https://som-gpt4v.github.io/) using any vision model

### System Requirements

- Mac with Apple Silicon (M1/M2/M3/M4 series)
- macOS 15 (Sequoia) or newer
- Disk space for VM images (30GB+ recommended)


# 💻 For Developers

### Step 1: Install Lume CLI

```bash
/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/trycua/cua/main/libs/lume/scripts/install.sh)&quot;
```

Lume CLI manages high-performance macOS/Linux VMs with near-native speed on Apple Silicon.

### Step 2: Pull the macOS CUA Image

```bash
lume pull macos-sequoia-cua:latest
```

The macOS CUA image contains the default Mac apps and the Computer Server for easy automation.

### Step 3: Install Python SDK

```bash
pip install &quot;cua-computer[all]&quot; &quot;cua-agent[all]&quot;
```

Alternatively, see the [Developer Guide](./docs/Developer-Guide.md) for building from source.

### Step 4: Use in Your Code

```python
from computer import Computer
from agent import ComputerAgent, LLM

async def main():
    # Start a local macOS VM with a 1024x768 display
    async with Computer(os_type=&quot;macos&quot;, display=&quot;1024x768&quot;) as computer:

        # Example: Direct control of a macOS VM with Computer
        await computer.interface.left_click(100, 200)
        await computer.interface.type_text(&quot;Hello, world!&quot;)
        screenshot_bytes = await computer.interface.screenshot()
        
        # Example: Create and run an agent locally using mlx-community/UI-TARS-1.5-7B-6bit
        agent = ComputerAgent(
          computer=computer,
          loop=&quot;UITARS&quot;,
          model=LLM(provider=&quot;MLXVLM&quot;, name=&quot;mlx-community/UI-TARS-1.5-7B-6bit&quot;)
        )
        await agent.run(&quot;Find the trycua/cua repository on GitHub and follow the quick start guide&quot;)

main()
```

For ready-to-use examples, check out our [Notebooks](./notebooks/) collection.

### Lume CLI Reference

```bash
# Install Lume CLI and background service
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/trycua/cua/main/libs/lume/scripts/install.sh | bash

# List all VMs
lume ls

# Pull a VM image
lume pull macos-sequoia-cua:latest

# Create a new VM
lume create my-vm --os macos --cpu 4 --memory 8GB --disk-size 50GB

# Run a VM (creates and starts if it doesn&#039;t exist)
lume run macos-sequoia-cua:latest

# Stop a VM
lume stop macos-sequoia-cua_latest

# Delete a VM
lume delete macos-sequoia-cua_latest
```

### Lumier CLI Reference

For advanced container-like virtualization, check out [Lumier](./libs/lumier/README.md) - a Docker interface for macOS and Linux VMs.

```bash
# Install Lume CLI and background service
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/trycua/cua/main/libs/lume/scripts/install.sh | bash

# Run macOS in a Docker container
docker run -it --rm \
    --name lumier-vm \
    -p 8006:8006 \
    -v $(pwd)/storage:/storage \
    -v $(pwd)/shared:/shared \
    -e VM_NAME=lumier-vm \
    -e VERSION=ghcr.io/trycua/macos-sequoia-cua:latest \
    -e CPU_CORES=4 \
    -e RAM_SIZE=8192 \
    -e HOST_STORAGE_PATH=$(pwd)/storage \
    -e HOST_SHARED_PATH=$(pwd)/shared \
    trycua/lumier:latest
```

## Resources

- [How to use the MCP Server with Claude Desktop or other MCP clients](./libs/mcp-server/README.md) - One of the easiest ways to get started with C/ua
- [How to use OpenAI Computer-Use, Anthropic, OmniParser, or UI-TARS for your Computer-Use Agent](./libs/agent/README.md)
- [How to use Lume CLI for managing desktops](./libs/lume/README.md)
- [Training Computer-Use Models: Collecting Human Trajectories with C/ua (Part 1)](https://www.trycua.com/blog/training-computer-use-models-trajectories-1)
- [Build Your Own Operator on macOS (Part 1)](https://www.trycua.com/blog/build-your-own-operator-on-macos-1)

## Modules

| Module | Description | Installation |
|--------|-------------|---------------|
| [**Lume**](./libs/lume/README.md) | VM management for macOS/Linux using Apple&#039;s Virtualization.Framework | `curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/trycua/cua/main/libs/lume/scripts/install.sh \| bash` |
| [**Lumier**](./libs/lumier/README.md) | Docker interface for macOS and Linux VMs | `docker pull trycua/lumier:latest` |
| [**Computer**](./libs/computer/README.md) | Interface for controlling virtual machines | `pip install &quot;cua-computer[all]&quot;` |
| [**Agent**](./libs/agent/README.md) | AI agent framework for automating tasks | `pip install &quot;cua-agent[all]&quot;` |
| [**MCP Server**](./libs/mcp-server/README.md) | MCP server for using CUA with Claude Desktop | `pip install cua-mcp-server` |
| [**SOM**](./libs/som/README.md) | Self-of-Mark library for Agent | `pip install cua-som` |
| [**PyLume**](./libs/pylume/README.md) | Python bindings for Lume | `pip install pylume` |
| [**Computer Server**](./libs/computer-server/README.md) | Server component for Computer | `pip install cua-computer-server` |
| [**Core**](./libs/core/README.md) | Core utilities | `pip install cua-core` |

## Computer Interface Reference

For complete examples, see [computer_examples.py](./examples/computer_examples.py) or [computer_nb.ipynb](./notebooks/computer_nb.ipynb)

```python
# Mouse Actions
await computer.interface.left_click(x, y)       # Left click at coordinates
await computer.interface.right_click(x, y)      # Right click at coordinates
await computer.interface.double_click(x, y)     # Double click at coordinates
await computer.interface.move_cursor(x, y)      # Move cursor to coordinates
await computer.interface.drag_to(x, y, duration)  # Drag to coordinates
await computer.interface.get_cursor_position()  # Get current cursor position

# Keyboard Actions
await computer.interface.type_text(&quot;Hello&quot;)     # Type text
await computer.interface.press_key(&quot;enter&quot;)     # Press a single key
await computer.interface.hotkey(&quot;command&quot;, &quot;c&quot;) # Press key combination

# Screen Actions
await computer.interface.screenshot()           # Take a screenshot
await computer.interface.get_screen_size()      # Get screen dimensions

# Clipboard Actions
await computer.interface.set_clipboard(text)    # Set clipboard content
await computer.interface.copy_to_clipboard()    # Get clipboard content

# File System Operations
await computer.interface.file_exists(path)      # Check if file exists
await computer.interface.directory_exists(path) # Check if directory exists
await computer.interface.run_command(cmd)       # Run shell command

# Accessibility
await computer.interface.get_accessibility_tree() # Get accessibility tree
```

## ComputerAgent Reference

For complete examples, see [agent_examples.py](./examples/agent_examples.py) or [agent_nb.ipynb](./notebooks/agent_nb.ipynb)

```python
# Import necessary components
from agent import ComputerAgent, LLM, AgentLoop, LLMProvider

# UI-TARS-1.5 agent for local execution with MLX
ComputerAgent(loop=AgentLoop.UITARS, model=LLM(provider=LLMProvider.MLXVLM, name=&quot;mlx-community/UI-TARS-1.5-7B-6bit&quot;))   
# OpenAI Computer-Use agent using OPENAI_API_KEY  
ComputerAgent(loop=AgentLoop.OPENAI, model=LLM(provider=LLMProvider.OPENAI, name=&quot;computer-use-preview&quot;))
# Anthropic Claude agent using ANTHROPIC_API_KEY
ComputerAgent(loop=AgentLoop.ANTHROPIC, model=LLM(provider=LLMProvider.ANTHROPIC))

# OmniParser loop for UI control using Set-of-Marks (SOM) prompting and any vision LLM
ComputerAgent(loop=AgentLoop.OMNI, model=LLM(provider=LLMProvider.OLLAMA, name=&quot;gemma3:12b-it-q4_K_M&quot;))      
# OpenRouter example using OAICOMPAT provider
ComputerAgent(
    loop=AgentLoop.OMNI,
    model=LLM(
        provider=LLMProvider.OAICOMPAT, 
        name=&quot;openai/gpt-4o-mini&quot;,
        provider_base_url=&quot;https://openrouter.ai/api/v1&quot;
    ),
    api_key=&quot;your-openrouter-api-key&quot;
)
```

## Demos

Check out these demos of the Computer-Use Agent in action:

&lt;details open&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;MCP Server: Work with Claude Desktop and Tableau&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/9f573547-5149-493e-9a72-396f3cff29df&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; controls&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;AI-Gradio: Multi-app workflow with browser, VS Code and terminal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/723a115d-1a07-4c8e-b517-88fbdf53ed0f&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; controls&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notebook: Fix GitHub issue in Cursor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f67f0107-a1e1-46dc-aa9f-0146eb077077&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; controls&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

## Community

Join our [Discord community](https://discord.com/invite/mVnXXpdE85) to discuss ideas, get assistance, or share your demos!

## License

Cua is open-sourced under the MIT License - see the [LICENSE](LICENSE) file for details.

Microsoft&#039;s OmniParser, which is used in this project, is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License (CC-BY-4.0) - see the [OmniParser LICENSE](https://github.com/microsoft/OmniParser/blob/master/LICENSE) file for details.

## Contributing

We welcome contributions to CUA! Please refer to our [Contributing Guidelines](CONTRIBUTING.md) for details.

## Trademarks

Apple, macOS, and Apple Silicon are trademarks of Apple Inc. Ubuntu and Canonical are registered trademarks of Canonical Ltd. Microsoft is a registered trademark of Microsoft Corporation. This project is not affiliated with, endorsed by, or sponsored by Apple Inc., Canonical Ltd., or Microsoft Corporation.

## Stargazers

Thank you to all our supporters!

[![Stargazers over time](https://starchart.cc/trycua/cua.svg?variant=adaptive)](https://starchart.cc/trycua/cua)

## Contributors

&lt;!-- ALL-CONTRIBUTORS-LIST:START - Do not remove or modify this section --&gt;
&lt;!-- prettier-ignore-start --&gt;
&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable --&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/f-trycua&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/195596869?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;f-trycua&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;f-trycua&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-f-trycua&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pepicrft.me&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/663605?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Pedro Piñera Buendía&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pedro Piñera Buendía&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-pepicrft&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iamit.in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/5647941?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Amit Kumar&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Amit Kumar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-aktech&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://productsway.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/870029?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Dung Duc Huynh (Kaka)&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dung Duc Huynh (Kaka)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-jellydn&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zaydkrunz.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/70227235?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Zayd Krunz&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zayd Krunz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-ShrootBuck&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PrashantRaj18198&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/23168997?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Prashant Raj&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prashant Raj&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-PrashantRaj18198&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobile.dev&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/847683?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Leland Takamine&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Leland Takamine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-Leland-Takamine&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ddupont808&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/3820588?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;ddupont&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;ddupont&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-ddupont808&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Lizzard1123&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/46036335?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Ethan Gutierrez&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ethan Gutierrez&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-Lizzard1123&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ricterz.me&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/5282759?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Ricter Zheng&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ricter Zheng&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-RicterZ&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trytruffle.ai/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/50844303?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Rahul Karajgikar&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rahul Karajgikar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-rahulkarajgikar&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/trospix&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/81363696?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;trospix&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;trospix&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-trospix&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wavee.world/invitation/b96d00e6-b802-4a1b-8a66-2e3854a01ffd&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/22633385?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Ikko Eltociear Ashimine&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ikko Eltociear Ashimine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-eltociear&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dp221125&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/10572119?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;한석호(MilKyo)&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;한석호(MilKyo)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-dp221125&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.encona.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/891558?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Rahim Nathwani&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rahim Nathwani&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-rahimnathwani&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mjspeck.github.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/20689127?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Matt Speck&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Matt Speck&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-mjspeck&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FinnBorge&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/9272726?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;FinnBorge&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;FinnBorge&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-FinnBorge&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jklapacz&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/5343758?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Jakub Klapacz&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jakub Klapacz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-jklapacz&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; width=&quot;14.28%&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/evnsnclr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/139897548?v=4?s=100&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Evan smith&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evan smith&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#code-evnsnclr&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!-- markdownlint-restore --&gt;
&lt;!-- prettier-ignore-end --&gt;

&lt;!-- ALL-CONTRIBUTORS-LIST:END --&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[llmware-ai/llmware]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Unified framework for building enterprise RAG pipelines with small, specialized models]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware">llmware-ai/llmware</a></h1>
            <p>Unified framework for building enterprise RAG pipelines with small, specialized models</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 13,665</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,631</p>
            <p>Stars today: 74 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># llmware
![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.9_%7C_3.10%7C_3.11%7C_3.12%7C_3.13-blue?color=blue)
![PyPI - Version](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/llmware?color=blue)
[![discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Chat%20on-Discord-blue?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/MhZn5Nc39h)   
[![Documentation](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/actions/workflows/pages.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/actions/workflows/pages.yml)  

🆕Check out [Model Depot](https://medium.com/@darrenoberst/model-depot-9e6625c5fc55)  
Are you using a Windows/Linux x86 machine?  
- Getting started with [OpenVino example](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/blob/main/examples/Models/using_openvino_models.py)  
- Getting started with [ONNX example](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/blob/main/examples/Models/using_onnx_models.py)  

## Table of Contents

- [Building Enterprise RAG Pipelines with Small, Specialized Models](%EF%B8%8Fbuilding-enterprise-rag-pipelines-with-small-specialized-models)
- [Key Features](#--key-features)
- [What&#039;s New](#️-whats-new)
- [Getting Started](#-getting-started)
- [Working with the llmware Github repository](#%EF%B8%8F-working-with-the-llmware-github-repository)
- [Data Store Options](#data-store-options)
- [Meet our Models](#meet-our-models)
- [Using LLMs and setting-up API keys &amp; secrets](#using-llms-and-setting-up-api-keys--secrets)
- [Release notes and Change Log](#--release-notes-and-change-log)

## 🧰🛠️🔩Building Enterprise RAG Pipelines with Small, Specialized Models  

`llmware` provides a unified framework for building LLM-based applications (e.g., RAG, Agents), using small, specialized models that can be deployed privately, integrated with enterprise knowledge sources safely and securely, and cost-effectively tuned and adapted for any business process.  

 `llmware` has two main components:  
 
 1.  **RAG Pipeline** - integrated components for the full lifecycle of connecting knowledge sources to generative AI models; and 

 2.  **50+ small, specialized models** fine-tuned for key tasks in enterprise process automation, including fact-based question-answering, classification, summarization, and extraction.  

By bringing together both of these components, along with integrating leading open source models and underlying technologies, `llmware` offers a comprehensive set of tools to rapidly build knowledge-based enterprise LLM applications.  

Most of our examples can be run without a GPU server - get started right away on your laptop.   

[Join us on Discord](https://discord.gg/MhZn5Nc39h)   |  [Watch Youtube Tutorials](https://www.youtube.com/@llmware)  | [Explore our Model Families on Huggingface](https://www.huggingface.co/llmware)   

New to Agents?  [Check out the Agent Fast Start series](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/tree/main/fast_start/agents)  

New to RAG?  [Check out the Fast Start video series](https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL1-dn33KwsmD7SB9iSO6vx4ZLRAWea1DB)  

🔥🔥🔥 [**Multi-Model Agents with SLIM Models**](examples/SLIM-Agents/) - [**Intro-Video**](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cQfdaTcmBpY) 🔥🔥🔥   

[Intro to SLIM Function Call Models](https://github.com/llmware-ai/llmware/blob/main/examples/Models/using_function_calls.py)  
Can&#039;t wait?  Get SLIMs right away:  

```python 
from llmware.models import ModelCatalog

ModelCatalog().get_llm_toolkit()  # get all SLIM models, delivered as small, fast quantized tools 
ModelCatalog().tool_test_run(&quot;slim-sentiment-tool&quot;) # see the model in action with test script included  
```

## 🎯  Key features 
Writing code with`llmware` is based on a few main concepts:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Model Catalog&lt;/b&gt;: Access all models the same way with easy lookup, regardless of underlying implementation. 
&lt;/summary&gt;  


```python
#   150+ Models in Catalog with 50+ RAG-optimized BLING, DRAGON and Industry BERT models
#   Full support for GGUF, HuggingFace, Sentence Transformers and major API-based models
#   Easy to extend to add custom models - see examples

from llmware.models import ModelCatalog
from llmware.prompts import Prompt

#   all models accessed through the ModelCatalog
models = ModelCatalog().list_all_models()

#   to use any model in the ModelCatalog - &quot;load_model&quot; method and pass the model_name parameter
my_model = ModelCatalog().load_model(&quot;llmware/bling-phi-3-gguf&quot;)
output = my_model.inference(&quot;what is the future of AI?&quot;, add_context=&quot;Here is the article to read&quot;)

#   to integrate model into a Prompt
prompter = Prompt().load_model(&quot;llmware/bling-tiny-llama-v0&quot;)
response = prompter.prompt_main(&quot;what is the future of AI?&quot;, context=&quot;Insert Sources of information&quot;)
```

&lt;/details&gt;  

&lt;details&gt;  
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Library&lt;/b&gt;:  ingest, organize and index a collection of knowledge at scale - Parse, Text Chunk and Embed. &lt;/summary&gt;  

```python

from llmware.library import Library

#   to parse and text chunk a set of documents (pdf, pptx, docx, xlsx, txt, csv, md, json/jsonl, wav, png, jpg, html)  

#   step 1 - create a library, which is the &#039;knowledge-base container&#039; construct
#          - libraries have both text collection (DB) resources, and file resources (e.g., llmware_data/accounts/{library_name})
#          - embeddings and queries are run against a library

lib = Library().create_new_library(&quot;my_library&quot;)

#    step 2 - add_files is the universal ingestion function - point it at a local file folder with mixed file types
#           - files will be routed by file extension to the correct parser, parsed, text chunked and indexed in text collection DB

lib.add_files(&quot;/folder/path/to/my/files&quot;)

#   to install an embedding on a library - pick an embedding model and vector_db
lib.install_new_embedding(embedding_model_name=&quot;mini-lm-sbert&quot;, vector_db=&quot;milvus&quot;, batch_size=500)

#   to add a second embedding to the same library (mix-and-match models + vector db)  
lib.install_new_embedding(embedding_model_name=&quot;industry-bert-sec&quot;, vector_db=&quot;chromadb&quot;, batch_size=100)

#   easy to create multiple libraries for different projects and groups

finance_lib = Library().create_new_library(&quot;finance_q4_2023&quot;)
finance_lib.add_files(&quot;/finance_folder/&quot;)

hr_lib = Library().create_new_library(&quot;hr_policies&quot;)
hr_lib.add_files(&quot;/hr_folder/&quot;)

#    pull library card with key metadata - documents, text chunks, images, tables, embedding record
lib_card = Library().get_library_card(&quot;my_library&quot;)

#   see all libraries
all_my_libs = Library().get_all_library_cards()

```
&lt;/details&gt;  

&lt;details&gt; 
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Query&lt;/b&gt;: query libraries with mix of text, semantic, hybrid, metadata, and custom filters. &lt;/summary&gt;

```python

from llmware.retrieval import Query
from llmware.library import Library

#   step 1 - load the previously created library 
lib = Library().load_library(&quot;my_library&quot;)

#   step 2 - create a query object and pass the library
q = Query(lib)

#    step 3 - run lots of different queries  (many other options in the examples)

#    basic text query
results1 = q.text_query(&quot;text query&quot;, result_count=20, exact_mode=False)

#    semantic query
results2 = q.semantic_query(&quot;semantic query&quot;, result_count=10)

#    combining a text query restricted to only certain documents in the library and &quot;exact&quot; match to the query
results3 = q.text_query_with_document_filter(&quot;new query&quot;, {&quot;file_name&quot;: &quot;selected file name&quot;}, exact_mode=True)

#   to apply a specific embedding (if multiple on library), pass the names when creating the query object
q2 = Query(lib, embedding_model_name=&quot;mini_lm_sbert&quot;, vector_db=&quot;milvus&quot;)
results4 = q2.semantic_query(&quot;new semantic query&quot;)
```

&lt;/details&gt;  

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prompt with Sources&lt;/b&gt;: the easiest way to combine knowledge retrieval with a LLM inference. &lt;/summary&gt;

```python

from llmware.prompts import Prompt
from llmware.retrieval import Query
from llmware.library import Library

#   build a prompt
prompter = Prompt().load_model(&quot;llmware/bling-tiny-llama-v0&quot;)

#   add a file -&gt; file is parsed, text chunked, filtered by query, and then packaged as model-ready context,
#   including in batches, if needed, to fit the model context window

source = prompter.add_source_document(&quot;/folder/to/one/doc/&quot;, &quot;filename&quot;, query=&quot;fast query&quot;)

#   attach query results (from a Query) into a Prompt
my_lib = Library().load_library(&quot;my_library&quot;)
results = Query(my_lib).query(&quot;my query&quot;)
source2 = prompter.add_source_query_results(results)

#   run a new query against a library and load directly into a prompt
source3 = prompter.add_source_new_query(my_lib, query=&quot;my new query&quot;, query_type=&quot;semantic&quot;, result_count=15)

#   to run inference with &#039;prompt with sources&#039;
responses = prompter.prompt_with_source(&quot;my query&quot;)

#   to run fact-checks - post inference
fact_check = prompter.evidence_check_sources(responses)

#   to view source materials (batched &#039;model-ready&#039; and attached to prompt)
source_materials = prompter.review_sources_summary()

#   to see the full prompt history
prompt_history = prompter.get_current_history()
```

&lt;/details&gt;  

&lt;details&gt; 
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;RAG-Optimized Models&lt;/b&gt; -  1-7B parameter models designed for RAG workflow integration and running locally. &lt;/summary&gt;  

```
&quot;&quot;&quot; This &#039;Hello World&#039; example demonstrates how to get started using local BLING models with provided context, using both
Pytorch and GGUF versions. &quot;&quot;&quot;

import time
from llmware.prompts import Prompt


def hello_world_questions():

    test_list = [

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;What is the total amount of the invoice?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;$22,500.00&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;Services Vendor Inc. \n100 Elm Street Pleasantville, NY \nTO Alpha Inc. 5900 1st Street &quot;
                &quot;Los Angeles, CA \nDescription Front End Engineering Service $5000.00 \n Back End Engineering&quot;
                &quot; Service $7500.00 \n Quality Assurance Manager $10,000.00 \n Total Amount $22,500.00 \n&quot;
                &quot;Make all checks payable to Services Vendor Inc. Payment is due within 30 days.&quot;
                &quot;If you have any questions concerning this invoice, contact Bia Hermes. &quot;
                &quot;THANK YOU FOR YOUR BUSINESS!  INVOICE INVOICE # 0001 DATE 01/01/2022 FOR Alpha Project P.O. # 1000&quot;},

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;What was the amount of the trade surplus?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;62.4 billion yen ($416.6 million)&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;Japan’s September trade balance swings into surplus, surprising expectations&quot;
                &quot;Japan recorded a trade surplus of 62.4 billion yen ($416.6 million) for September, &quot;
                &quot;beating expectations from economists polled by Reuters for a trade deficit of 42.5 &quot;
                &quot;billion yen. Data from Japan’s customs agency revealed that exports in September &quot;
                &quot;increased 4.3% year on year, while imports slid 16.3% compared to the same period &quot;
                &quot;last year. According to FactSet, exports to Asia fell for the ninth straight month, &quot;
                &quot;which reflected ongoing China weakness. Exports were supported by shipments to &quot;
                &quot;Western markets, FactSet added. — Lim Hui Jie&quot;},

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;When did the LISP machine market collapse?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;1987.&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;The attendees became the leaders of AI research in the 1960s.&quot;
                &quot;  They and their students produced programs that the press described as &#039;astonishing&#039;: &quot;
                &quot;computers were learning checkers strategies, solving word problems in algebra, &quot;
                &quot;proving logical theorems and speaking English.  By the middle of the 1960s, research in &quot;
                &quot;the U.S. was heavily funded by the Department of Defense and laboratories had been &quot;
                &quot;established around the world. Herbert Simon predicted, &#039;machines will be capable, &quot;
                &quot;within twenty years, of doing any work a man can do&#039;.  Marvin Minsky agreed, writing, &quot;
                &quot;&#039;within a generation ... the problem of creating &#039;artificial intelligence&#039; will &quot;
                &quot;substantially be solved&#039;. They had, however, underestimated the difficulty of the problem.  &quot;
                &quot;Both the U.S. and British governments cut off exploratory research in response &quot;
                &quot;to the criticism of Sir James Lighthill and ongoing pressure from the US Congress &quot;
                &quot;to fund more productive projects. Minsky&#039;s and Papert&#039;s book Perceptrons was understood &quot;
                &quot;as proving that artificial neural networks approach would never be useful for solving &quot;
                &quot;real-world tasks, thus discrediting the approach altogether.  The &#039;AI winter&#039;, a period &quot;
                &quot;when obtaining funding for AI projects was difficult, followed.  In the early 1980s, &quot;
                &quot;AI research was revived by the commercial success of expert systems, a form of AI &quot;
                &quot;program that simulated the knowledge and analytical skills of human experts. By 1985, &quot;
                &quot;the market for AI had reached over a billion dollars. At the same time, Japan&#039;s fifth &quot;
                &quot;generation computer project inspired the U.S. and British governments to restore funding &quot;
                &quot;for academic research. However, beginning with the collapse of the Lisp Machine market &quot;
                &quot;in 1987, AI once again fell into disrepute, and a second, longer-lasting winter began.&quot;},

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;What is the current rate on 10-year treasuries?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;4.58%&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;Stocks rallied Friday even after the release of stronger-than-expected U.S. jobs data &quot;
                &quot;and a major increase in Treasury yields.  The Dow Jones Industrial Average gained 195.12 points, &quot;
                &quot;or 0.76%, to close at 31,419.58. The S&amp;P 500 added 1.59% at 4,008.50. The tech-heavy &quot;
                &quot;Nasdaq Composite rose 1.35%, closing at 12,299.68. The U.S. economy added 438,000 jobs in &quot;
                &quot;August, the Labor Department said. Economists polled by Dow Jones expected 273,000 &quot;
                &quot;jobs. However, wages rose less than expected last month.  Stocks posted a stunning &quot;
                &quot;turnaround on Friday, after initially falling on the stronger-than-expected jobs report. &quot;
                &quot;At its session low, the Dow had fallen as much as 198 points; it surged by more than &quot;
                &quot;500 points at the height of the rally. The Nasdaq and the S&amp;P 500 slid by 0.8% during &quot;
                &quot;their lowest points in the day.  Traders were unclear of the reason for the intraday &quot;
                &quot;reversal. Some noted it could be the softer wage number in the jobs report that made &quot;
                &quot;investors rethink their earlier bearish stance. Others noted the pullback in yields from &quot;
                &quot;the day’s highs. Part of the rally may just be to do a market that had gotten extremely &quot;
                &quot;oversold with the S&amp;P 500 at one point this week down more than 9% from its high earlier &quot;
                &quot;this year.  Yields initially surged after the report, with the 10-year Treasury rate trading &quot;
                &quot;near its highest level in 14 years. The benchmark rate later eased from those levels, but &quot;
                &quot;was still up around 6 basis points at 4.58%.  &#039;We’re seeing a little bit of a give back &quot;
                &quot;in yields from where we were around 4.8%. [With] them pulling back a bit, I think that’s &quot;
                &quot;helping the stock market,&#039; said Margaret Jones, chief investment officer at Vibrant Industries &quot;
                &quot;Capital Advisors. &#039;We’ve had a lot of weakness in the market in recent weeks, and potentially &quot;
                &quot;some oversold conditions.&#039;&quot;},

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;Is the expected gross margin greater than 70%?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;Yes, between 71.5% and 72.%&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;Outlook NVIDIA’s outlook for the third quarter of fiscal 2024 is as follows:&quot;
                &quot;Revenue is expected to be $16.00 billion, plus or minus 2%. GAAP and non-GAAP &quot;
                &quot;gross margins are expected to be 71.5% and 72.5%, respectively, plus or minus &quot;
                &quot;50 basis points.  GAAP and non-GAAP operating expenses are expected to be &quot;
                &quot;approximately $2.95 billion and $2.00 billion, respectively.  GAAP and non-GAAP &quot;
                &quot;other income and expense are expected to be an income of approximately $100 &quot;
                &quot;million, excluding gains and losses from non-affiliated investments. GAAP and &quot;
                &quot;non-GAAP tax rates are expected to be 14.5%, plus or minus 1%, excluding any discrete items.&quot;
                &quot;Highlights NVIDIA achieved progress since its previous earnings announcement &quot;
                &quot;in these areas:  Data Center Second-quarter revenue was a record $10.32 billion, &quot;
                &quot;up 141% from the previous quarter and up 171% from a year ago. Announced that the &quot;
                &quot;NVIDIA® GH200 Grace™ Hopper™ Superchip for complex AI and HPC workloads is shipping &quot;
                &quot;this quarter, with a second-generation version with HBM3e memory expected to ship &quot;
                &quot;in Q2 of calendar 2024. &quot;},

    {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;What is Bank of America&#039;s rating on Target?&quot;,
     &quot;answer&quot;: &quot;Buy&quot;,
     &quot;context&quot;: &quot;Here are some of the tickers on my radar for Thursday, Oct. 12, taken directly from &quot;
                &quot;my reporter’s notebook: It’s the one-year anniversary of the S&amp;P 500′s bear market bottom &quot;
                &quot;of 3,577. Since then, as of Wednesday’s close of 4,376, the broad market index &quot;
                &quot;soared more than 22%.  Hotter than expected September consumer price index, consumer &quot;
                &quot;inflation. The Social Security Administration issues announced a 3.2% cost-of-living &quot;
                &quot;adjustment for 2024.  Chipotle Mexican Grill (CMG) plans price increases. Pricing power. &quot;
                &quot;Cites consumer price index showing sticky retail inflation for the fourth time &quot;
                &quot;in two years. Bank of America upgrades Target (TGT) to buy from neutral. Cites &quot;
                &quot;risk/reward from depressed levels. Traffic could improve. Gross margin upside. &quot;
                &quot;Merchandising better. Freight and transportation better. Target to report quarter &quot;
                &quot;next month. In retail, the CNBC Investing Club portfolio owns TJX Companies (TJX), &quot;
                &quot;the off-price juggernaut behind T.J. Maxx, Marshalls and HomeGoods. Goldman Sachs &quot;
                &quot;tactical buy trades on Club names Wells Fargo (WFC), which reports quarter Friday, &quot;
                &quot;Humana (HUM) and Nvidia (NVDA). BofA initiates Snowflake (SNOW) with a buy rating.&quot;
                &quot;If you like this story, sign up for Jim Cramer’s Top 10 Morning Thoughts on the &quot;
                &quot;Market email newsletter for free. Barclays cuts price targets on consumer products: &quot;
                &quot;UTZ Brands (UTZ) to $16 per share from $17. Kraft Heinz (KHC) to $36 per share from &quot;
                &quot;$38. Cyclical drag. J.M. Smucker (SJM) to $129 from $160. Secular headwinds. &quot;
                &quot;Coca-Cola (KO) to $59 from $70. Barclays cut PTs on housing-related stocks: Toll Brothers&quot;
                &quot;(TOL) to $74 per share from $82. Keeps underweight. Lowers Trex (TREX) and Azek&quot;
                &quot;(AZEK), too. Goldman Sachs (GS) announces sale of fintech platform and warns on &quot;
                &quot;third quarter of 19-cent per share drag on earnings. The buyer: investors led by &quot;
                &quot;private equity firm Sixth Street. Exiting a mistake. Rise in consumer engagement for &quot;
                &quot;Spotify (SPOT), says Morgan Stanley. The analysts hike price target to $190 per share &quot;
                &quot;from $185. Keeps overweight (buy) rating. JPMorgan loves elf Beauty (ELF). Keeps &quot;
                &quot;overweight (buy) rating but lowers price target to $139 per share from $150. &quot;
                &quot;Sees “still challenging” environment into third-quarter print. The Club owns shares &quot;
                &quot;in high-end beauty company Estee Lauder (EL). Barclays upgrades First Solar (FSLR) &quot;
                &quot;to overweight from equal weight (buy

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huanshere/VideoLingo]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Netflix-level subtitle cutting, translation, alignment, and even dubbing - one-click fully automated AI video subtitle team | Netflix级字幕切割、翻译、对齐、甚至加上配音，一键全自动视频搬运AI字幕组]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo">Huanshere/VideoLingo</a></h1>
            <p>Netflix-level subtitle cutting, translation, alignment, and even dubbing - one-click fully automated AI video subtitle team | Netflix级字幕切割、翻译、对齐、甚至加上配音，一键全自动视频搬运AI字幕组</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 12,930</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,303</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/docs/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;VideoLingo Logo&quot; height=&quot;140&quot;&gt;

# Connect the World, Frame by Frame

&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/12200&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/12200&quot; alt=&quot;Huanshere%2FVideoLingo | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

[**English**](/README.md)｜[**简体中文**](/translations/README.zh.md)｜[**繁體中文**](/translations/README.zh-TW.md)｜[**日本語**](/translations/README.ja.md)｜[**Español**](/translations/README.es.md)｜[**Русский**](/translations/README.ru.md)｜[**Français**](/translations/README.fr.md)

&lt;/div&gt;

## 🌟 Overview ([Try VL Now!](https://videolingo.io))

VideoLingo is an all-in-one video translation, localization, and dubbing tool aimed at generating Netflix-quality subtitles. It eliminates stiff machine translations and multi-line subtitles while adding high-quality dubbing, enabling global knowledge sharing across language barriers.

Key features:
- 🎥 YouTube video download via yt-dlp

- **🎙️ Word-level and Low-illusion subtitle recognition with WhisperX**

- **📝 NLP and AI-powered subtitle segmentation**

- **📚 Custom + AI-generated terminology for coherent translation**

- **🔄 3-step Translate-Reflect-Adaptation for cinematic quality**

- **✅ Netflix-standard, Single-line subtitles Only**

- **🗣️ Dubbing with GPT-SoVITS, Azure, OpenAI, and more**

- 🚀 One-click startup and processing in Streamlit

- 🌍 Multi-language support in Streamlit UI

- 📝 Detailed logging with progress resumption

Difference from similar projects: **Single-line subtitles only, superior translation quality, seamless dubbing experience**

## 🎥 Demo

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;

### Dual Subtitles
---
https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a5c3d8d1-2b29-4ba9-b0d0-25896829d951

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;

### Cosy2 Voice Clone
---
https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/e065fe4c-3694-477f-b4d6-316917df7c0a

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;

### GPT-SoVITS with my voice
---
https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/47d965b2-b4ab-4a0b-9d08-b49a7bf3508c

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

### Language Support

**Input Language Support(more to come):**

🇺🇸 English 🤩 | 🇷🇺 Russian 😊 | 🇫🇷 French 🤩 | 🇩🇪 German 🤩 | 🇮🇹 Italian 🤩 | 🇪🇸 Spanish 🤩 | 🇯🇵 Japanese 😐 | 🇨🇳 Chinese* 😊

&gt; *Chinese uses a separate punctuation-enhanced whisper model, for now...

**Translation supports all languages, while dubbing language depends on the chosen TTS method.**

## Installation

Meet any problem? Chat with our free online AI agent [**here**](https://share.fastgpt.in/chat/share?shareId=066w11n3r9aq6879r4z0v9rh) to help you.

&gt; **Note:** For Windows users with NVIDIA GPU, follow these steps before installation:
&gt; 1. Install [CUDA Toolkit 12.6](https://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/12.6.0/local_installers/cuda_12.6.0_560.76_windows.exe)
&gt; 2. Install [CUDNN 9.3.0](https://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cudnn/9.3.0/local_installers/cudnn_9.3.0_windows.exe)
&gt; 3. Add `C:\Program Files\NVIDIA\CUDNN\v9.3\bin\12.6` to your system PATH
&gt; 4. Restart your computer

&gt; **Note:** FFmpeg is required. Please install it via package managers:
&gt; - Windows: ```choco install ffmpeg``` (via [Chocolatey](https://chocolatey.org/))
&gt; - macOS: ```brew install ffmpeg``` (via [Homebrew](https://brew.sh/))
&gt; - Linux: ```sudo apt install ffmpeg``` (Debian/Ubuntu)

1. Clone the repository

```bash
git clone https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo.git
cd VideoLingo
```

2. Install dependencies(requires `python=3.10`)

```bash
conda create -n videolingo python=3.10.0 -y
conda activate videolingo
python install.py
```

3. Start the application

```bash
streamlit run st.py
```

### Docker
Alternatively, you can use Docker (requires CUDA 12.4 and NVIDIA Driver version &gt;550), see [Docker docs](/docs/pages/docs/docker.en-US.md):

```bash
docker build -t videolingo .
docker run -d -p 8501:8501 --gpus all videolingo
```

## APIs
VideoLingo supports OpenAI-Like API format and various TTS interfaces:
- LLM: `claude-3-5-sonnet`, `gpt-4.1`, `deepseek-v3`, `gemini-2.0-flash`, ... (sorted by performance, be cautious with gemini-2.5-flash...)
- WhisperX: Run whisperX (large-v3) locally or use 302.ai API
- TTS: `azure-tts`, `openai-tts`, `siliconflow-fishtts`, **`fish-tts`**, `GPT-SoVITS`, `edge-tts`, `*custom-tts`(You can modify your own TTS in custom_tts.py!)

&gt; **Note:** VideoLingo works with **[302.ai](https://gpt302.saaslink.net/C2oHR9)** - one API key for all services (LLM, WhisperX, TTS). Or run locally with Ollama and Edge-TTS for free, no API needed!

For detailed installation, API configuration, and batch mode instructions, please refer to the documentation: [English](/docs/pages/docs/start.en-US.md) | [中文](/docs/pages/docs/start.zh-CN.md)

## Current Limitations

1. WhisperX transcription performance may be affected by video background noise, as it uses wav2vac model for alignment. For videos with loud background music, please enable Voice Separation Enhancement. Additionally, subtitles ending with numbers or special characters may be truncated early due to wav2vac&#039;s inability to map numeric characters (e.g., &quot;1&quot;) to their spoken form (&quot;one&quot;).

2. Using weaker models can lead to errors during processes due to strict JSON format requirements for responses (tried my best to prompt llm😊). If this error occurs, please delete the `output` folder and retry with a different LLM, otherwise repeated execution will read the previous erroneous response causing the same error.

3. The dubbing feature may not be 100% perfect due to differences in speech rates and intonation between languages, as well as the impact of the translation step. However, this project has implemented extensive engineering processing for speech rates to ensure the best possible dubbing results.

4. **Multilingual video transcription recognition will only retain the main language**. This is because whisperX uses a specialized model for a single language when forcibly aligning word-level subtitles, and will delete unrecognized languages.

5. **For now, cannot dub multiple characters separately**, as whisperX&#039;s speaker distinction capability is not sufficiently reliable.

## 📄 License

This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 License. Special thanks to the following open source projects for their contributions:

[whisperX](https://github.com/m-bain/whisperX), [yt-dlp](https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp), [json_repair](https://github.com/mangiucugna/json_repair), [BELLE](https://github.com/LianjiaTech/BELLE)

## 📬 Contact Me

- Submit [Issues](https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo/issues) or [Pull Requests](https://github.com/Huanshere/VideoLingo/pulls) on GitHub
- DM me on Twitter: [@Huanshere](https://twitter.com/Huanshere)
- Email me at: team@videolingo.io

## ⭐ Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=Huanshere/VideoLingo&amp;type=Timeline)](https://star-history.com/#Huanshere/VideoLingo&amp;Timeline)

---

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;If you find VideoLingo helpful, please give me a ⭐️!&lt;/p&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[kyutai-labs/moshi]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Moshi is a speech-text foundation model and full-duplex spoken dialogue framework. It uses Mimi, a state-of-the-art streaming neural audio codec.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi">kyutai-labs/moshi</a></h1>
            <p>Moshi is a speech-text foundation model and full-duplex spoken dialogue framework. It uses Mimi, a state-of-the-art streaming neural audio codec.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 8,274</p>
            <p>Forks: 698</p>
            <p>Stars today: 15 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Moshi: a speech-text foundation model for real time dialogue

![precommit badge](https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi/workflows/precommit/badge.svg)
![rust ci badge](https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi/workflows/Rust%20CI/badge.svg)

[[Read the paper]][moshi] [[Demo]](https://moshi.chat) [[Hugging Face]](https://huggingface.co/collections/kyutai/moshi-v01-release-66eaeaf3302bef6bd9ad7acd)

 [Moshi][moshi] is a speech-text foundation model and **full-duplex** spoken dialogue framework.
 It uses [Mimi][moshi], a state-of-the-art streaming neural audio codec. Mimi processes 24 kHz audio, down to a 12.5 Hz representation
 with a bandwidth of 1.1 kbps, in a fully streaming manner (latency of 80ms, the frame size),
 yet performs better than existing, non-streaming, codecs like
 [SpeechTokenizer](https://github.com/ZhangXInFD/SpeechTokenizer) (50 Hz, 4kbps), or [SemantiCodec](https://github.com/haoheliu/SemantiCodec-inference) (50 Hz, 1.3kbps).

 Moshi models **two streams of audio**: one corresponds to Moshi, and the other one to the user.
 At inference, the stream from the user is taken from the audio input,
and the one for Moshi is sampled from the model&#039;s output. Along these two audio streams, Moshi predicts text tokens corresponding to its own speech, its **inner monologue**,
which greatly improves the quality of its generation. A small Depth Transformer models inter codebook dependencies for a given time step,
while a large, 7B parameter Temporal Transformer models the temporal dependencies. Moshi achieves a theoretical latency
of 160ms (80ms for the frame size of Mimi + 80ms of acoustic delay), with a practical overall latency as low as 200ms on an L4 GPU.

[Talk to Moshi](https://moshi.chat) now on our live demo.


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./moshi.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schema representing the structure of Moshi. Moshi models two streams of audio:
    one corresponds to Moshi, and the other one to the user. At inference, the audio stream of the user is taken from the audio input, and the audio stream for Moshi is sampled from the model&#039;s output. Along that, Moshi predicts text tokens corresponding to its own speech for improved accuracy. A small Depth Transformer models inter codebook dependencies for a given step.&quot;
width=&quot;650px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

Mimi builds on previous neural audio codecs such as [SoundStream](https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.03312)
and [EnCodec](https://github.com/facebookresearch/encodec), adding a Transformer both in the encoder and decoder,
and adapting the strides to match an overall frame rate of 12.5 Hz. This allows Mimi to get closer to the
average frame rate of text tokens (~3-4 Hz), and limit the number of autoregressive steps in Moshi.
Similarly to SpeechTokenizer, Mimi uses a distillation loss so that the first codebook tokens match
a self-supervised representation from [WavLM](https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13900), which allows modeling semantic and acoustic information with a single model. Interestingly, while Mimi is fully causal and streaming, it learns to match sufficiently well the non-causal
representation from WavLM, without introducing any delays. Finally, and similarly to [EBEN](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2210.14090),
Mimi uses **only an adversarial training loss**, along with feature matching, showing strong improvements in terms of
subjective quality despite its low bitrate.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./mimi.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schema representing the structure of Mimi, our proposed neural codec. Mimi contains a Transformer
in both its encoder and decoder, and achieves a frame rate closer to that of text tokens. This allows us to reduce
the number of auto-regressive steps taken by Moshi, thus reducing the latency of the model.&quot;
width=&quot;800px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



## Organisation of the repository

There are three separate versions of the moshi inference stack in this repo.
- The Python version using PyTorch is in the [`moshi/`](moshi/) directory.
- The Python version using MLX for M series Macs is in the [`moshi_mlx/`](moshi_mlx/) directory.
- The Rust version used in production is in the [`rust/`](rust/) directory.
    This contains in particular a Mimi implementation in Rust, with Python bindings available
    as `rustymimi`.

Finally, the code for the live demo is provided in the [`client/`](client/) directory.

If you want to fine tune Moshi, head out to [kyutai-labs/moshi-finetune](https://github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi-finetune).


## Models

We release three models:
- our speech codec Mimi,
- Moshi fine-tuned on a male synthetic voice (Moshiko),
- Moshi fine-tuned on a female synthetic voice (Moshika).

Note that this codebase also supports [Hibiki](https://github.com/kyutai-labs/hibiki), check out the dedicated repo for more information.

Depending on the backend, the file format and quantization available will vary. Here is the list
of the HuggingFace repo with each model. Mimi is bundled in each of those, and always use the same checkpoint format.

- Moshika for PyTorch (bf16, int8): [kyutai/moshika-pytorch-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-pytorch-bf16), [kyutai/moshika-pytorch-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-pytorch-q8) (experimental).
- Moshiko for PyTorch (bf16, int8): [kyutai/moshiko-pytorch-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-pytorch-bf16), [kyutai/moshiko-pytorch-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-pytorch-q8) (experimental).
- Moshika for MLX (int4, int8, bf16): [kyutai/moshika-mlx-q4](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-mlx-q4), [kyutai/moshika-mlx-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-mlx-q8),  [kyutai/moshika-mlx-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-mlx-bf16).
- Moshiko for MLX (int4, int8, bf16): [kyutai/moshiko-mlx-q4](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-mlx-q4), [kyutai/moshiko-mlx-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-mlx-q8),  [kyutai/moshiko-mlx-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-mlx-bf16).
- Moshika for Rust/Candle (int8, bf16): [kyutai/moshika-candle-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-candle-q8),  [kyutai/moshika-mlx-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshika-candle-bf16).
- Moshiko for Rust/Candle (int8, bf16): [kyutai/moshiko-candle-q8](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-candle-q8),  [kyutai/moshiko-mlx-bf16](https://huggingface.co/kyutai/moshiko-candle-bf16).

All models are released under the CC-BY 4.0 license.

## Requirements

You will need at least Python 3.10, with 3.12 recommended. For specific requirements, please check the individual backends
directories. You can install the PyTorch and MLX clients with the following:

```bash
pip install -U moshi      # moshi PyTorch, from PyPI
pip install -U moshi_mlx  # moshi MLX, from PyPI, best with Python 3.12.
# Or the bleeding edge versions for Moshi and Moshi-MLX.
pip install -U -e &quot;git+https://git@github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi.git#egg=moshi&amp;subdirectory=moshi&quot;
pip install -U -e &quot;git+https://git@github.com/kyutai-labs/moshi.git#egg=moshi_mlx&amp;subdirectory=moshi_mlx&quot;

pip install rustymimi  # mimi, rust implementation with Python bindings from PyPI
```

If you are not using Python 3.12, you might get an error when installing
`moshi_mlx` or `rustymimi` (which `moshi_mlx` depends on). Then, you will need to install the [Rust toolchain](https://rustup.rs/), or switch to Python 3.12.

While we hope that the present codebase will work on Windows, we do not provide official support for it.
We have tested the MLX version on a MacBook Pro M3. At the moment, we do not support quantization
for the PyTorch version, so you will need a GPU with a significant amount of memory (24GB).

For using the Rust backend, you will need a recent version of the [Rust toolchain](https://rustup.rs/).
To compile GPU support, you will also need the [CUDA](https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-toolkit) properly installed for your GPU, in particular with `nvcc`.

## Python (PyTorch)

The PyTorch based API can be found in the `moshi` directory. It provides a streaming
version of the audio tokenizer (mimi) and the language model (moshi).

In order to run in interactive mode, you need to start a server which will
run the model, you can then use either the web UI or a command line client.

Start the server with:
```bash
python -m moshi.server [--gradio-tunnel] [--hf-repo kyutai/moshika-pytorch-bf16]
```

And then access the web UI on [localhost:8998](http://localhost:8998).
If your GPU is on a distant machine this will not work as websites using http
are not allowed to use the audio worklet api. There are two ways to get around
this:
- Forward the remote 8998 port to your localhost using ssh `-L` flag. Then
  connects to [localhost:8998](http://localhost:8998) as mentionned previously.
- Use the `--gradio-tunnel` argument, this sets up a tunnel with a URL accessible from anywhere.
  Keep in mind that this tunnel goes through the US and can add significant
  latency (up to 500ms from Europe). You can use `--gradio-tunnel-token` to set a
  fixed secret token and reuse the same address over time.

You can use `--hf-repo` to select a different pretrained model, by setting the proper Hugging Face repository.

Accessing a server that is not localhost via http may cause issues with using
the microphone in the web UI (in some browsers this is only allowed using
https).

A local client is also available, as
```bash
python -m moshi.client [--url URL_TO_GRADIO]
```
However note that, unlike the web browser, this client is barebone: it does not perform any echo cancellation,
nor does it try to compensate for a growing lag by skipping frames.

For more information, in particular on how to use the API directly, please
checkout [moshi/README.md](moshi/README.md).

## Python (MLX) for local inference on macOS

Once you have installed `moshi_mlx`, you can run
```bash
python -m moshi_mlx.local -q 4   # weights quantized to 4 bits
python -m moshi_mlx.local -q 8   # weights quantized to 8 bits
# And using a different pretrained model:
python -m moshi_mlx.local -q 4 --hf-repo kyutai/moshika-mlx-q4
python -m moshi_mlx.local -q 8 --hf-repo kyutai/moshika-mlx-q8
# be careful to always match the `-q` and `--hf-repo` flag.
```

This command line interface is also barebone. It does not perform any echo cancellation,
nor does it try to compensate for a growing lag by skipping frames.

Alternatively you can run `python -m moshi_mlx.local_web` to use
the web UI, the connection is via http and will be at [localhost:8998](http://localhost:8998).


## Rust

In order to run the Rust inference server, use the following command from within
the `rust` directory:

```bash
cargo run --features cuda --bin moshi-backend -r -- --config moshi-backend/config.json standalone
```

When using macOS, you can replace `--features cuda` with `--features metal`.

Alternatively you can use `config-q8.json` rather than `config.json` to use the
quantized q8 model. You can select a different pretrained model, e.g. Moshika,
by changing the `&quot;hf_repo&quot;` key in either file.

Once the server has printed &#039;standalone worker listening&#039;, you can use the web
UI. By default the Rust server uses https so it will be at
[localhost:8998](https://localhost:8998).

You will get warnings about the site being unsafe. When using chrome you
can bypass these by selecting &quot;Details&quot; or &quot;Advanced&quot;, then &quot;Visit this unsafe
site&quot; or &quot;Proceed to localhost (unsafe)&quot;.

## Clients

We recommend using the web UI as it provides additional echo cancellation that helps
the overall model quality. Note that most commands will directly serve this UI
in the provided URL, and there is in general nothing more to do.

Alternatively, we provide command line interfaces
for the Rust and Python versions, the protocol is the same as with the web UI so
there is nothing to change on the server side.

For reference, here is the list of clients for Moshi.

### Rust Command Line

From within the `rust` directory, run the following:
```bash
cargo run --bin moshi-cli -r -- tui --host localhost
```

### Python with PyTorch

```bash
python -m moshi.client
```

### Gradio Demo

You can launch a Gradio demo locally with the following command:

```bash
python -m moshi.client_gradio --url &lt;moshi-server-url&gt;
```

Prior to running the Gradio demo, please install `gradio-webrtc&gt;=0.0.18`.

### Docker Compose (CUDA only)

```bash
docker compose up
```

* Requires [NVIDIA Container Toolkit](https://docs.nvidia.com/datacenter/cloud-native/container-toolkit/latest/install-guide.html)

### WebUI

The web UI can be built from this repo via the
following steps (these will require `npm` being installed).
```bash
cd client
npm install
npm run build
```

The web UI can then be found in the `client/dist` directory.

## Development

If you wish to install from a clone of this repository, maybe to further develop Moshi, you can do the following:
```bash
# From the root of the clone of the repo
pip install -e &#039;moshi[dev]&#039;
pip install -e &#039;moshi_mlx[dev]&#039;
pre-commit install
```

If you wish to build locally `rustymimi` (assuming you have Rust properly installed):
```bash
pip install maturin
maturin dev -r -m rust/mimi-pyo3/Cargo.toml
```

## FAQ

Checkout the [Frequently Asked Questions](FAQ.md) section before opening an issue.


## License

The present code is provided under the MIT license for the Python parts, and Apache license for the Rust backend.
The web client code is provided under the MIT license.
Note that parts of this code is based on [AudioCraft](https://github.com/facebookresearch/audiocraft), released under
the MIT license.

The weights for the models are released under the CC-BY 4.0 license.

## Citation

If you use either Mimi or Moshi, please cite the following paper,

```
@techreport{kyutai2024moshi,
      title={Moshi: a speech-text foundation model for real-time dialogue},
      author={Alexandre D\&#039;efossez and Laurent Mazar\&#039;e and Manu Orsini and
      Am\&#039;elie Royer and Patrick P\&#039;erez and Herv\&#039;e J\&#039;egou and Edouard Grave and Neil Zeghidour},
      year={2024},
      eprint={2410.00037},
      archivePrefix={arXiv},
      primaryClass={eess.AS},
      url={https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00037},
}
```

[moshi]: https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00037
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[a list of disposable email domains]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains">disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains</a></h1>
            <p>a list of disposable email domains</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,996</p>
            <p>Forks: 646</p>
            <p>Stars today: 190 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>List of disposable email domains
========================
This repo contains a [list of disposable and temporary email address domains](disposable_email_blocklist.conf) often used to register dummy users in order to spam or abuse some services.

We cannot guarantee all of these can still be considered disposable but we do basic checking so chances are they were disposable at one point in time.

&gt; One of the most impactful mechanisms we currently have is prohibiting known &quot;throw-away&quot; email domains from creating accounts on the index. We currently use the `disposable-email-domains` list as well as our own internal list to block registration with －or association of － such domains for PyPI accounts.

-- Ee Durbin, PyPI Admin, Director of Infrastructure (PSF) [link](https://blog.pypi.org/posts/2024-06-16-prohibiting-msn-emails/)

Allowlist
=========
The file [allowlist.conf](allowlist.conf) gathers email domains that are often identified as disposable but in fact are not.

Contributing
============
Feel free to create PR with additions or request removal of some domain (with reasons).

**Specifically, please cite in your PR where one can generate a disposable email address which uses that domain, so the maintainers can verify it.**

Please add new disposable domains directly into [disposable_email_blocklist.conf](disposable_email_blocklist.conf) in the same format (only second level domains on new line without @), then run [maintain.sh](maintain.sh). The shell script will help you convert uppercase to lowercase, sort, remove duplicates and remove allowlisted domains.

License
=======
You can copy, modify, distribute and use the work, even for commercial purposes, all without asking permission.

[![Licensed under CC0](https://licensebuttons.net/p/zero/1.0/88x31.png)](https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/) 

Changelog
============

* 1/9/25 Enabled [GitHub sponsorhip](https://github.com/sponsors/disposable-email-domains) for this work. Everybody can do it, but currently only one person does it. Send them $2 for a coffee if you care.

* 2/11/21 We created a github [org account](https://github.com/disposable-email-domains) and transferred the repository to it.

* 4/18/19 [@di](https://github.com/di) [joined](https://github.com/martenson/disposable-email-domains/issues/205) as a core maintainer of this project. Thank you!

* 7/31/17 [@deguif](https://github.com/deguif) [joined](https://github.com/martenson/disposable-email-domains/issues/106) as a core maintainer of this project. Thanks!

* 12/6/16 - Available as [PyPI module](https://pypi.org/project/disposable-email-domains) thanks to [@di](https://github.com/di)

* 7/27/16 - Converted all domains to the second level. This means that starting from [this commit](https://github.com/martenson/disposable-email-domains/commit/61ae67aacdab0b19098de2e13069d7c35b74017a) the implementers should take care of matching the second level domain names properly i.e. `@xxx.yyy.zzz` should match `yyy.zzz` in blocklist where `zzz` is a [public suffix](https://publicsuffix.org/). More info in [#46](https://github.com/martenson/disposable-email-domains/issues/46)

* 9/2/14 - First commit [393c21f5](https://github.com/disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains/commit/393c21f56b5186f8db7d197b11cf1d7c5490a6f9)
  
Example Usage
=============

TOC: [Python](#python), [PHP](#php), [Go](#go), [Ruby on Rails](#ruby-on-rails), [NodeJS](#nodejs), [C#](#c), [bash](#bash), [Java](#java), [Swift](#swift)

### Python
```Python
with open(&#039;disposable_email_blocklist.conf&#039;) as blocklist:
    blocklist_content = {line.rstrip() for line in blocklist.readlines()}
if email.partition(&#039;@&#039;)[2] in blocklist_content:
    message = &quot;Please enter your permanent email address.&quot;
    return (False, message)
else:
    return True
```

Available as [PyPI module](https://pypi.org/project/disposable-email-domains) thanks to [@di](https://github.com/di)
```python
&gt;&gt;&gt; from disposable_email_domains import blocklist
&gt;&gt;&gt; &#039;bearsarefuzzy.com&#039; in blocklist
True
```

### PHP
contributed by [@txt3rob](https://github.com/txt3rob), [@deguif](https://github.com/deguif), [@pjebs](https://github.com/pjebs) and [@Wruczek](https://github.com/Wruczek)

1. Make sure the passed email is valid. You can check that with [filter_var](https://secure.php.net/manual/en/function.filter-var.php)
2. Make sure you have the mbstring extension installed on your server
```php
function isDisposableEmail($email, $blocklist_path = null) {
    if (!$blocklist_path) $blocklist_path = __DIR__ . &#039;/disposable_email_blocklist.conf&#039;;
    $disposable_domains = file($blocklist_path, FILE_IGNORE_NEW_LINES | FILE_SKIP_EMPTY_LINES);
    $domain = mb_strtolower(explode(&#039;@&#039;, trim($email))[1]);
    return in_array($domain, $disposable_domains);
}
```

Alternatively check out Composer package https://github.com/elliotjreed/disposable-emails-filter-php.

### Go
contributed by [@pjebs](https://github.com/pjebs)

```go
import (&quot;bufio&quot;; &quot;os&quot;; &quot;strings&quot;;)
var disposableList = make(map[string]struct{}, 3500)
func init() {
	f, _ := os.Open(&quot;disposable_email_blocklist.conf&quot;)
	for scanner := bufio.NewScanner(f); scanner.Scan(); {
		disposableList[scanner.Text()] = struct{}{}
	}
	f.Close()
}

func isDisposableEmail(email string) (disposable bool) {
	segs := strings.Split(email, &quot;@&quot;)
	_, disposable = disposableList[strings.ToLower(segs[len(segs)-1])]
	return
}
```

Alternatively check out Go package https://github.com/rocketlaunchr/anti-disposable-email.

### Ruby on Rails
contributed by [@MitsunChieh](https://github.com/MitsunChieh)

In the resource model, usually it is `user.rb`:

```Ruby
before_validation :reject_email_blocklist

def reject_email_blocklist
  blocklist = File.read(&#039;config/disposable_email_blocklist.conf&#039;).split(&quot;\n&quot;)

  if blocklist.include?(email.split(&#039;@&#039;)[1])
    errors[:email] &lt;&lt; &#039;invalid email&#039;
    return false
  else
    return true
  end
end
```

### Node.js
contributed by [@boywithkeyboard](https://github.com/boywithkeyboard)

```js
import { readFile } from &#039;node:fs/promises&#039;

let blocklist

async function isDisposable(email) {
  if (!blocklist) {
    const content = await readFile(&#039;disposable_email_blocklist.conf&#039;, { encoding: &#039;utf-8&#039; })

    blocklist = content.split(&#039;\r\n&#039;).slice(0, -1)
  }

  return blocklist.includes(email.split(&#039;@&#039;)[1])
}
```

Alternatively check out NPM package https://github.com/mziyut/disposable-email-domains-js.

### C#
```C#
private static readonly Lazy&lt;HashSet&lt;string&gt;&gt; _emailBlockList = new Lazy&lt;HashSet&lt;string&gt;&gt;(() =&gt;
{
  var lines = File.ReadLines(&quot;disposable_email_blocklist.conf&quot;)
    .Where(line =&gt; !string.IsNullOrWhiteSpace(line) &amp;&amp; !line.TrimStart().StartsWith(&quot;//&quot;));
  return new HashSet&lt;string&gt;(lines, StringComparer.OrdinalIgnoreCase);
});

private static bool IsBlocklisted(string domain) =&gt; _emailBlockList.Value.Contains(domain);

...

var addr = new MailAddress(email);
if (IsBlocklisted(addr.Host)))
  throw new ApplicationException(&quot;Email is blocklisted.&quot;);
```

### Bash

```
#!/bin/bash

# This script checks if an email address is temporary.

# Read blocklist file into a bash array
mapfile -t blocklist &lt; disposable_email_blocklist.conf

# Check if email domain is in blocklist
if [[ &quot; ${blocklist[@]} &quot; =~ &quot; ${email#*@} &quot; ]]; then
    message=&quot;Please enter your permanent email address.&quot;
    return_value=false
else
    return_value=true
fi

# Return result
echo &quot;$return_value&quot;
```

### Java

Code assumes that you have added `disposable_email_blocklist.conf` next to your class as classpath resource.

```Java
private static final Set&lt;String&gt; DISPOSABLE_EMAIL_DOMAINS;

static {
    Set&lt;String&gt; domains = new HashSet&lt;&gt;();
    try (BufferedReader in = new BufferedReader(
            new InputStreamReader(
                EMailChecker.class.getResourceAsStream(&quot;disposable_email_blocklist.conf&quot;), StandardCharsets.UTF_8))) {
        String line;
        while ((line = in.readLine()) != null) {
            line = line.trim();
            if (line.isEmpty()) {
                continue;
            }
            
            domains.add(line);
        }
    } catch (IOException ex) {
        LOG.error(&quot;Failed to load list of disposable email domains.&quot;, ex);
    }
    DISPOSABLE_EMAIL_DOMAINS = domains;
}

public static boolean isDisposable(String email) throws AddressException {
    InternetAddress contact = new InternetAddress(email);
    return isDisposable(contact);
}

public static boolean isDisposable(InternetAddress contact) throws AddressException {
    String address = contact.getAddress();
    int domainSep = address.indexOf(&#039;@&#039;);
    String domain = (domainSep &gt;= 0) ? address.substring(domainSep + 1) : address;
    return DISPOSABLE_EMAIL_DOMAINS.contains(domain);
}
```

### Swift
contributed by [@1998code](https://github.com/1998code)

```swift
func checkBlockList(email: String, completion: @escaping (Bool) -&gt; Void) {
    let url = URL(string: &quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/disposable-email-domains/disposable-email-domains/master/disposable_email_blocklist.conf&quot;)!
    let task = URLSession.shared.dataTask(with: url) { data, response, error in
        if let data = data {
            if let string = String(data: data, encoding: .utf8) {
                let lines = string.components(separatedBy: &quot;\n&quot;)
                for line in lines {
                    if email.contains(line) {
                        completion(true)
                        return
                    }
                }
            }
        }
        completion(false)
    }
    task.resume()
}
```
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[home-assistant/supervisor]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/home-assistant/supervisor</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/home-assistant/supervisor</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🏡 Home Assistant Supervisor]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/home-assistant/supervisor">home-assistant/supervisor</a></h1>
            <p>🏡 Home Assistant Supervisor</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,939</p>
            <p>Forks: 704</p>
            <p>Stars today: 5 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Home Assistant Supervisor

## First private cloud solution for home automation

Home Assistant (former Hass.io) is a container-based system for managing your
Home Assistant Core installation and related applications. The system is
controlled via Home Assistant which communicates with the Supervisor. The
Supervisor provides an API to manage the installation. This includes changing
network settings or installing and updating software.

## Installation

Installation instructions can be found at https://home-assistant.io/getting-started.

## Development

For small changes and bugfixes you can just follow this, but for significant changes open a RFC first.
Development instructions can be found [here][development].

## Release

Releases are done in 3 stages (channels) with this structure:

1. Pull requests are merged to the `main` branch.
2. A new build is pushed to the `dev` stage.
3. Releases are published.
4. A new build is pushed to the `beta` stage.
5. The [`stable.json`][stable] file is updated.
6. The build that was pushed to `beta` will now be pushed to `stable`.

[development]: https://developers.home-assistant.io/docs/supervisor/development
[stable]: https://github.com/home-assistant/version/blob/master/stable.json

[![Home Assistant - A project from the Open Home Foundation](https://www.openhomefoundation.org/badges/home-assistant.png)](https://www.openhomefoundation.org/)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[yeongpin/cursor-free-vip]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[[Support 0.49.x]（Reset Cursor AI MachineID & Bypass Higher Token Limit） Cursor Ai ，自动重置机器ID ， 免费升级使用Pro功能: You've reached your trial request limit. / Too many free trial accounts used on this machine. Please upgrade to pro. We have this limit in place to prevent abuse. Please let us know if you believe this is a mistake.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip">yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</a></h1>
            <p>[Support 0.49.x]（Reset Cursor AI MachineID & Bypass Higher Token Limit） Cursor Ai ，自动重置机器ID ， 免费升级使用Pro功能: You've reached your trial request limit. / Too many free trial accounts used on this machine. Please upgrade to pro. We have this limit in place to prevent abuse. Please let us know if you believe this is a mistake.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 27,046</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,391</p>
            <p>Stars today: 107 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># ➤ Cursor Free VIP

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./images/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cursor Pro Logo&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; style=&quot;border-radius: 6px;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Release](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/release/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/releases/latest)
[![License: CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-CC_BY--NC--ND_4.0-lightgrey.svg)](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/)
[![Stars](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/stars/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/stargazers)
[![Downloads](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/downloads/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/total)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/releases/latest)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://buymeacoffee.com/yeongpin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Buy Me a Coffee&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Buy%20Me%20a%20Coffee-Support%20Me-FFDA33&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 [&lt;img src=&quot;https://devin.ai/assets/deepwiki-badge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ask DeepWiki.com&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;](https://deepwiki.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13425&quot; alt=&quot;yeongpin%2Fcursor-free-vip | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/yeongpin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?text=buy me a coffee&amp;emoji=☕&amp;slug=yeongpin&amp;button_colour=ffda33&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Bree&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;coffee_colour=FFDD00&amp;latest=2&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; height=&#039;55&#039; alt=&quot;Buy Me a Coffee&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Support Latest 0.49.x Version | 支持最新 0.49.x 版本&lt;/h4&gt;

This tool is for educational purposes, currently the repo does not violate any laws. Please support the original project.
This tool will not generate any fake email accounts and OAuth access.

Supports Windows, macOS and Linux.

For optimal performance, run with privileges and always stay up to date.

這是一款用於學習和研究的工具，目前 repo 沒有違反任何法律。請支持原作者。
這款工具不會生成任何假的電子郵件帳戶和 OAuth 訪問。

支持 Windows、macOS 和 Linux。

對於最佳性能，請以管理員身份運行並始終保持最新。


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./images/product_2025-04-16_10-40-21.png&quot; alt=&quot;new&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; style=&quot;border-radius: 6px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

## 🔄 Change Log | 更新日志

[Watch Change Log | 查看更新日志](CHANGELOG.md)

## ✨ Features | 功能特點

* Support Windows macOS and Linux systems&lt;br&gt;支持 Windows、macOS 和 Linux 系統&lt;br&gt;

* Reset Cursor&#039;s configuration&lt;br&gt;重置 Cursor 的配置&lt;br&gt;

* Multi-language support (English, 简体中文, 繁體中文, Vietnamese)&lt;br&gt;多語言支持（英文、简体中文、繁體中文、越南語）&lt;br&gt;

## 💻 System Support | 系統支持

| Operating System | Architecture      | Supported |
|------------------|-------------------|-----------|
| Windows          | x64, x86          | ✅         |
| macOS            | Intel, Apple Silicon | ✅      |
| Linux            | x64, x86, ARM64   | ✅         |

## 👀 How to use | 如何使用

&lt;details open&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;⭐ Auto Run Script | 腳本自動化運行&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

### **Linux/macOS**

```bash
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/main/scripts/install.sh -o install.sh &amp;&amp; chmod +x install.sh &amp;&amp; ./install.sh
```

### **Archlinux**

Install via [AUR](https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/cursor-free-vip-git)

```bash
yay -S cursor-free-vip-git
```

### **Windows**

```powershell
irm https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/main/scripts/install.ps1 | iex
```

&lt;/details&gt;

If you want to stop the script, please press Ctrl+C&lt;br&gt;要停止腳本，請按 Ctrl+C

## ❗ Note | 注意事項

📝 Config | 文件配置
`Win / Macos / Linux Path | 路徑 [Documents/.cursor-free-vip/config.ini]`
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;⭐ Config | 文件配置&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```
[Chrome]
# Default Google Chrome Path | 默認Google Chrome 遊覽器路徑
chromepath = C:\Program Files\Google/Chrome/Application/chrome.exe

[Turnstile]
# Handle Turnstile Wait Time | 等待人機驗證時間
handle_turnstile_time = 2
# Handle Turnstile Wait Random Time (must merge 1-3 or 1,3) | 等待人機驗證隨機時間（必須是 1-3 或者 1,3 這樣的組合）
handle_turnstile_random_time = 1-3

[OSPaths]
# Storage Path | 存儲路徑
storage_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/User/globalStorage/storage.json
# SQLite Path | SQLite路徑
sqlite_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/User/globalStorage/state.vscdb
# Machine ID Path | 機器ID路徑
machine_id_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/machineId
# For Linux users: ~/.config/cursor/machineid

[Timing]
# Min Random Time | 最小隨機時間
min_random_time = 0.1
# Max Random Time | 最大隨機時間
max_random_time = 0.8
# Page Load Wait | 頁面加載等待時間
page_load_wait = 0.1-0.8
# Input Wait | 輸入等待時間
input_wait = 0.3-0.8
# Submit Wait | 提交等待時間
submit_wait = 0.5-1.5
# Verification Code Input | 驗證碼輸入等待時間
verification_code_input = 0.1-0.3
# Verification Success Wait | 驗證成功等待時間
verification_success_wait = 2-3
# Verification Retry Wait | 驗證重試等待時間
verification_retry_wait = 2-3
# Email Check Initial Wait | 郵件檢查初始等待時間
email_check_initial_wait = 4-6
# Email Refresh Wait | 郵件刷新等待時間
email_refresh_wait = 2-4
# Settings Page Load Wait | 設置頁面加載等待時間
settings_page_load_wait = 1-2
# Failed Retry Time | 失敗重試時間
failed_retry_time = 0.5-1
# Retry Interval | 重試間隔
retry_interval = 8-12
# Max Timeout | 最大超時時間
max_timeout = 160

[Utils]
# Check Update | 檢查更新
check_update = True
# Show Account Info | 顯示賬號信息
show_account_info = True

[TempMailPlus]
# Enable TempMailPlus | 啓用 TempMailPlus（任何轉發到TempMailPlus的郵件都支持獲取驗證碼，例如cloudflare郵件Catch-all）
enabled = false
# TempMailPlus Email | TempMailPlus 電子郵件
email = xxxxx@mailto.plus
# TempMailPlus pin | TempMailPlus pin碼
epin = 

[WindowsPaths]
storage_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\User\globalStorage\storage.json
sqlite_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\User\globalStorage\state.vscdb
machine_id_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\machineId
cursor_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app
updater_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\cursor-updater
update_yml_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app-update.yml
product_json_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app\product.json

[Browser]
default_browser = opera
chrome_path = C:\Program Files\Google\Chrome\Application\chrome.exe
edge_path = C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft\Edge\Application\msedge.exe
firefox_path = C:\Program Files\Mozilla Firefox\firefox.exe
brave_path = C:\Program Files\BraveSoftware/Brave-Browser/Application/brave.exe
chrome_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe
edge_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\msedgedriver.exe
firefox_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\geckodriver.exe
brave_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe
opera_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Opera\opera.exe
opera_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe

[OAuth]
show_selection_alert = False
timeout = 120
max_attempts = 3
```

&lt;/details&gt;

* Use administrator privileges to run the script &lt;br&gt;請使用管理員身份運行腳本

* Confirm that Cursor is closed before running the script &lt;br&gt;請確保在運行腳本前已經關閉 Cursor&lt;br&gt;

* This tool is only for learning and research purposes &lt;br&gt;此工具僅供學習和研究使用&lt;br&gt;

* Please comply with the relevant software usage terms when using this tool &lt;br&gt;使用本工具時請遵守相關軟件使用條款

## 🚨 Common Issues | 常見問題

|                   如果遇到權限問題，請確保：                    |                   此腳本以管理員身份運行                    |
|:--------------------------------------------------:|:------------------------------------------------:|
| If you encounter permission issues, please ensure: | This script is run with administrator privileges |
| Error &#039;User is not authorized&#039; | This means your account was banned for using temporary (disposal) mail. Ensure using a non-temporary mail service |
## 🤩 Contribution | 貢獻

歡迎提交 Issue 和 Pull Request！


&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;preview=true&amp;max=&amp;columns=&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

## 📩 Disclaimer | 免責聲明

本工具僅供學習和研究使用，使用本工具所產生的任何後果由使用者自行承擔。 &lt;br&gt;

This tool is only for learning and research purposes, and any consequences arising from the use of this tool are borne
by the user.

## 💰 Buy Me a Coffee | 請我喝杯咖啡

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./images/provi-code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy_me_a_coffee&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./images/paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;buy_me_a_coffee&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## ⭐ Star History | 星星數

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;Date)

&lt;/div&gt;

## 📝 License | 授權

本項目採用 [CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/) 授權。
Please refer to the [LICENSE](LICENSE.md) file for details.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>