<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for python - Python Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for python.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[frdel/agent-zero]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/frdel/agent-zero</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/frdel/agent-zero</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Agent Zero AI framework]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/frdel/agent-zero">frdel/agent-zero</a></h1>
            <p>Agent Zero AI framework</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 8,791</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,734</p>
            <p>Stars today: 324 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# `Agent Zero`

[![Agent Zero Website](https://img.shields.io/badge/Website-agent--zero.ai-0A192F?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=vercel&amp;logoColor=white)](https://agent-zero.ai) [![Thanks to Sponsors](https://img.shields.io/badge/GitHub%20Sponsors-Thanks%20to%20Sponsors-FF69B4?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=githubsponsors&amp;logoColor=white)](https://github.com/sponsors/frdel) [![Follow on X](https://img.shields.io/badge/X-Follow-000000?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=x&amp;logoColor=white)](https://x.com/Agent0ai) [![Join our Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join%20our%20server-5865F2?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/B8KZKNsPpj) [![Subscribe on YouTube](https://img.shields.io/badge/YouTube-Subscribe-red?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=youtube&amp;logoColor=white)](https://www.youtube.com/@AgentZeroFW) [![Connect on LinkedIn](https://img.shields.io/badge/LinkedIn-Connect-blue?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=linkedin&amp;logoColor=white)](https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-tomasek/) [![Follow on Warpcast](https://img.shields.io/badge/Warpcast-Follow-5A32F3?style=for-the-badge)](https://warpcast.com/agent-zero)

[Introduction](#a-personal-organic-agentic-framework-that-grows-and-learns-with-you) •
[Installation](./docs/installation.md) •
[Hacking Edition](#hacking-edition) •
[How to update](./docs/installation.md#how-to-update-agent-zero) •
[Documentation](./docs/README.md) •
[Usage](./docs/usage.md)

&lt;/div&gt;


[![Showcase](/docs/res/showcase-thumb.png)](https://youtu.be/lazLNcEYsiQ)





## A personal, organic agentic framework that grows and learns with you

- Agent Zero is not a predefined agentic framework. It is designed to be dynamic, organically growing, and learning as you use it.
- Agent Zero is fully transparent, readable, comprehensible, customizable, and interactive.
- Agent Zero uses the computer as a tool to accomplish its (your) tasks.

# 💡 Key Features

1. **General-purpose Assistant**

- Agent Zero is not pre-programmed for specific tasks (but can be). It is meant to be a general-purpose personal assistant. Give it a task, and it will gather information, execute commands and code, cooperate with other agent instances, and do its best to accomplish it.
- It has a persistent memory, allowing it to memorize previous solutions, code, facts, instructions, etc., to solve tasks faster and more reliably in the future.

![Agent 0 Working](/docs/res/ui-screen-2.png)

2. **Computer as a Tool**

- Agent Zero uses the operating system as a tool to accomplish its tasks. It has no single-purpose tools pre-programmed. Instead, it can write its own code and use the terminal to create and use its own tools as needed.
- The only default tools in its arsenal are online search, memory features, communication (with the user and other agents), and code/terminal execution. Everything else is created by the agent itself or can be extended by the user.
- Tool usage functionality has been developed from scratch to be the most compatible and reliable, even with very small models.
- **Default Tools:** Agent Zero includes tools like knowledge, webpage content, code execution, and communication.
- **Creating Custom Tools:** Extend Agent Zero&#039;s functionality by creating your own custom tools.
- **Instruments:** Instruments are a new type of tool that allow you to create custom functions and procedures that can be called by Agent Zero.

3. **Multi-agent Cooperation**

- Every agent has a superior agent giving it tasks and instructions. Every agent then reports back to its superior.
- In the case of the first agent in the chain (Agent 0), the superior is the human user; the agent sees no difference.
- Every agent can create its subordinate agent to help break down and solve subtasks. This helps all agents keep their context clean and focused.

![Multi-agent](docs/res/physics.png)
![Multi-agent 2](docs/res/physics-2.png)

4. **Completely Customizable and Extensible**

- Almost nothing in this framework is hard-coded. Nothing is hidden. Everything can be extended or changed by the user.
- The whole behavior is defined by a system prompt in the **prompts/default/agent.system.md** file. Change this prompt and change the framework dramatically.
- The framework does not guide or limit the agent in any way. There are no hard-coded rails that agents have to follow.
- Every prompt, every small message template sent to the agent in its communication loop can be found in the **prompts/** folder and changed.
- Every default tool can be found in the **python/tools/** folder and changed or copied to create new predefined tools.

![Prompts](/docs/res/prompts.png)

5. **Communication is Key**

- Give your agent a proper system prompt and instructions, and it can do miracles.
- Agents can communicate with their superiors and subordinates, asking questions, giving instructions, and providing guidance. Instruct your agents in the system prompt on how to communicate effectively.
- The terminal interface is real-time streamed and interactive. You can stop and intervene at any point. If you see your agent heading in the wrong direction, just stop and tell it right away.
- There is a lot of freedom in this framework. You can instruct your agents to regularly report back to superiors asking for permission to continue. You can instruct them to use point-scoring systems when deciding when to delegate subtasks. Superiors can double-check subordinates&#039; results and dispute. The possibilities are endless.

## 🚀 Things you can build with Agent Zero

- **Development Projects** - `&quot;Create a React dashboard with real-time data visualization&quot;`

- **Data Analysis** - `&quot;Analyze last quarter&#039;s NVIDIA sales data and create trend reports&quot;`

- **Content Creation** - `&quot;Write a technical blog post about microservices&quot;`

- **System Admin** - `&quot;Set up a monitoring system for our web servers&quot;`

- **Research** - `&quot;Gather and summarize five recent AI papers about CoT prompting&quot;`

# Hacking Edition
- Agent Zero also offers a Hacking Edition based on Kali linux with modified prompts for cybersecurity tasks
- The setup is the same as the regular version, just use the frdel/agent-zero-run:hacking image instead of frdel/agent-zero-run


# ⚙️ Installation

Click to open a video to learn how to install Agent Zero:

[![Easy Installation guide](/docs/res/easy_ins_vid.png)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L1_peV8szf8)

A detailed setup guide for Windows, macOS, and Linux with a video can be found in the Agent Zero Documentation at [this page](./docs/installation.md).

### ⚡ Quick Start

```bash
# Pull and run with Docker

docker pull frdel/agent-zero-run
docker run -p 50001:80 frdel/agent-zero-run

# Visit http://localhost:50001 to start
```

## 🐳 Fully Dockerized, with Speech-to-Text and TTS

![Settings](docs/res/settings-page-ui.png)

- Customizable settings allow users to tailor the agent&#039;s behavior and responses to their needs.
- The Web UI output is very clean, fluid, colorful, readable, and interactive; nothing is hidden.
- You can load or save chats directly within the Web UI.
- The same output you see in the terminal is automatically saved to an HTML file in **logs/** folder for every session.

![Time example](/docs/res/time_example.jpg)

- Agent output is streamed in real-time, allowing users to read along and intervene at any time.
- No coding is required; only prompting and communication skills are necessary.
- With a solid system prompt, the framework is reliable even with small models, including precise tool usage.

## 👀 Keep in Mind

1. **Agent Zero Can Be Dangerous!**

- With proper instruction, Agent Zero is capable of many things, even potentially dangerous actions concerning your computer, data, or accounts. Always run Agent Zero in an isolated environment (like Docker) and be careful what you wish for.

2. **Agent Zero Is Prompt-based.**

- The whole framework is guided by the **prompts/** folder. Agent guidelines, tool instructions, messages, utility AI functions, it&#039;s all there.


## 📚 Read the Documentation

| Page | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [Installation](./docs/installation.md) | Installation, setup and configuration |
| [Usage](./docs/usage.md) | Basic and advanced usage |
| [Architecture](./docs/architecture.md) | System design and components |
| [Contributing](./docs/contribution.md) | How to contribute |
| [Troubleshooting](./docs/troubleshooting.md) | Common issues and their solutions |

## Coming soon

- **MCP**
- **Knowledge and RAG Tools**

## 🎯 Changelog

### v0.8.4.1
- Various bugfixes related to context management
- Message formatting improvements
- Scheduler improvements
- New model provider
- Input tool fix
- Compatibility and stability improvements

### v0.8.4
[Release video](https://youtu.be/QBh_h_D_E24)

- **Remote access (mobile)**

### v0.8.3.1
[Release video](https://youtu.be/AGNpQ3_GxFQ)

- **Automatic embedding**


### v0.8.3
[Release video](https://youtu.be/bPIZo0poalY)

- ***Planning and scheduling***

### v0.8.2
[Release video](https://youtu.be/xMUNynQ9x6Y)

- **Multitasking in terminal**
- **Chat names**

### v0.8.1
[Release video](https://youtu.be/quv145buW74)

- **Browser Agent**
- **UX Improvements**

### v0.8
[Release video](https://youtu.be/cHDCCSr1YRI)

- **Docker Runtime**
- **New Messages History and Summarization System**
- **Agent Behavior Change and Management**
- **Text-to-Speech (TTS) and Speech-to-Text (STT)**
- **Settings Page in Web UI**
- **SearXNG Integration Replacing Perplexity + DuckDuckGo**
- **File Browser Functionality**
- **KaTeX Math Visualization Support**
- **In-chat File Attachments**

### v0.7
[Release video](https://youtu.be/U_Gl0NPalKA)

- **Automatic Memory**
- **UI Improvements**
- **Instruments**
- **Extensions Framework**
- **Reflection Prompts**
- **Bug Fixes**

## 🤝 Community and Support

- [Join our Discord](https://discord.gg/B8KZKNsPpj) for live discussions or [visit our Skool Community](https://www.skool.com/agent-zero).
- [Follow our YouTube channel](https://www.youtube.com/@AgentZeroFW) for hands-on explanations and tutorials
- [Report Issues](https://github.com/frdel/agent-zero/issues) for bug fixes and features
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[nautechsystems/nautilus_trader]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A high-performance algorithmic trading platform and event-driven backtester]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader">nautechsystems/nautilus_trader</a></h1>
            <p>A high-performance algorithmic trading platform and event-driven backtester</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,888</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,003</p>
            <p>Stars today: 300 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/raw/develop/assets/nautilus-trader-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;

[![codecov](https://codecov.io/gh/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/branch/master/graph/badge.svg?token=DXO9QQI40H)](https://codecov.io/gh/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader)
[![codspeed](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://codspeed.io/badge.json)](https://codspeed.io/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader)
![pythons](https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/nautilus_trader)
![pypi-version](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/nautilus_trader)
![pypi-format](https://img.shields.io/pypi/format/nautilus_trader?color=blue)
[![Downloads](https://pepy.tech/badge/nautilus-trader)](https://pepy.tech/project/nautilus-trader)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-%235865F2.svg?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/NautilusTrader)

| Branch    | Version                                                                                                                                                                                                                     | Status                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| :-------- | :-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | :------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| `master`  | [![version](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Fnautechsystems%2Fnautilus_trader%2Fmaster%2Fversion.json)](https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple/nautilus-trader/index.html)  | [![build](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?branch=nightly)](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml) |
| `nightly` | [![version](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Fnautechsystems%2Fnautilus_trader%2Fnightly%2Fversion.json)](https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple/nautilus-trader/index.html) | [![build](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?branch=nightly)](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml) |
| `develop` | [![version](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Fnautechsystems%2Fnautilus_trader%2Fdevelop%2Fversion.json)](https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple/nautilus-trader/index.html) | [![build](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?branch=develop)](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/actions/workflows/build.yml) |

| Platform           | Rust    | Python     |
| :----------------- | :------ | :--------- |
| `Linux (x86_64)`   | 1.87.0+ | 3.11-3.13  |
| `Linux (ARM64)`    | 1.87.0+ | 3.11-3.13  |
| `macOS (ARM64)`    | 1.87.0+ | 3.11-3.13  |
| `Windows (x86_64)` | 1.87.0+ | 3.11-3.13  |

- **Docs**: &lt;https://nautilustrader.io/docs/&gt;
- **Website**: &lt;https://nautilustrader.io&gt;
- **Support**: [support@nautilustrader.io](mailto:support@nautilustrader.io)

## Introduction

NautilusTrader is an open-source, high-performance, production-grade algorithmic trading platform,
providing quantitative traders with the ability to backtest portfolios of automated trading strategies
on historical data with an event-driven engine, and also deploy those same strategies live, with no code changes.

The platform is *AI-first*, designed to develop and deploy algorithmic trading strategies within a highly performant
and robust Python-native environment. This helps to address the parity challenge of keeping the Python research/backtest
environment consistent with the production live trading environment.

NautilusTrader&#039;s design, architecture, and implementation philosophy prioritizes software correctness and safety at the
highest level, with the aim of supporting Python-native, mission-critical, trading system backtesting
and live deployment workloads.

The platform is also universal, and asset-class-agnostic —  with any REST API or WebSocket feed able to be integrated via modular
adapters. It supports high-frequency trading across a wide range of asset classes and instrument types
including FX, Equities, Futures, Options, Crypto and Betting, enabling seamless operations across multiple venues simultaneously.

![nautilus-trader](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/raw/develop/assets/nautilus-trader.png &quot;nautilus-trader&quot;)

## Features

- **Fast**: Core is written in Rust with asynchronous networking using [tokio](https://crates.io/crates/tokio).
- **Reliable**: Rust-powered type- and thread-safety, with optional Redis-backed state persistence.
- **Portable**: OS independent, runs on Linux, macOS, and Windows. Deploy using Docker.
- **Flexible**: Modular adapters mean any REST API or WebSocket feed can be integrated.
- **Advanced**: Time in force `IOC`, `FOK`, `GTC`, `GTD`, `DAY`, `AT_THE_OPEN`, `AT_THE_CLOSE`, advanced order types and conditional triggers. Execution instructions `post-only`, `reduce-only`, and icebergs. Contingency orders including `OCO`, `OUO`, `OTO`.
- **Customizable**: Add user-defined custom components, or assemble entire systems from scratch leveraging the [cache](https://nautilustrader.io/docs/latest/concepts/cache) and [message bus](https://nautilustrader.io/docs/latest/concepts/message_bus).
- **Backtesting**: Run with multiple venues, instruments and strategies simultaneously using historical quote tick, trade tick, bar, order book and custom data with nanosecond resolution.
- **Live**: Use identical strategy implementations between backtesting and live deployments.
- **Multi-venue**: Multiple venue capabilities facilitate market-making and statistical arbitrage strategies.
- **AI Training**: Backtest engine fast enough to be used to train AI trading agents (RL/ES).

![Alt text](https://github.com/nautechsystems/nautilus_trader/raw/develop/assets/nautilus-art.png &quot;nautilus&quot;)

&gt; *nautilus - from ancient Greek &#039;sailor&#039; and naus &#039;ship&#039;.*
&gt;
&gt; *The nautilus shell consists of modular chambers with a growth factor which approximates a logarithmic spiral.
&gt; The idea is that this can be translated to the aesthetics of design and architecture.*

## Why NautilusTrader?

- **Highly performant event-driven Python**: Native binary core components.
- **Parity between backtesting and live trading**: Identical strategy code.
- **Reduced operational risk**: Enhanced risk management functionality, logical accuracy, and type safety.
- **Highly extendable**: Message bus, custom components and actors, custom data, custom adapters.

Traditionally, trading strategy research and backtesting might be conducted in Python
using vectorized methods, with the strategy then needing to be reimplemented in a more event-driven way
using C++, C#, Java or other statically typed language(s). The reasoning here is that vectorized backtesting code cannot
express the granular time and event dependent complexity of real-time trading, where compiled languages have
proven to be more suitable due to their inherently higher performance, and type safety.

One of the key advantages of NautilusTrader here, is that this reimplementation step is now circumvented - as the critical core components of the platform
have all been written entirely in [Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/) or [Cython](https://cython.org/).
This means we&#039;re using the right tools for the job, where systems programming languages compile performant binaries,
with CPython C extension modules then able to offer a Python-native environment, suitable for professional quantitative traders and trading firms.

## Why Python?

Python was originally created decades ago as a simple scripting language with a clean straightforward syntax.
It has since evolved into a fully fledged general purpose object-oriented programming language.
Based on the TIOBE index, Python is currently the most popular programming language in the world.
Not only that, Python has become the *de facto lingua franca* of data science, machine learning, and artificial intelligence.

developer/user communities.
However, Python has performance and typing limitations for large-scale, latency-sensitive systems. Cython addresses many of these issues by introducing static typing into Python&#039;s rich ecosystem of libraries and communities.

## Why Rust?

[Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/) is a multi-paradigm programming language designed for performance and safety, especially safe
concurrency. Rust is &quot;blazingly fast&quot; and memory-efficient (comparable to C and C++) with no garbage collector.
It can power mission-critical systems, run on embedded devices, and easily integrates with other languages.

Rust’s rich type system and ownership model guarantees memory-safety and thread-safety deterministically —
eliminating many classes of bugs at compile-time.

The project increasingly utilizes Rust for core performance-critical components. Python bindings are implemented via Cython and [PyO3](https://pyo3.rs)—no Rust toolchain is required at install time.

This project makes the [Soundness Pledge](https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/2020/01/18/soundness-pledge.html):

&gt; “The intent of this project is to be free of soundness bugs.
&gt; The developers will do their best to avoid them, and welcome help in analyzing and fixing them.”

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; **MSRV:** NautilusTrader relies heavily on improvements in the Rust language and compiler.
&gt; As a result, the Minimum Supported Rust Version (MSRV) is generally equal to the latest stable release of Rust.

## Integrations

NautilusTrader is modularly designed to work with *adapters*, enabling connectivity to trading venues
and data providers by translating their raw APIs into a unified interface and normalized domain model.

The following integrations are currently supported; see [docs/integrations/](https://nautilustrader.io/docs/latest/integrations/) for details:

| Name                                                                         | ID                    | Type                    | Status                                                  | Docs                                        |
| :--------------------------------------------------------------------------- | :-------------------- | :---------------------- | :------------------------------------------------------ | :------------------------------------------ |
| [Betfair](https://betfair.com)                                               | `BETFAIR`             | Sports Betting Exchange | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/betfair.md)       |
| [Binance](https://binance.com)                                               | `BINANCE`             | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/binance.md)       |
| [Binance US](https://binance.us)                                             | `BINANCE`             | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/binance.md)       |
| [Binance Futures](https://www.binance.com/en/futures)                        | `BINANCE`             | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/binance.md)       |
| [Bybit](https://www.bybit.com)                                               | `BYBIT`               | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/bybit.md)         |
| [Coinbase International](https://www.coinbase.com/en/international-exchange) | `COINBASE_INTX`       | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/coinbase_intx.md) |
| [Databento](https://databento.com)                                           | `DATABENTO`           | Data Provider           | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/databento.md)     |
| [dYdX](https://dydx.exchange/)                                               | `DYDX`                | Crypto Exchange (DEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/dydx.md)          |
| [Interactive Brokers](https://www.interactivebrokers.com)                    | `INTERACTIVE_BROKERS` | Brokerage (multi-venue) | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/ib.md)            |
| [OKX](https://okx.com)                                                       | `OKX`                 | Crypto Exchange (CEX)   | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/building-orange) | [Guide](docs/integrations/okx.md)           |
| [Polymarket](https://polymarket.com)                                         | `POLYMARKET`          | Prediction Market (DEX) | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/polymarket.md)    |
| [Tardis](https://tardis.dev)                                                 | `TARDIS`              | Crypto Data Provider    | ![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/stable-green)    | [Guide](docs/integrations/tardis.md)        |

- **ID**: The default client ID for the integrations adapter clients.
- **Type**: The type of integration (often the venue type).

### Status

- `building`: Under construction and likely not in a usable state.
- `beta`: Completed to a minimally working state and in a beta testing phase.
- `stable`: Stabilized feature set and API, the integration has been tested by both developers and users to a reasonable level (some bugs may still remain).

See the [Integrations](https://nautilustrader.io/docs/latest/integrations/index.html) documentation for further details.

## Versioning and releases

**NautilusTrader is still under active development**. Some features may be incomplete, and while
the API is becoming more stable, breaking changes can occur between releases.
We strive to document these changes in the release notes on a **best-effort basis**.

We aim to follow a **bi-weekly release schedule**, though experimental or larger features may cause delays.

### Branches

We aim to maintain a stable, passing build across all branches.

- `master`: Reflects the source code for the latest released version; recommended for production use.
- `nightly`: Daily snapshots of the `develop` branch for early testing; merged at **14:00 UTC** or on demand.
- `develop`: Active development branch for contributors and feature work.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; Our [roadmap](/ROADMAP.md) aims to achieve a **stable API for version 2.x** (likely after the Rust port).
&gt; Once this milestone is reached, we plan to implement a formal deprecation process for any API changes.
&gt; This approach allows us to maintain a rapid development pace for now.

## Precision mode

NautilusTrader supports two precision modes for its core value types (`Price`, `Quantity`, `Money`),
which differ in their internal bit-width and maximum decimal precision.

- **High-precision**: 128-bit integers with up to 16 decimals of precision, and a larger value range.
- **Standard-precision**: 64-bit integers with up to 9 decimals of precision, and a smaller value range.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; By default, the official Python wheels **ship** in high-precision (128-bit) mode on Linux and macOS.
&gt; On Windows, only standard-precision (64-bit) is available due to the lack of native 128-bit integer support.
&gt; For the Rust crates, the default is standard-precision unless you explicitly enable the `high-precision` feature flag.

See the [Installation Guide](https://nautilustrader.io/docs/latest/getting_started/installation) for further details.

**Rust feature flag**: To enable high-precision mode in Rust, add the `high-precision` feature to your Cargo.toml:

```toml
[dependencies]
nautilus_model = { version = &quot;*&quot;, features = [&quot;high-precision&quot;] }
```

## Installation

We recommend using the latest supported version of Python and installing [nautilus_trader](https://pypi.org/project/nautilus_trader/) inside a virtual environment to isolate dependencies.

**There are two supported ways to install**:

1. Pre-built binary wheel from PyPI *or* the Nautech Systems package index.
2. Build from source.

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt;
&gt; We highly recommend installing using the [uv](https://docs.astral.sh/uv) package manager with a &quot;vanilla&quot; CPython.
&gt;
&gt; Conda and other Python distributions *may* work but aren’t officially supported.

### From PyPI

To install the latest binary wheel (or sdist package) from PyPI using Python&#039;s pip package manager:

```bash
pip install -U nautilus_trader
```

### From the Nautech Systems package index

The Nautech Systems package index (`packages.nautechsystems.io`) is [PEP-503](https://peps.python.org/pep-0503/) compliant and hosts both stable and development binary wheels for `nautilus_trader`.
This enables users to install either the latest stable release or pre-release versions for testing.

#### Stable wheels

Stable wheels correspond to official releases of `nautilus_trader` on PyPI, and use standard versioning.

To install the latest stable release:

```bash
pip install -U nautilus_trader --index-url=https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple
```

#### Development wheels

Development wheels are published from both the `nightly` and `develop` branches,
allowing users to test features and fixes ahead of stable releases.

**Note**: Wheels from the `develop` branch are only built for the Linux x86_64 platform to save time
and compute resources, while `nightly` wheels support additional platforms as shown below.

| Platform           | Nightly | Develop |
| :----------------- | :------ | :------ |
| `Linux (x86_64)`   | ✓       | ✓       |
| `Linux (ARM64)`    | ✓       | -       |
| `macOS (ARM64)`    | ✓       | -       |
| `Windows (x86_64)` | ✓       | -       |

This process also helps preserve compute resources and ensures easy access to the exact binaries tested in CI pipelines,
while adhering to [PEP-440](https://peps.python.org/pep-0440/) versioning standards:

- `develop` wheels use the version format `dev{date}+{build_number}` (e.g., `1.208.0.dev20241212+7001`).
- `nightly` wheels use the version format `a{date}` (alpha) (e.g., `1.208.0a20241212`).

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt;
&gt; We don&#039;t recommend using development wheels in production environments, such as live trading controlling real capital.

#### Installation commands

By default, pip installs the latest stable release. Adding the `--pre` flag ensures that pre-release versions, including development wheels, are considered.

To install the latest available pre-release (including development wheels):

```bash
pip install -U nautilus_trader --pre --index-url=https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple
```

To install a specific development wheel (e.g., `1.208.0a20241212` for December 12, 2024):

```bash
pip install nautilus_trader==1.208.0a20241212 --index-url=https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple
```

#### Available versions

You can view all available versions of `nautilus_trader` on the [package index](https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple/nautilus-trader/index.html).

To programmatically fetch and list available versions:

```bash
curl -s https://packages.nautechsystems.io/simple/nautilus-trader/index.html | grep -oP &#039;(?&lt;=&lt;a href=&quot;)[^&quot;]+(?=&quot;)&#039; | awk -F&#039;#&#039; &#039;{print $1}&#039; | sort
```

#### Branch updates

- `develop` branch wheels (`.dev`): Are built and published continuously with every merged commit.
- `nightly` branch wheels (`a`): Are built and published daily when `develop` branch is automatic

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[scrapy/scrapy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/scrapy/scrapy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/scrapy/scrapy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Scrapy, a fast high-level web crawling & scraping framework for Python.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/scrapy/scrapy">scrapy/scrapy</a></h1>
            <p>Scrapy, a fast high-level web crawling & scraping framework for Python.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 56,110</p>
            <p>Forks: 10,873</p>
            <p>Stars today: 451 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[topoteretes/cognee]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Memory for AI Agents in 5 lines of code]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee">topoteretes/cognee</a></h1>
            <p>Memory for AI Agents in 5 lines of code</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,859</p>
            <p>Forks: 260</p>
            <p>Stars today: 296 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/topoteretes/cognee/refs/heads/dev/assets/cognee-logo-transparent.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cognee Logo&quot; height=&quot;60&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;br /&gt;

  cognee - Memory for AI Agents in 5 lines of code

  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1bezuvLwJmw&amp;t=2s&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;
  .
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://cognee.ai&quot;&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/NQPKmU5CCg&quot;&gt;Join Discord&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AIMemory/&quot;&gt;Join r/AIMemory&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;


  [![GitHub forks](https://img.shields.io/github/forks/topoteretes/cognee.svg?style=social&amp;label=Fork&amp;maxAge=2592000)](https://GitHub.com/topoteretes/cognee/network/)
  [![GitHub stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/topoteretes/cognee.svg?style=social&amp;label=Star&amp;maxAge=2592000)](https://GitHub.com/topoteretes/cognee/stargazers/)
  [![GitHub commits](https://badgen.net/github/commits/topoteretes/cognee)](https://GitHub.com/topoteretes/cognee/commit/)
  [![Github tag](https://badgen.net/github/tag/topoteretes/cognee)](https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/tags/)
  [![Downloads](https://static.pepy.tech/badge/cognee)](https://pepy.tech/project/cognee)
  [![License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/topoteretes/cognee?colorA=00C586&amp;colorB=000000)](https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/blob/main/LICENSE)
  [![Contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/topoteretes/cognee?colorA=00C586&amp;colorB=000000)](https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/graphs/contributors)

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/cognee?embed=true&amp;utm_source=badge-top-post-badge&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_souce=badge-cognee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/top-post-badge.svg?post_id=946346&amp;theme=light&amp;period=daily&amp;t=1744472480704&quot; alt=&quot;cognee - Memory&amp;#0032;for&amp;#0032;AI&amp;#0032;Agents&amp;#0032;&amp;#0032;in&amp;#0032;5&amp;#0032;lines&amp;#0032;of&amp;#0032;code | Product Hunt&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;



Build dynamic memory for Agents and replace RAG using scalable, modular ECL (Extract, Cognify, Load) pipelines.

More on [use-cases](https://docs.cognee.ai/use-cases) and [evals](https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/tree/main/evals)

  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  🌐 Available Languages
  :
  &lt;a href=&quot;assets/community/README.pt.md&quot;&gt;🇵🇹 Português&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;assets/community/README.zh.md&quot;&gt;🇨🇳 [中文]&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;assets/community/README.ru.md&quot;&gt;🇷🇺 Русский&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/topoteretes/cognee/refs/heads/main/assets/cognee_benefits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Why cognee?&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


## Features

- Interconnect and retrieve your past conversations, documents, images and audio transcriptions
- Replaces RAG systems and reduces developer effort, and cost.
- Load data to graph and vector databases using only Pydantic
- Manipulate your data while ingesting from 30+ data sources

## Get Started

Get started quickly with a Google Colab  &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1jHbWVypDgCLwjE71GSXhRL3YxYhCZzG1?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;notebook&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepnote.com/workspace/cognee-382213d0-0444-4c89-8265-13770e333c02/project/cognee-demo-78ffacb9-5832-4611-bb1a-560386068b30/notebook/Notebook-1-75b24cda566d4c24ab348f7150792601?utm_source=share-modal&amp;utm_medium=product-shared-content&amp;utm_campaign=notebook&amp;utm_content=78ffacb9-5832-4611-bb1a-560386068b30&quot;&gt;Deepnote notebook&lt;/a&gt; or  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee-starter&quot;&gt;starter repo&lt;/a&gt;


## Contributing
Your contributions are at the core of making this a true open source project. Any contributions you make are **greatly appreciated**. See [`CONTRIBUTING.md`](CONTRIBUTING.md) for more information.





## 📦 Installation

You can install Cognee using either **pip**, **poetry**, **uv** or any other python package manager.
Cognee supports Python 3.8 to 3.12

### With pip

```bash
pip install cognee
```

## Local Cognee installation

You can install the local Cognee repo using **pip**, **poetry** and **uv**.
For local pip installation please make sure your pip version is above version 21.3.

### with UV with all optional dependencies

```bash
uv sync --all-extras
```

## 💻 Basic Usage

### Setup

```
import os
os.environ[&quot;LLM_API_KEY&quot;] = &quot;YOUR OPENAI_API_KEY&quot;

```

You can also set the variables by creating .env file, using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/blob/main/.env.template&quot;&gt;template.&lt;/a&gt;
To use different LLM providers, for more info check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.cognee.ai&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;


### Simple example

This script will run the default pipeline:

```python
import cognee
import asyncio


async def main():
    # Add text to cognee
    await cognee.add(&quot;Natural language processing (NLP) is an interdisciplinary subfield of computer science and information retrieval.&quot;)

    # Generate the knowledge graph
    await cognee.cognify()

    # Query the knowledge graph
    results = await cognee.search(&quot;Tell me about NLP&quot;)

    # Display the results
    for result in results:
        print(result)


if __name__ == &#039;__main__&#039;:
    asyncio.run(main())

```
Example output:
```
  Natural Language Processing (NLP) is a cross-disciplinary and interdisciplinary field that involves computer science and information retrieval. It focuses on the interaction between computers and human language, enabling machines to understand and process natural language.

```

## Our paper is out! &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.24478&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Read here&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cognee-paper.png&quot; alt=&quot;cognee paper&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

## Cognee UI

You can also cognify your files and query using cognee UI.

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/cognee-ui-2.webp&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Cognee UI 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Try cognee UI out locally [here](https://docs.cognee.ai/how-to-guides/cognee-ui).

## Understand our architecture

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cognee_diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;cognee concept diagram&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



## Demos

1. What is AI memory:

[Learn about cognee](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8b2a0050-5ec4-424c-b417-8269971503f0)

2. Simple GraphRAG demo

[Simple GraphRAG demo](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d80b0776-4eb9-4b8e-aa22-3691e2d44b8f)

3. cognee with Ollama

[cognee with local models](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8621d3e8-ecb8-4860-afb2-5594f2ee17db)


## Code of Conduct

We are committed to making open source an enjoyable and respectful experience for our community. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/blob/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CODE_OF_CONDUCT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more information.

## 💫 Contributors

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/topoteretes/cognee/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;contributors&quot; src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=topoteretes/cognee&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


## Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=topoteretes/cognee&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#topoteretes/cognee&amp;Date)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[lastmile-ai/mcp-agent]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Build effective agents using Model Context Protocol and simple workflow patterns]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent">lastmile-ai/mcp-agent</a></h1>
            <p>Build effective agents using Model Context Protocol and simple workflow patterns</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,057</p>
            <p>Forks: 471</p>
            <p>Stars today: 36 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c8d059e5-bd56-4ea2-a72d-807fb4897bde&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Build effective agents with Model Context Protocol using simple, composable patterns.&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent/tree/main/examples&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/research/building-effective-agents&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Effective Agents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://modelcontextprotocol.io/introduction&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/mcp-agent/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/mcp-agent?color=%2334D058&amp;label=pypi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent/issues&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-raw/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lmai.link/discord/mcp-agent&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shields.io/discord/1089284610329952357&quot; alt=&quot;discord&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Pepy Total Downloads&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pepy/dt/mcp-agent?label=pypi%20%7C%20downloads&quot;/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lastmile-ai/mcp-agent/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/mcp-agent&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Overview

**`mcp-agent`** is a simple, composable framework to build agents using [Model Context Protocol](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/introduction).

**Inspiration**: Anthropic announced 2 foundational updates for AI application developers:

1. [Model Context Protocol](https://www.anthropic.com/news/model-context-protocol) - a standardized interface to let any software be accessible to AI assistants via MCP servers.
2. [Building Effective Agents](https://www.anthropic.com/research/building-effective-agents) - a seminal writeup on simple, composable patterns for building production-ready AI agents.

`mcp-agent` puts these two foundational pieces into an AI application framework:

1. It handles the pesky business of managing the lifecycle of MCP server connections so you don&#039;t have to.
2. It implements every pattern described in Building Effective Agents, and does so in a _composable_ way, allowing you to chain these patterns together.
3. **Bonus**: It implements [OpenAI&#039;s Swarm](https://github.com/openai/swarm) pattern for multi-agent orchestration, but in a model-agnostic way.

Altogether, this is the simplest and easiest way to build robust agent applications. Much like MCP, this project is in early development.
We welcome all kinds of [contributions](/CONTRIBUTING.md), feedback and your help in growing this to become a new standard.

## Get Started

We recommend using [uv](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/) to manage your Python projects:

```bash
uv add &quot;mcp-agent&quot;
```

Alternatively:

```bash
pip install mcp-agent
```

### Quickstart

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; The [`examples`](/examples) directory has several example applications to get started with.
&gt; To run an example, clone this repo, then:
&gt;
&gt; ```bash
&gt; cd examples/basic/mcp_basic_agent # Or any other example
&gt; cp mcp_agent.secrets.yaml.example mcp_agent.secrets.yaml # Update API keys
&gt; uv run main.py
&gt; ```

Here is a basic &quot;finder&quot; agent that uses the fetch and filesystem servers to look up a file, read a blog and write a tweet. [Example link](./examples/basic/mcp_basic_agent/):

&lt;details open&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;finder_agent.py&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
import asyncio
import os

from mcp_agent.app import MCPApp
from mcp_agent.agents.agent import Agent
from mcp_agent.workflows.llm.augmented_llm_openai import OpenAIAugmentedLLM

app = MCPApp(name=&quot;hello_world_agent&quot;)

async def example_usage():
    async with app.run() as mcp_agent_app:
        logger = mcp_agent_app.logger
        # This agent can read the filesystem or fetch URLs
        finder_agent = Agent(
            name=&quot;finder&quot;,
            instruction=&quot;&quot;&quot;You can read local files or fetch URLs.
                Return the requested information when asked.&quot;&quot;&quot;,
            server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;, &quot;filesystem&quot;], # MCP servers this Agent can use
        )

        async with finder_agent:
            # Automatically initializes the MCP servers and adds their tools for LLM use
            tools = await finder_agent.list_tools()
            logger.info(f&quot;Tools available:&quot;, data=tools)

            # Attach an OpenAI LLM to the agent (defaults to GPT-4o)
            llm = await finder_agent.attach_llm(OpenAIAugmentedLLM)

            # This will perform a file lookup and read using the filesystem server
            result = await llm.generate_str(
                message=&quot;Show me what&#039;s in README.md verbatim&quot;
            )
            logger.info(f&quot;README.md contents: {result}&quot;)

            # Uses the fetch server to fetch the content from URL
            result = await llm.generate_str(
                message=&quot;Print the first two paragraphs from https://www.anthropic.com/research/building-effective-agents&quot;
            )
            logger.info(f&quot;Blog intro: {result}&quot;)

            # Multi-turn interactions by default
            result = await llm.generate_str(&quot;Summarize that in a 128-char tweet&quot;)
            logger.info(f&quot;Tweet: {result}&quot;)

if __name__ == &quot;__main__&quot;:
    asyncio.run(example_usage())

```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;mcp_agent.config.yaml&lt;/summary&gt;

```yaml
execution_engine: asyncio
logger:
  transports: [console] # You can use [file, console] for both
  level: debug
  path: &quot;logs/mcp-agent.jsonl&quot; # Used for file transport
  # For dynamic log filenames:
  # path_settings:
  #   path_pattern: &quot;logs/mcp-agent-{unique_id}.jsonl&quot;
  #   unique_id: &quot;timestamp&quot;  # Or &quot;session_id&quot;
  #   timestamp_format: &quot;%Y%m%d_%H%M%S&quot;

mcp:
  servers:
    fetch:
      command: &quot;uvx&quot;
      args: [&quot;mcp-server-fetch&quot;]
    filesystem:
      command: &quot;npx&quot;
      args:
        [
          &quot;-y&quot;,
          &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/server-filesystem&quot;,
          &quot;&lt;add_your_directories&gt;&quot;,
        ]

openai:
  # Secrets (API keys, etc.) are stored in an mcp_agent.secrets.yaml file which can be gitignored
  default_model: gpt-4o
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Agent output&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;img width=&quot;2398&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/eaa60fdf-bcc6-460b-926e-6fa8534e9089&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

## Table of Contents

- [Why use mcp-agent?](#why-use-mcp-agent)
- [Example Applications](#examples)
  - [Claude Desktop](#claude-desktop)
  - [Streamlit](#streamlit)
    - [Gmail Agent](#gmail-agent)
    - [RAG](#simple-rag-chatbot)
  - [Marimo](#marimo)
  - [Python](#python)
    - [Swarm (CLI)](#swarm)
- [Core Concepts](#core-components)
- [Workflows Patterns](#workflows)
  - [Augmented LLM](#augmentedllm)
  - [Parallel](#parallel)
  - [Router](#router)
  - [Intent-Classifier](#intentclassifier)
  - [Orchestrator-Workers](#orchestrator-workers)
  - [Evaluator-Optimizer](#evaluator-optimizer)
  - [OpenAI Swarm](#swarm-1)
- [Advanced](#advanced)
  - [Composing multiple workflows](#composability)
  - [Signaling and Human input](#signaling-and-human-input)
  - [App Config](#app-config)
  - [MCP Server Management](#mcp-server-management)
- [Contributing](#contributing)
- [Roadmap](#roadmap)
- [FAQs](#faqs)

## Why use `mcp-agent`?

There are too many AI frameworks out there already. But `mcp-agent` is the only one that is purpose-built for a shared protocol - [MCP](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/introduction). It is also the most lightweight, and is closer to an agent pattern library than a framework.

As [more services become MCP-aware](https://github.com/punkpeye/awesome-mcp-servers), you can use mcp-agent to build robust and controllable AI agents that can leverage those services out-of-the-box.

## Examples

Before we go into the core concepts of mcp-agent, let&#039;s show what you can build with it.

In short, you can build any kind of AI application with mcp-agent: multi-agent collaborative workflows, human-in-the-loop workflows, RAG pipelines and more.

### Claude Desktop

You can integrate mcp-agent apps into MCP clients like Claude Desktop.

#### mcp-agent server

This app wraps an mcp-agent application inside an MCP server, and exposes that server to Claude Desktop.
The app exposes agents and workflows that Claude Desktop can invoke to service of the user&#039;s request.

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7807cffd-dba7-4f0c-9c70-9482fd7e0699

This demo shows a multi-agent evaluation task where each agent evaluates aspects of an input poem, and
then an aggregator summarizes their findings into a final response.

**Details**: Starting from a user&#039;s request over text, the application:

- dynamically defines agents to do the job
- uses the appropriate workflow to orchestrate those agents (in this case the Parallel workflow)

**Link to code**: [examples/basic/mcp_agent_server](./examples/basic/mcp_agent_server)

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Huge thanks to [Jerron Lim (@StreetLamb)](https://github.com/StreetLamb)
&gt; for developing and contributing this example!

### Streamlit

You can deploy mcp-agent apps using Streamlit.

#### Gmail agent

This app is able to perform read and write actions on gmail using text prompts -- i.e. read, delete, send emails, mark as read/unread, etc.
It uses an MCP server for Gmail.

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/54899cac-de24-4102-bd7e-4b2022c956e3

**Link to code**: [gmail-mcp-server](https://github.com/jasonsum/gmail-mcp-server/blob/add-mcp-agent-streamlit/streamlit_app.py)

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Huge thanks to [Jason Summer (@jasonsum)](https://github.com/jasonsum)
&gt; for developing and contributing this example!

#### Simple RAG Chatbot

This app uses a Qdrant vector database (via an MCP server) to do Q&amp;A over a corpus of text.

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f4dcd227-cae9-4a59-aa9e-0eceeb4acaf4

**Link to code**: [examples/usecases/streamlit_mcp_rag_agent](./examples/usecases/streamlit_mcp_rag_agent/)

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Huge thanks to [Jerron Lim (@StreetLamb)](https://github.com/StreetLamb)
&gt; for developing and contributing this example!

### Marimo

[Marimo](https://github.com/marimo-team/marimo) is a reactive Python notebook that replaces Jupyter and Streamlit.
Here&#039;s the &quot;file finder&quot; agent from [Quickstart](#quickstart) implemented in Marimo:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/139a95a5-e3ac-4ea7-9c8f-bad6577e8597&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;/&gt;

**Link to code**: [examples/usecases/marimo_mcp_basic_agent](./examples/usecases/marimo_mcp_basic_agent/)

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Huge thanks to [Akshay Agrawal (@akshayka)](https://github.com/akshayka)
&gt; for developing and contributing this example!

### Python

You can write mcp-agent apps as Python scripts or Jupyter notebooks.

#### Swarm

This example demonstrates a multi-agent setup for handling different customer service requests in an airline context using the Swarm workflow pattern. The agents can triage requests, handle flight modifications, cancellations, and lost baggage cases.

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b314d75d-7945-4de6-965b-7f21eb14a8bd

**Link to code**: [examples/workflows/workflow_swarm](./examples/workflows/workflow_swarm/)

## Core Components

The following are the building blocks of the mcp-agent framework:

- **[MCPApp](./src/mcp_agent/app.py)**: global state and app configuration
- **MCP server management**: [`gen_client`](./src/mcp_agent/mcp/gen_client.py) and [`MCPConnectionManager`](./src/mcp_agent/mcp/mcp_connection_manager.py) to easily connect to MCP servers.
- **[Agent](./src/mcp_agent/agents/agent.py)**: An Agent is an entity that has access to a set of MCP servers and exposes them to an LLM as tool calls. It has a name and purpose (instruction).
- **[AugmentedLLM](./src/mcp_agent/workflows/llm/augmented_llm.py)**: An LLM that is enhanced with tools provided from a collection of MCP servers. Every Workflow pattern described below is an `AugmentedLLM` itself, allowing you to compose and chain them together.

Everything in the framework is a derivative of these core capabilities.

## Workflows

mcp-agent provides implementations for every pattern in Anthropic’s [Building Effective Agents](https://www.anthropic.com/research/building-effective-agents), as well as the OpenAI [Swarm](https://github.com/openai/swarm) pattern.
Each pattern is model-agnostic, and exposed as an `AugmentedLLM`, making everything very composable.

### AugmentedLLM

[AugmentedLLM](./src/mcp_agent/workflows/llm/augmented_llm.py) is an LLM that has access to MCP servers and functions via Agents.

LLM providers implement the AugmentedLLM interface to expose 3 functions:

- `generate`: Generate message(s) given a prompt, possibly over multiple iterations and making tool calls as needed.
- `generate_str`: Calls `generate` and returns result as a string output.
- `generate_structured`: Uses [Instructor](https://github.com/instructor-ai/instructor) to return the generated result as a Pydantic model.

Additionally, `AugmentedLLM` has memory, to keep track of long or short-term history.

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Example&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
from mcp_agent.agents.agent import Agent
from mcp_agent.workflows.llm.augmented_llm_anthropic import AnthropicAugmentedLLM

finder_agent = Agent(
    name=&quot;finder&quot;,
    instruction=&quot;You are an agent with filesystem + fetch access. Return the requested file or URL contents.&quot;,
    server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;, &quot;filesystem&quot;],
)

async with finder_agent:
   llm = await finder_agent.attach_llm(AnthropicAugmentedLLM)

   result = await llm.generate_str(
      message=&quot;Print the first 2 paragraphs of https://www.anthropic.com/research/building-effective-agents&quot;,
      # Can override model, tokens and other defaults
   )
   logger.info(f&quot;Result: {result}&quot;)

   # Multi-turn conversation
   result = await llm.generate_str(
      message=&quot;Summarize those paragraphs in a 128 character tweet&quot;,
   )
   logger.info(f&quot;Result: {result}&quot;)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### [Parallel](src/mcp_agent/workflows/parallel/parallel_llm.py)

![Parallel workflow (Image credit: Anthropic)](https://www.anthropic.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F406bb032ca007fd1624f261af717d70e6ca86286-2401x1000.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75)

Fan-out tasks to multiple sub-agents and fan-in the results. Each subtask is an AugmentedLLM, as is the overall Parallel workflow, meaning each subtask can optionally be a more complex workflow itself.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; **[Link to full example](examples/workflows/workflow_parallel/main.py)**

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Example&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
proofreader = Agent(name=&quot;proofreader&quot;, instruction=&quot;Review grammar...&quot;)
fact_checker = Agent(name=&quot;fact_checker&quot;, instruction=&quot;Check factual consistency...&quot;)
style_enforcer = Agent(name=&quot;style_enforcer&quot;, instruction=&quot;Enforce style guidelines...&quot;)

grader = Agent(name=&quot;grader&quot;, instruction=&quot;Combine feedback into a structured report.&quot;)

parallel = ParallelLLM(
    fan_in_agent=grader,
    fan_out_agents=[proofreader, fact_checker, style_enforcer],
    llm_factory=OpenAIAugmentedLLM,
)

result = await parallel.generate_str(&quot;Student short story submission: ...&quot;, RequestParams(model=&quot;gpt4-o&quot;))
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### [Router](src/mcp_agent/workflows/router/)

![Router workflow (Image credit: Anthropic)](https://www.anthropic.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F5c0c0e9fe4def0b584c04d37849941da55e5e71c-2401x1000.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75)

Given an input, route to the `top_k` most relevant categories. A category can be an Agent, an MCP server or a regular function.

mcp-agent provides several router implementations, including:

- [`EmbeddingRouter`](src/mcp_agent/workflows/router/router_embedding.py): uses embedding models for classification
- [`LLMRouter`](src/mcp_agent/workflows/router/router_llm.py): uses LLMs for classification

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; **[Link to full example](examples/workflows/workflow_router/main.py)**

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Example&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
def print_hello_world:
     print(&quot;Hello, world!&quot;)

finder_agent = Agent(name=&quot;finder&quot;, server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;, &quot;filesystem&quot;])
writer_agent = Agent(name=&quot;writer&quot;, server_names=[&quot;filesystem&quot;])

llm = OpenAIAugmentedLLM()
router = LLMRouter(
    llm=llm,
    agents=[finder_agent, writer_agent],
    functions=[print_hello_world],
)

results = await router.route( # Also available: route_to_agent, route_to_server
    request=&quot;Find and print the contents of README.md verbatim&quot;,
    top_k=1
)
chosen_agent = results[0].result
async with chosen_agent:
    ...
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### [IntentClassifier](src/mcp_agent/workflows/intent_classifier/)

A close sibling of Router, the Intent Classifier pattern identifies the `top_k` Intents that most closely match a given input.
Just like a Router, mcp-agent provides both an [embedding](src/mcp_agent/workflows/intent_classifier/intent_classifier_embedding.py) and [LLM-based](src/mcp_agent/workflows/intent_classifier/intent_classifier_llm.py) intent classifier.

### [Evaluator-Optimizer](src/mcp_agent/workflows/evaluator_optimizer/evaluator_optimizer.py)

![Evaluator-optimizer workflow (Image credit: Anthropic)](https://www.anthropic.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F14f51e6406ccb29e695da48b17017e899a6119c7-2401x1000.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75)

One LLM (the “optimizer”) refines a response, another (the “evaluator”) critiques it until a response exceeds a quality criteria.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; **[Link to full example](examples/workflows/workflow_evaluator_optimizer/main.py)**

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Example&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
optimizer = Agent(name=&quot;cover_letter_writer&quot;, server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;], instruction=&quot;Generate a cover letter ...&quot;)
evaluator = Agent(name=&quot;critiquer&quot;, instruction=&quot;Evaluate clarity, specificity, relevance...&quot;)

llm = EvaluatorOptimizerLLM(
    optimizer=optimizer,
    evaluator=evaluator,
    llm_factory=OpenAIAugmentedLLM,
    min_rating=QualityRating.EXCELLENT, # Keep iterating until the minimum quality bar is reached
)

result = await eo_llm.generate_str(&quot;Write a job cover letter for an AI framework developer role at LastMile AI.&quot;)
print(&quot;Final refined cover letter:&quot;, result)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### [Orchestrator-workers](src/mcp_agent/workflows/orchestrator/orchestrator.py)

![Orchestrator workflow (Image credit: Anthropic)](https://www.anthropic.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww-cdn.anthropic.com%2Fimages%2F4zrzovbb%2Fwebsite%2F8985fc683fae4780fb34eab1365ab78c7e51bc8e-2401x1000.png&amp;w=3840&amp;q=75)

A higher-level LLM generates a plan, then assigns them to sub-agents, and synthesizes the results.
The Orchestrator workflow automatically parallelizes steps that can be done in parallel, and blocks on dependencies.

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; **[Link to full example](examples/workflows/workflow_orchestrator_worker/main.py)**

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Example&lt;/summary&gt;

```python
finder_agent = Agent(name=&quot;finder&quot;, server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;, &quot;filesystem&quot;])
writer_agent = Agent(name=&quot;writer&quot;, server_names=[&quot;filesystem&quot;])
proofreader = Agent(name=&quot;proofreader&quot;, ...)
fact_checker = Agent(name=&quot;fact_checker&quot;, ...)
style_enforcer = Agent(name=&quot;style_enforcer&quot;, instructions=&quot;Use APA style guide from ...&quot;, server_names=[&quot;fetch&quot;])

orchestrator = Orchestrator(
    llm_factory=AnthropicAugmentedLLM,
    available_agents=[finder_agent, writer_agent, proofreader, fact_checker, style_enforcer],
)

task = &quot;Load short_story.md, evaluate it, produce a graded_report.md with multiple feedback aspects.&quot;
result = await orchestrator.generate_str(task, RequestParams(model=&quot;gpt-4o&quot;))
print(result)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### [Swarm](src/mcp_agent/workflows/swarm/swarm.py)

OpenAI has an experimental multi-agent pattern called [Swarm](https://github.com/openai/swarm), which we provide a model-agnostic reference implementation for in mcp-agent.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/openai/swarm/blob/main/assets/swarm_diagram.png?raw=true&quot; width=500 /&gt;

The mcp-agent Swarm pattern works seamlessly with MCP servers, and is exposed as an `AugmentedLLM`, allowing for composability with other patterns above

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[dreammis/social-auto-upload]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[自动化上传视频到社交媒体：抖音、小红书、视频号、tiktok、youtube、bilibili]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload">dreammis/social-auto-upload</a></h1>
            <p>自动化上传视频到社交媒体：抖音、小红书、视频号、tiktok、youtube、bilibili</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,146</p>
            <p>Forks: 861</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># social-auto-upload

`social-auto-upload` 是一个强大的自动化工具，旨在帮助内容创作者和运营者高效地将视频内容一键发布到多个国内外主流社交媒体平台。
项目实现了对 `抖音`、`Bilibili`、`小红书`、`快手`、`视频号`、`百家号` 以及 `TikTok` 等平台的视频上传、定时发布等功能。
结合各平台 `uploader` 模块，您可以轻松配置和扩展支持的平台，并通过示例脚本快速上手。

&lt;img src=&quot;media/show/tkupload.gif&quot; alt=&quot;tiktok show&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;

## 目录

- [💡 功能特性](#💡功能特性)
- [🚀 支持的平台](#🚀支持的平台)
- [💾 安装指南](#💾安装指南)
- [🏁 快速开始](#🏁快速开始)
- [🐇 项目背景](#🐇项目背景)
- [📃 详细文档](#📃详细文档)
- [🐾 交流与支持](#🐾交流与支持)
- [🤝 贡献指南](#🤝贡献指南)
- [📜 许可证](#📜许可证)
- [⭐ Star History](#⭐Star-History)

## 💡功能特性

### 已支持平台

-   **国内平台**:
    -   [x] 抖音
    -   [x] 视频号
    -   [x] Bilibili
    -   [x] 小红书
    -   [x] 快手
    -   [x] 百家号
-   **国外平台**:
    -   [x] TikTok

### 核心功能

-   [x] 定时上传 (Cron Job / Scheduled Upload)
-   [ ] Cookie 管理 (部分实现，持续优化中)
-   [ ] 国外平台 Proxy 设置 (部分实现)

### 计划支持与开发中

-   **平台扩展**:
    -   [ ] QQ视频
    -   [ ] YouTube
-   **功能增强**:
    -   [x] 更易用的版本 (GUI / CLI 交互优化)
    -   [x] API 封装
    -   [ ] Docker 部署
    -   [ ] 自动化上传 (更智能的调度策略)
    -   [ ] 多线程/异步上传优化
    -   [ ] Slack/消息推送通知

---

## 🚀支持的平台

本项目通过各平台对应的 `uploader` 模块实现视频上传功能。您可以在 `examples` 目录下找到各个平台的使用示例脚本。

每个示例脚本展示了如何配置和调用相应的 uploader。

## 💾安装指南

1.  **克隆项目**:
    ```bash
    git clone https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload.git
    cd social-auto-upload
    ```

2.  **安装依赖**:
    建议在虚拟环境中安装依赖。
    ```bash
    conda create -n social-auto-upload python=3.10
    conda activate social-auto-upload
    # 挂载清华镜像 or 命令行代理
    pip install -r requirements.txt
    ```

3.  **安装 Playwright 浏览器驱动**:
    ```bash
    playwright install chromium firefox
    ```
    根据您的需求，至少需要安装 `chromium`。`firefox` 主要用于 TikTok 上传（旧版）。

4.  **修改配置文件**:
    复制 `conf.example.py` 并重命名为 `conf.py`。
    在 `conf.py` 中，您需要配置以下内容：
    -   `LOCAL_CHROME_PATH`: 本地 Chrome 浏览器的路径，比如 `C:\Program Files\Google\Chrome\Application\chrome.exe` 保存。

5.  **配置数据库**:
    如果 db/database.db 文件不存在，您可以运行以下命令来初始化数据库：
    ```bash
    cd db
    python createTable.py
    ```
    此命令将初始化 SQLite 数据库。

6.  **启动后端项目**:
    ```bash
    python sau_backend.py
    ```
    后端项目将在 `http://localhost:5409` 启动。

7.  **启动前端项目**:
    ```bash
    cd sau_frontend
    npm install
    npm run dev
    ```
    前端项目将在 `http://localhost:5173` 启动，在浏览器中打开此链接即可访问。


&gt; 非程序员用户可以参考：[新手级教程](https://juejin.cn/post/7372114027840208911)


## 🏁快速开始

1.  **准备 Cookie**: 
    大多数平台需要登录后的 Cookie 信息才能进行操作。请参照 examples 目录下各 `get_xxx_cookie.py` 脚本（例如 get_douyin_cookie.py, get_ks_cookie.py）的说明，运行脚本以生成并保存 Cookie 文件（通常在 `cookies/[PLATFORM]_uploader/account.json`）。

2.  **准备视频文件**: 
    将需要上传的视频文件（通常为 `.mp4` 格式）放置在 videos 目录下。
    部分平台支持视频封面，可以将封面图片（例如 `.png` 格式，与视频同名）也放在此目录。
    如果需要上传标题及标签，请在视频文件旁边创建一个同名的 `.txt` 文件，内容为标题和标签，以换行分隔。

3.  **修改并运行示例脚本**:
    打开 examples 目录中您想使用的平台的上传脚本（例如 upload_video_to_douyin.py）。
    -   根据脚本内的注释和说明，确认 Cookie 文件路径、视频文件路径等配置是否正确。
    -   您可以修改脚本以适应您的具体需求，例如批量上传、自定义标题、标签等。

4.  **执行上传**:
    运行修改后的示例脚本，例如：
    ```bash
    python examples/upload_video_to_douyin.py
    ```

## 🐇项目背景

该项目最初是我个人用于自动化管理社交媒体视频发布的工具。我的主要发布策略是提前一天设置定时发布，因此项目中很多定时发布相关的逻辑是基于“第二天”的时间进行计算的。

如果您需要立即发布或其他定制化的发布策略，欢迎研究源码或在社区提问。

## 📃详细文档

更详细的文档和说明，请查看：[social-auto-upload 官方文档](https://sap-doc.nasdaddy.com/)

## 🐾交流与支持

[☕ Donate as u like](https://www.buymeacoffee.com/hysn2001m) - 如果您觉得这个项目对您有帮助，可以考虑赞助。

如果您也是独立开发者、技术爱好者，对 #技术变现 #AI创业 #跨境电商 #自动化工具 #视频创作 等话题感兴趣，欢迎加入社群交流。

### Creator

&lt;table&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://sap-doc.nasdaddy.com/&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;media/mp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;NasDaddy公众号&quot;/&gt;
            &lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;微信公众号&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload/commits?author=dreammis&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        关注公众号，后台回复 `上传` 获取加群方式
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://sap-doc.nasdaddy.com/&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;media/QR.png&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;赞赏码/入群引导&quot;/&gt;
            &lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;交流群 (通过公众号获取)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://sap-doc.nasdaddy.com/&quot; title=&quot;Documentation&quot;&gt;📖&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        如果您觉得项目有用，可以考虑打赏支持一下
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

### Active Core Team

&lt;table&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://leedebug.github.io/&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;media/edan-qrcode.png&quot; width=&quot;100px;&quot; alt=&quot;Edan Lee&quot;/&gt;
            &lt;br /&gt;
            &lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Edan Lee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dreammis/social-auto-upload/commits?author=LeeDebug&quot; title=&quot;Code&quot;&gt;💻&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://leedebug.github.io/&quot; title=&quot;Documentation&quot;&gt;📖&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;br /&gt;
        封装了 api 接口和 web 前端管理界面
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

## 🤝贡献指南

欢迎各种形式的贡献，包括但不限于：

-   提交 Bug报告 和 Feature请求。
-   改进代码、文档。
-   分享使用经验和教程。

如果您希望贡献代码，请遵循以下步骤：

1.  Fork 本仓库。
2.  创建一个新的分支 (`git checkout -b feature/YourFeature` 或 `bugfix/YourBugfix`)。
3.  提交您的更改 (`git commit -m &#039;Add some feature&#039;`)。
4.  Push到您的分支 (`git push origin feature/YourFeature`)。
5.  创建一个 Pull Request。

## 📜许可证

本项目暂时采用 [MIT License](LICENSE) 开源许可证。

## ⭐Star-History

&gt; 如果这个项目对您有帮助，请给一个 ⭐ Star 以表示支持！

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=dreammis/social-auto-upload&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#dreammis/social-auto-upload&amp;Date)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[huggingface/lerobot]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🤗 LeRobot: Making AI for Robotics more accessible with end-to-end learning]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot">huggingface/lerobot</a></h1>
            <p>🤗 LeRobot: Making AI for Robotics more accessible with end-to-end learning</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,075</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,741</p>
            <p>Stars today: 72 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;media/lerobot-logo-thumbnail.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;media/lerobot-logo-thumbnail.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;LeRobot, Hugging Face Robotics Library&quot; src=&quot;media/lerobot-logo-thumbnail.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Tests](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/actions/workflows/nightly-tests.yml/badge.svg?branch=main)](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/actions/workflows/nightly-tests.yml?query=branch%3Amain)
[![Coverage](https://codecov.io/gh/huggingface/lerobot/branch/main/graph/badge.svg?token=TODO)](https://codecov.io/gh/huggingface/lerobot)
[![Python versions](https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/lerobot)](https://www.python.org/downloads/)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache%202.0-blue.svg)](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/LICENSE)
[![Status](https://img.shields.io/pypi/status/lerobot)](https://pypi.org/project/lerobot/)
[![Version](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/lerobot)](https://pypi.org/project/lerobot/)
[![Examples](https://img.shields.io/badge/Examples-green.svg)](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/tree/main/examples)
[![Contributor Covenant](https://img.shields.io/badge/Contributor%20Covenant-v2.1%20adopted-ff69b4.svg)](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md)
[![Discord](https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/C5P34WJ68S?style=flat)](https://discord.gg/s3KuuzsPFb)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/examples/12_use_so101.md&quot;&gt;
        Build Your Own SO-101 Robot!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; gap: 1rem; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&quot; &gt;
    &lt;img
      src=&quot;media/so101/so101.webp?raw=true&quot;
      alt=&quot;SO-101 follower arm&quot;
      title=&quot;SO-101 follower arm&quot;
      style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot;
    /&gt;
    &lt;img
      src=&quot;media/so101/so101-leader.webp?raw=true&quot;
      alt=&quot;SO-101 leader arm&quot;
      title=&quot;SO-101 leader arm&quot;
      style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot;
    /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet the updated SO100, the SO-101 – Just €114 per arm!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Train it in minutes with a few simple moves on your laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then sit back and watch your creation act autonomously! 🤯&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/examples/12_use_so101.md&quot;&gt;
      See the full SO-101 tutorial here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Want to take it to the next level? Make your SO-101 mobile by building LeKiwi!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/examples/11_use_lekiwi.md&quot;&gt;LeKiwi tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and bring your robot to life on wheels.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;media/lekiwi/kiwi.webp?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;LeKiwi mobile robot&quot; title=&quot;LeKiwi mobile robot&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;LeRobot: State-of-the-art AI for real-world robotics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;

---

🤗 LeRobot aims to provide models, datasets, and tools for real-world robotics in PyTorch. The goal is to lower the barrier to entry to robotics so that everyone can contribute and benefit from sharing datasets and pretrained models.

🤗 LeRobot contains state-of-the-art approaches that have been shown to transfer to the real-world with a focus on imitation learning and reinforcement learning.

🤗 LeRobot already provides a set of pretrained models, datasets with human collected demonstrations, and simulation environments to get started without assembling a robot. In the coming weeks, the plan is to add more and more support for real-world robotics on the most affordable and capable robots out there.

🤗 LeRobot hosts pretrained models and datasets on this Hugging Face community page: [huggingface.co/lerobot](https://huggingface.co/lerobot)

#### Examples of pretrained models on simulation environments

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/gym/aloha_act.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;ACT policy on ALOHA env&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/gym/simxarm_tdmpc.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;TDMPC policy on SimXArm env&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;media/gym/pusht_diffusion.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;Diffusion policy on PushT env&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;ACT policy on ALOHA env&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;TDMPC policy on SimXArm env&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Diffusion policy on PushT env&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

### Acknowledgment

- Thanks to Tony Zhao, Zipeng Fu and colleagues for open sourcing ACT policy, ALOHA environments and datasets. Ours are adapted from [ALOHA](https://tonyzhaozh.github.io/aloha) and [Mobile ALOHA](https://mobile-aloha.github.io).
- Thanks to Cheng Chi, Zhenjia Xu and colleagues for open sourcing Diffusion policy, Pusht environment and datasets, as well as UMI datasets. Ours are adapted from [Diffusion Policy](https://diffusion-policy.cs.columbia.edu) and [UMI Gripper](https://umi-gripper.github.io).
- Thanks to Nicklas Hansen, Yunhai Feng and colleagues for open sourcing TDMPC policy, Simxarm environments and datasets. Ours are adapted from [TDMPC](https://github.com/nicklashansen/tdmpc) and [FOWM](https://www.yunhaifeng.com/FOWM).
- Thanks to Antonio Loquercio and Ashish Kumar for their early support.
- Thanks to [Seungjae (Jay) Lee](https://sjlee.cc/), [Mahi Shafiullah](https://mahis.life/) and colleagues for open sourcing [VQ-BeT](https://sjlee.cc/vq-bet/) policy and helping us adapt the codebase to our repository. The policy is adapted from [VQ-BeT repo](https://github.com/jayLEE0301/vq_bet_official).


## Installation

Download our source code:
```bash
git clone https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot.git
cd lerobot
```

Create a virtual environment with Python 3.10 and activate it, e.g. with [`miniconda`](https://docs.anaconda.com/free/miniconda/index.html):
```bash
conda create -y -n lerobot python=3.10
conda activate lerobot
```

When using `miniconda`, install `ffmpeg` in your environment:
```bash
conda install ffmpeg -c conda-forge
```

&gt; **NOTE:** This usually installs `ffmpeg 7.X` for your platform compiled with the `libsvtav1` encoder. If `libsvtav1` is not supported (check supported encoders with `ffmpeg -encoders`), you can:
&gt;  - _[On any platform]_ Explicitly install `ffmpeg 7.X` using:
&gt;  ```bash
&gt;  conda install ffmpeg=7.1.1 -c conda-forge
&gt;  ```
&gt;  - _[On Linux only]_ Install [ffmpeg build dependencies](https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/CompilationGuide/Ubuntu#GettheDependencies) and [compile ffmpeg from source with libsvtav1](https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/CompilationGuide/Ubuntu#libsvtav1), and make sure you use the corresponding ffmpeg binary to your install with `which ffmpeg`.

Install 🤗 LeRobot:
```bash
pip install -e .
```

&gt; **NOTE:** If you encounter build errors, you may need to install additional dependencies (`cmake`, `build-essential`, and `ffmpeg libs`). On Linux, run:
`sudo apt-get install cmake build-essential python3-dev pkg-config libavformat-dev libavcodec-dev libavdevice-dev libavutil-dev libswscale-dev libswresample-dev libavfilter-dev pkg-config`. For other systems, see: [Compiling PyAV](https://pyav.org/docs/develop/overview/installation.html#bring-your-own-ffmpeg)

For simulations, 🤗 LeRobot comes with gymnasium environments that can be installed as extras:
- [aloha](https://github.com/huggingface/gym-aloha)
- [xarm](https://github.com/huggingface/gym-xarm)
- [pusht](https://github.com/huggingface/gym-pusht)

For instance, to install 🤗 LeRobot with aloha and pusht, use:
```bash
pip install -e &quot;.[aloha, pusht]&quot;
```

To use [Weights and Biases](https://docs.wandb.ai/quickstart) for experiment tracking, log in with
```bash
wandb login
```

(note: you will also need to enable WandB in the configuration. See below.)

## Walkthrough

```
.
├── examples             # contains demonstration examples, start here to learn about LeRobot
|   └── advanced         # contains even more examples for those who have mastered the basics
├── lerobot
|   ├── configs          # contains config classes with all options that you can override in the command line
|   ├── common           # contains classes and utilities
|   |   ├── datasets       # various datasets of human demonstrations: aloha, pusht, xarm
|   |   ├── envs           # various sim environments: aloha, pusht, xarm
|   |   ├── policies       # various policies: act, diffusion, tdmpc
|   |   ├── robot_devices  # various real devices: dynamixel motors, opencv cameras, koch robots
|   |   └── utils          # various utilities
|   └── scripts          # contains functions to execute via command line
|       ├── eval.py                 # load policy and evaluate it on an environment
|       ├── train.py                # train a policy via imitation learning and/or reinforcement learning
|       ├── control_robot.py        # teleoperate a real robot, record data, run a policy
|       ├── push_dataset_to_hub.py  # convert your dataset into LeRobot dataset format and upload it to the Hugging Face hub
|       └── visualize_dataset.py    # load a dataset and render its demonstrations
├── outputs               # contains results of scripts execution: logs, videos, model checkpoints
└── tests                 # contains pytest utilities for continuous integration
```

### Visualize datasets

Check out [example 1](./examples/1_load_lerobot_dataset.py) that illustrates how to use our dataset class which automatically downloads data from the Hugging Face hub.

You can also locally visualize episodes from a dataset on the hub by executing our script from the command line:
```bash
python lerobot/scripts/visualize_dataset.py \
    --repo-id lerobot/pusht \
    --episode-index 0
```

or from a dataset in a local folder with the `root` option and the `--local-files-only` (in the following case the dataset will be searched for in `./my_local_data_dir/lerobot/pusht`)
```bash
python lerobot/scripts/visualize_dataset.py \
    --repo-id lerobot/pusht \
    --root ./my_local_data_dir \
    --local-files-only 1 \
    --episode-index 0
```


It will open `rerun.io` and display the camera streams, robot states and actions, like this:

https://github-production-user-asset-6210df.s3.amazonaws.com/4681518/328035972-fd46b787-b532-47e2-bb6f-fd536a55a7ed.mov?X-Amz-Algorithm=AWS4-HMAC-SHA256&amp;X-Amz-Credential=AKIAVCODYLSA53PQK4ZA%2F20240505%2Fus-east-1%2Fs3%2Faws4_request&amp;X-Amz-Date=20240505T172924Z&amp;X-Amz-Expires=300&amp;X-Amz-Signature=d680b26c532eeaf80740f08af3320d22ad0b8a4e4da1bcc4f33142c15b509eda&amp;X-Amz-SignedHeaders=host&amp;actor_id=24889239&amp;key_id=0&amp;repo_id=748713144


Our script can also visualize datasets stored on a distant server. See `python lerobot/scripts/visualize_dataset.py --help` for more instructions.

### The `LeRobotDataset` format

A dataset in `LeRobotDataset` format is very simple to use. It can be loaded from a repository on the Hugging Face hub or a local folder simply with e.g. `dataset = LeRobotDataset(&quot;lerobot/aloha_static_coffee&quot;)` and can be indexed into like any Hugging Face and PyTorch dataset. For instance `dataset[0]` will retrieve a single temporal frame from the dataset containing observation(s) and an action as PyTorch tensors ready to be fed to a model.

A specificity of `LeRobotDataset` is that, rather than retrieving a single frame by its index, we can retrieve several frames based on their temporal relationship with the indexed frame, by setting `delta_timestamps` to a list of relative times with respect to the indexed frame. For example, with `delta_timestamps = {&quot;observation.image&quot;: [-1, -0.5, -0.2, 0]}`  one can retrieve, for a given index, 4 frames: 3 &quot;previous&quot; frames 1 second, 0.5 seconds, and 0.2 seconds before the indexed frame, and the indexed frame itself (corresponding to the 0 entry). See example [1_load_lerobot_dataset.py](examples/1_load_lerobot_dataset.py) for more details on `delta_timestamps`.

Under the hood, the `LeRobotDataset` format makes use of several ways to serialize data which can be useful to understand if you plan to work more closely with this format. We tried to make a flexible yet simple dataset format that would cover most type of features and specificities present in reinforcement learning and robotics, in simulation and in real-world, with a focus on cameras and robot states but easily extended to other types of sensory inputs as long as they can be represented by a tensor.

Here are the important details and internal structure organization of a typical `LeRobotDataset` instantiated with `dataset = LeRobotDataset(&quot;lerobot/aloha_static_coffee&quot;)`. The exact features will change from dataset to dataset but not the main aspects:

```
dataset attributes:
  ├ hf_dataset: a Hugging Face dataset (backed by Arrow/parquet). Typical features example:
  │  ├ observation.images.cam_high (VideoFrame):
  │  │   VideoFrame = {&#039;path&#039;: path to a mp4 video, &#039;timestamp&#039; (float32): timestamp in the video}
  │  ├ observation.state (list of float32): position of an arm joints (for instance)
  │  ... (more observations)
  │  ├ action (list of float32): goal position of an arm joints (for instance)
  │  ├ episode_index (int64): index of the episode for this sample
  │  ├ frame_index (int64): index of the frame for this sample in the episode ; starts at 0 for each episode
  │  ├ timestamp (float32): timestamp in the episode
  │  ├ next.done (bool): indicates the end of an episode ; True for the last frame in each episode
  │  └ index (int64): general index in the whole dataset
  ├ episode_data_index: contains 2 tensors with the start and end indices of each episode
  │  ├ from (1D int64 tensor): first frame index for each episode — shape (num episodes,) starts with 0
  │  └ to: (1D int64 tensor): last frame index for each episode — shape (num episodes,)
  ├ stats: a dictionary of statistics (max, mean, min, std) for each feature in the dataset, for instance
  │  ├ observation.images.cam_high: {&#039;max&#039;: tensor with same number of dimensions (e.g. `(c, 1, 1)` for images, `(c,)` for states), etc.}
  │  ...
  ├ info: a dictionary of metadata on the dataset
  │  ├ codebase_version (str): this is to keep track of the codebase version the dataset was created with
  │  ├ fps (float): frame per second the dataset is recorded/synchronized to
  │  ├ video (bool): indicates if frames are encoded in mp4 video files to save space or stored as png files
  │  └ encoding (dict): if video, this documents the main options that were used with ffmpeg to encode the videos
  ├ videos_dir (Path): where the mp4 videos or png images are stored/accessed
  └ camera_keys (list of string): the keys to access camera features in the item returned by the dataset (e.g. `[&quot;observation.images.cam_high&quot;, ...]`)
```

A `LeRobotDataset` is serialised using several widespread file formats for each of its parts, namely:
- hf_dataset stored using Hugging Face datasets library serialization to parquet
- videos are stored in mp4 format to save space
- metadata are stored in plain json/jsonl files

Dataset can be uploaded/downloaded from the HuggingFace hub seamlessly. To work on a local dataset, you can specify its location with the `root` argument if it&#039;s not in the default `~/.cache/huggingface/lerobot` location.

### Evaluate a pretrained policy

Check out [example 2](./examples/2_evaluate_pretrained_policy.py) that illustrates how to download a pretrained policy from Hugging Face hub, and run an evaluation on its corresponding environment.

We also provide a more capable script to parallelize the evaluation over multiple environments during the same rollout. Here is an example with a pretrained model hosted on [lerobot/diffusion_pusht](https://huggingface.co/lerobot/diffusion_pusht):
```bash
python lerobot/scripts/eval.py \
    --policy.path=lerobot/diffusion_pusht \
    --env.type=pusht \
    --eval.batch_size=10 \
    --eval.n_episodes=10 \
    --policy.use_amp=false \
    --policy.device=cuda
```

Note: After training your own policy, you can re-evaluate the checkpoints with:

```bash
python lerobot/scripts/eval.py --policy.path={OUTPUT_DIR}/checkpoints/last/pretrained_model
```

See `python lerobot/scripts/eval.py --help` for more instructions.

### Train your own policy

Check out [example 3](./examples/3_train_policy.py) that illustrates how to train a model using our core library in python, and [example 4](./examples/4_train_policy_with_script.md) that shows how to use our training script from command line.

To use wandb for logging training and evaluation curves, make sure you&#039;ve run `wandb login` as a one-time setup step. Then, when running the training command above, enable WandB in the configuration by adding `--wandb.enable=true`.

A link to the wandb logs for the run will also show up in yellow in your terminal. Here is an example of what they look like in your browser. Please also check [here](./examples/4_train_policy_with_script.md#typical-logs-and-metrics) for the explanation of some commonly used metrics in logs.

![](media/wandb.png)

Note: For efficiency, during training every checkpoint is evaluated on a low number of episodes. You may use `--eval.n_episodes=500` to evaluate on more episodes than the default. Or, after training, you may want to re-evaluate your best checkpoints on more episodes or change the evaluation settings. See `python lerobot/scripts/eval.py --help` for more instructions.

#### Reproduce state-of-the-art (SOTA)

We provide some pretrained policies on our [hub page](https://huggingface.co/lerobot) that can achieve state-of-the-art performances.
You can reproduce their training by loading the config from their run. Simply running:
```bash
python lerobot/scripts/train.py --config_path=lerobot/diffusion_pusht
```
reproduces SOTA results for Diffusion Policy on the PushT task.

## Contribute

If you would like to contribute to 🤗 LeRobot, please check out our [contribution guide](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md).

&lt;!-- ### Add a new dataset

To add a dataset to the hub, you need to login using a write-access token, which can be generated from the [Hugging Face settings](https://huggingface.co/settings/tokens):
```bash
huggingface-cli login --token ${HUGGINGFACE_TOKEN} --add-to-git-credential
```

Then point to your raw dataset folder (e.g. `data/aloha_static_pingpong_test_raw`), and push your dataset to the hub with:
```bash
python lerobot/scripts/push_dataset_to_hub.py \
--raw-dir data/aloha_static_pingpong_test_raw \
--out-dir data \
--repo-id lerobot/aloha_static_pingpong_test \
--raw-format aloha_hdf5
```

See `python lerobot/scripts/push_dataset_to_hub.py --help` for more instructions.

If your dataset format is not supported, implement your own in `lerobot/common/datasets/push_dataset_to_hub/${raw_format}_format.py` by copying examples like [pusht_zarr](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/lerobot/common/datasets/push_dataset_to_hub/pusht_zarr_format.py), [umi_zarr](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/lerobot/common/datasets/push_dataset_to_hub/umi_zarr_format.py), [aloha_hdf5](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/lerobot/common/datasets/push_dataset_to_hub/aloha_hdf5_format.py), or [xarm_pkl](https://github.com/huggingface/lerobot/blob/main/lerobot/common/datasets/push_dataset_to_hub/xarm_pkl_format.py). --&gt;


### Add a pretrained policy

Once you have trained a policy you may upload it to the Hugging Face hub using a hub id that looks like `${hf_user}/${repo_name}` (e.g. [lerobot/diffusion_pusht](https://huggingface.co/lerobot/diffusion_pusht)).

You first need to find the checkpoint folder located inside your experiment directory (e.g. `outputs/train/2024-05-05/20-21-12_aloha_act_default/checkpoints/002500`). Within that there is a `pretrained_model` directory which should contain:
- `config.json`: A serialized version of the policy configuration (following the policy&#039;s dataclass config).
- `model.safetensors`: A set of `torch.nn.Module` parameters, saved in [Hugging Face Safetensors](https://huggingfac

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Create Reddit Videos with just✨ one command ✨]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot">elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot</a></h1>
            <p>Create Reddit Videos with just✨ one command ✨</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,893</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,046</p>
            <p>Stars today: 175 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Reddit Video Maker Bot 🎥

All done WITHOUT video editing or asset compiling. Just pure ✨programming magic✨.

Created by Lewis Menelaws &amp; [TMRRW](https://tmrrwinc.ca)

&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://tmrrwinc.ca&quot;&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6053155/170528535-e274dc0b-7972-4b27-af22-637f8c370133.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6053155/170528582-cb6671e7-5a2f-4bd4-a048-0e6cfa54f0f7.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6053155/170528582-cb6671e7-5a2f-4bd4-a048-0e6cfa54f0f7.png&quot; width=&quot;350&quot;&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;/a&gt;

## Video Explainer

[![lewisthumbnail](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6053155/173631669-1d1b14ad-c478-4010-b57d-d79592a789f2.png)
](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3gjcY_00U1w)

## Motivation 🤔

These videos on TikTok, YouTube and Instagram get MILLIONS of views across all platforms and require very little effort.
The only original thing being done is the editing and gathering of all materials...

... but what if we can automate that process? 🤔

## Disclaimers 🚨

- **At the moment**, this repository won&#039;t attempt to upload this content through this bot. It will give you a file that
  you will then have to upload manually. This is for the sake of avoiding any sort of community guideline issues.

## Requirements

- Python 3.10
- Playwright (this should install automatically in installation)

## Installation 👩‍💻

1. Clone this repository
2. Run `pip install -r requirements.txt`
3. Run `python -m playwright install` and `python -m playwright install-deps`

**EXPERIMENTAL!!!!**

On macOS and Linux (debian, arch, fedora and centos, and based on those), you can run an install script that will automatically install steps 1 to 3. (requires bash)

`bash &lt;(curl -sL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/elebumm/RedditVideoMakerBot/master/install.sh)`

This can also be used to update the installation

4. Run `python main.py`
5. Visit [the Reddit Apps page.](https://www.reddit.com/prefs/apps), and set up an app that is a &quot;script&quot;. Paste any URL in redirect URL. Ex:`https://jasoncameron.dev`
6. The bot will ask you to fill in your details to connect to the Reddit API, and configure the bot to your liking
7. Enjoy 😎
8. If you need to reconfigure the bot, simply open the `config.toml` file and delete the lines that need to be changed. On the next run of the bot, it will help you reconfigure those options.

(Note if you got an error installing or running the bot try first rerunning the command with a three after the name e.g. python3 or pip3)

If you want to read more detailed guide about the bot, please refer to the [documentation](https://reddit-video-maker-bot.netlify.app/)

## Video

https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/66544866/173453972-6526e4e6-c6ef-41c5-ab40-5d275e724e7c.mp4

## Contributing &amp; Ways to improve 📈

In its current state, this bot does exactly what it needs to do. However, improvements can always be made!

I have tried to simplify the code so anyone can read it and start contributing at any skill level. Don&#039;t be shy :) contribute!

- [ ] Creating better documentation and adding a command line interface.
- [x] Allowing the user to choose background music for their videos.
- [x] Allowing users to choose a reddit thread instead of being randomized.
- [x] Allowing users to choose a background that is picked instead of the Minecraft one.
- [x] Allowing users to choose between any subreddit.
- [x] Allowing users to change voice.
- [x] Checks if a video has already been created
- [x] Light and Dark modes
- [x] NSFW post filter

Please read our [contributing guidelines](CONTRIBUTING.md) for more detailed information.

### For any questions or support join the [Discord](https://discord.gg/qfQSx45xCV) server

## Developers and maintainers.

Elebumm (Lewis#6305) - https://github.com/elebumm (Founder)

Jason Cameron - https://github.com/JasonLovesDoggo (Maintainer)

Simon (OpenSourceSimon) - https://github.com/OpenSourceSimon

CallumIO (c.#6837) - https://github.com/CallumIO

Verq (Verq#2338) - https://github.com/CordlessCoder

LukaHietala (Pix.#0001) - https://github.com/LukaHietala

Freebiell (Freebie#3263) - https://github.com/FreebieII

Aman Raza (electro199#8130) - https://github.com/electro199

Cyteon (cyteon) - https://github.com/cyteon


## LICENSE
[Roboto Fonts](https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Roboto/about) are licensed under [Apache License V2](https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[donnemartin/system-design-primer]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Learn how to design large-scale systems. Prep for the system design interview. Includes Anki flashcards.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer">donnemartin/system-design-primer</a></h1>
            <p>Learn how to design large-scale systems. Prep for the system design interview. Includes Anki flashcards.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 304,290</p>
            <p>Forks: 50,336</p>
            <p>Stars today: 422 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>*[English](README.md) ∙ [日本語](README-ja.md) ∙ [简体中文](README-zh-Hans.md) ∙ [繁體中文](README-zh-TW.md) | [العَرَبِيَّة‎](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/170) ∙ [বাংলা](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/220) ∙ [Português do Brasil](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/40) ∙ [Deutsch](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/186) ∙ [ελληνικά](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/130) ∙ [עברית](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/272) ∙ [Italiano](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/104) ∙ [한국어](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/102) ∙ [فارسی](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/110) ∙ [Polski](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/68) ∙ [русский язык](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/87) ∙ [Español](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/136) ∙ [ภาษาไทย](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/187) ∙ [Türkçe](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/39) ∙ [tiếng Việt](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/127) ∙ [Français](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/250) | [Add Translation](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/28)*

**Help [translate](TRANSLATIONS.md) this guide!**

# The System Design Primer

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;images/jj3A5N8.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Motivation

&gt; Learn how to design large-scale systems.
&gt;
&gt; Prep for the system design interview.

### Learn how to design large-scale systems

Learning how to design scalable systems will help you become a better engineer.

System design is a broad topic.  There is a **vast amount of resources scattered throughout the web** on system design principles.

This repo is an **organized collection** of resources to help you learn how to build systems at scale.

### Learn from the open source community

This is a continually updated, open source project.

[Contributions](#contributing) are welcome!

### Prep for the system design interview

In addition to coding interviews, system design is a **required component** of the **technical interview process** at many tech companies.

**Practice common system design interview questions** and **compare** your results with **sample solutions**: discussions, code, and diagrams.

Additional topics for interview prep:

* [Study guide](#study-guide)
* [How to approach a system design interview question](#how-to-approach-a-system-design-interview-question)
* [System design interview questions, **with solutions**](#system-design-interview-questions-with-solutions)
* [Object-oriented design interview questions, **with solutions**](#object-oriented-design-interview-questions-with-solutions)
* [Additional system design interview questions](#additional-system-design-interview-questions)

## Anki flashcards

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;images/zdCAkB3.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

The provided [Anki flashcard decks](https://apps.ankiweb.net/) use spaced repetition to help you retain key system design concepts.

* [System design deck](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/tree/master/resources/flash_cards/System%20Design.apkg)
* [System design exercises deck](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/tree/master/resources/flash_cards/System%20Design%20Exercises.apkg)
* [Object oriented design exercises deck](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/tree/master/resources/flash_cards/OO%20Design.apkg)

Great for use while on-the-go.

### Coding Resource: Interactive Coding Challenges

Looking for resources to help you prep for the [**Coding Interview**](https://github.com/donnemartin/interactive-coding-challenges)?

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;images/b4YtAEN.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

Check out the sister repo [**Interactive Coding Challenges**](https://github.com/donnemartin/interactive-coding-challenges), which contains an additional Anki deck:

* [Coding deck](https://github.com/donnemartin/interactive-coding-challenges/tree/master/anki_cards/Coding.apkg)

## Contributing

&gt; Learn from the community.

Feel free to submit pull requests to help:

* Fix errors
* Improve sections
* Add new sections
* [Translate](https://github.com/donnemartin/system-design-primer/issues/28)

Content that needs some polishing is placed [under development](#under-development).

Review the [Contributing Guidelines](CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Index of system design topics

&gt; Summaries of various system design topics, including pros and cons.  **Everything is a trade-off**.
&gt;
&gt; Each section contains links to more in-depth resources.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;images/jrUBAF7.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

* [System design topics: start here](#system-design-topics-start-here)
    * [Step 1: Review the scalability video lecture](#step-1-review-the-scalability-video-lecture)
    * [Step 2: Review the scalability article](#step-2-review-the-scalability-article)
    * [Next steps](#next-steps)
* [Performance vs scalability](#performance-vs-scalability)
* [Latency vs throughput](#latency-vs-throughput)
* [Availability vs consistency](#availability-vs-consistency)
    * [CAP theorem](#cap-theorem)
        * [CP - consistency and partition tolerance](#cp---consistency-and-partition-tolerance)
        * [AP - availability and partition tolerance](#ap---availability-and-partition-tolerance)
* [Consistency patterns](#consistency-patterns)
    * [Weak consistency](#weak-consistency)
    * [Eventual consistency](#eventual-consistency)
    * [Strong consistency](#strong-consistency)
* [Availability patterns](#availability-patterns)
    * [Fail-over](#fail-over)
    * [Replication](#replication)
    * [Availability in numbers](#availability-in-numbers)
* [Domain name system](#domain-name-system)
* [Content delivery network](#content-delivery-network)
    * [Push CDNs](#push-cdns)
    * [Pull CDNs](#pull-cdns)
* [Load balancer](#load-balancer)
    * [Active-passive](#active-passive)
    * [Active-active](#active-active)
    * [Layer 4 load balancing](#layer-4-load-balancing)
    * [Layer 7 load balancing](#layer-7-load-balancing)
    * [Horizontal scaling](#horizontal-scaling)
* [Reverse proxy (web server)](#reverse-proxy-web-server)
    * [Load balancer vs reverse proxy](#load-balancer-vs-reverse-proxy)
* [Application layer](#application-layer)
    * [Microservices](#microservices)
    * [Service discovery](#service-discovery)
* [Database](#database)
    * [Relational database management system (RDBMS)](#relational-database-management-system-rdbms)
        * [Master-slave replication](#master-slave-replication)
        * [Master-master replication](#master-master-replication)
        * [Federation](#federation)
        * [Sharding](#sharding)
        * [Denormalization](#denormalization)
        * [SQL tuning](#sql-tuning)
    * [NoSQL](#nosql)
        * [Key-value store](#key-value-store)
        * [Document store](#document-store)
        * [Wide column store](#wide-column-store)
        * [Graph Database](#graph-database)
    * [SQL or NoSQL](#sql-or-nosql)
* [Cache](#cache)
    * [Client caching](#client-caching)
    * [CDN caching](#cdn-caching)
    * [Web server caching](#web-server-caching)
    * [Database caching](#database-caching)
    * [Application caching](#application-caching)
    * [Caching at the database query level](#caching-at-the-database-query-level)
    * [Caching at the object level](#caching-at-the-object-level)
    * [When to update the cache](#when-to-update-the-cache)
        * [Cache-aside](#cache-aside)
        * [Write-through](#write-through)
        * [Write-behind (write-back)](#write-behind-write-back)
        * [Refresh-ahead](#refresh-ahead)
* [Asynchronism](#asynchronism)
    * [Message queues](#message-queues)
    * [Task queues](#task-queues)
    * [Back pressure](#back-pressure)
* [Communication](#communication)
    * [Transmission control protocol (TCP)](#transmission-control-protocol-tcp)
    * [User datagram protocol (UDP)](#user-datagram-protocol-udp)
    * [Remote procedure call (RPC)](#remote-procedure-call-rpc)
    * [Representational state transfer (REST)](#representational-state-transfer-rest)
* [Security](#security)
* [Appendix](#appendix)
    * [Powers of two table](#powers-of-two-table)
    * [Latency numbers every programmer should know](#latency-numbers-every-programmer-should-know)
    * [Additional system design interview questions](#additional-system-design-interview-questions)
    * [Real world architectures](#real-world-architectures)
    * [Company architectures](#company-architectures)
    * [Company engineering blogs](#company-engineering-blogs)
* [Under development](#under-development)
* [Credits](#credits)
* [Contact info](#contact-info)
* [License](#license)

## Study guide

&gt; Suggested topics to review based on your interview timeline (short, medium, long).

![Imgur](images/OfVllex.png)

**Q: For interviews, do I need to know everything here?**

**A: No, you don&#039;t need to know everything here to prepare for the interview**.

What you are asked in an interview depends on variables such as:

* How much experience you have
* What your technical background is
* What positions you are interviewing for
* Which companies you are interviewing with
* Luck

More experienced candidates are generally expected to know more about system design.  Architects or team leads might be expected to know more than individual contributors.  Top tech companies are likely to have one or more design interview rounds.

Start broad and go deeper in a few areas.  It helps to know a little about various key system design topics.  Adjust the following guide based on your timeline, experience, what positions you are interviewing for, and which companies you are interviewing with.

* **Short timeline** - Aim for **breadth** with system design topics.  Practice by solving **some** interview questions.
* **Medium timeline** - Aim for **breadth** and **some depth** with system design topics.  Practice by solving **many** interview questions.
* **Long timeline** - Aim for **breadth** and **more depth** with system design topics.  Practice by solving **most** interview questions.

| | Short | Medium | Long |
|---|---|---|---|
| Read through the [System design topics](#index-of-system-design-topics) to get a broad understanding of how systems work | :+1: | :+1: | :+1: |
| Read through a few articles in the [Company engineering blogs](#company-engineering-blogs) for the companies you are interviewing with | :+1: | :+1: | :+1: |
| Read through a few [Real world architectures](#real-world-architectures) | :+1: | :+1: | :+1: |
| Review [How to approach a system design interview question](#how-to-approach-a-system-design-interview-question) | :+1: | :+1: | :+1: |
| Work through [System design interview questions with solutions](#system-design-interview-questions-with-solutions) | Some | Many | Most |
| Work through [Object-oriented design interview questions with solutions](#object-oriented-design-interview-questions-with-solutions) | Some | Many | Most |
| Review [Additional system design interview questions](#additional-system-design-interview-questions) | Some | Many | Most |

## How to approach a system design interview question

&gt; How to tackle a system design interview question.

The system design interview is an **open-ended conversation**.  You are expected to lead it.

You can use the following steps to guide the discussion.  To help solidify this process, work through the [System design interview questions with solutions](#system-design-interview-questions-with-solutions) section using the following steps.

### Step 1: Outline use cases, constraints, and assumptions

Gather requirements and scope the problem.  Ask questions to clarify use cases and constraints.  Discuss assumptions.

* Who is going to use it?
* How are they going to use it?
* How many users are there?
* What does the system do?
* What are the inputs and outputs of the system?
* How much data do we expect to handle?
* How many requests per second do we expect?
* What is the expected read to write ratio?

### Step 2: Create a high level design

Outline a high level design with all important components.

* Sketch the main components and connections
* Justify your ideas

### Step 3: Design core components

Dive into details for each core component.  For example, if you were asked to [design a url shortening service](solutions/system_design/pastebin/README.md), discuss:

* Generating and storing a hash of the full url
    * [MD5](solutions/system_design/pastebin/README.md) and [Base62](solutions/system_design/pastebin/README.md)
    * Hash collisions
    * SQL or NoSQL
    * Database schema
* Translating a hashed url to the full url
    * Database lookup
* API and object-oriented design

### Step 4: Scale the design

Identify and address bottlenecks, given the constraints.  For example, do you need the following to address scalability issues?

* Load balancer
* Horizontal scaling
* Caching
* Database sharding

Discuss potential solutions and trade-offs.  Everything is a trade-off.  Address bottlenecks using [principles of scalable system design](#index-of-system-design-topics).

### Back-of-the-envelope calculations

You might be asked to do some estimates by hand.  Refer to the [Appendix](#appendix) for the following resources:

* [Use back of the envelope calculations](http://highscalability.com/blog/2011/1/26/google-pro-tip-use-back-of-the-envelope-calculations-to-choo.html)
* [Powers of two table](#powers-of-two-table)
* [Latency numbers every programmer should know](#latency-numbers-every-programmer-should-know)

### Source(s) and further reading

Check out the following links to get a better idea of what to expect:

* [How to ace a systems design interview](https://www.palantir.com/2011/10/how-to-rock-a-systems-design-interview/)
* [The system design interview](http://www.hiredintech.com/system-design)
* [Intro to Architecture and Systems Design Interviews](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZgdS0EUmn70)
* [System design template](https://leetcode.com/discuss/career/229177/My-System-Design-Template)

## System design interview questions with solutions

&gt; Common system design interview questions with sample discussions, code, and diagrams.
&gt;
&gt; Solutions linked to content in the `solutions/` folder.

| Question | |
|---|---|
| Design Pastebin.com (or Bit.ly) | [Solution](solutions/system_design/pastebin/README.md) |
| Design the Twitter timeline and search (or Facebook feed and search) | [Solution](solutions/system_design/twitter/README.md) |
| Design a web crawler | [Solution](solutions/system_design/web_crawler/README.md) |
| Design Mint.com | [Solution](solutions/system_design/mint/README.md) |
| Design the data structures for a social network | [Solution](solutions/system_design/social_graph/README.md) |
| Design a key-value store for a search engine | [Solution](solutions/system_design/query_cache/README.md) |
| Design Amazon&#039;s sales ranking by category feature | [Solution](solutions/system_design/sales_rank/README.md) |
| Design a system that scales to millions of users on AWS | [Solution](solutions/system_design/scaling_aws/README.md) |
| Add a system design question | [Contribute](#contributing) |

### Design Pastebin.com (or Bit.ly)

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/pastebin/README.md)

![Imgur](images/4edXG0T.png)

### Design the Twitter timeline and search (or Facebook feed and search)

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/twitter/README.md)

![Imgur](images/jrUBAF7.png)

### Design a web crawler

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/web_crawler/README.md)

![Imgur](images/bWxPtQA.png)

### Design Mint.com

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/mint/README.md)

![Imgur](images/V5q57vU.png)

### Design the data structures for a social network

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/social_graph/README.md)

![Imgur](images/cdCv5g7.png)

### Design a key-value store for a search engine

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/query_cache/README.md)

![Imgur](images/4j99mhe.png)

### Design Amazon&#039;s sales ranking by category feature

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/sales_rank/README.md)

![Imgur](images/MzExP06.png)

### Design a system that scales to millions of users on AWS

[View exercise and solution](solutions/system_design/scaling_aws/README.md)

![Imgur](images/jj3A5N8.png)

## Object-oriented design interview questions with solutions

&gt; Common object-oriented design interview questions with sample discussions, code, and diagrams.
&gt;
&gt; Solutions linked to content in the `solutions/` folder.

&gt;**Note: This section is under development**

| Question | |
|---|---|
| Design a hash map | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/hash_table/hash_map.ipynb)  |
| Design a least recently used cache | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/lru_cache/lru_cache.ipynb)  |
| Design a call center | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/call_center/call_center.ipynb)  |
| Design a deck of cards | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/deck_of_cards/deck_of_cards.ipynb)  |
| Design a parking lot | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/parking_lot/parking_lot.ipynb)  |
| Design a chat server | [Solution](solutions/object_oriented_design/online_chat/online_chat.ipynb)  |
| Design a circular array | [Contribute](#contributing)  |
| Add an object-oriented design question | [Contribute](#contributing) |

## System design topics: start here

New to system design?

First, you&#039;ll need a basic understanding of common principles, learning about what they are, how they are used, and their pros and cons.

### Step 1: Review the scalability video lecture

[Scalability Lecture at Harvard](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-W9F__D3oY4)

* Topics covered:
    * Vertical scaling
    * Horizontal scaling
    * Caching
    * Load balancing
    * Database replication
    * Database partitioning

### Step 2: Review the scalability article

[Scalability](https://web.archive.org/web/20221030091841/http://www.lecloud.net/tagged/scalability/chrono)

* Topics covered:
    * [Clones](https://web.archive.org/web/20220530193911/https://www.lecloud.net/post/7295452622/scalability-for-dummies-part-1-clones)
    * [Databases](https://web.archive.org/web/20220602114024/https://www.lecloud.net/post/7994751381/scalability-for-dummies-part-2-database)
    * [Caches](https://web.archive.org/web/20230126233752/https://www.lecloud.net/post/9246290032/scalability-for-dummies-part-3-cache)
    * [Asynchronism](https://web.archive.org/web/20220926171507/https://www.lecloud.net/post/9699762917/scalability-for-dummies-part-4-asynchronism)

### Next steps

Next, we&#039;ll look at high-level trade-offs:

* **Performance** vs **scalability**
* **Latency** vs **throughput**
* **Availability** vs **consistency**

Keep in mind that **everything is a trade-off**.

Then we&#039;ll dive into more specific topics such as DNS, CDNs, and load balancers.

## Performance vs scalability

A service is **scalable** if it results in increased **performance** in a manner proportional to resources added. Generally, increasing performance means serving more units of work, but it can also be to handle larger units of work, such as when datasets grow.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2006/03/a_word_on_scalability.html&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

Another way to look at performance vs scalability:

* If you have a **performance** problem, your system is slow for a single user.
* If you have a **scalability** problem, your system is fast for a single user but slow under heavy load.

### Source(s) and further reading

* [A word on scalability](http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2006/03/a_word_on_scalability.html)
* [Scalability, availability, s

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ LLMs & VLMs (ACL 2024)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory">hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory</a></h1>
            <p>Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ LLMs & VLMs (ACL 2024)</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 51,678</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,246</p>
            <p>Stars today: 144 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![# LLaMA Factory](assets/logo.png)

[![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory?style=social)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/stargazers)
[![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/commits/main)
[![GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory?color=orange)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/graphs/contributors)
[![GitHub workflow](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/actions/workflows/tests.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/actions/workflows/tests.yml)
[![PyPI](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/llamafactory)](https://pypi.org/project/llamafactory/)
[![Citation](https://img.shields.io/badge/citation-561-green)](https://scholar.google.com/scholar?cites=12620864006390196564)
[![Docker Pulls](https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/hiyouga/llamafactory)](https://hub.docker.com/r/hiyouga/llamafactory/tags)

[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/llamafactory_ai)](https://twitter.com/llamafactory_ai)
[![Discord](https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/rKfvV9r9FK?compact=true&amp;style=flat)](https://discord.gg/rKfvV9r9FK)
[![GitCode](https://gitcode.com/zhengyaowei/LLaMA-Factory/star/badge.svg)](https://gitcode.com/zhengyaowei/LLaMA-Factory)

[![Open in Colab](https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg)](https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing)
[![Open in DSW](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/assets/open-in-dsw.svg)](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory)
[![Open in Alaya](assets/alaya_new.svg)](https://docs.alayanew.com/docs/documents/newActivities/llamafactory/?utm_source=LLaMA-Factory)
[![Open in Spaces](https://img.shields.io/badge/🤗-Open%20in%20Spaces-blue)](https://huggingface.co/spaces/hiyouga/LLaMA-Board)
[![Open in Studios](https://img.shields.io/badge/ModelScope-Open%20in%20Studios-blue)](https://modelscope.cn/studios/hiyouga/LLaMA-Board)
[![Open in Novita](https://img.shields.io/badge/Novita-Deploy%20Template-blue)](https://novita.ai/templates-library/105981?sharer=88115474-394e-4bda-968e-b88e123d0c47)

### Used by [Amazon](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/), [NVIDIA](https://developer.nvidia.com/rtx/ai-toolkit), [Aliyun](https://help.aliyun.com/zh/pai/use-cases/fine-tune-a-llama-3-model-with-llama-factory), etc.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; markdown=&quot;1&quot;&gt;

### Supporters ❤️

&lt;a href=&quot;https://warp.dev/llama-factory&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Warp sponsorship&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ab8dd143-b0fd-4904-bdc5-dd7ecac94eae&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

#### [Warp, the agentic terminal for developers](https://warp.dev/llama-factory)

[Available for MacOS, Linux, &amp; Windows](https://warp.dev/llama-factory)

----

### Easily fine-tune 100+ large language models with zero-code [CLI](#quickstart) and [Web UI](#fine-tuning-with-llama-board-gui-powered-by-gradio)

![GitHub Trend](https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/4535)

&lt;/div&gt;

👋 Join our [WeChat group](assets/wechat.jpg), [NPU user group](assets/wechat_npu.jpg) or [Alaya NeW user group](assets/wechat_alaya.png).

\[ English | [中文](README_zh.md) \]

**Fine-tuning a large language model can be easy as...**

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3991a3a8-4276-4d30-9cab-4cb0c4b9b99e

Choose your path:

- **Documentation**: https://llamafactory.readthedocs.io/en/latest/
- **Colab (free)**: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing
- **Local machine**: Please refer to [usage](#getting-started)
- **PAI-DSW (free trial)**: https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory
- **Alaya NeW (cloud GPU deal)**: https://docs.alayanew.com/docs/documents/newActivities/llamafactory/?utm_source=LLaMA-Factory

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; Except for the above links, all other websites are unauthorized third-party websites. Please carefully use them.

## Table of Contents

- [Features](#features)
- [Blogs](#blogs)
- [Changelog](#changelog)
- [Supported Models](#supported-models)
- [Supported Training Approaches](#supported-training-approaches)
- [Provided Datasets](#provided-datasets)
- [Requirement](#requirement)
- [Getting Started](#getting-started)
  - [Installation](#installation)
  - [Data Preparation](#data-preparation)
  - [Quickstart](#quickstart)
  - [Fine-Tuning with LLaMA Board GUI](#fine-tuning-with-llama-board-gui-powered-by-gradio)
  - [Build Docker](#build-docker)
  - [Deploy with OpenAI-style API and vLLM](#deploy-with-openai-style-api-and-vllm)
  - [Download from ModelScope Hub](#download-from-modelscope-hub)
  - [Download from Modelers Hub](#download-from-modelers-hub)
  - [Use W&amp;B Logger](#use-wb-logger)
  - [Use SwanLab Logger](#use-swanlab-logger)
- [Projects using LLaMA Factory](#projects-using-llama-factory)
- [License](#license)
- [Citation](#citation)
- [Acknowledgement](#acknowledgement)

## Features

- **Various models**: LLaMA, LLaVA, Mistral, Mixtral-MoE, Qwen, Qwen2-VL, DeepSeek, Yi, Gemma, ChatGLM, Phi, etc.
- **Integrated methods**: (Continuous) pre-training, (multimodal) supervised fine-tuning, reward modeling, PPO, DPO, KTO, ORPO, etc.
- **Scalable resources**: 16-bit full-tuning, freeze-tuning, LoRA and 2/3/4/5/6/8-bit QLoRA via AQLM/AWQ/GPTQ/LLM.int8/HQQ/EETQ.
- **Advanced algorithms**: [GaLore](https://github.com/jiaweizzhao/GaLore), [BAdam](https://github.com/Ledzy/BAdam), [APOLLO](https://github.com/zhuhanqing/APOLLO), [Adam-mini](https://github.com/zyushun/Adam-mini), [Muon](https://github.com/KellerJordan/Muon), DoRA, LongLoRA, LLaMA Pro, Mixture-of-Depths, LoRA+, LoftQ and PiSSA.
- **Practical tricks**: [FlashAttention-2](https://github.com/Dao-AILab/flash-attention), [Unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth), [Liger Kernel](https://github.com/linkedin/Liger-Kernel), RoPE scaling, NEFTune and rsLoRA.
- **Wide tasks**: Multi-turn dialogue, tool using, image understanding, visual grounding, video recognition, audio understanding, etc.
- **Experiment monitors**: LlamaBoard, TensorBoard, Wandb, MLflow, [SwanLab](https://github.com/SwanHubX/SwanLab), etc.
- **Faster inference**: OpenAI-style API, Gradio UI and CLI with [vLLM worker](https://github.com/vllm-project/vllm) or [SGLang worker](https://github.com/sgl-project/sglang).

### Day-N Support for Fine-Tuning Cutting-Edge Models

| Support Date | Model Name                                                   |
| ------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Day 0        | Qwen3 / Qwen2.5-VL / Gemma 3 / InternLM 3 / MiniCPM-o-2.6    |
| Day 1        | Llama 3 / GLM-4 / Mistral Small / PaliGemma2 / Llama 4       |

## Blogs

- [Fine-tune Qwen2.5-VL for Autonomous Driving using LLaMA-Factory](https://docs.alayanew.com/docs/documents/useGuide/LLaMAFactory/mutiple/?utm_source=LLaMA-Factory) (Chinese)
- [How Apoidea Group enhances visual information extraction from banking documents with multimodal models using LLaMA-Factory on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/) (English)
- [Easy Dataset × LLaMA Factory: Enabling LLMs to Efficiently Learn Domain Knowledge](https://buaa-act.feishu.cn/wiki/GVzlwYcRFiR8OLkHbL6cQpYin7g) (English)

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;All Blogs&lt;/summary&gt;

- [LLaMA Factory: Fine-tuning the DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-7B Model for News Classifier](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory_deepseek_r1_distill_7b) (Chinese)
- [A One-Stop Code-Free Model Fine-Tuning \&amp; Deployment Platform based on SageMaker and LLaMA-Factory](https://aws.amazon.com/cn/blogs/china/a-one-stop-code-free-model-fine-tuning-deployment-platform-based-on-sagemaker-and-llama-factory/) (Chinese)
- [LLaMA Factory Multi-Modal Fine-Tuning Practice: Fine-Tuning Qwen2-VL for Personal Tourist Guide](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory_qwen2vl) (Chinese)
- [LLaMA Factory: Fine-tuning the LLaMA3 Model for Role-Playing](https://gallery.pai-ml.com/#/preview/deepLearning/nlp/llama_factory) (Chinese)

&lt;/details&gt;

## Changelog

[25/04/28] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen3](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen3/)** model family.

[25/04/21] We supported the **[Muon](https://github.com/KellerJordan/Muon)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage. Thank [@tianshijing](https://github.com/tianshijing)&#039;s PR.

[25/04/16] We supported fine-tuning the **[InternVL3](https://huggingface.co/OpenGVLab/InternVL3-8B)** model. See [PR #7258](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7258) to get started.

[25/04/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[GLM-Z1](https://huggingface.co/THUDM/GLM-Z1-9B-0414)** and **[Kimi-VL](https://huggingface.co/moonshotai/Kimi-VL-A3B-Instruct)** models.

[25/04/06] We supported fine-tuning the **[Llama 4](https://ai.meta.com/blog/llama-4-multimodal-intelligence/)** model. See [PR #7611](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7611) to get started.

&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Full Changelog&lt;/summary&gt;

[25/03/31] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2.5 Omni](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2.5-omni/)** model. See [PR #7537](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/pull/7537) to get started.

[25/03/15] We supported **[SGLang](https://github.com/sgl-project/sglang)** as inference backend. Try `infer_backend: sglang` to accelerate inference.

[25/03/12] We supported fine-tuning the **[Gemma 3](https://huggingface.co/blog/gemma3)** model.

[25/02/24] Announcing **[EasyR1](https://github.com/hiyouga/EasyR1)**, an efficient, scalable and multi-modality RL training framework for efficient GRPO training.

[25/02/11] We supported saving the **[Ollama](https://github.com/ollama/ollama)** modelfile when exporting the model checkpoints. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[25/02/05] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2-Audio](Qwen/Qwen2-Audio-7B-Instruct)** and **[MiniCPM-o-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-o-2_6)** on audio understanding tasks.

[25/01/31] We supported fine-tuning the **[DeepSeek-R1](https://huggingface.co/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1)** and **[Qwen2.5-VL](https://huggingface.co/Qwen/Qwen2.5-VL-7B-Instruct)** models.

[25/01/15] We supported **[APOLLO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.05270)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[25/01/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[MiniCPM-o-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-o-2_6)** and **[MiniCPM-V-2.6](https://huggingface.co/openbmb/MiniCPM-V-2_6)** models. Thank [@BUAADreamer](https://github.com/BUAADreamer)&#039;s PR.

[25/01/14] We supported fine-tuning the **[InternLM 3](https://huggingface.co/collections/internlm/)** models. Thank [@hhaAndroid](https://github.com/hhaAndroid)&#039;s PR.

[25/01/10] We supported fine-tuning the **[Phi-4](https://huggingface.co/microsoft/phi-4)** model.

[24/12/21] We supported using **[SwanLab](https://github.com/SwanHubX/SwanLab)** for experiment tracking and visualization. See [this section](#use-swanlab-logger) for details.

[24/11/27] We supported fine-tuning the **[Skywork-o1](https://huggingface.co/Skywork/Skywork-o1-Open-Llama-3.1-8B)** model and the **[OpenO1](https://huggingface.co/datasets/O1-OPEN/OpenO1-SFT)** dataset.

[24/10/09] We supported downloading pre-trained models and datasets from the **[Modelers Hub](https://modelers.cn/models)**. See [this tutorial](#download-from-modelers-hub) for usage.

[24/09/19] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2.5](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2.5/)** models.

[24/08/30] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2-VL](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2-vl/)** models. Thank [@simonJJJ](https://github.com/simonJJJ)&#039;s PR.

[24/08/27] We supported **[Liger Kernel](https://github.com/linkedin/Liger-Kernel)**. Try `enable_liger_kernel: true` for efficient training.

[24/08/09] We supported **[Adam-mini](https://github.com/zyushun/Adam-mini)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage. Thank [@relic-yuexi](https://github.com/relic-yuexi)&#039;s PR.

[24/07/04] We supported [contamination-free packed training](https://github.com/MeetKai/functionary/tree/main/functionary/train/packing). Use `neat_packing: true` to activate it. Thank [@chuan298](https://github.com/chuan298)&#039;s PR.

[24/06/16] We supported **[PiSSA](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02948)** algorithm. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/06/07] We supported fine-tuning the **[Qwen2](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen2/)** and **[GLM-4](https://github.com/THUDM/GLM-4)** models.

[24/05/26] We supported **[SimPO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.14734)** algorithm for preference learning. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/05/20] We supported fine-tuning the **PaliGemma** series models. Note that the PaliGemma models are pre-trained models, you need to fine-tune them with `paligemma` template for chat completion.

[24/05/18] We supported **[KTO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01306)** algorithm for preference learning. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/05/14] We supported training and inference on the Ascend NPU devices. Check [installation](#installation) section for details.

[24/04/26] We supported fine-tuning the **LLaVA-1.5** multimodal LLMs. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/22] We provided a **[Colab notebook](https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1eRTPn37ltBbYsISy9Aw2NuI2Aq5CQrD9?usp=sharing)** for fine-tuning the Llama-3 model on a free T4 GPU. Two Llama-3-derived models fine-tuned using LLaMA Factory are available at Hugging Face, check [Llama3-8B-Chinese-Chat](https://huggingface.co/shenzhi-wang/Llama3-8B-Chinese-Chat) and [Llama3-Chinese](https://huggingface.co/zhichen/Llama3-Chinese) for details.

[24/04/21] We supported **[Mixture-of-Depths](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02258)** according to [AstraMindAI&#039;s implementation](https://github.com/astramind-ai/Mixture-of-depths). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/16] We supported **[BAdam](https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.02827)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/04/16] We supported **[unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth)**&#039;s long-sequence training (Llama-2-7B-56k within 24GB). It achieves **117%** speed and **50%** memory compared with FlashAttention-2, more benchmarks can be found in [this page](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/wiki/Performance-comparison).

[24/03/31] We supported **[ORPO](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.07691)**. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/21] Our paper &quot;[LlamaFactory: Unified Efficient Fine-Tuning of 100+ Language Models](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.13372)&quot; is available at arXiv!

[24/03/20] We supported **FSDP+QLoRA** that fine-tunes a 70B model on 2x24GB GPUs. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/13] We supported **[LoRA+](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12354)**. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/07] We supported **[GaLore](https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.03507)** optimizer. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/03/07] We integrated **[vLLM](https://github.com/vllm-project/vllm)** for faster and concurrent inference. Try `infer_backend: vllm` to enjoy **270%** inference speed.

[24/02/28] We supported weight-decomposed LoRA (**[DoRA](https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09353)**). Try `use_dora: true` to activate DoRA training.

[24/02/15] We supported **block expansion** proposed by [LLaMA Pro](https://github.com/TencentARC/LLaMA-Pro). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[24/02/05] Qwen1.5 (Qwen2 beta version) series models are supported in LLaMA-Factory. Check this [blog post](https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwen1.5/) for details.

[24/01/18] We supported **agent tuning** for most models, equipping model with tool using abilities by fine-tuning with `dataset: glaive_toolcall_en`.

[23/12/23] We supported **[unsloth](https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth)**&#039;s implementation to boost LoRA tuning for the LLaMA, Mistral and Yi models. Try `use_unsloth: true` argument to activate unsloth patch. It achieves **170%** speed in our benchmark, check [this page](https://github.com/hiyouga/LLaMA-Factory/wiki/Performance-comparison) for details.

[23/12/12] We supported fine-tuning the latest MoE model **[Mixtral 8x7B](https://huggingface.co/mistralai/Mixtral-8x7B-v0.1)** in our framework. See hardware requirement [here](#hardware-requirement).

[23/12/01] We supported downloading pre-trained models and datasets from the **[ModelScope Hub](https://modelscope.cn/models)**. See [this tutorial](#download-from-modelscope-hub) for usage.

[23/10/21] We supported **[NEFTune](https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05914)** trick for fine-tuning. Try `neftune_noise_alpha: 5` argument to activate NEFTune.

[23/09/27] We supported **$S^2$-Attn** proposed by [LongLoRA](https://github.com/dvlab-research/LongLoRA) for the LLaMA models. Try `shift_attn: true` argument to enable shift short attention.

[23/09/23] We integrated MMLU, C-Eval and CMMLU benchmarks in this repo. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[23/09/10] We supported **[FlashAttention-2](https://github.com/Dao-AILab/flash-attention)**. Try `flash_attn: fa2` argument to enable FlashAttention-2 if you are using RTX4090, A100 or H100 GPUs.

[23/08/12] We supported **RoPE scaling** to extend the context length of the LLaMA models. Try `rope_scaling: linear` argument in training and `rope_scaling: dynamic` argument at inference to extrapolate the position embeddings.

[23/08/11] We supported **[DPO training](https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.18290)** for instruction-tuned models. See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

[23/07/31] We supported **dataset streaming**. Try `streaming: true` and `max_steps: 10000` arguments to load your dataset in streaming mode.

[23/07/29] We released two instruction-tuned 13B models at Hugging Face. See these Hugging Face Repos ([LLaMA-2](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Llama-2-Chinese-13b-chat) / [Baichuan](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Baichuan-13B-sft)) for details.

[23/07/18] We developed an **all-in-one Web UI** for training, evaluation and inference. Try `train_web.py` to fine-tune models in your Web browser. Thank [@KanadeSiina](https://github.com/KanadeSiina) and [@codemayq](https://github.com/codemayq) for their efforts in the development.

[23/07/09] We released **[FastEdit](https://github.com/hiyouga/FastEdit)** ⚡🩹, an easy-to-use package for editing the factual knowledge of large language models efficiently. Please follow [FastEdit](https://github.com/hiyouga/FastEdit) if you are interested.

[23/06/29] We provided a **reproducible example** of training a chat model using instruction-following datasets, see [Baichuan-7B-sft](https://huggingface.co/hiyouga/Baichuan-7B-sft) for details.

[23/06/22] We aligned the [demo API](src/api_demo.py) with the [OpenAI&#039;s](https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/chat) format where you can insert the fine-tuned model in **arbitrary ChatGPT-based applications**.

[23/06/03] We supported quantized training and inference (aka **[QLoRA](https://github.com/artidoro/qlora)**). See [examples](examples/README.md) for usage.

&lt;/details&gt;

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; If you cannot use the latest feature, please pull the latest code and install LLaMA-Factory again.

## Supported Models

| Model                                                             | Model size                       | Template            |
| ----------------------------------------------------------------- | -------------------------------- | ------------------- |
| [Baichuan 2](https://huggingface.co/baichuan-inc)                 | 7B/13B                           | baichuan2    

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HKUDS/LightRAG]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA["LightRAG: Simple and Fast Retrieval-Augmented Generation"]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG">HKUDS/LightRAG</a></h1>
            <p>"LightRAG: Simple and Fast Retrieval-Augmented Generation"</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 17,116</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,363</p>
            <p>Stars today: 58 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;center&gt;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 LightRAG: Simple and Fast Retrieval-Augmented Generation&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;100&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/logo.png&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; alt=&quot;lightrag&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://lightrag.github.io&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/Project-Page-Green&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://youtu.be/oageL-1I0GE&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://badges.aleen42.com/src/youtube.svg&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05779&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/arXiv-2410.05779-b31b1b&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://learnopencv.com/lightrag&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/LearnOpenCV-blue&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/hkuds/lightrag?color=green&amp;style=social&#039; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.10-blue&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/lightrag-hku/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/lightrag-hku.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://pepy.tech/project/lightrag-hku&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pepy.tech/badge/lightrag-hku/month&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://discord.gg/yF2MmDJyGJ&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://discordapp.com/api/guilds/1296348098003734629/widget.png?style=shield&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#039;https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG/issues/285&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/群聊-wechat-green&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;./README.assets/b2aaf634151b4706892693ffb43d9093.png&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;LightRAG Diagram&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13043&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13043&quot; alt=&quot;HKUDS%2FLightRAG | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 🎉 News
- [X] [2025.06.05]🎯📢LightRAG now supports multimodal document parsing and RAG with MinerU integration (PDF, images, Office, tables, formulas, etc.). See the new [multimodal section](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG/?tab=readme-ov-file#multimodal-document-processing-mineru-integration) below.
- [X] [2025.03.18]🎯📢LightRAG now supports citation functionality, enabling proper source attribution.
- [X] [2025.02.05]🎯📢Our team has released [VideoRAG](https://github.com/HKUDS/VideoRAG) understanding extremely long-context videos.
- [X] [2025.01.13]🎯📢Our team has released [MiniRAG](https://github.com/HKUDS/MiniRAG) making RAG simpler with small models.
- [X] [2025.01.06]🎯📢You can now [use PostgreSQL for Storage](#using-postgresql-for-storage).
- [X] [2024.12.31]🎯📢LightRAG now supports [deletion by document ID](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#delete).
- [X] [2024.11.25]🎯📢LightRAG now supports seamless integration of [custom knowledge graphs](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#insert-custom-kg), empowering users to enhance the system with their own domain expertise.
- [X] [2024.11.19]🎯📢A comprehensive guide to LightRAG is now available on [LearnOpenCV](https://learnopencv.com/lightrag). Many thanks to the blog author.
- [X] [2024.11.11]🎯📢LightRAG now supports [deleting entities by their names](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#delete).
- [X] [2024.11.09]🎯📢Introducing the [LightRAG Gui](https://lightrag-gui.streamlit.app), which allows you to insert, query, visualize, and download LightRAG knowledge.
- [X] [2024.11.04]🎯📢You can now [use Neo4J for Storage](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#using-neo4j-for-storage).
- [X] [2024.10.29]🎯📢LightRAG now supports multiple file types, including PDF, DOC, PPT, and CSV via `textract`.
- [X] [2024.10.20]🎯📢We&#039;ve added a new feature to LightRAG: Graph Visualization.
- [X] [2024.10.18]🎯📢We&#039;ve added a link to a [LightRAG Introduction Video](https://youtu.be/oageL-1I0GE). Thanks to the author!
- [X] [2024.10.17]🎯📢We have created a [Discord channel](https://discord.gg/yF2MmDJyGJ)! Welcome to join for sharing and discussions! 🎉🎉
- [X] [2024.10.16]🎯📢LightRAG now supports [Ollama models](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#quick-start)!
- [X] [2024.10.15]🎯📢LightRAG now supports [Hugging Face models](https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG?tab=readme-ov-file#quick-start)!

&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary style=&quot;font-size: 1.4em; font-weight: bold; cursor: pointer; display: list-item;&quot;&gt;
    Algorithm Flowchart
  &lt;/summary&gt;

![LightRAG Indexing Flowchart](https://learnopencv.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/LightRAG-VectorDB-Json-KV-Store-Indexing-Flowchart-scaled.jpg)
*Figure 1: LightRAG Indexing Flowchart - Img Caption : [Source](https://learnopencv.com/lightrag/)*
![LightRAG Retrieval and Querying Flowchart](https://learnopencv.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/LightRAG-Querying-Flowchart-Dual-Level-Retrieval-Generation-Knowledge-Graphs-scaled.jpg)
*Figure 2: LightRAG Retrieval and Querying Flowchart - Img Caption : [Source](https://learnopencv.com/lightrag/)*

&lt;/details&gt;

## Installation

### Install LightRAG Server

The LightRAG Server is designed to provide Web UI and API support. The Web UI facilitates document indexing, knowledge graph exploration, and a simple RAG query interface. LightRAG Server also provide an Ollama compatible interfaces, aiming to emulate LightRAG as an Ollama chat model. This allows AI chat bot, such as Open WebUI, to access LightRAG easily.

* Install from PyPI

```bash
pip install &quot;lightrag-hku[api]&quot;
```

* Installation from Source

```bash
git clone https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG.git
cd LightRAG
# create a Python virtual enviroment if neccesary
# Install in editable mode with API support
pip install -e &quot;.[api]&quot;
```

* Launching the LightRAG Server with Docker Compose

```
git clone https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG.git
cd LightRAG
cp env.example .env
# modify LLM and Embedding settings in .env
docker compose up
```

&gt; Historical versions of LightRAG docker images can be found here: [LightRAG Docker Images]( https://github.com/HKUDS/LightRAG/pkgs/container/lightrag)

### Install  LightRAG Core

* Install from source (Recommend)

```bash
cd LightRAG
pip install -e .
```

* Install from PyPI

```bash
pip install lightrag-hku
```

## Quick Start

### Quick Start for LightRAG Server

* For more information about LightRAG Server, please refer to [LightRAG Server](./lightrag/api/README.md).

### Quick Start for LightRAG core

To get started with LightRAG core, refer to the sample codes available in the `examples` folder. Additionally, a [video demo](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g21royNJ4fw) demonstration is provided to guide you through the local setup process. If you already possess an OpenAI API key, you can run the demo right away:

```bash
### you should run the demo code with project folder
cd LightRAG
### provide your API-KEY for OpenAI
export OPENAI_API_KEY=&quot;sk-...your_opeai_key...&quot;
### download the demo document of &quot;A Christmas Carol&quot; by Charles Dickens
curl https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gusye1234/nano-graphrag/main/tests/mock_data.txt &gt; ./book.txt
### run the demo code
python examples/lightrag_openai_demo.py
```

For a streaming response implementation example, please see `examples/lightrag_openai_compatible_demo.py`. Prior to execution, ensure you modify the sample code’s LLM and embedding configurations accordingly.

**Note 1**: When running the demo program, please be aware that different test scripts may use different embedding models. If you switch to a different embedding model, you must clear the data directory (`./dickens`); otherwise, the program may encounter errors. If you wish to retain the LLM cache, you can preserve the `kv_store_llm_response_cache.json` file while clearing the data directory.

**Note 2**: Only `lightrag_openai_demo.py` and `lightrag_openai_compatible_demo.py` are officially supported sample codes. Other sample files are community contributions that haven&#039;t undergone full testing and optimization.

## Programing with LightRAG Core

&gt; If you would like to integrate LightRAG into your project, we recommend utilizing the REST API provided by the LightRAG Server. LightRAG Core is typically intended for embedded applications or for researchers who wish to conduct studies and evaluations.

### A Simple Program

Use the below Python snippet to initialize LightRAG, insert text to it, and perform queries:

```python
import os
import asyncio
from lightrag import LightRAG, QueryParam
from lightrag.llm.openai import gpt_4o_mini_complete, gpt_4o_complete, openai_embed
from lightrag.kg.shared_storage import initialize_pipeline_status
from lightrag.utils import setup_logger

setup_logger(&quot;lightrag&quot;, level=&quot;INFO&quot;)

WORKING_DIR = &quot;./rag_storage&quot;
if not os.path.exists(WORKING_DIR):
    os.mkdir(WORKING_DIR)

async def initialize_rag():
    rag = LightRAG(
        working_dir=WORKING_DIR,
        embedding_func=openai_embed,
        llm_model_func=gpt_4o_mini_complete,
    )
    await rag.initialize_storages()
    await initialize_pipeline_status()
    return rag

async def main():
    try:
        # Initialize RAG instance
        rag = await initialize_rag()
        rag.insert(&quot;Your text&quot;)

        # Perform hybrid search
        mode=&quot;hybrid&quot;
        print(
          await rag.query(
              &quot;What are the top themes in this story?&quot;,
              param=QueryParam(mode=mode)
          )
        )

    except Exception as e:
        print(f&quot;An error occurred: {e}&quot;)
    finally:
        if rag:
            await rag.finalize_storages()

if __name__ == &quot;__main__&quot;:
    asyncio.run(main())
```

Important notes for the above snippet:

- Export your OPENAI_API_KEY environment variable before running the script.
- This program uses the default storage settings for LightRAG, so all data will be persisted to WORKING_DIR/rag_storage.
- This program demonstrates only the simplest way to initialize a LightRAG object: Injecting the embedding and LLM functions, and initializing storage and pipeline status after creating the LightRAG object.

### LightRAG init parameters

A full list of LightRAG init parameters:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt; Parameters &lt;/summary&gt;

| **Parameter** | **Type** | **Explanation** | **Default** |
|--------------|----------|-----------------|-------------|
| **working_dir** | `str` | Directory where the cache will be stored | `lightrag_cache+timestamp` |
| **kv_storage** | `str` | Storage type for documents and text chunks. Supported types: `JsonKVStorage`,`PGKVStorage`,`RedisKVStorage`,`MongoKVStorage` | `JsonKVStorage` |
| **vector_storage** | `str` | Storage type for embedding vectors. Supported types: `NanoVectorDBStorage`,`PGVectorStorage`,`MilvusVectorDBStorage`,`ChromaVectorDBStorage`,`FaissVectorDBStorage`,`MongoVectorDBStorage`,`QdrantVectorDBStorage` | `NanoVectorDBStorage` |
| **graph_storage** | `str` | Storage type for graph edges and nodes. Supported types: `NetworkXStorage`,`Neo4JStorage`,`PGGraphStorage`,`AGEStorage` | `NetworkXStorage` |
| **doc_status_storage** | `str` | Storage type for documents process status. Supported types: `JsonDocStatusStorage`,`PGDocStatusStorage`,`MongoDocStatusStorage` | `JsonDocStatusStorage` |
| **chunk_token_size** | `int` | Maximum token size per chunk when splitting documents | `1200` |
| **chunk_overlap_token_size** | `int` | Overlap token size between two chunks when splitting documents | `100` |
| **tokenizer** | `Tokenizer` | The function used to convert text into tokens (numbers) and back using .encode() and .decode() functions following `TokenizerInterface` protocol. If you don&#039;t specify one, it will use the default Tiktoken tokenizer. | `TiktokenTokenizer` |
| **tiktoken_model_name** | `str` | If you&#039;re using the default Tiktoken tokenizer, this is the name of the specific Tiktoken model to use. This setting is ignored if you provide your own tokenizer. | `gpt-4o-mini` |
| **entity_extract_max_gleaning** | `int` | Number of loops in the entity extraction process, appending history messages | `1` |
| **entity_summary_to_max_tokens** | `int` | Maximum token size for each entity summary | `500` |
| **node_embedding_algorithm** | `str` | Algorithm for node embedding (currently not used) | `node2vec` |
| **node2vec_params** | `dict` | Parameters for node embedding | `{&quot;dimensions&quot;: 1536,&quot;num_walks&quot;: 10,&quot;walk_length&quot;: 40,&quot;window_size&quot;: 2,&quot;iterations&quot;: 3,&quot;random_seed&quot;: 3,}` |
| **embedding_func** | `EmbeddingFunc` | Function to generate embedding vectors from text | `openai_embed` |
| **embedding_batch_num** | `int` | Maximum batch size for embedding processes (multiple texts sent per batch) | `32` |
| **embedding_func_max_async** | `int` | Maximum number of concurrent asynchronous embedding processes | `16` |
| **llm_model_func** | `callable` | Function for LLM generation | `gpt_4o_mini_complete` |
| **llm_model_name** | `str` | LLM model name for generation | `meta-llama/Llama-3.2-1B-Instruct` |
| **llm_model_max_token_size** | `int` | Maximum token size for LLM generation (affects entity relation summaries) | `32768`（default value changed by env var MAX_TOKENS) |
| **llm_model_max_async** | `int` | Maximum number of concurrent asynchronous LLM processes | `4`（default value changed by env var MAX_ASYNC) |
| **llm_model_kwargs** | `dict` | Additional parameters for LLM generation | |
| **vector_db_storage_cls_kwargs** | `dict` | Additional parameters for vector database, like setting the threshold for nodes and relations retrieval | cosine_better_than_threshold: 0.2（default value changed by env var COSINE_THRESHOLD) |
| **enable_llm_cache** | `bool` | If `TRUE`, stores LLM results in cache; repeated prompts return cached responses | `TRUE` |
| **enable_llm_cache_for_entity_extract** | `bool` | If `TRUE`, stores LLM results in cache for entity extraction; Good for beginners to debug your application | `TRUE` |
| **addon_params** | `dict` | Additional parameters, e.g., `{&quot;example_number&quot;: 1, &quot;language&quot;: &quot;Simplified Chinese&quot;, &quot;entity_types&quot;: [&quot;organization&quot;, &quot;person&quot;, &quot;geo&quot;, &quot;event&quot;]}`: sets example limit, entiy/relation extraction output language | `example_number: all examples, language: English` |
| **convert_response_to_json_func** | `callable` | Not used | `convert_response_to_json` |
| **embedding_cache_config** | `dict` | Configuration for question-answer caching. Contains three parameters: `enabled`: Boolean value to enable/disable cache lookup functionality. When enabled, the system will check cached responses before generating new answers. `similarity_threshold`: Float value (0-1), similarity threshold. When a new question&#039;s similarity with a cached question exceeds this threshold, the cached answer will be returned directly without calling the LLM. `use_llm_check`: Boolean value to enable/disable LLM similarity verification. When enabled, LLM will be used as a secondary check to verify the similarity between questions before returning cached answers. | Default: `{&quot;enabled&quot;: False, &quot;similarity_threshold&quot;: 0.95, &quot;use_llm_check&quot;: False}` |

&lt;/details&gt;

### Query Param

Use QueryParam to control the behavior your query:

```python
class QueryParam:
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Configuration parameters for query execution in LightRAG.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    mode: Literal[&quot;local&quot;, &quot;global&quot;, &quot;hybrid&quot;, &quot;naive&quot;, &quot;mix&quot;, &quot;bypass&quot;] = &quot;global&quot;
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Specifies the retrieval mode:
    - &quot;local&quot;: Focuses on context-dependent information.
    - &quot;global&quot;: Utilizes global knowledge.
    - &quot;hybrid&quot;: Combines local and global retrieval methods.
    - &quot;naive&quot;: Performs a basic search without advanced techniques.
    - &quot;mix&quot;: Integrates knowledge graph and vector retrieval.
    &quot;&quot;&quot;

    only_need_context: bool = False
    &quot;&quot;&quot;If True, only returns the retrieved context without generating a response.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    only_need_prompt: bool = False
    &quot;&quot;&quot;If True, only returns the generated prompt without producing a response.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    response_type: str = &quot;Multiple Paragraphs&quot;
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Defines the response format. Examples: &#039;Multiple Paragraphs&#039;, &#039;Single Paragraph&#039;, &#039;Bullet Points&#039;.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    stream: bool = False
    &quot;&quot;&quot;If True, enables streaming output for real-time responses.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    top_k: int = int(os.getenv(&quot;TOP_K&quot;, &quot;60&quot;))
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Number of top items to retrieve. Represents entities in &#039;local&#039; mode and relationships in &#039;global&#039; mode.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    max_token_for_text_unit: int = int(os.getenv(&quot;MAX_TOKEN_TEXT_CHUNK&quot;, &quot;4000&quot;))
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Maximum number of tokens allowed for each retrieved text chunk.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    max_token_for_global_context: int = int(
        os.getenv(&quot;MAX_TOKEN_RELATION_DESC&quot;, &quot;4000&quot;)
    )
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Maximum number of tokens allocated for relationship descriptions in global retrieval.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    max_token_for_local_context: int = int(os.getenv(&quot;MAX_TOKEN_ENTITY_DESC&quot;, &quot;4000&quot;))
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Maximum number of tokens allocated for entity descriptions in local retrieval.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    conversation_history: list[dict[str, str]] = field(default_factory=list)
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Stores past conversation history to maintain context.
    Format: [{&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user/assistant&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: &quot;message&quot;}].
    &quot;&quot;&quot;

    history_turns: int = 3
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Number of complete conversation turns (user-assistant pairs) to consider in the response context.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    ids: list[str] | None = None
    &quot;&quot;&quot;List of ids to filter the results.&quot;&quot;&quot;

    model_func: Callable[..., object] | None = None
    &quot;&quot;&quot;Optional override for the LLM model function to use for this specific query.
    If provided, this will be used instead of the global model function.
    This allows using different models for different query modes.
    &quot;&quot;&quot;

    user_prompt: str | None = None
    &quot;&quot;&quot;User-provided prompt for the query.
    If proivded, this will be use instead of the default vaulue from prompt template.
    &quot;&quot;&quot;
```

&gt; default value of Top_k can be change by environment  variables  TOP_K.

### LLM and Embedding Injection

LightRAG requires the utilization of LLM and Embedding models to accomplish document indexing and querying tasks. During the initialization phase, it is necessary to inject the invocation methods of the relevant models into LightRAG：

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Using Open AI-like APIs&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;

* LightRAG also supports Open AI-like chat/embeddings APIs:

```python
async def llm_model_func(
    prompt, system_prompt=None, history_messages=[], keyword_extraction=False, **kwargs
) -&gt; str:
    return await openai_complete_if_cache(
        &quot;solar-mini&quot;,
        prompt,
        system_prompt=system_prompt,
        history_messages=history_messages,
        api_key=os.getenv(&quot;UPSTAGE_API_KEY&quot;),
        base_url=&quot;https://api.upstage.ai/v1/solar&quot;,
        **kwargs
    )

async def embedding_func(texts: list[str]) -&gt; np.ndarray:
    return await openai_embed(
        texts,
        model=&quot;solar-embedding-1-large-query&quot;,
        api_key=os.getenv(&quot;UPSTAGE_API_KEY&quot;),
        base_url=&quot;https://api.upstage.ai/v1/solar&quot;
    )

async def initialize_rag():
    rag = LightRAG(
        working_dir=WORKING_DIR,
        llm_model_func=llm_model_func,
        embedding_func=EmbeddingFunc(
            embedding_dim=4096,
            max_token_size=8192,
            func=embedding_func
        )
    )

    await rag.initialize_storages()
    await initialize_pipeline_status()

    return rag
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt; &lt;b&gt;Using Hugging Face Models&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/summary&gt;

* If you want to use Hugging Face models, you only need to set LightRAG as follows:

See `lightrag_hf_demo.py`

```python
# Initialize LightRAG with Hugging Face model
rag = LightRAG(
    working_dir=WORKING_DIR,
    llm_model_func=hf_model_complete,  # Use Hugging Face model for text generation
    llm_model_name=&#039;meta-llama/Llama-3.1-8B-Instruct&#039;,  # Model name from Hugging Face
    # Use Hugging Face embedding function
    embedding_func=EmbeddingFunc(
        embedding_dim=384,
        max_token_size=5000,
        func=lambda texts: hf_embed(
            texts,
            tokenizer=AutoTokenizer.from_pretrained(&quot;sentence-transformers/all-MiniLM-L6-v2&quot;),
            embed_model=AutoModel.from_pretrained(&quot;sentence-transformers/all-MiniLM-L6-

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[yeongpin/cursor-free-vip]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[[Support 0.49.x]（Reset Cursor AI MachineID & Bypass Higher Token Limit） Cursor Ai ，自动重置机器ID ， 免费升级使用Pro功能: You've reached your trial request limit. / Too many free trial accounts used on this machine. Please upgrade to pro. We have this limit in place to prevent abuse. Please let us know if you believe this is a mistake.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip">yeongpin/cursor-free-vip</a></h1>
            <p>[Support 0.49.x]（Reset Cursor AI MachineID & Bypass Higher Token Limit） Cursor Ai ，自动重置机器ID ， 免费升级使用Pro功能: You've reached your trial request limit. / Too many free trial accounts used on this machine. Please upgrade to pro. We have this limit in place to prevent abuse. Please let us know if you believe this is a mistake.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 28,936</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,652</p>
            <p>Stars today: 196 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># ➤ Cursor Free VIP

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./images/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cursor Pro Logo&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; style=&quot;border-radius: 6px;&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Release](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/release/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/releases/latest)
[![License: CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-CC_BY--NC--ND_4.0-lightgrey.svg)](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/)
[![Stars](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/stars/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/stargazers)
[![Downloads](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://api.pinstudios.net/api/badges/downloads/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/total)](https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/releases/latest)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://buymeacoffee.com/yeongpin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Buy Me a Coffee&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Buy%20Me%20a%20Coffee-Support%20Me-FFDA33&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 [&lt;img src=&quot;https://devin.ai/assets/deepwiki-badge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ask DeepWiki.com&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;/&gt;](https://deepwiki.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip)

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13425&quot; alt=&quot;yeongpin%2Fcursor-free-vip | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/yeongpin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.buymeacoffee.com/button-api/?text=buy me a coffee&amp;emoji=☕&amp;slug=yeongpin&amp;button_colour=ffda33&amp;font_colour=000000&amp;font_family=Bree&amp;outline_colour=000000&amp;coffee_colour=FFDD00&amp;latest=2&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; height=&#039;55&#039; alt=&quot;Buy Me a Coffee&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Support Latest 0.49.x Version | 支持最新 0.49.x 版本&lt;/h4&gt;

This tool is for educational purposes, currently the repo does not violate any laws. Please support the original project.
This tool will not generate any fake email accounts and OAuth access.

Supports Windows, macOS and Linux.

For optimal performance, run with privileges and always stay up to date.

這是一款用於學習和研究的工具，目前 repo 沒有違反任何法律。請支持原作者。
這款工具不會生成任何假的電子郵件帳戶和 OAuth 訪問。

支持 Windows、macOS 和 Linux。

對於最佳性能，請以管理員身份運行並始終保持最新。


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./images/product_2025-04-16_10-40-21.png&quot; alt=&quot;new&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; style=&quot;border-radius: 6px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

## 🔄 Change Log | 更新日志

[Watch Change Log | 查看更新日志](CHANGELOG.md)

## ✨ Features | 功能特點

* Support Windows macOS and Linux systems&lt;br&gt;支持 Windows、macOS 和 Linux 系統&lt;br&gt;

* Reset Cursor&#039;s configuration&lt;br&gt;重置 Cursor 的配置&lt;br&gt;

* Multi-language support (English, 简体中文, 繁體中文, Vietnamese)&lt;br&gt;多語言支持（英文、简体中文、繁體中文、越南語）&lt;br&gt;

## 💻 System Support | 系統支持

| Operating System | Architecture      | Supported |
|------------------|-------------------|-----------|
| Windows          | x64, x86          | ✅         |
| macOS            | Intel, Apple Silicon | ✅      |
| Linux            | x64, x86, ARM64   | ✅         |

## 👀 How to use | 如何使用

&lt;details open&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;⭐ Auto Run Script | 腳本自動化運行&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

### **Linux/macOS**

```bash
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/main/scripts/install.sh -o install.sh &amp;&amp; chmod +x install.sh &amp;&amp; ./install.sh
```

### **Archlinux**

Install via [AUR](https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/cursor-free-vip-git)

```bash
yay -S cursor-free-vip-git
```

### **Windows**

```powershell
irm https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/main/scripts/install.ps1 | iex
```

&lt;/details&gt;

If you want to stop the script, please press Ctrl+C&lt;br&gt;要停止腳本，請按 Ctrl+C

## ❗ Note | 注意事項

📝 Config | 文件配置
`Win / Macos / Linux Path | 路徑 [Documents/.cursor-free-vip/config.ini]`
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;⭐ Config | 文件配置&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```
[Chrome]
# Default Google Chrome Path | 默認Google Chrome 遊覽器路徑
chromepath = C:\Program Files\Google/Chrome/Application/chrome.exe

[Turnstile]
# Handle Turnstile Wait Time | 等待人機驗證時間
handle_turnstile_time = 2
# Handle Turnstile Wait Random Time (must merge 1-3 or 1,3) | 等待人機驗證隨機時間（必須是 1-3 或者 1,3 這樣的組合）
handle_turnstile_random_time = 1-3

[OSPaths]
# Storage Path | 存儲路徑
storage_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/User/globalStorage/storage.json
# SQLite Path | SQLite路徑
sqlite_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/User/globalStorage/state.vscdb
# Machine ID Path | 機器ID路徑
machine_id_path = /Users/username/Library/Application Support/Cursor/machineId
# For Linux users: ~/.config/cursor/machineid

[Timing]
# Min Random Time | 最小隨機時間
min_random_time = 0.1
# Max Random Time | 最大隨機時間
max_random_time = 0.8
# Page Load Wait | 頁面加載等待時間
page_load_wait = 0.1-0.8
# Input Wait | 輸入等待時間
input_wait = 0.3-0.8
# Submit Wait | 提交等待時間
submit_wait = 0.5-1.5
# Verification Code Input | 驗證碼輸入等待時間
verification_code_input = 0.1-0.3
# Verification Success Wait | 驗證成功等待時間
verification_success_wait = 2-3
# Verification Retry Wait | 驗證重試等待時間
verification_retry_wait = 2-3
# Email Check Initial Wait | 郵件檢查初始等待時間
email_check_initial_wait = 4-6
# Email Refresh Wait | 郵件刷新等待時間
email_refresh_wait = 2-4
# Settings Page Load Wait | 設置頁面加載等待時間
settings_page_load_wait = 1-2
# Failed Retry Time | 失敗重試時間
failed_retry_time = 0.5-1
# Retry Interval | 重試間隔
retry_interval = 8-12
# Max Timeout | 最大超時時間
max_timeout = 160

[Utils]
# Check Update | 檢查更新
check_update = True
# Show Account Info | 顯示賬號信息
show_account_info = True

[TempMailPlus]
# Enable TempMailPlus | 啓用 TempMailPlus（任何轉發到TempMailPlus的郵件都支持獲取驗證碼，例如cloudflare郵件Catch-all）
enabled = false
# TempMailPlus Email | TempMailPlus 電子郵件
email = xxxxx@mailto.plus
# TempMailPlus pin | TempMailPlus pin碼
epin = 

[WindowsPaths]
storage_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\User\globalStorage\storage.json
sqlite_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\User\globalStorage\state.vscdb
machine_id_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Roaming\Cursor\machineId
cursor_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app
updater_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\cursor-updater
update_yml_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app-update.yml
product_json_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Cursor\resources\app\product.json

[Browser]
default_browser = opera
chrome_path = C:\Program Files\Google\Chrome\Application\chrome.exe
edge_path = C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft\Edge\Application\msedge.exe
firefox_path = C:\Program Files\Mozilla Firefox\firefox.exe
brave_path = C:\Program Files\BraveSoftware/Brave-Browser/Application/brave.exe
chrome_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe
edge_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\msedgedriver.exe
firefox_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\geckodriver.exe
brave_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe
opera_path = C:\Users\yeongpin\AppData\Local\Programs\Opera\opera.exe
opera_driver_path = D:\VisualCode\cursor-free-vip-new\drivers\chromedriver.exe

[OAuth]
show_selection_alert = False
timeout = 120
max_attempts = 3
```

&lt;/details&gt;

* Use administrator privileges to run the script &lt;br&gt;請使用管理員身份運行腳本

* Confirm that Cursor is closed before running the script &lt;br&gt;請確保在運行腳本前已經關閉 Cursor&lt;br&gt;

* This tool is only for learning and research purposes &lt;br&gt;此工具僅供學習和研究使用&lt;br&gt;

* Please comply with the relevant software usage terms when using this tool &lt;br&gt;使用本工具時請遵守相關軟件使用條款

## 🚨 Common Issues | 常見問題

|                   如果遇到權限問題，請確保：                    |                   此腳本以管理員身份運行                    |
|:--------------------------------------------------:|:------------------------------------------------:|
| If you encounter permission issues, please ensure: | This script is run with administrator privileges |
| Error &#039;User is not authorized&#039; | This means your account was banned for using temporary (disposal) mail. Ensure using a non-temporary mail service |
## 🤩 Contribution | 貢獻

歡迎提交 Issue 和 Pull Request！


&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yeongpin/cursor-free-vip/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;preview=true&amp;max=&amp;columns=&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

## 📩 Disclaimer | 免責聲明

本工具僅供學習和研究使用，使用本工具所產生的任何後果由使用者自行承擔。 &lt;br&gt;

This tool is only for learning and research purposes, and any consequences arising from the use of this tool are borne
by the user.

## 💰 Buy Me a Coffee | 請我喝杯咖啡

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./images/provi-code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy_me_a_coffee&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./images/paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;buy_me_a_coffee&quot; width=&quot;280&quot;/&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## ⭐ Star History | 星星數

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#yeongpin/cursor-free-vip&amp;Date)

&lt;/div&gt;

## 📝 License | 授權

本項目採用 [CC BY-NC-ND 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/) 授權。
Please refer to the [LICENSE](LICENSE.md) file for details.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[fishaudio/fish-speech]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/fishaudio/fish-speech</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/fishaudio/fish-speech</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[SOTA Open Source TTS]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/fishaudio/fish-speech">fishaudio/fish-speech</a></h1>
            <p>SOTA Open Source TTS</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 21,442</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,730</p>
            <p>Stars today: 70 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fish Speech&lt;/h1&gt;

**English** | [简体中文](docs/README.zh.md) | [Portuguese](docs/README.pt-BR.md) | [日本語](docs/README.ja.md) | [한국어](docs/README.ko.md) &lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/fish-speech-1-4?embed=true&amp;utm_source=badge-featured&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_souce=badge-fish&amp;#0045;speech&amp;#0045;1&amp;#0045;4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/featured.svg?post_id=488440&amp;theme=light&quot; alt=&quot;Fish&amp;#0032;Speech&amp;#0032;1&amp;#0046;4 - Open&amp;#0045;Source&amp;#0032;Multilingual&amp;#0032;Text&amp;#0045;to&amp;#0045;Speech&amp;#0032;with&amp;#0032;Voice&amp;#0032;Cloning | Product Hunt&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/7014&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/7014&quot; alt=&quot;fishaudio%2Ffish-speech | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://count.getloli.com/get/@fish-speech?theme=asoul&quot; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://discord.gg/Es5qTB9BcN&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/1214047546020728892?color=%23738ADB&amp;label=Discord&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=flat-square&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/fishaudio/fish-speech&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Docker&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/fishaudio/fish-speech?style=flat-square&amp;logo=docker&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://pd.qq.com/s/bwxia254o&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img alt=&quot;QQ Channel&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/QQ-blue?logo=tencentqq&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/spaces/TTS-AGI/TTS-Arena-V2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img alt=&quot;TTS-Arena2 Score&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/TTS_Arena2-Rank_%231-gold?style=flat-square&amp;logo=trophy&amp;logoColor=white&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/spaces/fishaudio/fish-speech-1&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Huggingface&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/🤗%20-space%20demo-yellow&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/fishaudio/openaudio-s1-mini&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;HuggingFace Model&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/🤗%20-models-orange&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; **License Notice**  
&gt; This codebase is released under **Apache License** and all model weights are released under **CC-BY-NC-SA-4.0 License**. Please refer to [LICENSE](LICENSE) for more details.

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; **Legal Disclaimer**  
&gt; We do not hold any responsibility for any illegal usage of the codebase. Please refer to your local laws about DMCA and other related laws.

---

## 🎉 Announcement

We are excited to announce that we have rebranded to **OpenAudio** — introducing a revolutionary new series of advanced Text-to-Speech models that builds upon the foundation of Fish-Speech.

We are proud to release **OpenAudio-S1** as the first model in this series, delivering significant improvements in quality, performance, and capabilities.

OpenAudio-S1 comes in two versions: **OpenAudio-S1** and **OpenAudio-S1-mini**. Both models are now available on [Fish Audio Playground](https://fish.audio) (for **OpenAudio-S1**) and [Hugging Face](https://huggingface.co/fishaudio/openaudio-s1-mini) (for **OpenAudio-S1-mini**).

Visit the [OpenAudio website](https://openaudio.com/blogs/s1) for blog &amp; tech report.

## Highlights ✨

### **Excellent TTS quality**

We use Seed TTS Eval Metrics to evaluate the model performance, and the results show that OpenAudio S1 achieves **0.008 WER** and **0.004 CER** on English text, which is significantly better than previous models. (English, auto eval, based on OpenAI gpt-4o-transcribe, speaker distance using Revai/pyannote-wespeaker-voxceleb-resnet34-LM)

| Model | Word Error Rate (WER) | Character Error Rate (CER) | Speaker Distance |
|-------|----------------------|---------------------------|------------------|
| **S1** | **0.008**  | **0.004**  | **0.332** |
| **S1-mini** | **0.011** | **0.005** | **0.380** |

### **Best Model in TTS-Arena2** 🏆

OpenAudio S1 has achieved the **#1 ranking** on [TTS-Arena2](https://arena.speechcolab.org/), the benchmark for text-to-speech evaluation:

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;docs/assets/Elo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TTS-Arena2 Ranking&quot; style=&quot;width: 75%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

### **Speech Control**

OpenAudio S1 **supports a variety of emotional, tone, and special markers** to enhance speech synthesis:

- **Basic emotions**:
```
(angry) (sad) (excited) (surprised) (satisfied) (delighted) 
(scared) (worried) (upset) (nervous) (frustrated) (depressed)
(empathetic) (embarrassed) (disgusted) (moved) (proud) (relaxed)
(grateful) (confident) (interested) (curious) (confused) (joyful)
```

- **Advanced emotions**:
```
(disdainful) (unhappy) (anxious) (hysterical) (indifferent) 
(impatient) (guilty) (scornful) (panicked) (furious) (reluctant)
(keen) (disapproving) (negative) (denying) (astonished) (serious)
(sarcastic) (conciliative) (comforting) (sincere) (sneering)
(hesitating) (yielding) (painful) (awkward) (amused)
```

- **Tone markers**:
```
(in a hurry tone) (shouting) (screaming) (whispering) (soft tone)
```

- **Special audio effects**:
```
(laughing) (chuckling) (sobbing) (crying loudly) (sighing) (panting)
(groaning) (crowd laughing) (background laughter) (audience laughing)
```

You can also use Ha,ha,ha to control, there&#039;s many other cases waiting to be explored by yourself.

(Support for English, Chinese and Japanese now, and more languages is coming soon!)

### **Two Type of Models**

| Model | Size | Availability | Features |
|-------|------|--------------|----------|
| **S1** | 4B parameters | Avaliable on [fish.audio](fish.audio) | Full-featured flagship model |
| **S1-mini** | 0.5B parameters | Avaliable on huggingface [hf space](https://huggingface.co/spaces/fishaudio/openaudio-s1-mini) | Distilled version with core capabilities |

Both S1 and S1-mini incorporate online Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF).

## **Features**

1. **Zero-shot &amp; Few-shot TTS:** Input a 10 to 30-second vocal sample to generate high-quality TTS output. **For detailed guidelines, see [Voice Cloning Best Practices](https://docs.fish.audio/text-to-speech/voice-clone-best-practices).**

2. **Multilingual &amp; Cross-lingual Support:** Simply copy and paste multilingual text into the input box—no need to worry about the language. Currently supports English, Japanese, Korean, Chinese, French, German, Arabic, and Spanish.

3. **No Phoneme Dependency:** The model has strong generalization capabilities and does not rely on phonemes for TTS. It can handle text in any language script.

4. **Highly Accurate:** Achieves a low CER (Character Error Rate) of around 0.4% and WER (Word Error Rate) of around 0.8% for Seed-TTS Eval.

5. **Fast:** With fish-tech acceleration, the real-time factor is approximately 1:5 on an Nvidia RTX 4060 laptop and 1:15 on an Nvidia RTX 4090.

6. **WebUI Inference:** Features an easy-to-use, Gradio-based web UI compatible with Chrome, Firefox, Edge, and other browsers.

7. **GUI Inference:** Offers a PyQt6 graphical interface that works seamlessly with the API server. Supports Linux, Windows, and macOS. [See GUI](https://github.com/AnyaCoder/fish-speech-gui).

8. **Deploy-Friendly:** Easily set up an inference server with native support for Linux, Windows (MacOS comming soon), minimizing speed loss.

## **Media &amp; Demos**

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

### **Social Media**
&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/FishAudio/status/1929915992299450398&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/𝕏-Latest_Demo-black?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=x&amp;logoColor=white&quot; alt=&quot;Latest Demo on X&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### **Interactive Demos**
&lt;a href=&quot;https://fish.audio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Fish_Audio-Try_OpenAudio_S1-blue?style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Try OpenAudio S1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/spaces/fishaudio/openaudio-s1-mini&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Hugging_Face-Try_S1_Mini-yellow?style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Try S1 Mini&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### **Video Showcases**

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYuPvd7m06A&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;docs/assets/Thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OpenAudio S1 Video&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### **Audio Samples**
&lt;div style=&quot;margin: 20px 0;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt; High-quality audio samples will be available soon, demonstrating our multilingual TTS capabilities across different languages and emotions.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

---

## Documents

- [Build Envrionment](docs/en/install.md)
- [Inference](docs/en/inference.md)

## Credits

- [VITS2 (daniilrobnikov)](https://github.com/daniilrobnikov/vits2)
- [Bert-VITS2](https://github.com/fishaudio/Bert-VITS2)
- [GPT VITS](https://github.com/innnky/gpt-vits)
- [MQTTS](https://github.com/b04901014/MQTTS)
- [GPT Fast](https://github.com/pytorch-labs/gpt-fast)
- [GPT-SoVITS](https://github.com/RVC-Boss/GPT-SoVITS)
- [Qwen3](https://github.com/QwenLM/Qwen3)

## Tech Report (V1.4)
```bibtex
@misc{fish-speech-v1.4,
      title={Fish-Speech: Leveraging Large Language Models for Advanced Multilingual Text-to-Speech Synthesis},
      author={Shijia Liao and Yuxuan Wang and Tianyu Li and Yifan Cheng and Ruoyi Zhang and Rongzhi Zhou and Yijin Xing},
      year={2024},
      eprint={2411.01156},
      archivePrefix={arXiv},
      primaryClass={cs.SD},
      url={https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.01156},
}
```
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LMCache/LMCache]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Redis for LLMs]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache">LMCache/LMCache</a></h1>
            <p>Redis for LLMs</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,266</p>
            <p>Forks: 192</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># LMCache core library

## Installation

**Prerequisite:** Python &gt;= 3.10

```bash
pip install -e .
```

## Demos
Feel free to try our docker-based demos yourself! All the demos are available [in this repo](https://github.com/LMCache/demo).

## Quickstart: 

**Prerequisites**: To run the quickstart demo, your server should have 1 GPU and the [docker environment](https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/) installed.

**Step 1:** Pull docker images
```bash
docker pull apostacyh/vllm:lmcache-0.1.0
```

**Step 2:** Start vLLM + LMCache 
```bash
model=mistralai/Mistral-7B-Instruct-v0.2    # Replace with your model name
sudo docker run --runtime nvidia --gpus &#039;&quot;device=0&quot;&#039; \
    -v &lt;Huggingface cache dir on your local machine&gt;:/root/.cache/huggingface \
    -p 8000:8000 \
    --env &quot;HF_TOKEN=&lt;Your huggingface access token&gt;&quot; \
    --ipc=host \
    --network=host \
    apostacyh/vllm:lmcache-0.1.0 \
    --model $model --gpu-memory-utilization 0.6 --port 8000 \
    --lmcache-config-file /lmcache/LMCache/examples/example-local.yaml
```
Please fill `Huggingface cache dir on your local machine` and `Your huggingface access token` in the above command. 

You can also change the `model` variable to use different models.

The vLLM engine is ready after you see the logs like this:
```
INFO:     Started server process [865615]
INFO:     Waiting for application startup.
INFO:     Application startup complete.
INFO:     Uvicorn running on http://0.0.0.0:8000 (Press CTRL+C to quit)
```

**Step 3:** Run demo application

You can now run the demo application in the LMCache repo. Please execute the following commands on the server
```bash
git clone https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache
cd LMCache/examples/

# Install openai client library
pip install openai

# Start the demo chat application
python openai_chat_completion_client.py 8000
```

This demo is a QA application based on a long context (`examples/f.txt`). The TTFT should be drastically reduced since the second round of QA.



## Use case 1: share prefix KV between different vLLM instance through LMCache
The following instructions help deploy LMCache backend + multile vLLM instance by docker containers. The architecture of the demo application looks like this:

&lt;img width=&quot;817&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache/assets/25103655/ab64f84d-26e1-46ce-a503-e7e917b618bc&quot;&gt;


**Prerequisites**: To run the quickstart demo, your server must have 2 GPUs and the [docker environment](https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/) installed.


**Step 1:** Pull docker images
```bash
docker pull apostacyh/lmcache-server:0.1.0
docker pull apostacyh/vllm:lmcache-0.1.0
```

**Step 2:** Start LMCache backend server 
```bash
docker run --name lmcache-server --network host -d apostacyh/lmcache-server:0.1.0 0.0.0.0 65432
```

**Step 3:** start 2 vLLM instances
```bash
# The first vLLM instance listens at port 8000
model=mistralai/Mistral-7B-Instruct-v0.2    # Replace with your model name
sudo docker run --runtime nvidia --gpus &#039;&quot;device=0&quot;&#039; \
    -v &lt;Huggingface cache dir on your local machine&gt;:/root/.cache/huggingface \
    -p 8000:8000 \
    --env &quot;HF_TOKEN=&lt;Your huggingface token&gt;&quot; \
    --ipc=host \
    --network=host \
    apostacyh/vllm:lmcache-0.1.0 \
    --model $model --gpu-memory-utilization 0.7 --port 8000 \
    --lmcache-config-file /lmcache/LMCache/examples/example.yaml
```

Now, open another terminal and start another vLLM instance
```bash
# The second vLLM instance listens at port 8001
model=mistralai/Mistral-7B-Instruct-v0.2    # Replace with your model name
sudo docker run --runtime nvidia --gpus &#039;&quot;device=1&quot;&#039; \
    -v &lt;Huggingface cache dir on your local machine&gt;:/root/.cache/huggingface \
    -p 8001:8001 \
    --env &quot;HF_TOKEN=&lt;Your huggingface token&gt;&quot; \
    --ipc=host \
    --network=host \
    apostacyh/vllm:lmcache-0.1.0 \
    --model $model --gpu-memory-utilization 0.7 --port 8001 \
    --lmcache-config-file /lmcache/LMCache/examples/example.yaml
```

Remember to replace the `Huggingface cache dir on your local machine` and `Your huggingface token` in the commandline.

The vLLM engines are ready after you see the logs like this:
```
INFO:     Started server process [865615]
INFO:     Waiting for application startup.
INFO:     Application startup complete.
INFO:     Uvicorn running on http://0.0.0.0:8000 (Press CTRL+C to quit)
```

**Step 4:** Run demo application
You can run the demo application in the LMCache repo. Please execute the following commands on the server
```bash
git clone https://github.com/LMCache/LMCache
cd LMCache/examples/

# Install openai client library
pip install openai
```

In one terminal:
```
# Connect to the first vLLM engine
python openai_chat_completion_client.py 8000
```

In another terminal
```
# Connect to the second vLLM engine
python openai_chat_completion_client.py 8001
```

You should be able to see the second vLLM engine has much lower response delay.
This is because the KV cache of the long context can be shared across both vLLM engines by using LMCache.

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[modelcontextprotocol/servers]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Model Context Protocol Servers]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers">modelcontextprotocol/servers</a></h1>
            <p>Model Context Protocol Servers</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 51,592</p>
            <p>Forks: 5,913</p>
            <p>Stars today: 280 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Model Context Protocol servers

This repository is a collection of *reference implementations* for the [Model Context Protocol](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/) (MCP), as well as references
to community built servers and additional resources.

The servers in this repository showcase the versatility and extensibility of MCP, demonstrating how it can be used to give Large Language Models (LLMs) secure, controlled access to tools and data sources.
Each MCP server is implemented with either the [Typescript MCP SDK](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk) or [Python MCP SDK](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/python-sdk).

&gt; Note: Lists in this README are maintained in alphabetical order to minimize merge conflicts when adding new items.

## 🌟 Reference Servers

These servers aim to demonstrate MCP features and the TypeScript and Python SDKs.

- **[Everything](src/everything)** - Reference / test server with prompts, resources, and tools
- **[Fetch](src/fetch)** - Web content fetching and conversion for efficient LLM usage
- **[Filesystem](src/filesystem)** - Secure file operations with configurable access controls
- **[Git](src/git)** - Tools to read, search, and manipulate Git repositories
- **[Memory](src/memory)** - Knowledge graph-based persistent memory system
- **[Sequential Thinking](src/sequentialthinking)** - Dynamic and reflective problem-solving through thought sequences
- **[Time](src/time)** - Time and timezone conversion capabilities

### Archived

The following reference servers are now archived and can be found at [servers-archived](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived).

- **[AWS KB Retrieval](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/aws-kb-retrieval-server)** - Retrieval from AWS Knowledge Base using Bedrock Agent Runtime
- **[Brave Search](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/brave-search)** - Web and local search using Brave&#039;s Search API
- **[EverArt](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/everart)** - AI image generation using various models
- **[GitHub](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/github)** - Repository management, file operations, and GitHub API integration
- **[GitLab](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/gitlab)** - GitLab API, enabling project management
- **[Google Drive](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/gdrive)** - File access and search capabilities for Google Drive
- **[Google Maps](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/google-maps)** - Location services, directions, and place details
- **[PostgreSQL](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/postgres)** - Read-only database access with schema inspection
- **[Puppeteer](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/puppeteer)** - Browser automation and web scraping
- **[Redis](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/redis)** - Interact with Redis key-value stores
- **[Sentry](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/sentry)** - Retrieving and analyzing issues from Sentry.io
- **[Slack](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/slack)** - Channel management and messaging capabilities
- **[Sqlite](https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/servers-archived/tree/main/src/sqlite)** - Database interaction and business intelligence capabilities

## 🤝 Third-Party Servers

### 🎖️ Official Integrations

Official integrations are maintained by companies building production ready MCP servers for their platforms.

- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.21st.dev/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;21st.dev Logo&quot; /&gt; **[21st.dev Magic](https://github.com/21st-dev/magic-mcp)** - Create crafted UI components inspired by the best 21st.dev design engineers.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://invoxx-public-bucket.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/frontend-resources/adfin-logo-small.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Adfin Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Adfin](https://github.com/Adfin-Engineering/mcp-server-adfin)** - The only platform you need to get paid - all payments in one place, invoicing and accounting reconciliations with [Adfin](https://www.adfin.com/).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.agentql.com/favicon/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;AgentQL Logo&quot; /&gt; **[AgentQL](https://github.com/tinyfish-io/agentql-mcp)** - Enable AI agents to get structured data from unstructured web with [AgentQL](https://www.agentql.com/).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://agentrpc.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;AgentRPC Logo&quot; /&gt; **[AgentRPC](https://github.com/agentrpc/agentrpc)** - Connect to any function, any language, across network boundaries using [AgentRPC](https://www.agentrpc.com/).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://aiven.io/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Aiven Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Aiven](https://github.com/Aiven-Open/mcp-aiven)** - Navigate your [Aiven projects](https://go.aiven.io/mcp-server) and interact with the PostgreSQL®, Apache Kafka®, ClickHouse® and OpenSearch® services
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.alation.com/resource-center/download/7p3vnbbznfiw/34FMtBTex5ppvs2hNYa9Fc/c877c37e88e5339878658697c46d2d58/Alation-Logo-Bug-Primary.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Alation Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Alation](https://github.com/Alation/alation-ai-agent-sdk)** - Unlock the power of the enterprise Data Catalog by harnessing tools provided by the Alation MCP server.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.algolia.com/files/live/sites/algolia-assets/files/icons/algolia-logo-for-favicon.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Algolia Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Algolia MCP](https://github.com/algolia/mcp-node)** Algolia MCP Server exposes a natural language interface to query, inspect, and manage Algolia indices and configs. Useful for monitoring, debugging and optimizing search performance within your agentic workflows. See [demo](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UgCOLcDI9Lg).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/aliyun/alibabacloud-rds-openapi-mcp-server/blob/main/assets/alibabacloudrds.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alibaba Cloud RDS MySQL Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Alibaba Cloud RDS](https://github.com/aliyun/alibabacloud-rds-openapi-mcp-server)** - An MCP server designed to interact with the Alibaba Cloud RDS OpenAPI, enabling programmatic management of RDS resources via an LLM.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://img.alicdn.com/imgextra/i4/O1CN01epkXwH1WLAXkZfV6N_!!6000000002771-2-tps-200-200.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alibaba Cloud AnalyticDB for MySQL Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Alibaba Cloud AnalyticDB for MySQL](https://github.com/aliyun/alibabacloud-adb-mysql-mcp-server)** - Connect to a [AnalyticDB for MySQL](https://www.alibabacloud.com/en/product/analyticdb-for-mysql) cluster for getting database or table metadata, querying and analyzing data.It will be supported to add the openapi for cluster operation in the future.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/aliyun/alibaba-cloud-ops-mcp-server/blob/master/image/alibaba-cloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alibaba Cloud OPS Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Alibaba Cloud OPS](https://github.com/aliyun/alibaba-cloud-ops-mcp-server)** - Manage the lifecycle of your Alibaba Cloud resources with [CloudOps Orchestration Service](https://www.alibabacloud.com/en/product/oos) and Alibaba Cloud OpenAPI.  
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://iotdb.apache.org/img/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Apache IoTDB Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Apache IoTDB](https://github.com/apache/iotdb-mcp-server)** - MCP Server for [Apache IoTDB](https://github.com/apache/iotdb) database and its tools
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://apify.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Apify Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Apify](https://github.com/apify/actors-mcp-server)** - [Actors MCP Server](https://apify.com/apify/actors-mcp-server): Use 3,000+ pre-built cloud tools to extract data from websites, e-commerce, social media, search engines, maps, and more
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://2052727.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/2052727/cropped-cropped-apimaticio-favicon-1-32x32.png&quot; alt=&quot;APIMatic Logo&quot; /&gt; **[APIMatic MCP](https://github.com/apimatic/apimatic-validator-mcp)** - APIMatic MCP Server is used to validate OpenAPI specifications using [APIMatic](https://www.apimatic.io/). The server processes OpenAPI files and returns validation summaries by leveraging APIMatic&#039;s API.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://apollo-server-landing-page.cdn.apollographql.com/_latest/assets/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Apollo Graph Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Apollo MCP Server](https://github.com/apollographql/apollo-mcp-server/)** - Connect your GraphQL APIs to AI agents
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://phoenix.arize.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/cropped-Favicon-32x32.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arize-Phoenix Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Arize Phoenix](https://github.com/Arize-ai/phoenix/tree/main/js/packages/phoenix-mcp)** - Inspect traces, manage prompts, curate datasets, and run experiments using [Arize Phoenix](https://github.com/Arize-ai/phoenix), an open-source AI and LLM observability tool.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://console.asgardeo.io/app/libs/themes/wso2is/assets/images/branding/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Asgardeo Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Asgardeo](https://github.com/asgardeo/asgardeo-mcp-server)** - MCP server to interact with your [Asgardeo](https://wso2.com/asgardeo) organization through LLM tools.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.datastax.com/favicon-32x32.png&quot; alt=&quot;DataStax logo&quot; /&gt; **[Astra DB](https://github.com/datastax/astra-db-mcp)** - Comprehensive tools for managing collections and documents in a [DataStax Astra DB](https://www.datastax.com/products/datastax-astra) NoSQL database with a full range of operations such as create, update, delete, find, and associated bulk actions.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.atlan.com/assets/atlan-a-logo-blue-background.png&quot; alt=&quot;Atlan Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Atlan](https://github.com/atlanhq/agent-toolkit/tree/main/modelcontextprotocol)** - The Atlan Model Context Protocol server allows you to interact with the [Atlan](https://www.atlan.com/) services through multiple tools.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://resources.audiense.com/hubfs/favicon-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Audiense Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Audiense Insights](https://github.com/AudienseCo/mcp-audiense-insights)** - Marketing insights and audience analysis from [Audiense](https://www.audiense.com/products/audiense-insights) reports, covering demographic, cultural, influencer, and content engagement analysis.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://a0.awsstatic.com/libra-css/images/site/fav/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;AWS Logo&quot; /&gt; **[AWS](https://github.com/awslabs/mcp)** -  Specialized MCP servers that bring AWS best practices directly to your development workflow.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://axiom.co/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Axiom Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Axiom](https://github.com/axiomhq/mcp-server-axiom)** - Query and analyze your Axiom logs, traces, and all other event data in natural language
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-dynmedia-1.microsoft.com/is/content/microsoftcorp/acom_social_icon_azure&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Azure Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Azure](https://github.com/Azure/azure-mcp)** - The Azure MCP Server gives MCP Clients access to key Azure services and tools like Azure Storage, Cosmos DB, the Azure CLI, and more.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bankless.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Bankless Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Bankless Onchain](https://github.com/bankless/onchain-mcp)** - Query Onchain data, like ERC20 tokens, transaction history, smart contract state.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://bicscan.io/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;BICScan Logo&quot; /&gt; **[BICScan](https://github.com/ahnlabio/bicscan-mcp)** - Risk score / asset holdings of EVM blockchain address (EOA, CA, ENS) and even domain names.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://web-cdn.bitrise.io/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Bitrise Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Bitrise](https://github.com/bitrise-io/bitrise-mcp)** - Chat with your builds, CI, and [more](https://bitrise.io/blog/post/chat-with-your-builds-ci-and-more-introducing-the-bitrise-mcp-server).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.box.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Box Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Box](https://github.com/box-community/mcp-server-box)** - Interact with the Intelligent Content Management platform through Box AI.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://browserbase.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Browserbase Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Browserbase](https://github.com/browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase)** - Automate browser interactions in the cloud (e.g. web navigation, data extraction, form filling, and more)
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://browserstack.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/themes/browserstack/img/favicons/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;BrowserStack Logo&quot; /&gt; **[BrowserStack](https://github.com/browserstack/mcp-server)** - Access BrowserStack&#039;s [Test Platform](https://www.browserstack.com/test-platform) to debug, write and fix tests, do accessibility testing and more.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://portswigger.net/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;PortSwigger Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Burp Suite](https://github.com/PortSwigger/mcp-server)** - MCP Server extension allowing AI clients to connect to [Burp Suite](https://portswigger.net)
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://play.cartesia.ai/icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cartesia logo&quot; /&gt; **[Cartesia](https://github.com/cartesia-ai/cartesia-mcp)** - Connect to the [Cartesia](https://cartesia.ai/) voice platform to perform text-to-speech, voice cloning etc. 
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.chargebee.com/static/resources/brand/favicon.png&quot; /&gt; **[Chargebee](https://github.com/chargebee/agentkit/tree/main/modelcontextprotocol)** - MCP Server that connects AI agents to [Chargebee platform](https://www.chargebee.com).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.chiki.studio/brand/logo.png&quot; /&gt; **[Chiki StudIO](https://chiki.studio/galimybes/mcp/)** - Create your own configurable MCP servers purely via configuration (no code), with instructions, prompts, and tools support.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://trychroma.com/_next/static/media/chroma-logo.ae2d6e4b.svg&quot; /&gt; **[Chroma](https://github.com/chroma-core/chroma-mcp)** - Embeddings, vector search, document storage, and full-text search with the open-source AI application database
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.chronulus.com/favicon/chronulus-logo-blue-on-alpha-square-128x128.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Chronulus AI Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Chronulus AI](https://github.com/ChronulusAI/chronulus-mcp)** - Predict anything with Chronulus AI forecasting and prediction agents.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://circleci.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;CircleCI Logo&quot; /&gt; **[CircleCI](https://github.com/CircleCI-Public/mcp-server-circleci)** - Enable AI Agents to fix build failures from CircleCI.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://clickhouse.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;ClickHouse Logo&quot; /&gt; **[ClickHouse](https://github.com/ClickHouse/mcp-clickhouse)** - Query your [ClickHouse](https://clickhouse.com/) database server.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.simpleicons.org/cloudflare&quot; /&gt; **[Cloudflare](https://github.com/cloudflare/mcp-server-cloudflare)** - Deploy, configure &amp; interrogate your resources on the Cloudflare developer platform (e.g. Workers/KV/R2/D1)
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://app.codacy.com/static/images/favicon-16x16.png&quot; alt=&quot;Codacy Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Codacy](https://github.com/codacy/codacy-mcp-server/)** - Interact with [Codacy](https://www.codacy.com) API to query code quality issues, vulnerabilities, and coverage insights about your code.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://codelogic.com/wp-content/themes/codelogic/assets/img/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;CodeLogic Logo&quot; /&gt; **[CodeLogic](https://github.com/CodeLogicIncEngineering/codelogic-mcp-server)** - Interact with [CodeLogic](https://codelogic.com), a Software Intelligence platform that graphs complex code and data architecture dependencies, to boost AI accuracy and insight.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.comet.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Comet Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Comet Opik](https://github.com/comet-ml/opik-mcp)** - Query and analyze your [Opik](https://github.com/comet-ml/opik) logs, traces, prompts and all other telemtry data from your LLMs in natural language.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.confluent.io/favicon.ico&quot; /&gt; **[Confluent](https://github.com/confluentinc/mcp-confluent)** - Interact with Confluent Kafka and Confluent Cloud REST APIs.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.convex.dev/favicon.ico&quot; /&gt; **[Convex](https://stack.convex.dev/convex-mcp-server)** - Introspect and query your apps deployed to Convex.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.couchbase.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/couchbase-favicon.svg&quot; /&gt; **[Couchbase](https://github.com/Couchbase-Ecosystem/mcp-server-couchbase)** - Interact with the data stored in Couchbase clusters.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b256f9fa-2020-4b37-9644-c77229ef182b&quot; alt=&quot;CRIC 克而瑞 LOGO&quot;&gt; **[CRIC Wuye AI](https://github.com/wuye-ai/mcp-server-wuye-ai)** - Interact with capabilities of the CRIC Wuye AI platform, an intelligent assistant specifically for the property management industry.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;http://app.itsdart.com/static/img/favicon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dart Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Dart](https://github.com/its-dart/dart-mcp-server)** - Interact with task, doc, and project data in [Dart](https://itsdart.com), an AI-native project management tool
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://datahub.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/cropped-Artboard-1-32x32.png&quot; alt=&quot;DataHub Logo&quot; /&gt; **[DataHub](https://github.com/acryldata/mcp-server-datahub)** - Search your data assets, traverse data lineage, write SQL queries, and more using [DataHub](https://datahub.com/) metadata.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://dexpaprika.com/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;DexPaprika Logo&quot; /&gt; **[DexPaprika (CoinPaprika)](https://github.com/coinpaprika/dexpaprika-mcp)** - Access real-time DEX data, liquidity pools, token information, and trading analytics across multiple blockchain networks with [DexPaprika](https://dexpaprika.com) by CoinPaprika.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.devhub.com/img/upload/favicon-196x196-dh.png&quot; alt=&quot;DevHub Logo&quot; /&gt; **[DevHub](https://github.com/devhub/devhub-cms-mcp)** - Manage and utilize website content within the [DevHub](https://www.devhub.com) CMS platform
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://devrev.ai/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;DevRev Logo&quot; /&gt; **[DevRev](https://github.com/devrev/mcp-server)** - An MCP server to integrate with DevRev APIs to search through your DevRev Knowledge Graph where objects can be imported from diff. Sources listed [here](https://devrev.ai/docs/import#available-sources).
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/58178984&quot; alt=&quot;Dynatrace Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Dynatrace](https://github.com/dynatrace-oss/dynatrace-mcp)** - Manage and interact with the [Dynatrace Platform ](https://www.dynatrace.com/platform) for real-time observability and monitoring.
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://e2b.dev/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;E2B Logo&quot; /&gt; **[E2B](https://github.com/e2b-dev/mcp-server)** - Run code in secure sandboxes hosted by [E2B](https://e2b.dev)
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.edgee.cloud/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Edgee Logo&quot; /&gt; **[Edgee](https://github.com/edgee-cloud/mcp-server-edgee)** - Deploy and manage [Edgee](https://www.edgee.cloud) components and projects
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://static.edubase.net/media/brand/favicon/favicon-32x32.png&quot; alt=&quot;EduBase Logo&quot; /&gt; **[EduBase](https://github.com/EduBase/MCP)** - Interact with [EduBase](https://www.edubase.net), a comprehensive e-learning platform with advanced quizzing, exam management, and content organization capabilities
- &lt;img height=&quot;12&quot; width=&quot;12&quot; src=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/favicon.ico&quot; alt=&quot;Elasticsearch Logo

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azure/azure-sdk-for-python]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This repository is for active development of the Azure SDK for Python. For consumers of the SDK we recommend visiting our public developer docs at https://learn.microsoft.com/python/azure/ or our versioned developer docs at https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk-for-python.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python">Azure/azure-sdk-for-python</a></h1>
            <p>This repository is for active development of the Azure SDK for Python. For consumers of the SDK we recommend visiting our public developer docs at https://learn.microsoft.com/python/azure/ or our versioned developer docs at https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk-for-python.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,953</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,010</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Azure SDK for Python

[![Packages](https://img.shields.io/badge/packages-latest-blue.svg)](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/releases/latest/python.html) [![Dependencies](https://img.shields.io/badge/dependency-report-blue.svg)](https://azuresdkartifacts.blob.core.windows.net/azure-sdk-for-python/dependencies/dependencies.html) [![DepGraph](https://img.shields.io/badge/dependency-graph-blue.svg)](https://azuresdkartifacts.blob.core.windows.net/azure-sdk-for-python/dependencies/dependencyGraph/index.html) [![Python](https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/azure-core.svg?maxAge=2592000)](https://pypi.python.org/pypi/azure/) [![Build Status](https://dev.azure.com/azure-sdk/public/_apis/build/status/python/python%20-%20core%20-%20ci?branchName=main)](https://dev.azure.com/azure-sdk/public/_build/latest?definitionId=458&amp;branchName=main)

This repository is for the active development of the Azure SDK for Python. For consumers of the SDK we recommend visiting our [public developer docs](https://docs.microsoft.com/python/azure/) or our versioned [developer docs](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk-for-python).

## Getting started

For your convenience, each service has a separate set of libraries that you can choose to use instead of one, large Azure package. To get started with a specific library, see the `README.md` (or `README.rst`) file located in the library&#039;s project folder.

You can find service libraries in the `/sdk` directory.

### Prerequisites

The client libraries are supported on Python 3.9 or later. For more details, please read our page on [Azure SDK for Python version support policy](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python/wiki/Azure-SDKs-Python-version-support-policy).

## Packages available

Each service might have a number of libraries available from each of the following categories:
* [Client - New Releases](#client-new-releases)
* [Client - Previous Versions](#client-previous-versions)
* [Management - New Releases](#management-new-releases)
* [Management - Previous Versions](#management-previous-versions)

### Client: New Releases

New wave of packages that we are announcing as **GA** and several that are currently releasing in **preview**. These libraries allow you to use and consume existing resources and interact with them, for example: upload a blob. These libraries share  several core functionalities such as: retries, logging, transport protocols, authentication protocols, etc. that can be found in the [azure-core](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python/blob/main/sdk/core/azure-core) library. You can learn more about these libraries by reading guidelines that they follow [here](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/python/guidelines/index.html).

You can find the [most up to date list of all of the new packages on our page](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/releases/latest/index.html#python)

&gt; NOTE: If you need to ensure your code is ready for production use one of the stable, non-preview libraries.

### Client: Previous Versions

Last stable versions of packages that have been provided for usage with Azure and are production-ready. These libraries provide you with similar functionalities to the Preview ones as they allow you to use and consume existing resources and interact with them, for example: upload a blob. They might not implement the [guidelines](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/python/guidelines/index.html) or have the same feature set as the November releases. They do however offer wider coverage of services.

### Management: New Releases
A new set of management libraries that follow the [Azure SDK Design Guidelines for Python](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/python/guidelines/) are now available. These new libraries provide a number of core capabilities that are shared amongst all Azure SDKs, including the intuitive Azure Identity library, an HTTP Pipeline with custom policies, error-handling, distributed tracing, and much more.
Documentation and code samples for these new libraries can be found [here](https://aka.ms/azsdk/python/mgmt). In addition, a migration guide that shows how to transition from older versions of libraries is located [here](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python/blob/main/doc/sphinx/mgmt_quickstart.rst#migration-guide).

You can find the [most up to date list of all of the new packages on our page](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/releases/latest/mgmt/python.html)

&gt; NOTE: If you need to ensure your code is ready for production use one of the stable, non-preview libraries. Also, if you are experiencing authentication issues with the management libraries after upgrading certain packages, it&#039;s possible that you upgraded to the new versions of SDK without changing the authentication code, please refer to the migration guide mentioned above for proper instructions.

### Management: Previous Versions
For a complete list of management libraries that enable you to provision and manage Azure resources, please [check here](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/releases/latest/all/python.html). They might not have the same feature set as the new releases but they do offer wider coverage of services.
Management libraries can be identified by namespaces that start with `azure-mgmt-`, e.g. `azure-mgmt-compute`

## Need help?

* For detailed documentation visit our [Azure SDK for Python documentation](https://aka.ms/python-docs)
* File an issue via [GitHub Issues](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python/issues)
* Check [previous questions](https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/azure+python) or ask new ones on StackOverflow using `azure` and `python` tags.


## Data Collection
The software may collect information about you and your use of the software and send it to Microsoft. Microsoft may use this information to provide services and improve our products and services. You may turn off the telemetry as described below. You can learn more about data collection and use in the help documentation and Microsoft’s [privacy statement](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=824704). For more information on the data collected by the Azure SDK, please visit the [Telemetry Guidelines](https://azure.github.io/azure-sdk/general_azurecore.html#telemetry-policy) page.

### Telemetry Configuration
Telemetry collection is on by default.

To opt out, you can disable telemetry at client construction. Define a `NoUserAgentPolicy` class that is a subclass of `UserAgentPolicy` with an `on_request` method that does nothing. Then pass instance of this class as kwargs `user_agent_policy=NoUserAgentPolicy()` during client creation. This will disable telemetry for all methods in the client. Do this for every new client.

The example below uses the `azure-storage-blob` package. In your code, you can replace `azure-storage-blob` with the package you are using.

```python
import os
from azure.identity import ManagedIdentityCredential
from azure.storage.blob import BlobServiceClient
from azure.core.pipeline.policies import UserAgentPolicy


# Create your credential you want to use
mi_credential = ManagedIdentityCredential()

account_url = &quot;https://&lt;storageaccountname&gt;.blob.core.windows.net&quot;

# Set up user-agent override
class NoUserAgentPolicy(UserAgentPolicy):
    def on_request(self, request):
        pass

# Create the BlobServiceClient object
blob_service_client = BlobServiceClient(account_url, credential=mi_credential, user_agent_policy=NoUserAgentPolicy())

container_client = blob_service_client.get_container_client(container=&lt;container_name&gt;) 
# TODO: do something with the container client like download blob to a file
```

### Reporting security issues and security bugs

Security issues and bugs should be reported privately, via email, to the Microsoft Security Response Center (MSRC) &lt;secure@microsoft.com&gt;. You should receive a response within 24 hours. If for some reason you do not, please follow up via email to ensure we received your original message. Further information, including the MSRC PGP key, can be found in the [Security TechCenter](https://www.microsoft.com/msrc/faqs-report-an-issue).

## Contributing

For details on contributing to this repository, see the [contributing guide](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-python/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md).

This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit
https://cla.microsoft.com.

When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repositories using our CLA.

This project has adopted the [Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct](https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/).
For more information see the [Code of Conduct FAQ](https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/)
or contact [opencode@microsoft.com](mailto:opencode@microsoft.com) with any additional questions or comments.



</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[pytorch/pytorch]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Tensors and Dynamic neural networks in Python with strong GPU acceleration]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch">pytorch/pytorch</a></h1>
            <p>Tensors and Dynamic neural networks in Python with strong GPU acceleration</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 90,573</p>
            <p>Forks: 24,355</p>
            <p>Stars today: 32 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![PyTorch Logo](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/raw/main/docs/source/_static/img/pytorch-logo-dark.png)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

PyTorch is a Python package that provides two high-level features:
- Tensor computation (like NumPy) with strong GPU acceleration
- Deep neural networks built on a tape-based autograd system

You can reuse your favorite Python packages such as NumPy, SciPy, and Cython to extend PyTorch when needed.

Our trunk health (Continuous Integration signals) can be found at [hud.pytorch.org](https://hud.pytorch.org/ci/pytorch/pytorch/main).

&lt;!-- toc --&gt;

- [More About PyTorch](#more-about-pytorch)
  - [A GPU-Ready Tensor Library](#a-gpu-ready-tensor-library)
  - [Dynamic Neural Networks: Tape-Based Autograd](#dynamic-neural-networks-tape-based-autograd)
  - [Python First](#python-first)
  - [Imperative Experiences](#imperative-experiences)
  - [Fast and Lean](#fast-and-lean)
  - [Extensions Without Pain](#extensions-without-pain)
- [Installation](#installation)
  - [Binaries](#binaries)
    - [NVIDIA Jetson Platforms](#nvidia-jetson-platforms)
  - [From Source](#from-source)
    - [Prerequisites](#prerequisites)
      - [NVIDIA CUDA Support](#nvidia-cuda-support)
      - [AMD ROCm Support](#amd-rocm-support)
      - [Intel GPU Support](#intel-gpu-support)
    - [Get the PyTorch Source](#get-the-pytorch-source)
    - [Install Dependencies](#install-dependencies)
    - [Install PyTorch](#install-pytorch)
      - [Adjust Build Options (Optional)](#adjust-build-options-optional)
  - [Docker Image](#docker-image)
    - [Using pre-built images](#using-pre-built-images)
    - [Building the image yourself](#building-the-image-yourself)
  - [Building the Documentation](#building-the-documentation)
    - [Building a PDF](#building-a-pdf)
  - [Previous Versions](#previous-versions)
- [Getting Started](#getting-started)
- [Resources](#resources)
- [Communication](#communication)
- [Releases and Contributing](#releases-and-contributing)
- [The Team](#the-team)
- [License](#license)

&lt;!-- tocstop --&gt;

## More About PyTorch

[Learn the basics of PyTorch](https://pytorch.org/tutorials/beginner/basics/intro.html)

At a granular level, PyTorch is a library that consists of the following components:

| Component | Description |
| ---- | --- |
| [**torch**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/torch.html) | A Tensor library like NumPy, with strong GPU support |
| [**torch.autograd**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/autograd.html) | A tape-based automatic differentiation library that supports all differentiable Tensor operations in torch |
| [**torch.jit**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit.html) | A compilation stack (TorchScript) to create serializable and optimizable models from PyTorch code  |
| [**torch.nn**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/nn.html) | A neural networks library deeply integrated with autograd designed for maximum flexibility |
| [**torch.multiprocessing**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/multiprocessing.html) | Python multiprocessing, but with magical memory sharing of torch Tensors across processes. Useful for data loading and Hogwild training |
| [**torch.utils**](https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/data.html) | DataLoader and other utility functions for convenience |

Usually, PyTorch is used either as:

- A replacement for NumPy to use the power of GPUs.
- A deep learning research platform that provides maximum flexibility and speed.

Elaborating Further:

### A GPU-Ready Tensor Library

If you use NumPy, then you have used Tensors (a.k.a. ndarray).

![Tensor illustration](./docs/source/_static/img/tensor_illustration.png)

PyTorch provides Tensors that can live either on the CPU or the GPU and accelerates the
computation by a huge amount.

We provide a wide variety of tensor routines to accelerate and fit your scientific computation needs
such as slicing, indexing, mathematical operations, linear algebra, reductions.
And they are fast!

### Dynamic Neural Networks: Tape-Based Autograd

PyTorch has a unique way of building neural networks: using and replaying a tape recorder.

Most frameworks such as TensorFlow, Theano, Caffe, and CNTK have a static view of the world.
One has to build a neural network and reuse the same structure again and again.
Changing the way the network behaves means that one has to start from scratch.

With PyTorch, we use a technique called reverse-mode auto-differentiation, which allows you to
change the way your network behaves arbitrarily with zero lag or overhead. Our inspiration comes
from several research papers on this topic, as well as current and past work such as
[torch-autograd](https://github.com/twitter/torch-autograd),
[autograd](https://github.com/HIPS/autograd),
[Chainer](https://chainer.org), etc.

While this technique is not unique to PyTorch, it&#039;s one of the fastest implementations of it to date.
You get the best of speed and flexibility for your crazy research.

![Dynamic graph](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/raw/main/docs/source/_static/img/dynamic_graph.gif)

### Python First

PyTorch is not a Python binding into a monolithic C++ framework.
It is built to be deeply integrated into Python.
You can use it naturally like you would use [NumPy](https://www.numpy.org/) / [SciPy](https://www.scipy.org/) / [scikit-learn](https://scikit-learn.org) etc.
You can write your new neural network layers in Python itself, using your favorite libraries
and use packages such as [Cython](https://cython.org/) and [Numba](http://numba.pydata.org/).
Our goal is to not reinvent the wheel where appropriate.

### Imperative Experiences

PyTorch is designed to be intuitive, linear in thought, and easy to use.
When you execute a line of code, it gets executed. There isn&#039;t an asynchronous view of the world.
When you drop into a debugger or receive error messages and stack traces, understanding them is straightforward.
The stack trace points to exactly where your code was defined.
We hope you never spend hours debugging your code because of bad stack traces or asynchronous and opaque execution engines.

### Fast and Lean

PyTorch has minimal framework overhead. We integrate acceleration libraries
such as [Intel MKL](https://software.intel.com/mkl) and NVIDIA ([cuDNN](https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn), [NCCL](https://developer.nvidia.com/nccl)) to maximize speed.
At the core, its CPU and GPU Tensor and neural network backends
are mature and have been tested for years.

Hence, PyTorch is quite fast — whether you run small or large neural networks.

The memory usage in PyTorch is extremely efficient compared to Torch or some of the alternatives.
We&#039;ve written custom memory allocators for the GPU to make sure that
your deep learning models are maximally memory efficient.
This enables you to train bigger deep learning models than before.

### Extensions Without Pain

Writing new neural network modules, or interfacing with PyTorch&#039;s Tensor API was designed to be straightforward
and with minimal abstractions.

You can write new neural network layers in Python using the torch API
[or your favorite NumPy-based libraries such as SciPy](https://pytorch.org/tutorials/advanced/numpy_extensions_tutorial.html).

If you want to write your layers in C/C++, we provide a convenient extension API that is efficient and with minimal boilerplate.
No wrapper code needs to be written. You can see [a tutorial here](https://pytorch.org/tutorials/advanced/cpp_extension.html) and [an example here](https://github.com/pytorch/extension-cpp).


## Installation

### Binaries
Commands to install binaries via Conda or pip wheels are on our website: [https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/](https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/)


#### NVIDIA Jetson Platforms

Python wheels for NVIDIA&#039;s Jetson Nano, Jetson TX1/TX2, Jetson Xavier NX/AGX, and Jetson AGX Orin are provided [here](https://forums.developer.nvidia.com/t/pytorch-for-jetson-version-1-10-now-available/72048) and the L4T container is published [here](https://catalog.ngc.nvidia.com/orgs/nvidia/containers/l4t-pytorch)

They require JetPack 4.2 and above, and [@dusty-nv](https://github.com/dusty-nv) and [@ptrblck](https://github.com/ptrblck) are maintaining them.


### From Source

#### Prerequisites
If you are installing from source, you will need:
- Python 3.9 or later
- A compiler that fully supports C++17, such as clang or gcc (gcc 9.4.0 or newer is required, on Linux)
- Visual Studio or Visual Studio Build Tool (Windows only)

\* PyTorch CI uses Visual C++ BuildTools, which come with Visual Studio Enterprise,
Professional, or Community Editions. You can also install the build tools from
https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/visual-cpp-build-tools/. The build tools *do not*
come with Visual Studio Code by default.

An example of environment setup is shown below:

* Linux:

```bash
$ source &lt;CONDA_INSTALL_DIR&gt;/bin/activate
$ conda create -y -n &lt;CONDA_NAME&gt;
$ conda activate &lt;CONDA_NAME&gt;
```

* Windows:

```bash
$ source &lt;CONDA_INSTALL_DIR&gt;\Scripts\activate.bat
$ conda create -y -n &lt;CONDA_NAME&gt;
$ conda activate &lt;CONDA_NAME&gt;
$ call &quot;C:\Program Files\Microsoft Visual Studio\&lt;VERSION&gt;\Community\VC\Auxiliary\Build\vcvarsall.bat&quot; x64
```

##### NVIDIA CUDA Support
If you want to compile with CUDA support, [select a supported version of CUDA from our support matrix](https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/), then install the following:
- [NVIDIA CUDA](https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-downloads)
- [NVIDIA cuDNN](https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn) v8.5 or above
- [Compiler](https://gist.github.com/ax3l/9489132) compatible with CUDA

Note: You could refer to the [cuDNN Support Matrix](https://docs.nvidia.com/deeplearning/cudnn/backend/latest/reference/support-matrix.html) for cuDNN versions with the various supported CUDA, CUDA driver and NVIDIA hardware

If you want to disable CUDA support, export the environment variable `USE_CUDA=0`.
Other potentially useful environment variables may be found in `setup.py`.

If you are building for NVIDIA&#039;s Jetson platforms (Jetson Nano, TX1, TX2, AGX Xavier), Instructions to install PyTorch for Jetson Nano are [available here](https://devtalk.nvidia.com/default/topic/1049071/jetson-nano/pytorch-for-jetson-nano/)

##### AMD ROCm Support
If you want to compile with ROCm support, install
- [AMD ROCm](https://rocm.docs.amd.com/en/latest/deploy/linux/quick_start.html) 4.0 and above installation
- ROCm is currently supported only for Linux systems.

By default the build system expects ROCm to be installed in `/opt/rocm`. If ROCm is installed in a different directory, the `ROCM_PATH` environment variable must be set to the ROCm installation directory. The build system automatically detects the AMD GPU architecture. Optionally, the AMD GPU architecture can be explicitly set with the `PYTORCH_ROCM_ARCH` environment variable [AMD GPU architecture](https://rocm.docs.amd.com/projects/install-on-linux/en/latest/reference/system-requirements.html#supported-gpus)

If you want to disable ROCm support, export the environment variable `USE_ROCM=0`.
Other potentially useful environment variables may be found in `setup.py`.

##### Intel GPU Support
If you want to compile with Intel GPU support, follow these
- [PyTorch Prerequisites for Intel GPUs](https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/developer/articles/tool/pytorch-prerequisites-for-intel-gpus.html) instructions.
- Intel GPU is supported for Linux and Windows.

If you want to disable Intel GPU support, export the environment variable `USE_XPU=0`.
Other potentially useful environment variables may be found in `setup.py`.

#### Get the PyTorch Source
```bash
git clone https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch
cd pytorch
# if you are updating an existing checkout
git submodule sync
git submodule update --init --recursive
```

#### Install Dependencies

**Common**

```bash
conda install cmake ninja
# Run this command from the PyTorch directory after cloning the source code using the “Get the PyTorch Source“ section below
pip install -r requirements.txt
```

**On Linux**

```bash
pip install mkl-static mkl-include
# CUDA only: Add LAPACK support for the GPU if needed
# magma installation: run with active conda environment. specify CUDA version to install
.ci/docker/common/install_magma_conda.sh 12.4

# (optional) If using torch.compile with inductor/triton, install the matching version of triton
# Run from the pytorch directory after cloning
# For Intel GPU support, please explicitly `export USE_XPU=1` before running command.
make triton
```

**On MacOS**

```bash
# Add this package on intel x86 processor machines only
pip install mkl-static mkl-include
# Add these packages if torch.distributed is needed
conda install pkg-config libuv
```

**On Windows**

```bash
pip install mkl-static mkl-include
# Add these packages if torch.distributed is needed.
# Distributed package support on Windows is a prototype feature and is subject to changes.
conda install -c conda-forge libuv=1.39
```

#### Install PyTorch
**On Linux**

If you&#039;re compiling for AMD ROCm then first run this command:
```bash
# Only run this if you&#039;re compiling for ROCm
python tools/amd_build/build_amd.py
```

Install PyTorch
```bash
export CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH=&quot;${CONDA_PREFIX:-&#039;$(dirname $(which conda))/../&#039;}:${CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH}&quot;
python setup.py develop
```

**On macOS**

```bash
python3 setup.py develop
```

**On Windows**

If you want to build legacy python code, please refer to [Building on legacy code and CUDA](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md#building-on-legacy-code-and-cuda)

**CPU-only builds**

In this mode PyTorch computations will run on your CPU, not your GPU.

```cmd
python setup.py develop
```

Note on OpenMP: The desired OpenMP implementation is Intel OpenMP (iomp). In order to link against iomp, you&#039;ll need to manually download the library and set up the building environment by tweaking `CMAKE_INCLUDE_PATH` and `LIB`. The instruction [here](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/blob/main/docs/source/notes/windows.rst#building-from-source) is an example for setting up both MKL and Intel OpenMP. Without these configurations for CMake, Microsoft Visual C OpenMP runtime (vcomp) will be used.

**CUDA based build**

In this mode PyTorch computations will leverage your GPU via CUDA for faster number crunching

[NVTX](https://docs.nvidia.com/gameworks/content/gameworkslibrary/nvtx/nvidia_tools_extension_library_nvtx.htm) is needed to build Pytorch with CUDA.
NVTX is a part of CUDA distributive, where it is called &quot;Nsight Compute&quot;. To install it onto an already installed CUDA run CUDA installation once again and check the corresponding checkbox.
Make sure that CUDA with Nsight Compute is installed after Visual Studio.

Currently, VS 2017 / 2019, and Ninja are supported as the generator of CMake. If `ninja.exe` is detected in `PATH`, then Ninja will be used as the default generator, otherwise, it will use VS 2017 / 2019.
&lt;br/&gt; If Ninja is selected as the generator, the latest MSVC will get selected as the underlying toolchain.

Additional libraries such as
[Magma](https://developer.nvidia.com/magma), [oneDNN, a.k.a. MKLDNN or DNNL](https://github.com/oneapi-src/oneDNN), and [Sccache](https://github.com/mozilla/sccache) are often needed. Please refer to the [installation-helper](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/tree/main/.ci/pytorch/win-test-helpers/installation-helpers) to install them.

You can refer to the [build_pytorch.bat](https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/blob/main/.ci/pytorch/win-test-helpers/build_pytorch.bat) script for some other environment variables configurations


```cmd
cmd

:: Set the environment variables after you have downloaded and unzipped the mkl package,
:: else CMake would throw an error as `Could NOT find OpenMP`.
set CMAKE_INCLUDE_PATH={Your directory}\mkl\include
set LIB={Your directory}\mkl\lib;%LIB%

:: Read the content in the previous section carefully before you proceed.
:: [Optional] If you want to override the underlying toolset used by Ninja and Visual Studio with CUDA, please run the following script block.
:: &quot;Visual Studio 2019 Developer Command Prompt&quot; will be run automatically.
:: Make sure you have CMake &gt;= 3.12 before you do this when you use the Visual Studio generator.
set CMAKE_GENERATOR_TOOLSET_VERSION=14.27
set DISTUTILS_USE_SDK=1
for /f &quot;usebackq tokens=*&quot; %i in (`&quot;%ProgramFiles(x86)%\Microsoft Visual Studio\Installer\vswhere.exe&quot; -version [15^,17^) -products * -latest -property installationPath`) do call &quot;%i\VC\Auxiliary\Build\vcvarsall.bat&quot; x64 -vcvars_ver=%CMAKE_GENERATOR_TOOLSET_VERSION%

:: [Optional] If you want to override the CUDA host compiler
set CUDAHOSTCXX=C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio\2019\Community\VC\Tools\MSVC\14.27.29110\bin\HostX64\x64\cl.exe

python setup.py develop

```

**Intel GPU builds**

In this mode PyTorch with Intel GPU support will be built.

Please make sure [the common prerequisites](#prerequisites) as well as [the prerequisites for Intel GPU](#intel-gpu-support) are properly installed and the environment variables are configured prior to starting the build. For build tool support, `Visual Studio 2022` is required.

Then PyTorch can be built with the command:

```cmd
:: CMD Commands:
:: Set the CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH to help find corresponding packages
:: %CONDA_PREFIX% only works after `conda activate custom_env`

if defined CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH (
    set &quot;CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH=%CONDA_PREFIX%\Library;%CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH%&quot;
) else (
    set &quot;CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH=%CONDA_PREFIX%\Library&quot;
)

python setup.py develop
```

##### Adjust Build Options (Optional)

You can adjust the configuration of cmake variables optionally (without building first), by doing
the following. For example, adjusting the pre-detected directories for CuDNN or BLAS can be done
with such a step.

On Linux
```bash
export CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH=&quot;${CONDA_PREFIX:-&#039;$(dirname $(which conda))/../&#039;}:${CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH}&quot;
python setup.py build --cmake-only
ccmake build  # or cmake-gui build
```

On macOS
```bash
export CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH=&quot;${CONDA_PREFIX:-&#039;$(dirname $(which conda))/../&#039;}:${CMAKE_PREFIX_PATH}&quot;
MACOSX_DEPLOYMENT_TARGET=10.9 CC=clang CXX=clang++ python setup.py build --cmake-only
ccmake build  # or cmake-gui build
```

### Docker Image

#### Using pre-built images

You can also pull a pre-built docker image from Docker Hub and run with docker v19.03+

```bash
docker run --gpus all --rm -ti --ipc=host pytorch/pytorch:latest
```

Please note that PyTorch uses shared memory to share data between processes, so if torch multiprocessing is used (e.g.
for multithreaded data loaders) the default shared memory segment size that container runs with is not enough, and you
should increase shared memory size either with `--ipc=host` or `--shm-size` command line options to `nvidia-docker run`.

#### Building the image yourself

**NOTE:** Must be built with a docker version &gt; 18.06

The `Dockerfile` is supplied to build images with CUDA 11.1 support and cuDNN v8.
You can pass `PYTHON_VERSION=x.y` make variable to specify which Python version is to be used by Miniconda, or leave it
unset to use the default.

```bash
make -f docker.Makefile
# images are tagged as docker.io/${your_docker_username}/pytorch
```

You can also pass the `CMAKE_VARS=&quot;...&quot;` environment variable to specify additional CMake variables to be passed to CMake during the build.
See [setup.py](./setup.py) for the list of available variables.

```bash
make -f docker.Makefile
```

### Building the Documentation

To build documentation in various formats, you will need [Sphinx](http://www.sphinx-doc.org)
and the pytorch_sphinx_theme2.

Before you build the documentation locally, ensure `torch` is
installed in your environment. For small fixes, you can install the
nightly version as described in [Getting Started](https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/).

For more complex fixes, such as adding a new module and docstrings for
the new module, you might need to inst

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HKUDS/AutoAgent]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA["AutoAgent: Fully-Automated and Zero-Code LLM Agent Framework"]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent">HKUDS/AutoAgent</a></h1>
            <p>"AutoAgent: Fully-Automated and Zero-Code LLM Agent Framework"</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,601</p>
            <p>Forks: 615</p>
            <p>Stars today: 80 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;a name=&quot;readme-top&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/AutoAgent_logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;AutoAgent: Fully-Automated &amp; Zero-Code&lt;/br&gt; LLM Agent Framework &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://autoagent-ai.github.io&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Project-Page-blue?style=for-the-badge&amp;color=FFE165&amp;logo=homepage&amp;logoColor=white&quot; alt=&quot;Credits&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/metachain-workspace/shared_invite/zt-2zibtmutw-v7xOJObBf9jE2w3x7nctFQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Slack-Join%20Us-red?logo=slack&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Join our Slack community&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/jQJdXyDB&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join%20Us-purple?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Join our Discord community&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent/blob/main/assets/autoagent-wechat.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Wechat-Join%20Us-green?logo=wechat&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Join our Wechat community&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://autoagent-ai.github.io/docs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Documentation-000?logo=googledocs&amp;logoColor=FFE165&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Check out the documentation&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05957&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Paper%20on%20Arxiv-000?logoColor=FFE165&amp;logo=arxiv&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Paper&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://gaia-benchmark-leaderboard.hf.space/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/GAIA%20Benchmark-000?logoColor=FFE165&amp;logo=huggingface&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Evaluation Benchmark Score&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Welcome to AutoAgent! AutoAgent is a **Fully-Automated** and highly **Self-Developing** framework that enables users to create and deploy LLM agents through **Natural Language Alone**. 

## ✨Key Features

* 🏆 Top Performers on the GAIA Benchmark
&lt;/br&gt;AutoAgent has secured top rankings among open-sourced methods, delivering comparable performance to **OpenAI&#039;s Deep Research**.

* 📚 Agentic-RAG with Native Self-Managing Vector Database
&lt;/br&gt;AutoAgent equipped with a native self-managing vector database, outperforms industry-leading solutions like **LangChain**. 

* ✨ Agent and Workflow Create with Ease
&lt;/br&gt;AutoAgent leverages natural language to effortlessly build ready-to-use **tools**, **agents** and **workflows** - no coding required.

* 🌐 Universal LLM Support
&lt;/br&gt;AutoAgent seamlessly integrates with **A Wide Range** of LLMs (e.g., OpenAI, Anthropic, Deepseek, vLLM, Grok, Huggingface ...)

* 🔀 Flexible Interaction 
&lt;/br&gt;Benefit from support for both **function-calling** and **ReAct** interaction modes.

* 🤖 Dynamic, Extensible, Lightweight 
&lt;/br&gt;AutoAgent is your **Personal AI Assistant**, designed to be dynamic, extensible, customized, and lightweight.

🚀 Unlock the Future of LLM Agents. Try 🔥AutoAgent🔥 Now!

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/AutoAgentnew-intro.pdf&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt; --&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/autoagent-intro.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quick Overview of AutoAgent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



## 🔥 News

&lt;div class=&quot;scrollable&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2025, Feb 17]&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;nbsp;🎉🎉We&#039;ve updated and released AutoAgent v0.2.0 (formerly known as MetaChain). Detailed changes include: 1) fix the bug of different LLM providers from issues; 2) add automatic installation of AutoAgent in the container environment according to issues; 3) add more easy-to-use commands for the CLI mode. 4) Rename the project to AutoAgent for better understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2025, Feb 10]&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;nbsp;🎉🎉We&#039;ve released &lt;b&gt;MetaChain!&lt;/b&gt;, including framework, evaluation codes and CLI mode! Check our &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05957&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&#039;table-of-contents&#039;/&gt;

## 📑 Table of Contents

* &lt;a href=&#039;#features&#039;&gt;✨ Features&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#news&#039;&gt;🔥 News&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#how-to-use&#039;&gt;🔍 How to Use AutoAgent&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#user-mode&#039;&gt;1. `user mode` (SOTA 🏆 Open Deep Research)&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#agent-editor&#039;&gt;2. `agent editor` (Agent Creation without Workflow)&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#workflow-editor&#039;&gt;3. `workflow editor` (Agent Creation with Workflow)&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#quick-start&#039;&gt;⚡ Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#installation&#039;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#api-keys-setup&#039;&gt;API Keys Setup&lt;/a&gt;
  * &lt;a href=&#039;#start-with-cli-mode&#039;&gt;Start with CLI Mode&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#todo&#039;&gt;☑️ Todo List&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#reproduce&#039;&gt;🔬 How To Reproduce the Results in the Paper&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#documentation&#039;&gt;📖 Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#community&#039;&gt;🤝 Join the Community&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#acknowledgements&#039;&gt;🙏 Acknowledgements&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#039;#cite&#039;&gt;🌟 Cite&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;span id=&#039;how-to-use&#039;/&gt;

## 🔍 How to Use AutoAgent

&lt;span id=&#039;user-mode&#039;/&gt;

### 1. `user mode` (SOTA 🏆 Open Deep Research)

AutoAgent have an out-of-the-box multi-agent system, which you could choose `user mode` in the start page to use it. This multi-agent system is a general AI assistant, having the same functionality with **OpenAI&#039;s Deep Research** and the comparable performance with it in [GAIA](https://gaia-benchmark-leaderboard.hf.space/) benchmark. 

- 🚀 **High Performance**: Matches Deep Research using Claude 3.5 rather than OpenAI&#039;s o3 model.
- 🔄 **Model Flexibility**: Compatible with any LLM (including Deepseek-R1, Grok, Gemini, etc.)
- 💰 **Cost-Effective**: Open-source alternative to Deep Research&#039;s $200/month subscription
- 🎯 **User-Friendly**: Easy-to-deploy CLI interface for seamless interaction
- 📁 **File Support**: Handles file uploads for enhanced data interaction

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;video width=&quot;80%&quot; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;./assets/video_v1_compressed.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/video&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🎥 Deep Research (aka User Mode)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;span id=&#039;agent-editor&#039;/&gt;

### 2. `agent editor` (Agent Creation without Workflow)

The most distinctive feature of AutoAgent is its natural language customization capability. Unlike other agent frameworks, AutoAgent allows you to create tools, agents, and workflows using natural language alone. Simply choose `agent editor` or `workflow editor` mode to start your journey of building agents through conversations.

You can use `agent editor` as shown in the following figure.

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/1-requirement.png&quot; alt=&quot;requirement&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Input what kind of agent you want to create.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/2-profiling.png&quot; alt=&quot;profiling&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Automated agent profiling.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/3-profiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;profiles&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Output the agent profiles.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/4-tools.png&quot; alt=&quot;tools&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Create the desired tools.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/5-task.png&quot; alt=&quot;task&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Input what do you want to complete with the agent. (Optional)&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/agent_editor/6-output-next.png&quot; alt=&quot;output&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Create the desired agent(s) and go to the next step.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;span id=&#039;workflow-editor&#039;/&gt;

### 3. `workflow editor` (Agent Creation with Workflow)

You can also create the agent workflows using natural language description with the `workflow editor` mode, as shown in the following figure. (Tips: this mode does not support tool creation temporarily.)

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/workflow_editor/1-requirement.png&quot; alt=&quot;requirement&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Input what kind of workflow you want to create.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/workflow_editor/2-profiling.png&quot; alt=&quot;profiling&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Automated workflow profiling.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/workflow_editor/3-profiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;profiles&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Output the workflow profiles.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/workflow_editor/4-task.png&quot; alt=&quot;task&quot; width=&quot;66%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Input what do you want to complete with the workflow. (Optional)&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/workflow_editor/5-output-next.png&quot; alt=&quot;output&quot; width=&quot;66%&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;em&gt;Create the desired workflow(s) and go to the next step.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;span id=&#039;quick-start&#039;/&gt;

## ⚡ Quick Start

&lt;span id=&#039;installation&#039;/&gt;

### Installation

#### AutoAgent Installation

```bash
git clone https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent.git
cd AutoAgent
pip install -e .
```

#### Docker Installation

We use Docker to containerize the agent-interactive environment. So please install [Docker](https://www.docker.com/) first. You don&#039;t need to manually pull the pre-built image, because we have let Auto-Deep-Research **automatically pull the pre-built image based on your architecture of your machine**.

&lt;span id=&#039;api-keys-setup&#039;/&gt;

### API Keys Setup

Create an environment variable file, just like `.env.template`, and set the API keys for the LLMs you want to use. Not every LLM API Key is required, use what you need.

```bash
# Required Github Tokens of your own
GITHUB_AI_TOKEN=

# Optional API Keys
OPENAI_API_KEY=
DEEPSEEK_API_KEY=
ANTHROPIC_API_KEY=
GEMINI_API_KEY=
HUGGINGFACE_API_KEY=
GROQ_API_KEY=
XAI_API_KEY=
```

&lt;span id=&#039;start-with-cli-mode&#039;/&gt;

### Start with CLI Mode

&gt; [🚨 **News**: ] We have updated a more easy-to-use command to start the CLI mode and fix the bug of different LLM providers from issues. You can follow the following steps to start the CLI mode with different LLM providers with much less configuration.

#### Command Options:

You can run `auto main` to start full part of AutoAgent, including `user mode`, `agent editor` and `workflow editor`. Btw, you can also run `auto deep-research` to start more lightweight `user mode`, just like the [Auto-Deep-Research](https://github.com/HKUDS/Auto-Deep-Research) project. Some configuration of this command is shown below. 

- `--container_name`: Name of the Docker container (default: &#039;deepresearch&#039;)
- `--port`: Port for the container (default: 12346)
- `COMPLETION_MODEL`: Specify the LLM model to use, you should follow the name of [Litellm](https://github.com/BerriAI/litellm) to set the model name. (Default: `claude-3-5-sonnet-20241022`)
- `DEBUG`: Enable debug mode for detailed logs (default: False)
- `API_BASE_URL`: The base URL for the LLM provider (default: None)
- `FN_CALL`: Enable function calling (default: None). Most of time, you could ignore this option because we have already set the default value based on the model name.
- `git_clone`: Clone the AutoAgent repository to the local environment (only support with the `auto main` command, default: True)
- `test_pull_name`: The name of the test pull. (only support with the `auto main` command, default: &#039;autoagent_mirror&#039;)

#### More details about `git_clone` and `test_pull_name`] 

In the `agent editor` and `workflow editor` mode, we should clone a mirror of the AutoAgent repository to the local agent-interactive environment and let our **AutoAgent** automatically update the AutoAgent itself, such as creating new tools, agents and workflows. So if you want to use the `agent editor` and `workflow editor` mode, you should set the `git_clone` to True and set the `test_pull_name` to &#039;autoagent_mirror&#039; or other branches.

#### `auto main` with different LLM Providers

Then I will show you how to use the full part of AutoAgent with the `auto main` command and different LLM providers. If you want to use the `auto deep-research` command, you can refer to the [Auto-Deep-Research](https://github.com/HKUDS/Auto-Deep-Research) project for more details.

##### Anthropic

* set the `ANTHROPIC_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
ANTHROPIC_API_KEY=your_anthropic_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
auto main # default model is claude-3-5-sonnet-20241022
```

##### OpenAI

* set the `OPENAI_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=your_openai_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=gpt-4o auto main
```

##### Mistral

* set the `MISTRAL_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
MISTRAL_API_KEY=your_mistral_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=mistral/mistral-large-2407 auto main
```

##### Gemini - Google AI Studio

* set the `GEMINI_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
GEMINI_API_KEY=your_gemini_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=gemini/gemini-2.0-flash auto main
```

##### Huggingface

* set the `HUGGINGFACE_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
HUGGINGFACE_API_KEY=your_huggingface_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=huggingface/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct auto main
```

##### Groq

* set the `GROQ_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
GROQ_API_KEY=your_groq_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=groq/deepseek-r1-distill-llama-70b auto main
```

##### OpenAI-Compatible Endpoints (e.g., Grok)

* set the `OPENAI_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key_for_openai_compatible_endpoints
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=openai/grok-2-latest API_BASE_URL=https://api.x.ai/v1 auto main
```

##### OpenRouter (e.g., DeepSeek-R1)

We recommend using OpenRouter as LLM provider of DeepSeek-R1 temporarily. Because official API of DeepSeek-R1 can not be used efficiently.

* set the `OPENROUTER_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
OPENROUTER_API_KEY=your_openrouter_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=openrouter/deepseek/deepseek-r1 auto main
```

##### DeepSeek

* set the `DEEPSEEK_API_KEY` in the `.env` file.

```bash
DEEPSEEK_API_KEY=your_deepseek_api_key
```

* run the following command to start Auto-Deep-Research.

```bash
COMPLETION_MODEL=deepseek/deepseek-chat auto main
```


After the CLI mode is started, you can see the start page of AutoAgent: 

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/AutoAgentnew-intro.pdf&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt; --&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start Page of AutoAgent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

### Tips

#### Import browser cookies to browser environment

You can import the browser cookies to the browser environment to let the agent better access some specific websites. For more details, please refer to the [cookies](./AutoAgent/environment/cookie_json/README.md) folder.

#### Add your own API keys for third-party Tool Platforms

If you want to create tools from the third-party tool platforms, such as RapidAPI, you should subscribe tools from the platform and add your own API keys by running [process_tool_docs.py](./process_tool_docs.py). 

```bash
python process_tool_docs.py
```

More features coming soon! 🚀 **Web GUI interface** under development.



&lt;span id=&#039;todo&#039;/&gt;

## ☑️ Todo List

AutoAgent is continuously evolving! Here&#039;s what&#039;s coming:

- 📊 **More Benchmarks**: Expanding evaluations to **SWE-bench**, **WebArena**, and more
- 🖥️ **GUI Agent**: Supporting *Computer-Use* agents with GUI interaction
- 🔧 **Tool Platforms**: Integration with more platforms like **Composio**
- 🏗️ **Code Sandboxes**: Supporting additional environments like **E2B**
- 🎨 **Web Interface**: Developing comprehensive GUI for better user experience

Have ideas or suggestions? Feel free to open an issue! Stay tuned for more exciting updates! 🚀

&lt;span id=&#039;reproduce&#039;/&gt;

## 🔬 How To Reproduce the Results in the Paper

### GAIA Benchmark
For the GAIA benchmark, you can run the following command to run the inference.

```bash
cd path/to/AutoAgent &amp;&amp; sh evaluation/gaia/scripts/run_infer.sh
```

For the evaluation, you can run the following command.

```bash
cd path/to/AutoAgent &amp;&amp; python evaluation/gaia/get_score.py
```

### Agentic-RAG

For the Agentic-RAG task, you can run the following command to run the inference.

Step1. Turn to [this page](https://huggingface.co/datasets/yixuantt/MultiHopRAG) and download it. Save them to your datapath.

Step2. Run the following command to run the inference.

```bash
cd path/to/AutoAgent &amp;&amp; sh evaluation/multihoprag/scripts/run_rag.sh
```

Step3. The result will be saved in the `evaluation/multihoprag/result.json`.

&lt;span id=&#039;documentation&#039;/&gt;

## 📖 Documentation

A more detailed documentation is coming soon 🚀, and we will update in the [Documentation](https://AutoAgent-ai.github.io/docs) page.

&lt;span id=&#039;community&#039;/&gt;

## 🤝 Join the Community

We want to build a community for AutoAgent, and we welcome everyone to join us. You can join our community by:

- [Join our Slack workspace](https://join.slack.com/t/AutoAgent-workspace/shared_invite/zt-2zibtmutw-v7xOJObBf9jE2w3x7nctFQ) - Here we talk about research, architecture, and future development.
- [Join our Discord server](https://discord.gg/z68KRvwB) - This is a community-run server for general discussion, questions, and feedback. 
- [Read or post Github Issues](https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent/issues) - Check out the issues we&#039;re working on, or add your own ideas.

&lt;span id=&#039;acknowledgements&#039;/&gt;



## Misc

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Stargazers repo roster for @HKUDS/AutoAgent](https://reporoster.com/stars/HKUDS/AutoAgent)](https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent/stargazers)

[![Forkers repo roster for @HKUDS/AutoAgent](https://reporoster.com/forks/HKUDS/AutoAgent)](https://github.com/HKUDS/AutoAgent/network/members)

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=HKUDS/AutoAgent&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#HKUDS/AutoAgent&amp;Date)

&lt;/div&gt;

## 🙏 Acknowledgements

Rome wasn&#039;t built in a day. AutoAgent stands on the shoulders of giants, and we are deeply grateful for the outstanding work that came before us. Our framework architecture draws inspiration from [OpenAI Swarm](https://github.com/openai/swarm), while our user mode&#039;s three-agent design benefits from [Magentic-one](https://github.com/microsoft/autogen/tree/main/python/packages/autogen-magentic-one)&#039;s insights. We&#039;ve also learned from [OpenHands](https://github.com/All-Hands-AI/OpenHands) for documentation structure and many other excellent projects for agent-environment interaction design, among others. We express our sincere gratitude and respect to all these pioneering works that have been instrumental in shaping AutoAgent.


&lt;span id=&#039;cite&#039;/&gt;

## 🌟 Cite

```tex
@misc{AutoAgent,
      title={{AutoAgent: A Fully-Automated and Zero-Code Framework for LLM Agents}},
      author={Jiabin Tang, Tianyu Fan, Chao Huang},
      year={2025},
      eprint={202502.05957},
      archivePrefix={arXiv},
      primaryClass={cs.AI},
      url={https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05957},
}
```





</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ucbepic/docetl]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ucbepic/docetl</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ucbepic/docetl</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:04:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A system for agentic LLM-powered data processing and ETL]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ucbepic/docetl">ucbepic/docetl</a></h1>
            <p>A system for agentic LLM-powered data processing and ETL</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,096</p>
            <p>Forks: 203</p>
            <p>Stars today: 20 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># 📜 DocETL: Powering Complex Document Processing Pipelines

[![Website](https://img.shields.io/badge/Website-docetl.org-blue)](https://docetl.org)
[![Documentation](https://img.shields.io/badge/Documentation-docs-green)](https://ucbepic.github.io/docetl)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/1285485891095236608?label=Discord&amp;logo=discord)](https://discord.gg/fHp7B2X3xx)
[![Paper](https://img.shields.io/badge/Paper-arXiv-red)](https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.12189)

![DocETL Figure](docs/assets/readmefig.png)

DocETL is a tool for creating and executing data processing pipelines, especially suited for complex document processing tasks. It offers:

1. An interactive UI playground for iterative prompt engineering and pipeline development
2. A Python package for running production pipelines from the command line or Python code

&gt; 💡 **Need Help Writing Your Pipeline?**  
&gt; Want to use an LLM like ChatGPT or Claude to help you write your pipeline? See [docetl.org/llms.txt](https://docetl.org/llms.txt) for a big prompt you can copy paste into ChatGPT or Claude, before describing your task.


### 🌟 Community Projects

- [Conversation Generator](https://github.com/PassionFruits-net/docetl-conversation)
- [Text-to-speech](https://github.com/PassionFruits-net/docetl-speaker)
- [YouTube Transcript Topic Extraction](https://github.com/rajib76/docetl_examples)

### 📚 Educational Resources

- [UI/UX Thoughts](https://x.com/sh_reya/status/1846235904664273201)
- [Using Gleaning to Improve Output Quality](https://x.com/sh_reya/status/1843354256335876262)
- [Deep Dive on Resolve Operator](https://x.com/sh_reya/status/1840796824636121288)


## 🚀 Getting Started

There are two main ways to use DocETL:

### 1. 🎮 DocWrangler, the Interactive UI Playground (Recommended for Development)

[DocWrangler](https://docetl.org/playground) helps you iteratively develop your pipeline:
- Experiment with different prompts and see results in real-time
- Build your pipeline step by step
- Export your finalized pipeline configuration for production use

![DocWrangler](docs/assets/tutorial/one-operation.png)

DocWrangler is hosted at [docetl.org/playground](https://docetl.org/playground). But to run the playground locally, you can either:
- Use Docker (recommended for quick start): `make docker`
- Set up the development environment manually

See the [Playground Setup Guide](https://ucbepic.github.io/docetl/playground/) for detailed instructions.

### 2. 📦 Python Package (For Production Use)

If you want to use DocETL as a Python package:

#### Prerequisites
- Python 3.10 or later
- OpenAI API key

```bash
pip install docetl
```

Create a `.env` file in your project directory:
```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key_here  # Required for LLM operations (or the key for the LLM of your choice)
```

To see examples of how to use DocETL, check out the [tutorial](https://ucbepic.github.io/docetl/tutorial/).

### 2. 🎮 DocWrangler Setup

To run DocWrangler locally, you have two options:

#### Option A: Using Docker (Recommended for Quick Start)

The easiest way to get the DocWrangler playground running:

1. Create the required environment files:

Create `.env` in the root directory:
```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key_here
# BACKEND configuration
BACKEND_ALLOW_ORIGINS=http://localhost:3000,http://127.0.0.1:3000
BACKEND_HOST=localhost
BACKEND_PORT=8000
BACKEND_RELOAD=True

# FRONTEND configuration
FRONTEND_HOST=0.0.0.0
FRONTEND_PORT=3000

# Host port mapping for docker-compose (if not set, defaults are used in docker-compose.yml)
FRONTEND_DOCKER_COMPOSE_PORT=3031
BACKEND_DOCKER_COMPOSE_PORT=8081

# Supported text file encodings
TEXT_FILE_ENCODINGS=utf-8,latin1,cp1252,iso-8859-1
```

Create `.env.local` in the `website` directory:
```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=sk-xxx
OPENAI_API_BASE=https://api.openai.com/v1
MODEL_NAME=gpt-4o-mini

NEXT_PUBLIC_BACKEND_HOST=localhost
NEXT_PUBLIC_BACKEND_PORT=8000
NEXT_PUBLIC_HOSTED_DOCWRANGLER=false
```

2. Run Docker:
```bash
make docker
```

This will:
- Create a Docker volume for persistent data
- Build the DocETL image
- Run the container with the UI accessible at http://localhost:3000

To clean up Docker resources (note that this will delete the Docker volume):
```bash
make docker-clean
```

##### AWS Bedrock

This framework supports integration with AWS Bedrock. To enable:

1. Configure AWS credentials:
```bash
aws configure
```

2. Test your AWS credentials:
```bash
make test-aws
```

3. Run with AWS support:
```bash
AWS_PROFILE=your-profile AWS_REGION=your-region make docker
```

Or using Docker Compose:
```bash
AWS_PROFILE=your-profile AWS_REGION=your-region docker compose --profile aws up
```

Environment variables:
- `AWS_PROFILE`: Your AWS CLI profile (default: &#039;default&#039;)
- `AWS_REGION`: AWS region (default: &#039;us-west-2&#039;)

Bedrock models are pefixed with `bedrock`. See liteLLM [docs](https://docs.litellm.ai/docs/providers/bedrock#supported-aws-bedrock-models) for more details.

#### Option B: Manual Setup (Development)

For development or if you prefer not to use Docker:

1. Clone the repository:
```bash
git clone https://github.com/ucbepic/docetl.git
cd docetl
```

2. Set up environment variables in `.env` in the root/top-level directory:
```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key_here
# BACKEND configuration
BACKEND_ALLOW_ORIGINS=http://localhost:3000,http://127.0.0.1:3000
BACKEND_HOST=localhost
BACKEND_PORT=8000
BACKEND_RELOAD=True

# FRONTEND configuration
FRONTEND_HOST=0.0.0.0
FRONTEND_PORT=3000

# Host port mapping for docker-compose (if not set, defaults are used in docker-compose.yml)
FRONTEND_DOCKER_COMPOSE_PORT=3031
BACKEND_DOCKER_COMPOSE_PORT=8081

# Supported text file encodings
TEXT_FILE_ENCODINGS=utf-8,latin1,cp1252,iso-8859-1
```

And create an .env.local file in the `website` directory with the following:
```bash
OPENAI_API_KEY=sk-xxx
OPENAI_API_BASE=https://api.openai.com/v1
MODEL_NAME=gpt-4o-mini

NEXT_PUBLIC_BACKEND_HOST=localhost
NEXT_PUBLIC_BACKEND_PORT=8000
NEXT_PUBLIC_HOSTED_DOCWRANGLER=false
```

3. Install dependencies:
```bash
make install      # Install Python package
make install-ui   # Install UI dependencies
```

Note that the OpenAI API key, base, and model name are for the UI assistant only; not the DocETL pipeline execution engine.

4. Start the development server:
```bash
make run-ui-dev
```

5. Visit http://localhost:3000/playground to access the interactive UI.

### 🛠️ Development Setup

If you&#039;re planning to contribute or modify DocETL, you can verify your setup by running the test suite:

```bash
make tests-basic  # Runs basic test suite (costs &lt; $0.01 with OpenAI)
```

For detailed documentation and tutorials, visit our [documentation](https://ucbepic.github.io/docetl).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>