<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for python - Python Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for python.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2026, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[huggingface/skills]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/huggingface/skills</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/huggingface/skills</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/skills">huggingface/skills</a></h1>
            <p></p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,234</p>
            <p>Forks: 335</p>
            <p>Stars today: 1,206 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Hugging Face Skills

Hugging Face Skills are definitions for AI/ML tasks like dataset creation, model training, and evaluation. They are interoperable with all major coding agent tools like OpenAI Codex, Anthropic&#039;s Claude Code, Google DeepMind&#039;s Gemini CLI, and Cursor.

The Skills in this repository follow the standardized format [Agent Skill](https://agentskills.io/home) format.

## How do Skills work?

In practice, skills are self-contained folders that package instructions, scripts, and resources together for an AI agent to use on a specific use case. Each folder includes a `SKILL.md` file with YAML frontmatter (name and description) followed by the guidance your coding agent follows while the skill is active. 

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; &#039;Skills&#039; is actually an Anthropic term used within Claude AI and Claude Code and not adopted by other agent tools, but we love it! OpenAI Codex uses an `AGENTS.md` file to define the instructions for your coding agent. Google Gemini uses &#039;extensions&#039; to define the instructions for your coding agent in a `gemini-extension.json` file. **This repo is compatible with all of them, and more!**

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; If your agent doesn&#039;t support skills, you can use [`agents/AGENTS.md`](agents/AGENTS.md) directly as a fallback.

## Installation

Hugging Face skills are compatible with Claude Code, Codex, Gemini CLI, and Cursor.

### Claude Code

1. Register the repository as a plugin marketplace:  
   
```
/plugin marketplace add huggingface/skills
```

2. To install a skill, run:  
   
```
/plugin install &lt;skill-name&gt;@huggingface/skills
```

For example:  

```
/plugin install hugging-face-cli@huggingface/skills
```

### Codex

1. Codex will identify the skills via the `AGENTS.md` file. You can verify the instructions are loaded with:

```
codex --ask-for-approval never &quot;Summarize the current instructions.&quot;
```

2. For more details, see the [Codex AGENTS guide](https://developers.openai.com/codex/guides/agents-md).

### Gemini CLI

1. This repo includes `gemini-extension.json` to integrate with the Gemini CLI.

2. Install locally:  

```
gemini extensions install . --consent
```

or use the GitHub URL:

```
gemini extensions install https://github.com/huggingface/skills.git --consent
```

4. See [Gemini CLI extensions docs](https://geminicli.com/docs/extensions/#installing-an-extension) for more help.

### Cursor

This repository includes Cursor plugin manifests:

- `.cursor-plugin/plugin.json`
- `.mcp.json` (configured with the Hugging Face MCP server URL)

Install from repository URL (or local checkout) via the Cursor plugin flow.

For contributors, regenerate manifests with:

```bash
./scripts/publish.sh
```

## Skills

This repository contains a few skills to get you started. You can also contribute your own skills to the repository.

### Available skills

&lt;!-- This table is auto-generated by scripts/generate_agents.py. Do not edit manually. --&gt;
&lt;!-- BEGIN_SKILLS_TABLE --&gt;
| Name | Description | Documentation |
|------|-------------|---------------|
| `hugging-face-cli` | Execute Hugging Face Hub operations using the hf CLI. Download models/datasets, upload files, manage repos, and run cloud compute jobs. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-cli/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-datasets` | Create and manage datasets on Hugging Face Hub. Supports initializing repos, defining configs/system prompts, streaming row updates, and SQL-based dataset querying/transformation. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-datasets/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-evaluation` | Add and manage evaluation results in Hugging Face model cards. Supports extracting eval tables from README content, importing scores from Artificial Analysis API, and running custom evaluations with vLLM/lighteval. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-evaluation/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-jobs` | Run compute jobs on Hugging Face infrastructure. Execute Python scripts, manage scheduled jobs, and monitor job status. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-jobs/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-model-trainer` | Train or fine-tune language models using TRL on Hugging Face Jobs infrastructure. Covers SFT, DPO, GRPO and reward modeling training methods, plus GGUF conversion for local deployment. Includes hardware selection, cost estimation, Trackio monitoring, and Hub persistence. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-model-trainer/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-paper-publisher` | Publish and manage research papers on Hugging Face Hub. Supports creating paper pages, linking papers to models/datasets, claiming authorship, and generating professional markdown-based research articles. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-paper-publisher/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-tool-builder` | Build reusable scripts for Hugging Face API operations. Useful for chaining API calls or automating repeated tasks. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-tool-builder/SKILL.md) |
| `hugging-face-trackio` | Track and visualize ML training experiments with Trackio. Log metrics via Python API and retrieve them via CLI. Supports real-time dashboards synced to HF Spaces. | [SKILL.md](skills/hugging-face-trackio/SKILL.md) |
&lt;!-- END_SKILLS_TABLE --&gt;

### Using skills in your coding agent

Once a skill is installed, mention it directly while giving your coding agent instructions:

- &quot;Use the HF LLM trainer skill to estimate the GPU memory needed for a 70B model run.&quot;
- &quot;Use the HF model evaluation skill to launch `run_eval_job.py` on the latest checkpoint.&quot;
- &quot;Use the HF dataset creator skill to draft new few-shot classification templates.&quot;
- &quot;Use the HF paper publisher skill to index my arXiv paper and link it to my model.&quot;

Your coding agent automatically loads the corresponding `SKILL.md` instructions and helper scripts while it completes the task.

### Contribute or customize a skill

1. Copy one of the existing skill folders (for example, `hf-datasets/`) and rename it.
2. Update the new folder&#039;s `SKILL.md` frontmatter:
   ```markdown
   ---
   name: my-skill-name
   description: Describe what the skill does and when to use it
   ---

   # Skill Title
   Guidance + examples + guardrails
   ```
3. Add or edit supporting scripts, templates, and documents referenced by your instructions.
4. Add an entry to `.claude-plugin/marketplace.json` with a concise, human-readable description.
5. Run:
   ```bash
   ./scripts/publish.sh
   ```
   to regenerate and validate all generated metadata.
6. Reinstall or reload the skill bundle in your coding agent so the updated folder is available.

### Marketplace

The `.claude-plugin/marketplace.json` file lists skills with human-readable descriptions for the plugin marketplace. The CI validates that skill names and paths match between `SKILL.md` files and `marketplace.json`, but descriptions are maintained separately: `SKILL.md` descriptions guide when Claude activates the skill, while marketplace descriptions are written for humans browsing available skills.

### Additional references
- Browse the latest instructions, scripts, and templates directly at [huggingface/skills](https://github.com/huggingface/skills).
- Review Hugging Face documentation for the specific libraries or workflows you reference inside each skill.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A comprehensive collection of Agent Skills for context engineering, multi-agent architectures, and production agent systems. Use when building, optimizing, or debugging agent systems that require effective context management.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering">muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering</a></h1>
            <p>A comprehensive collection of Agent Skills for context engineering, multi-agent architectures, and production agent systems. Use when building, optimizing, or debugging agent systems that require effective context management.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,851</p>
            <p>Forks: 780</p>
            <p>Stars today: 722 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Agent Skills for Context Engineering

A comprehensive, open collection of Agent Skills focused on context engineering principles for building production-grade AI agent systems. These skills teach the art and science of curating context to maximize agent effectiveness across any agent platform.

## What is Context Engineering?

Context engineering is the discipline of managing the language model&#039;s context window. Unlike prompt engineering, which focuses on crafting effective instructions, context engineering addresses the holistic curation of all information that enters the model&#039;s limited attention budget: system prompts, tool definitions, retrieved documents, message history, and tool outputs.

The fundamental challenge is that context windows are constrained not by raw token capacity but by attention mechanics. As context length increases, models exhibit predictable degradation patterns: the &quot;lost-in-the-middle&quot; phenomenon, U-shaped attention curves, and attention scarcity. Effective context engineering means finding the smallest possible set of high-signal tokens that maximize the likelihood of desired outcomes.

## Recognition

This repository is cited in academic research as foundational work on static skill architecture:

&gt; &quot;While static skills are well-recognized [Anthropic, 2025b; Muratcan Koylan, 2025], MCE is among the first to dynamically evolve them, bridging manual skill engineering and autonomous self-improvement.&quot;

— [Meta Context Engineering via Agentic Skill Evolution](https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.21557), Peking University State Key Laboratory of General Artificial Intelligence (2026)

## Skills Overview

### Foundational Skills

These skills establish the foundational understanding required for all subsequent context engineering work.

| Skill | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [context-fundamentals](skills/context-fundamentals/) | Understand what context is, why it matters, and the anatomy of context in agent systems |
| [context-degradation](skills/context-degradation/) | Recognize patterns of context failure: lost-in-middle, poisoning, distraction, and clash |
| [context-compression](skills/context-compression/) | Design and evaluate compression strategies for long-running sessions |

### Architectural Skills

These skills cover the patterns and structures for building effective agent systems.

| Skill | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [multi-agent-patterns](skills/multi-agent-patterns/) | Master orchestrator, peer-to-peer, and hierarchical multi-agent architectures |
| [memory-systems](skills/memory-systems/) | Design short-term, long-term, and graph-based memory architectures |
| [tool-design](skills/tool-design/) | Build tools that agents can use effectively |
| [filesystem-context](skills/filesystem-context/) | Use filesystems for dynamic context discovery, tool output offloading, and plan persistence |
| [hosted-agents](skills/hosted-agents/) | **NEW** Build background coding agents with sandboxed VMs, pre-built images, multiplayer support, and multi-client interfaces |

### Operational Skills

These skills address the ongoing operation and optimization of agent systems.

| Skill | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [context-optimization](skills/context-optimization/) | Apply compaction, masking, and caching strategies |
| [evaluation](skills/evaluation/) | Build evaluation frameworks for agent systems |
| [advanced-evaluation](skills/advanced-evaluation/) | Master LLM-as-a-Judge techniques: direct scoring, pairwise comparison, rubric generation, and bias mitigation |

### Development Methodology

These skills cover the meta-level practices for building LLM-powered projects.

| Skill | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [project-development](skills/project-development/) | Design and build LLM projects from ideation through deployment, including task-model fit analysis, pipeline architecture, and structured output design |

### Cognitive Architecture Skills

These skills cover formal cognitive modeling for rational agent systems.

| Skill | Description |
|-------|-------------|
| [bdi-mental-states](skills/bdi-mental-states/) | **NEW** Transform external RDF context into agent mental states (beliefs, desires, intentions) using formal BDI ontology patterns for deliberative reasoning and explainability |

## Design Philosophy

### Progressive Disclosure

Each skill is structured for efficient context use. At startup, agents load only skill names and descriptions. Full content loads only when a skill is activated for relevant tasks.

### Platform Agnosticism

These skills focus on transferable principles rather than vendor-specific implementations. The patterns work across Claude Code, Cursor, and any agent platform that supports skills or allows custom instructions.

### Conceptual Foundation with Practical Examples

Scripts and examples demonstrate concepts using Python pseudocode that works across environments without requiring specific dependency installations.

## Usage

### Usage with Claude Code

This repository is a **Claude Code Plugin Marketplace** containing context engineering skills that Claude automatically discovers and activates based on your task context.

### Installation

**Step 1: Add the Marketplace**

Run this command in Claude Code to register this repository as a plugin source:

```
/plugin marketplace add muratcankoylan/Agent-Skills-for-Context-Engineering
```

**Step 2: Browse and Install**

Option A - Browse available plugins:
1. Select `Browse and install plugins`
2. Select `context-engineering-marketplace`
3. Choose a plugin (e.g., `context-engineering-fundamentals`, `agent-architecture`)
4. Select `Install now`

Option B - Direct install via command:

```
/plugin install context-engineering-fundamentals@context-engineering-marketplace
/plugin install agent-architecture@context-engineering-marketplace
/plugin install agent-evaluation@context-engineering-marketplace
/plugin install agent-development@context-engineering-marketplace
/plugin install cognitive-architecture@context-engineering-marketplace
```

### Available Plugins

| Plugin | Skills Included |
|--------|-----------------|
| `context-engineering-fundamentals` | context-fundamentals, context-degradation, context-compression, context-optimization |
| `agent-architecture` | multi-agent-patterns, memory-systems, tool-design, filesystem-context, hosted-agents |
| `agent-evaluation` | evaluation, advanced-evaluation |
| `agent-development` | project-development |
| `cognitive-architecture` | bdi-mental-states |

### Skill Triggers

| Skill | Triggers On |
|-------|-------------|
| `context-fundamentals` | &quot;understand context&quot;, &quot;explain context windows&quot;, &quot;design agent architecture&quot; |
| `context-degradation` | &quot;diagnose context problems&quot;, &quot;fix lost-in-middle&quot;, &quot;debug agent failures&quot; |
| `context-compression` | &quot;compress context&quot;, &quot;summarize conversation&quot;, &quot;reduce token usage&quot; |
| `context-optimization` | &quot;optimize context&quot;, &quot;reduce token costs&quot;, &quot;implement KV-cache&quot; |
| `multi-agent-patterns` | &quot;design multi-agent system&quot;, &quot;implement supervisor pattern&quot; |
| `memory-systems` | &quot;implement agent memory&quot;, &quot;build knowledge graph&quot;, &quot;track entities&quot; |
| `tool-design` | &quot;design agent tools&quot;, &quot;reduce tool complexity&quot;, &quot;implement MCP tools&quot; |
| `filesystem-context` | &quot;offload context to files&quot;, &quot;dynamic context discovery&quot;, &quot;agent scratch pad&quot;, &quot;file-based context&quot; |
| `hosted-agents` | &quot;build background agent&quot;, &quot;create hosted coding agent&quot;, &quot;sandboxed execution&quot;, &quot;multiplayer agent&quot;, &quot;Modal sandboxes&quot; |
| `evaluation` | &quot;evaluate agent performance&quot;, &quot;build test framework&quot;, &quot;measure quality&quot; |
| `advanced-evaluation` | &quot;implement LLM-as-judge&quot;, &quot;compare model outputs&quot;, &quot;mitigate bias&quot; |
| `project-development` | &quot;start LLM project&quot;, &quot;design batch pipeline&quot;, &quot;evaluate task-model fit&quot; |
| `bdi-mental-states` | &quot;model agent mental states&quot;, &quot;implement BDI architecture&quot;, &quot;transform RDF to beliefs&quot;, &quot;build cognitive agent&quot; |

&lt;img width=&quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;894&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2025-12-26 at 12 34 47 PM&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f79aaf03-fd2d-4c71-a630-7027adeb9bfe&quot; /&gt;

### For Cursor &amp; Codex &amp; IDE

Copy skill content into `.rules` or create project-specific Skills folders. The skills provide the context and guidelines that agent needs for effective context engineering and agent design.

### For Custom Implementations

Extract the principles and patterns from any skill and implement them in your agent framework. The skills are deliberately platform-agnostic.

## Examples

The [examples](examples/) folder contains complete system designs that demonstrate how multiple skills work together in practice.

| Example | Description | Skills Applied |
|---------|-------------|----------------|
| [digital-brain-skill](examples/digital-brain-skill/) | **NEW** Personal operating system for founders and creators. Complete Claude Code skill with 6 modules, 4 automation scripts | context-fundamentals, context-optimization, memory-systems, tool-design, multi-agent-patterns, evaluation, project-development |
| [x-to-book-system](examples/x-to-book-system/) | Multi-agent system that monitors X accounts and generates daily synthesized books | multi-agent-patterns, memory-systems, context-optimization, tool-design, evaluation |
| [llm-as-judge-skills](examples/llm-as-judge-skills/) | Production-ready LLM evaluation tools with TypeScript implementation, 19 passing tests | advanced-evaluation, tool-design, context-fundamentals, evaluation |
| [book-sft-pipeline](examples/book-sft-pipeline/) | Train models to write in any author&#039;s style. Includes Gertrude Stein case study with 70% human score on Pangram, $2 total cost | project-development, context-compression, multi-agent-patterns, evaluation |

Each example includes:
- Complete PRD with architecture decisions
- Skills mapping showing which concepts informed each decision
- Implementation guidance

### Digital Brain Skill Example

The [digital-brain-skill](examples/digital-brain-skill/) example is a complete personal operating system demonstrating comprehensive skills application:

- **Progressive Disclosure**: 3-level loading (SKILL.md → MODULE.md → data files)
- **Module Isolation**: 6 independent modules (identity, content, knowledge, network, operations, agents)
- **Append-Only Memory**: JSONL files with schema-first lines for agent-friendly parsing
- **Automation Scripts**: 4 consolidated tools (weekly_review, content_ideas, stale_contacts, idea_to_draft)

Includes detailed traceability in [HOW-SKILLS-BUILT-THIS.md](examples/digital-brain-skill/HOW-SKILLS-BUILT-THIS.md) mapping every architectural decision to specific skill principles.

### LLM-as-Judge Skills Example

The [llm-as-judge-skills](examples/llm-as-judge-skills/) example is a complete TypeScript implementation demonstrating:

- **Direct Scoring**: Evaluate responses against weighted criteria with rubric support
- **Pairwise Comparison**: Compare responses with position bias mitigation
- **Rubric Generation**: Create domain-specific evaluation standards
- **EvaluatorAgent**: High-level agent combining all evaluation capabilities

### Book SFT Pipeline Example

The [book-sft-pipeline](examples/book-sft-pipeline/) example demonstrates training small models (8B) to write in any author&#039;s style:

- **Intelligent Segmentation**: Two-tier chunking with overlap for maximum training examples
- **Prompt Diversity**: 15+ templates to prevent memorization and force style learning
- **Tinker Integration**: Complete LoRA training workflow with $2 total cost
- **Validation Methodology**: Modern scenario testing proves style transfer vs content memorization

Integrates with context engineering skills: project-development, context-compression, multi-agent-patterns, evaluation.

## Star History
&lt;img width=&quot;3664&quot; height=&quot;2648&quot; alt=&quot;star-history-2026224&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b3bdbf23-4b6a-4774-ae85-42ef4d9b2d79&quot; /&gt;

## Structure

Each skill follows the Agent Skills specification:

```
skill-name/
├── SKILL.md              # Required: instructions + metadata
├── scripts/              # Optional: executable code demonstrating concepts
└── references/           # Optional: additional documentation and resources
```

See the [template](template/) folder for the canonical skill structure.

## Contributing

This repository follows the Agent Skills open development model. Contributions are welcome from the broader ecosystem. When contributing:

1. Follow the skill template structure
2. Provide clear, actionable instructions
3. Include working examples where appropriate
4. Document trade-offs and potential issues
5. Keep SKILL.md under 500 lines for optimal performance

Feel free to contact [Muratcan Koylan](https://x.com/koylanai) for collaboration opportunities or any inquiries.

## License

MIT License - see LICENSE file for details.

## References

The principles in these skills are derived from research and production experience at leading AI labs and framework developers. Each skill includes references to the underlying research and case studies that inform its recommendations.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenBB-finance/OpenBB]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Financial data platform for analysts, quants and AI agents.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB">OpenBB-finance/OpenBB</a></h1>
            <p>Financial data platform for analysts, quants and AI agents.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 61,859</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,027</p>
            <p>Stars today: 504 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/blob/develop/images/odp-light.svg?raw=true#gh-light-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Open Data Platform by OpenBB logo&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/blob/develop/images/odp-dark.svg?raw=true#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Open Data Platform by OpenBB logo&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/url/https/twitter.com/openbb_finance.svg?style=social&amp;label=Follow%20%40openbb_finance)](https://x.com/openbb_finance)
[![Discord Shield](https://img.shields.io/discord/831165782750789672)](https://discord.com/invite/xPHTuHCmuV)
[![Open in Dev Containers](https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=Dev%20Containers&amp;message=Open&amp;color=blue&amp;logo=visualstudiocode)](https://vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode://ms-vscode-remote.remote-containers/cloneInVolume?url=https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://codespaces.new/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/codespaces/badge.svg&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/blob/develop/examples/googleColab.ipynb&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Open In Colab&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
[![PyPI](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/openbb?color=blue&amp;label=PyPI%20Package)](https://pypi.org/project/openbb/)

Open Data Platform by OpenBB (ODP) is the open-source toolset that helps data engineers integrate proprietary, licensed, and public data sources into downstream applications like AI copilots and research dashboards.

ODP operates as the &quot;connect once, consume everywhere&quot; infrastructure layer that consolidates and exposes data to multiple surfaces at once: Python environments for quants, OpenBB Workspace and Excel for analysts, MCP servers for AI agents, and REST APIs for other applications.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://pro.openbb.co&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://openbb-cms.directus.app/assets/70b971ef-7a7e-486e-b5ae-1cc602f2162c.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Get started with: `pip install openbb`

```python
from openbb import obb
output = obb.equity.price.historical(&quot;AAPL&quot;)
df = output.to_dataframe()
```

Data integrations available can be found here: &lt;https://docs.openbb.co/python/reference&gt;

---

## OpenBB Workspace

While the Open Data Platform provides the open-source data integration foundation, **OpenBB Workspace** offers the enterprise UI for analysts to visualize datasets and leverage AI agents. The platform&#039;s &quot;connect once, consume everywhere&quot; architecture enables seamless integration between the two.

You can find OpenBB Workspace at &lt;https://pro.openbb.co&gt;.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pro.openbb.co&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://openbb-cms.directus.app/assets/f69b6aaf-0821-4bc8-a43c-715e03a924ef.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Data integration:

- You can learn more about adding data to the OpenBB workspace from the [docs](https://docs.openbb.co/workspace) or [this open source repository](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/backends-for-openbb).

AI Agents integration:

- You can learn more about adding AI agents to the OpenBB workspace from [this open source repository](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/agents-for-openbb).

### Integrating Open Data Platform to the OpenBB Workspace

Connect this library to the OpenBB Workspace with a few simple commands, in a Python (3.9.21 - 3.12) environment.

#### Run an ODP backend

- Install the packages.

```sh
pip install &quot;openbb[all]&quot;
```

- Start the API server over localhost.

```sh
openbb-api
```

This will launch a FastAPI server, via Uvicorn, at `127.0.0.1:6900`.

You can check that it works by going to &lt;http://127.0.0.1:6900&gt;.

#### Integrate the ODP Backend to OpenBB Workspace

Sign-in to the [OpenBB Workspace](https://pro.openbb.co/), and follow the following steps:

![CleanShot 2025-05-17 at 09 51 56@2x](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/75cffb4a-5e95-470a-b9d0-6ffd4067e069)

1. Go to the &quot;Apps&quot; tab
2. Click on &quot;Connect backend&quot;
3. Fill in the form with:
   Name: Open Data Platform
   URL: &lt;http://127.0.0.1:6900&gt;
4. Click on &quot;Test&quot;. You should get a &quot;Test successful&quot; with the number of apps found.
5. Click on &quot;Add&quot;.

That&#039;s it.

---

&lt;!-- TABLE OF CONTENTS --&gt;
&lt;details closed=&quot;closed&quot;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;&lt;h2 style=&quot;display: inline-block&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-contributing&quot;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4-disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5-contacts&quot;&gt;Contacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#6-star-history&quot;&gt;Star History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#7-contributors&quot;&gt;Contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

## 1. Installation

The ODP Python Package can be installed from [PyPI package](https://pypi.org/project/openbb/) by running `pip install openbb`

or by cloning the repository directly with `git clone https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.git`.

Please find more about the installation process, in the [OpenBB Documentation](https://docs.openbb.co/python/installation).

### ODP CLI installation

The ODP CLI is a command-line interface that allows you to access the ODP directly from your command line.

It can be installed by running `pip install openbb-cli`

or by cloning the repository directly with  `git clone https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.git`.

Please find more about the installation process in the [OpenBB Documentation](https://docs.openbb.co/cli/installation).

## 2. Contributing

There are three main ways of contributing to this project. (Hopefully you have starred the project by now ⭐️)

### Become a Contributor

- More information on our [Developer Documentation](https://docs.openbb.co/python/developer).

### Create a GitHub ticket

Before creating a ticket make sure the one you are creating doesn&#039;t exist already [among the existing issues](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues)

- [Report bug](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues/new?assignees=&amp;labels=bug&amp;template=bug_report.md&amp;title=%5BBug%5D)
- [Suggest improvement](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues/new?assignees=&amp;labels=enhancement&amp;template=enhancement.md&amp;title=%5BIMPROVE%5D)
- [Request a feature](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues/new?assignees=&amp;labels=new+feature&amp;template=feature_request.md&amp;title=%5BFR%5D)

### Provide feedback

We are most active on [our Discord](https://openbb.co/discord), but feel free to reach out to us in any of [our social media](https://openbb.co/links) for feedback.

## 3. License

Distributed under the AGPLv3 License. See
[LICENSE](https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/blob/main/LICENSE) for more information.

## 4. Disclaimer

Trading in financial instruments involves high risks including the risk of losing some, or all, of your investment
amount, and may not be suitable for all investors.

Before deciding to trade in a financial instrument you should be fully informed of the risks and costs associated with trading the financial markets, carefully consider your investment objectives, level of experience, and risk appetite, and seek professional advice where needed.

The data contained in the Open Data Platform is not necessarily accurate.

OpenBB and any provider of the data contained in this website will not accept liability for any loss or damage as a result of your trading, or your reliance on the information displayed.

All names, logos, and brands of third parties that may be referenced in our sites, products or documentation are trademarks of their respective owners. Unless otherwise specified, OpenBB and its products and services are not endorsed by, sponsored by, or affiliated with these third parties.

Our use of these names, logos, and brands is for identification purposes only, and does not imply any such endorsement, sponsorship, or affiliation.

## 5. Contacts

If you have any questions about the platform or anything OpenBB, feel free to email us at `support@openbb.co`

If you want to say hi, or are interested in partnering with us, feel free to reach us at `hello@openbb.co`

Any of our social media platforms: [openbb.co/links](https://openbb.co/links)

## 6. Star History

This is a proxy of our growth and that we are just getting started.

But for more metrics important to us check [openbb.co/open](https://openbb.co/open).

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=openbb-finance/OpenBB&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark)](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=openbb-finance/OpenBB&amp;type=Date&amp;theme=dark)

## 7. Contributors

OpenBB wouldn&#039;t be OpenBB without you. If we are going to disrupt financial industry, every contribution counts. Thank you for being part of this journey.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=OpenBB-finance/OpenBB&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;!-- MARKDOWN LINKS &amp; IMAGES --&gt;
&lt;!-- https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax/#reference-style-links --&gt;

[contributors-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.svg?style=for-the-badge
[contributors-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/graphs/contributors
[forks-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/forks/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.svg?style=for-the-badge
[forks-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/network/members
[stars-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/stars/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.svg?style=for-the-badge
[stars-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/stargazers
[issues-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/issues/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;color=blue
[issues-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues
[bugs-open-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/issues/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/bug.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;color=yellow
[bugs-open-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues?q=is%3Aissue+label%3Abug+is%3Aopen
[bugs-closed-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/issues-closed/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/bug.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;color=success
[bugs-closed-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/issues?q=is%3Aissue+label%3Abug+is%3Aclosed
[license-shield]: https://img.shields.io/github/license/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB.svg?style=for-the-badge
[license-url]: https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBB/blob/main/LICENSE.txt
[linkedin-shield]: https://img.shields.io/badge/-LinkedIn-black.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=linkedin&amp;colorB=555
[linkedin-url]: https://linkedin.com/in/DidierRLopes
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D4Vinci/Scrapling]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🕷️ An adaptive Web Scraping framework that handles everything from a single request to a full-scale crawl!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling">D4Vinci/Scrapling</a></h1>
            <p>🕷️ An adaptive Web Scraping framework that handles everything from a single request to a full-scale crawl!</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 12,541</p>
            <p>Forks: 846</p>
            <p>Stars today: 1,970 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!-- mcp-name: io.github.D4Vinci/Scrapling --&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/docs/assets/cover_dark.svg?sanitize=true&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img alt=&quot;Scrapling Poster&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/docs/assets/cover_light.svg?sanitize=true&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;Effortless Web Scraping for the Modern Web&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/14244&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/14244&quot; alt=&quot;D4Vinci%2FScrapling | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_AR.md&quot;&gt;العربيه&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_ES.md&quot;&gt;Español&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_DE.md&quot;&gt;Deutsch&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_CN.md&quot;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_JP.md&quot;&gt;日本語&lt;/a&gt; |  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/blob/main/docs/README_RU.md&quot;&gt;Русский&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/actions/workflows/tests.yml&quot; alt=&quot;Tests&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Tests&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/actions/workflows/tests.yml/badge.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/py/Scrapling&quot; alt=&quot;PyPI version&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;PyPI version&quot; src=&quot;https://badge.fury.io/py/Scrapling.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pepy.tech/project/scrapling&quot; alt=&quot;PyPI Downloads&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;PyPI Downloads&quot; src=&quot;https://static.pepy.tech/personalized-badge/scrapling?period=total&amp;units=INTERNATIONAL_SYSTEM&amp;left_color=GREY&amp;right_color=GREEN&amp;left_text=Downloads&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/EMgGbDceNQ&quot; alt=&quot;Discord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img alt=&quot;Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/1360786381042880532?style=social&amp;logo=discord&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fdiscord.gg%2FEMgGbDceNQ&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Scrapling_dev&quot; alt=&quot;X (formerly Twitter)&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img alt=&quot;X (formerly Twitter) Follow&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/Scrapling_dev?style=social&amp;logo=x&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fx.com%2FScrapling_dev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/scrapling/&quot; alt=&quot;Supported Python versions&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Supported Python versions&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/scrapling.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/parsing/selection/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;middot;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/fetching/choosing/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fetchers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;middot;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/spiders/architecture.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spiders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;middot;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/spiders/proxy-blocking.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proxy Rotation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;middot;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/cli/overview/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;middot;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ai/mcp-server/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MCP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

Scrapling is an adaptive Web Scraping framework that handles everything from a single request to a full-scale crawl.

Its parser learns from website changes and automatically relocates your elements when pages update. Its fetchers bypass anti-bot systems like Cloudflare Turnstile out of the box. And its spider framework lets you scale up to concurrent, multi-session crawls with pause/resume and automatic proxy rotation — all in a few lines of Python. One library, zero compromises.

Blazing fast crawls with real-time stats and streaming. Built by Web Scrapers for Web Scrapers and regular users, there&#039;s something for everyone.

```python
from scrapling.fetchers import Fetcher, AsyncFetcher, StealthyFetcher, DynamicFetcher
StealthyFetcher.adaptive = True
p = StealthyFetcher.fetch(&#039;https://example.com&#039;, headless=True, network_idle=True)  # Fetch website under the radar!
products = p.css(&#039;.product&#039;, auto_save=True)                                        # Scrape data that survives website design changes!
products = p.css(&#039;.product&#039;, adaptive=True)                                         # Later, if the website structure changes, pass `adaptive=True` to find them!
```
Or scale up to full crawls
```python
from scrapling.spiders import Spider, Response

class MySpider(Spider):
  name = &quot;demo&quot;
  start_urls = [&quot;https://example.com/&quot;]

  async def parse(self, response: Response):
      for item in response.css(&#039;.product&#039;):
          yield {&quot;title&quot;: item.css(&#039;h2::text&#039;).get()}

MySpider().start()
```

# Platinum Sponsors

# Sponsors 

&lt;!-- sponsors --&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrapeless.com/en?utm_source=official&amp;utm_term=scrapling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Effortless Web Scraping Toolkit for Business and Developers&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/scrapeless.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thordata.com/?ls=github&amp;lk=github&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Unblockable proxies and scraping infrastructure, delivering real-time, reliable web data to power AI models and workflows.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/thordata.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://evomi.com?utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;utm_campaign=d4vinci-scrapling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Evomi is your Swiss Quality Proxy Provider, starting at $0.49/GB&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/evomi.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://serpapi.com/?utm_source=scrapling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Scrape Google and other search engines with SerpApi&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/SerpApi.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://visit.decodo.com/Dy6W0b&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Try the Most Efficient Residential Proxies for Free&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/decodo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://petrosky.io/d4vinci&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;PetroSky delivers cutting-edge VPS hosting.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/petrosky.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hasdata.com/?utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;utm_campaign=D4Vinci&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The web scraping service that actually beats anti-bot systems!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/hasdata.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://proxyempire.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Collect The Data Your Project Needs with the Best Residential Proxies&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/ProxyEmpire.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hypersolutions.co/?utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=readme&amp;utm_campaign=scrapling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bot Protection Bypass API for Akamai, DataDome, Incapsula &amp; Kasada&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/HyperSolutions.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swiftproxy.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Unlock Reliable Proxy Services with Swiftproxy!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/swiftproxy.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rapidproxy.io/?ref=d4v&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Affordable Access to the Proxy World – bypass CAPTCHAs blocks, and avoid additional costs.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/rapidproxy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://browser.cash/?utm_source=D4Vinci&amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Browser Automation &amp; AI Browser Agent Platform&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/D4Vinci/Scrapling/main/images/browserCash.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;!-- /sponsors --&gt;

&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Do you want to show your ad here? Click [here](https://github.com/sponsors/D4Vinci) and choose the tier that suites you!&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;

---

## Key Features

### Spiders — A Full Crawling Framework
- 🕷️ **Scrapy-like Spider API**: Define spiders with `start_urls`, async `parse` callbacks, and `Request`/`Response` objects.
- ⚡ **Concurrent Crawling**: Configurable concurrency limits, per-domain throttling, and download delays.
- 🔄 **Multi-Session Support**: Unified interface for HTTP requests, and stealthy headless browsers in a single spider — route requests to different sessions by ID.
- 💾 **Pause &amp; Resume**: Checkpoint-based crawl persistence. Press Ctrl+C for a graceful shutdown; restart to resume from where you left off.
- 📡 **Streaming Mode**: Stream scraped items as they arrive via `async for item in spider.stream()` with real-time stats — ideal for UI, pipelines, and long-running crawls.
- 🛡️ **Blocked Request Detection**: Automatic detection and retry of blocked requests with customizable logic.
- 📦 **Built-in Export**: Export results through hooks and your own pipeline or the built-in JSON/JSONL with `result.items.to_json()` / `result.items.to_jsonl()` respectively.

### Advanced Websites Fetching with Session Support
- **HTTP Requests**: Fast and stealthy HTTP requests with the `Fetcher` class. Can impersonate browsers&#039; TLS fingerprint, headers, and use HTTP/3.
- **Dynamic Loading**: Fetch dynamic websites with full browser automation through the `DynamicFetcher` class supporting Playwright&#039;s Chromium and Google&#039;s Chrome.
- **Anti-bot Bypass**: Advanced stealth capabilities with `StealthyFetcher` and fingerprint spoofing. Can easily bypass all types of Cloudflare&#039;s Turnstile/Interstitial with automation.
- **Session Management**: Persistent session support with `FetcherSession`, `StealthySession`, and `DynamicSession` classes for cookie and state management across requests.
- **Proxy Rotation**: Built-in `ProxyRotator` with cyclic or custom rotation strategies across all session types, plus per-request proxy overrides.
- **Domain Blocking**: Block requests to specific domains (and their subdomains) in browser-based fetchers.
- **Async Support**: Complete async support across all fetchers and dedicated async session classes.

### Adaptive Scraping &amp; AI Integration
- 🔄 **Smart Element Tracking**: Relocate elements after website changes using intelligent similarity algorithms.
- 🎯 **Smart Flexible Selection**: CSS selectors, XPath selectors, filter-based search, text search, regex search, and more.
- 🔍 **Find Similar Elements**: Automatically locate elements similar to found elements.
- 🤖 **MCP Server to be used with AI**: Built-in MCP server for AI-assisted Web Scraping and data extraction. The MCP server features powerful, custom capabilities that leverage Scrapling to extract targeted content before passing it to the AI (Claude/Cursor/etc), thereby speeding up operations and reducing costs by minimizing token usage. ([demo video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyFk3ZNwOxE))

### High-Performance &amp; battle-tested Architecture
- 🚀 **Lightning Fast**: Optimized performance outperforming most Python scraping libraries.
- 🔋 **Memory Efficient**: Optimized data structures and lazy loading for a minimal memory footprint.
- ⚡ **Fast JSON Serialization**: 10x faster than the standard library.
- 🏗️ **Battle tested**: Not only does Scrapling have 92% test coverage and full type hints coverage, but it has been used daily by hundreds of Web Scrapers over the past year.

### Developer/Web Scraper Friendly Experience
- 🎯 **Interactive Web Scraping Shell**: Optional built-in IPython shell with Scrapling integration, shortcuts, and new tools to speed up Web Scraping scripts development, like converting curl requests to Scrapling requests and viewing requests results in your browser.
- 🚀 **Use it directly from the Terminal**: Optionally, you can use Scrapling to scrape a URL without writing a single line of code!
- 🛠️ **Rich Navigation API**: Advanced DOM traversal with parent, sibling, and child navigation methods.
- 🧬 **Enhanced Text Processing**: Built-in regex, cleaning methods, and optimized string operations.
- 📝 **Auto Selector Generation**: Generate robust CSS/XPath selectors for any element.
- 🔌 **Familiar API**: Similar to Scrapy/BeautifulSoup with the same pseudo-elements used in Scrapy/Parsel.
- 📘 **Complete Type Coverage**: Full type hints for excellent IDE support and code completion. The entire codebase is automatically scanned with **PyRight** and **MyPy** with each change.
- 🔋 **Ready Docker image**: With each release, a Docker image containing all browsers is automatically built and pushed.

## Getting Started

Let&#039;s give you a quick glimpse of what Scrapling can do without deep diving.

### Basic Usage
HTTP requests with session support
```python
from scrapling.fetchers import Fetcher, FetcherSession

with FetcherSession(impersonate=&#039;chrome&#039;) as session:  # Use latest version of Chrome&#039;s TLS fingerprint
    page = session.get(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;, stealthy_headers=True)
    quotes = page.css(&#039;.quote .text::text&#039;).getall()

# Or use one-off requests
page = Fetcher.get(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;)
quotes = page.css(&#039;.quote .text::text&#039;).getall()
```
Advanced stealth mode
```python
from scrapling.fetchers import StealthyFetcher, StealthySession

with StealthySession(headless=True, solve_cloudflare=True) as session:  # Keep the browser open until you finish
    page = session.fetch(&#039;https://nopecha.com/demo/cloudflare&#039;, google_search=False)
    data = page.css(&#039;#padded_content a&#039;).getall()

# Or use one-off request style, it opens the browser for this request, then closes it after finishing
page = StealthyFetcher.fetch(&#039;https://nopecha.com/demo/cloudflare&#039;)
data = page.css(&#039;#padded_content a&#039;).getall()
```
Full browser automation
```python
from scrapling.fetchers import DynamicFetcher, DynamicSession

with DynamicSession(headless=True, disable_resources=False, network_idle=True) as session:  # Keep the browser open until you finish
    page = session.fetch(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;, load_dom=False)
    data = page.xpath(&#039;//span[@class=&quot;text&quot;]/text()&#039;).getall()  # XPath selector if you prefer it

# Or use one-off request style, it opens the browser for this request, then closes it after finishing
page = DynamicFetcher.fetch(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;)
data = page.css(&#039;.quote .text::text&#039;).getall()
```

### Spiders
Build full crawlers with concurrent requests, multiple session types, and pause/resume:
```python
from scrapling.spiders import Spider, Request, Response

class QuotesSpider(Spider):
    name = &quot;quotes&quot;
    start_urls = [&quot;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&quot;]
    concurrent_requests = 10
    
    async def parse(self, response: Response):
        for quote in response.css(&#039;.quote&#039;):
            yield {
                &quot;text&quot;: quote.css(&#039;.text::text&#039;).get(),
                &quot;author&quot;: quote.css(&#039;.author::text&#039;).get(),
            }
            
        next_page = response.css(&#039;.next a&#039;)
        if next_page:
            yield response.follow(next_page[0].attrib[&#039;href&#039;])

result = QuotesSpider().start()
print(f&quot;Scraped {len(result.items)} quotes&quot;)
result.items.to_json(&quot;quotes.json&quot;)
```
Use multiple session types in a single spider:
```python
from scrapling.spiders import Spider, Request, Response
from scrapling.fetchers import FetcherSession, AsyncStealthySession

class MultiSessionSpider(Spider):
    name = &quot;multi&quot;
    start_urls = [&quot;https://example.com/&quot;]
    
    def configure_sessions(self, manager):
        manager.add(&quot;fast&quot;, FetcherSession(impersonate=&quot;chrome&quot;))
        manager.add(&quot;stealth&quot;, AsyncStealthySession(headless=True), lazy=True)
    
    async def parse(self, response: Response):
        for link in response.css(&#039;a::attr(href)&#039;).getall():
            # Route protected pages through the stealth session
            if &quot;protected&quot; in link:
                yield Request(link, sid=&quot;stealth&quot;)
            else:
                yield Request(link, sid=&quot;fast&quot;, callback=self.parse)  # explicit callback
```
Pause and resume long crawls with checkpoints by running the spider like this:
```python
QuotesSpider(crawldir=&quot;./crawl_data&quot;).start()
```
Press Ctrl+C to pause gracefully — progress is saved automatically. Later, when you start the spider again, pass the same `crawldir`, and it will resume from where it stopped.

### Advanced Parsing &amp; Navigation
```python
from scrapling.fetchers import Fetcher

# Rich element selection and navigation
page = Fetcher.get(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;)

# Get quotes with multiple selection methods
quotes = page.css(&#039;.quote&#039;)  # CSS selector
quotes = page.xpath(&#039;//div[@class=&quot;quote&quot;]&#039;)  # XPath
quotes = page.find_all(&#039;div&#039;, {&#039;class&#039;: &#039;quote&#039;})  # BeautifulSoup-style
# Same as
quotes = page.find_all(&#039;div&#039;, class_=&#039;quote&#039;)
quotes = page.find_all([&#039;div&#039;], class_=&#039;quote&#039;)
quotes = page.find_all(class_=&#039;quote&#039;)  # and so on...
# Find element by text content
quotes = page.find_by_text(&#039;quote&#039;, tag=&#039;div&#039;)

# Advanced navigation
quote_text = page.css(&#039;.quote&#039;)[0].css(&#039;.text::text&#039;).get()
quote_text = page.css(&#039;.quote&#039;).css(&#039;.text::text&#039;).getall()  # Chained selectors
first_quote = page.css(&#039;.quote&#039;)[0]
author = first_quote.next_sibling.css(&#039;.author::text&#039;)
parent_container = first_quote.parent

# Element relationships and similarity
similar_elements = first_quote.find_similar()
below_elements = first_quote.below_elements()
```
You can use the parser right away if you don&#039;t want to fetch websites like below:
```python
from scrapling.parser import Selector

page = Selector(&quot;&lt;html&gt;...&lt;/html&gt;&quot;)
```
And it works precisely the same way!

### Async Session Management Examples
```python
import asyncio
from scrapling.fetchers import FetcherSession, AsyncStealthySession, AsyncDynamicSession

async with FetcherSession(http3=True) as session:  # `FetcherSession` is context-aware and can work in both sync/async patterns
    page1 = session.get(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;)
    page2 = session.get(&#039;https://quotes.toscrape.com/&#039;, impersonate=&#039;firefox135&#039;)

# Async session usage
async with AsyncStealthySession(max_pages=2) as session:
    tasks = []
    urls = [&#039;https://example.com/page1&#039;, &#039;https://example.com/page2&#039;]
    
    for url in urls:
        task = session.fetch(url)
        tasks.append(task)
    
    print(session.get_pool_stats())  # Optional - The status of the browser tabs pool (busy/free/error)
    results = await asyncio.gather(*tasks)
    print(session.get_pool_stats())
```

## CLI &amp; Interactive Shell

Scrapling includes a powerful command-line interface:

[![asciicast](https://asciinema.org/a/736339.svg)](https://asciinema.org/a/736339)

Launch the interactive Web Scraping shell
```bash
scrapling shell
```
Extract pages to a file directly without programming (Extracts the content inside the `body` tag by default). If the output file ends with `.txt`, then the text content of the target will be extracted. If it ends in `.md`, it will be a Markdown representation of the HTML content; if it ends in `.html`, it will be the HTML content itself.
```bash
scrapling extract get &#039;https://example.com&#039; content.md
scrapling extract get &#039;https://example.com&#039; content.txt --css-selector &#039;#fromSkipToProducts&#039; --impersonate &#039;chrome&#039;  # All elements matching the CSS selector &#039;#fromSkipToProducts&#039;
scrapling extract fetch &#039;https://example.com&#039; content.md --css-selector &#039;#fromSkipToProducts&#039; --no-headless
scrapling extract stealthy-fetch &#039;https://nopecha.com/demo/cloudflare&#039; captchas.html --css-selector &#039;#padded_content a&#039; --solve-cloudflare
```

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; There are many additional features, but we want to keep this page concise, including the MCP server and the interactive Web Scraping Shell. Check out the full documentation [here](https://scrapling.readthedocs.io/en/latest/)

## Performance Benchmarks

Scrapling isn&#039;t just powerful—it&#039;s also blazing fast. The following benchmarks compare Scrapling&#039;s parser with the latest versions of other popular libraries.

###

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GVCLab/PersonaLive]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[[CVPR 2026] PersonaLive! : Expressive Portrait Image Animation for Live Streaming]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive">GVCLab/PersonaLive</a></h1>
            <p>[CVPR 2026] PersonaLive! : Expressive Portrait Image Animation for Live Streaming</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,947</p>
            <p>Forks: 288</p>
            <p>Stars today: 73 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/header.svg&quot; alt=&quot;PersonaLive&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Expressive Portrait Image Animation for Live Streaming&lt;/h2&gt;

#### [Zhiyuan Li&lt;sup&gt;1,2,3&lt;/sup&gt;](https://huai-chang.github.io/) · [Chi-Man Pun&lt;sup&gt;1,📪&lt;/sup&gt;](https://cmpun.github.io/) · [Chen Fang&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;](http://fangchen.org/) · [Jue Wang&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;](https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Bt4uDWMAAAAJ&amp;hl=en) · [Xiaodong Cun&lt;sup&gt;3,📪&lt;/sup&gt;](https://vinthony.github.io/academic/) 
&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Macau  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; [Dzine.ai](https://www.dzine.ai/)  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; [GVC Lab, Great Bay University](https://gvclab.github.io/)

&lt;a href=&#039;https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.11253&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/ArXiv-2512.11253-red&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#039;https://huggingface.co/huaichang/PersonaLive&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/%F0%9F%A4%97%20Hugging%20Face-Model-ffc107&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#039;https://modelscope.cn/models/huaichang/PersonaLive&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/ModelScope-Model-624AFF&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [![GitHub](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/GVCLab/PersonaLive?style=social)](https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive)

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/highlight.svg&quot; alt=&quot;highlight&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/demo_3.gif&quot; width=&quot;46%&quot;&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;img src=&quot;assets/demo_2.gif&quot; width=&quot;40.5%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 📋 TODO
- [ ] If you find PersonaLive useful or interesting, please give us a Star🌟! Your support drives us to keep improving.
- [ ] Fix bugs (If you encounter any issues, please feel free to open an issue or contact me! 🙏)
- [x] **[2026.02.21]** 🥳 PersonaLive is accepted by CVPR2026 🎉.
- [x] **[2025.12.29]** 🔥 Enhance WebUI (Support reference image replacement).
- [x] **[2025.12.22]** 🔥 Supported streaming strategy in offline inference to generate long videos on 12GB VRAM!
- [x] **[2025.12.17]** 🔥 [ComfyUI-PersonaLive](https://github.com/okdalto/ComfyUI-PersonaLive) is now supported! (Thanks to [@okdalto](https://github.com/okdalto))
- [x] **[2025.12.15]** 🔥 Release `paper`!
- [x] **[2025.12.12]** 🔥 Release `inference code`, `config`, and `pretrained weights`!
  
## ⚖️ Disclaimer

- [x] This project is released for **academic research only**.
- [x] Users must not use this repository to generate harmful, defamatory, or illegal content.
- [x] The authors bear no responsibility for any misuse or legal consequences arising from the use of this tool.
- [x] By using this code, you agree that you are solely responsible for any content generated.

## ⚙️ Framework
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image 1&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;


We present PersonaLive, a `real-time` and `streamable` diffusion framework capable of generating `infinite-length` portrait animations.


## 🚀 Getting Started
### 🛠 Installation
```
# clone this repo
git clone https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive
cd PersonaLive

# Create conda environment
conda create -n personalive python=3.10
conda activate personalive

# Install packages with pip
pip install -r requirements_base.txt
```

### ⏬ Download weights
Option 1: Download pre-trained weights of base models and other components ([sd-image-variations-diffusers](https://huggingface.co/lambdalabs/sd-image-variations-diffusers) and [sd-vae-ft-mse](https://huggingface.co/stabilityai/sd-vae-ft-mse)). You can run the following command to download weights automatically:
    
```bash
python tools/download_weights.py
```

Option 2: Download pre-trained weights into the `./pretrained_weights` folder from one of the below URLs:
    
&lt;a href=&#039;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1GOhDBKIeowkMpBnKhGB8jgEhJt_--vbT?usp=drive_link&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/Google%20Drive-5B8DEF?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=googledrive&amp;logoColor=white&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#039;https://pan.baidu.com/s/1DCv4NvUy_z7Gj2xCGqRMkQ?pwd=gj64&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/Baidu%20Netdisk-3E4A89?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=baidu&amp;logoColor=white&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#039;https://modelscope.cn/models/huaichang/PersonaLive&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/ModelScope-624AFF?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=alibabacloud&amp;logoColor=white&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#039;https://huggingface.co/huaichang/PersonaLive&#039;&gt;&lt;img src=&#039;https://img.shields.io/badge/HuggingFace-E67E22?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=huggingface&amp;logoColor=white&#039;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Finally, these weights should be organized as follows:
```
pretrained_weights
├── onnx
│   ├── unet_opt
│   │   ├── unet_opt.onnx
│   │   └── unet_opt.onnx.data
│   └── unet
├── personalive
│   ├── denoising_unet.pth
│   ├── motion_encoder.pth
│   ├── motion_extractor.pth
│   ├── pose_guider.pth
│   ├── reference_unet.pth
│   └── temporal_module.pth
├── sd-vae-ft-mse
│   ├── diffusion_pytorch_model.bin
│   └── config.json
├── sd-image-variations-diffusers
│   ├── image_encoder
│   │   ├── pytorch_model.bin
│   │   └── config.json
│   ├── unet
│   │   ├── diffusion_pytorch_model.bin
│   │   └── config.json
│   └── model_index.json
└── tensorrt
    └── unet_work.engine
```

### 🎞️ Offline Inference
Run offline inference with the default configuration:

```
python inference_offline.py
```

* `-L`: Max number of frames to generate. (Default: 100)
* `--use_xformers`: Enable xFormers memory efficient attention. (Default: True)
* `--stream_gen`: Enable streaming generation strategy. (Default: True)
* `--reference_image`: Path to a specific reference image. Overrides settings in config.
* `--driving_video`: Path to a specific driving video. Overrides settings in config.

⚠️ Note for RTX 50-Series (Blackwell) Users: xformers is not yet fully compatible with the new architecture. To avoid crashes, please disable it by running:

```
python inference_offline.py --use_xformers False
```

### 📸 Online Inference
#### 📦 Setup Web UI
```
# install Node.js 18+
curl -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nvm-sh/nvm/v0.39.1/install.sh | bash
nvm install 18

source web_start.sh
```

#### 🏎️ Acceleration (Optional)
Converting the model to TensorRT can significantly speed up inference (~ 2x ⚡️). Building the engine may take about `20 minutes` depending on your device. Note that TensorRT optimizations may lead to slight variations or a small drop in output quality.
```
# Install packages with pip
pip install -r requirements_trt.txt

# Converting the model to TensorRT
python torch2trt.py
```
💡 **PyCUDA Installation Issues**: If you encounter a &quot;Failed to build wheel for pycuda&quot; error during the installation above, please follow these steps:
```
# Install PyCUDA manually using Conda (avoids compilation issues):
conda install -c conda-forge pycuda &quot;numpy&lt;2.0&quot;

# Open requirements_trt.txt and comment out or remove the line &quot;pycuda==2024.1.2&quot;

# Install other packages with pip
pip install -r requirements_trt.txt

# Converting the model to TensorRT
python torch2trt.py
```
⚠️ The provided TensorRT model is from an `H100`. We recommend `ALL users` (including H100 users) re-run `python torch2trt.py` locally to ensure best compatibility.

#### ▶️ Start Streaming
```
python inference_online.py --acceleration none (for RTX 50-Series) or xformers or tensorrt
```
Then open `http://0.0.0.0:7860` in your browser. (*If `http://0.0.0.0:7860` does not work well, try `http://localhost:7860`)

**How to use**: Upload Image ➡️ Fuse Reference ➡️ Start Animation ➡️ Enjoy! 🎉
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/guide.png&quot; alt=&quot;PersonaLive&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

**Regarding Latency**: Latency varies depending on your device&#039;s computing power. You can try the following methods to optimize it:

1. Lower the &quot;Driving FPS&quot; setting in the WebUI to reduce the computational workload.
2. You can increase the multiplier (e.g., set to `num_frames_needed * 4` or higher) to better match your device&#039;s inference speed. https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive/blob/6953d1a8b409f360a3ee1d7325093622b29f1e22/webcam/util.py#L73

## 📚 Community Contribution

Special thanks to the community for providing helpful setups! 🥂

* **Windows + RTX 50-Series Guide**: Thanks to [@dknos](https://github.com/dknos) for providing a [detailed guide](https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive/issues/10#issuecomment-3662785532) on running this project on Windows with Blackwell GPUs.

* **TensorRT on Windows**: If you are trying to convert TensorRT models on Windows, [this discussion](https://github.com/GVCLab/PersonaLive/issues/8) might be helpful. Special thanks to [@MaraScott](https://github.com/MaraScott) and [@Jeremy8776](https://github.com/Jeremy8776) for their insights.
  
* **ComfyUI**: Thanks to [@okdalto](https://github.com/okdalto) for helping implement the [ComfyUI-PersonaLive](https://github.com/okdalto/ComfyUI-PersonaLive) support.

* **Useful Scripts**: Thanks to [@suruoxi](https://github.com/suruoxi) for implementing `download_weights.py`, and to [@andchir](https://github.com/andchir) for adding audio merging functionality.

## 🎬 More Results
#### 👀 Visualization results

&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/cdc885ef-5e1c-4139-987a-2fa50fefd6a4&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/014f7bae-74ce-4f56-8621-24bc76f3c123&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1e6a0809-15d2-4cab-ae8f-8cf1728c6281&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d9cf265d-9db0-4f83-81da-be967bbd5f26&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/86235139-b63e-4f26-b09c-d218466e8e24&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/238785de-3b4c-484e-9ad0-9d90e7962fee&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c71c4717-d528-4a98-b132-2b0ec8cec22d&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7e11fe71-fd16-4011-a6b2-2dbaf7e343fb&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f62e2162-d239-4575-9514-34575c16301c&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;25%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/813e7fbd-37e9-47d7-a270-59887fafeca5&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

#### 🤺 Comparisons

&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/36407cf9-bf82-43ff-9508-a794d223d3f7&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3be99b91-c6a1-4ca4-89e9-8fad42bb9583&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
      &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/5bd21fe4-96ae-4be6-bf06-a7c476b04ec9&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


## ⭐ Citation
If you find PersonaLive useful for your research, welcome to cite our work using the following BibTeX:
```bibtex
@article{li2025personalive,
  title={PersonaLive! Expressive Portrait Image Animation for Live Streaming},
  author={Li, Zhiyuan and Pun, Chi-Man and Fang, Chen and Wang, Jue and Cun, Xiaodong},
  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2512.11253},
  year={2025}
}
```

## ❤️ Acknowledgement
This code is mainly built upon [Moore-AnimateAnyone](https://github.com/MooreThreads/Moore-AnimateAnyone), [X-NeMo](https://byteaigc.github.io/X-Portrait2/), [StreamDiffusion](https://github.com/cumulo-autumn/StreamDiffusion), [RAIN](https://pscgylotti.github.io/pages/RAIN/) and [LivePortrait](https://github.com/KlingTeam/LivePortrait), thanks to their invaluable contributions.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HunxByts/GhostTrack]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Useful tool to track location or mobile number]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack">HunxByts/GhostTrack</a></h1>
            <p>Useful tool to track location or mobile number</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,431</p>
            <p>Forks: 983</p>
            <p>Stars today: 145 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># GhostTrack
Useful tool to track location or mobile number, so this tool can be called osint or also information gathering

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack/blob/main/asset/bn.png&quot;/&gt;

New update :
```Version 2.2```

### Instalation on Linux (deb)
```
sudo apt-get install git
sudo apt-get install python3
```

### Instalation on Termux
```
pkg install git
pkg install python3
```

### Usage Tool
```
git clone https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack.git
cd GhostTrack
pip3 install -r requirements.txt
python3 GhostTR.py
```

Display on the menu ```IP Tracker```

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack/blob/main/asset/ip.png &quot; /&gt;

on the IP Track menu, you can combo with the seeker tool to get the target IP
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;:zap: Install Seeker :&lt;/summary&gt;
- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thewhiteh4t/seeker&quot;&gt;Get Seeker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

Display on the menu ```Phone Tracker```

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack/blob/main/asset/phone.png&quot; /&gt;

on this menu you can search for information from the target phone number

Display on the menu ```Username Tracker```

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/HunxByts/GhostTrack/blob/main/asset/User.png&quot;/&gt;
on this menu you can search for information from the target username on social media

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;:zap: Author :&lt;/summary&gt;
- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HunxByts&quot;&gt;HunxByts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VectifyAI/PageIndex]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[📑 PageIndex: Document Index for Vectorless, Reasoning-based RAG]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex">VectifyAI/PageIndex</a></h1>
            <p>📑 PageIndex: Document Index for Vectorless, Reasoning-based RAG</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 17,223</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,225</p>
            <p>Stars today: 714 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vectify.ai/pageindex&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/46201e72-675b-43bc-bfbd-081cc6b65a1d&quot; alt=&quot;PageIndex Banner&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/14736&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/14736&quot; alt=&quot;VectifyAI%2FPageIndex | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

# PageIndex: Vectorless, Reasoning-based RAG

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reasoning-based RAG&amp;nbsp; ◦ &amp;nbsp;No Vector DB&amp;nbsp; ◦ &amp;nbsp;No Chunking&amp;nbsp; ◦ &amp;nbsp;Human-like Retrieval&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://vectify.ai&quot;&gt;🏠 Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; • &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.pageindex.ai&quot;&gt;🖥️ Chat Platform&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; • &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pageindex.ai/mcp&quot;&gt;🔌 MCP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; • &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pageindex.ai&quot;&gt;📚 Docs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; • &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/invite/VuXuf29EUj&quot;&gt;💬 Discord&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; • &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://ii2abc2jejf.typeform.com/to/tK3AXl8T&quot;&gt;✉️ Contact&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;details open&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;h3&gt;📢 Latest Updates&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

 **🔥 Releases:**
- [**PageIndex Chat**](https://chat.pageindex.ai): The first human-like document-analysis agent [platform](https://chat.pageindex.ai) built for professional long documents. Can also be integrated via [MCP](https://pageindex.ai/mcp) or [API](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart) (beta).
&lt;!-- - [**PageIndex Chat API**](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart): An API that brings PageIndex&#039;s advanced long-document intelligence directly into your applications and workflows. --&gt;
&lt;!-- - [PageIndex MCP](https://pageindex.ai/mcp): Bring PageIndex into Claude, Cursor, or any MCP-enabled agent. Chat with long PDFs in a reasoning-based, human-like way. --&gt;
 
 **📝 Articles:**
- [**PageIndex Framework**](https://pageindex.ai/blog/pageindex-intro): Introduces the PageIndex framework — an *agentic, in-context* *tree index* that enables LLMs to perform *reasoning-based*, *human-like retrieval* over long documents, without vector DB or chunking.
&lt;!-- - [Do We Still Need OCR?](https://pageindex.ai/blog/do-we-need-ocr): Explores how vision-based, reasoning-native RAG challenges the traditional OCR pipeline, and why the future of document AI might be *vectorless* and *vision-based*. --&gt;

 **🧪 Cookbooks:**
- [Vectorless RAG](https://docs.pageindex.ai/cookbook/vectorless-rag-pageindex): A minimal, hands-on example of reasoning-based RAG using PageIndex. No vectors, no chunking, and human-like retrieval.
- [Vision-based Vectorless RAG](https://docs.pageindex.ai/cookbook/vision-rag-pageindex): OCR-free, vision-only RAG with PageIndex&#039;s reasoning-native retrieval workflow that works directly over PDF page images.
&lt;/details&gt;

---

# 📑 Introduction to PageIndex

Are you frustrated with vector database retrieval accuracy for long professional documents? Traditional vector-based RAG relies on semantic *similarity* rather than true *relevance*. But **similarity ≠ relevance** — what we truly need in retrieval is **relevance**, and that requires **reasoning**. When working with professional documents that demand domain expertise and multi-step reasoning, similarity search often falls short.

Inspired by AlphaGo, we propose **[PageIndex](https://vectify.ai/pageindex)** — a **vectorless**, **reasoning-based RAG** system that builds a **hierarchical tree index** from long documents and uses LLMs to **reason** *over that index* for **agentic, context-aware retrieval**.
It simulates how *human experts* navigate and extract knowledge from complex documents through *tree search*, enabling LLMs to *think* and *reason* their way to the most relevant document sections. PageIndex performs retrieval in two steps:

1. Generate a “Table-of-Contents” **tree structure index** of documents
2. Perform reasoning-based retrieval through **tree search**

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pageindex.ai/blog/pageindex-intro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The PageIndex Framework&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.pageindex.ai/images/cookbook/vectorless-rag.png&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

### 🎯 Core Features 

Compared to traditional vector-based RAG, **PageIndex** features:
- **No Vector DB**: Uses document structure and LLM reasoning for retrieval, instead of vector similarity search.
- **No Chunking**: Documents are organized into natural sections, not artificial chunks.
- **Human-like Retrieval**: Simulates how human experts navigate and extract knowledge from complex documents.
- **Better Explainability and Traceability**: Retrieval is based on reasoning — traceable and interpretable, with page and section references. No more opaque, approximate vector search (“vibe retrieval”).

PageIndex powers a reasoning-based RAG system that achieved **state-of-the-art** [98.7% accuracy](https://github.com/VectifyAI/Mafin2.5-FinanceBench) on FinanceBench, demonstrating superior performance over vector-based RAG solutions in professional document analysis (see our [blog post](https://vectify.ai/blog/Mafin2.5) for details).

### 📍 Explore PageIndex

To learn more, please see a detailed introduction of the [PageIndex framework](https://pageindex.ai/blog/pageindex-intro). Check out this GitHub repo for open-source code, and the [cookbooks](https://docs.pageindex.ai/cookbook), [tutorials](https://docs.pageindex.ai/tutorials), and [blog](https://pageindex.ai/blog) for additional usage guides and examples. 

The PageIndex service is available as a ChatGPT-style [chat platform](https://chat.pageindex.ai), or can be integrated via [MCP](https://pageindex.ai/mcp) or [API](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart).

### 🛠️ Deployment Options
- Self-host — run locally with this open-source repo.
- Cloud Service — try instantly with our [Chat Platform](https://chat.pageindex.ai/), or integrate with [MCP](https://pageindex.ai/mcp) or [API](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart).
- _Enterprise_ — private or on-prem deployment. [Contact us](https://ii2abc2jejf.typeform.com/to/tK3AXl8T) or [book a demo](https://calendly.com/pageindex/meet) for more details.

### 🧪 Quick Hands-on

- Try the [**Vectorless RAG**](https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex/blob/main/cookbook/pageindex_RAG_simple.ipynb) notebook — a *minimal*, hands-on example of reasoning-based RAG using PageIndex.
- Experiment with [*Vision-based Vectorless RAG*](https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex/blob/main/cookbook/vision_RAG_pageindex.ipynb) — no OCR; a minimal, reasoning-native RAG pipeline that works directly over page images.
  
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/VectifyAI/PageIndex/blob/main/cookbook/pageindex_RAG_simple.ipynb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Open_In_Colab-Vectorless_RAG-orange?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=googlecolab&quot; alt=&quot;Open in Colab: Vectorless RAG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/VectifyAI/PageIndex/blob/main/cookbook/vision_RAG_pageindex.ipynb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Open_In_Colab-Vision_RAG-orange?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=googlecolab&quot; alt=&quot;Open in Colab: Vision RAG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---

# 🌲 PageIndex Tree Structure
PageIndex can transform lengthy PDF documents into a semantic **tree structure**, similar to a _&quot;table of contents&quot;_ but optimized for use with Large Language Models (LLMs). It&#039;s ideal for: financial reports, regulatory filings, academic textbooks, legal or technical manuals, and any document that exceeds LLM context limits.

Below is an example PageIndex tree structure. Also see more example [documents](https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex/tree/main/tests/pdfs) and generated [tree structures](https://github.com/VectifyAI/PageIndex/tree/main/tests/results).

```jsonc
...
{
  &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Financial Stability&quot;,
  &quot;node_id&quot;: &quot;0006&quot;,
  &quot;start_index&quot;: 21,
  &quot;end_index&quot;: 22,
  &quot;summary&quot;: &quot;The Federal Reserve ...&quot;,
  &quot;nodes&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Monitoring Financial Vulnerabilities&quot;,
      &quot;node_id&quot;: &quot;0007&quot;,
      &quot;start_index&quot;: 22,
      &quot;end_index&quot;: 28,
      &quot;summary&quot;: &quot;The Federal Reserve&#039;s monitoring ...&quot;
    },
    {
      &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Domestic and International Cooperation and Coordination&quot;,
      &quot;node_id&quot;: &quot;0008&quot;,
      &quot;start_index&quot;: 28,
      &quot;end_index&quot;: 31,
      &quot;summary&quot;: &quot;In 2023, the Federal Reserve collaborated ...&quot;
    }
  ]
}
...
```

You can generate the PageIndex tree structure with this open-source repo, or use our [API](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart) 

---

# ⚙️ Package Usage

You can follow these steps to generate a PageIndex tree from a PDF document.

### 1. Install dependencies

```bash
pip3 install --upgrade -r requirements.txt
```

### 2. Set your OpenAI API key

Create a `.env` file in the root directory and add your API key:

```bash
CHATGPT_API_KEY=your_openai_key_here
```

### 3. Run PageIndex on your PDF

```bash
python3 run_pageindex.py --pdf_path /path/to/your/document.pdf
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional parameters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You can customize the processing with additional optional arguments:

```
--model                 OpenAI model to use (default: gpt-4o-2024-11-20)
--toc-check-pages       Pages to check for table of contents (default: 20)
--max-pages-per-node    Max pages per node (default: 10)
--max-tokens-per-node   Max tokens per node (default: 20000)
--if-add-node-id        Add node ID (yes/no, default: yes)
--if-add-node-summary   Add node summary (yes/no, default: yes)
--if-add-doc-description Add doc description (yes/no, default: yes)
```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We also provide markdown support for PageIndex. You can use the `-md_path` flag to generate a tree structure for a markdown file.

```bash
python3 run_pageindex.py --md_path /path/to/your/document.md
```

&gt; Note: in this function, we use &quot;#&quot; to determine node heading and their levels. For example, &quot;##&quot; is level 2, &quot;###&quot; is level 3, etc. Make sure your markdown file is formatted correctly. If your Markdown file was converted from a PDF or HTML, we don&#039;t recommend using this function, since most existing conversion tools cannot preserve the original hierarchy. Instead, use our [PageIndex OCR](https://pageindex.ai/blog/ocr), which is designed to preserve the original hierarchy, to convert the PDF to a markdown file and then use this function.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;!-- 
# ☁️ Improved Tree Generation with PageIndex OCR

This repo is designed for generating PageIndex tree structure for simple PDFs, but many real-world use cases involve complex PDFs that are hard to parse by classic Python tools. However, extracting high-quality text from PDF documents remains a non-trivial challenge. Most OCR tools only extract page-level content, losing the broader document context and hierarchy.

To address this, we introduced PageIndex OCR — the first long-context OCR model designed to preserve the global structure of documents. PageIndex OCR significantly outperforms other leading OCR tools, such as those from Mistral and Contextual AI, in recognizing true hierarchy and semantic relationships across document pages.

- Experience next-level OCR quality with PageIndex OCR at our [Dashboard](https://dash.pageindex.ai/).
- Integrate PageIndex OCR seamlessly into your stack via our [API](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart).

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/eb35d8ae-865c-4e60-a33b-ebbd00c41732&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;

---

# 📈 Case Study: PageIndex Leads Finance QA Benchmark

[Mafin 2.5](https://vectify.ai/mafin) is a reasoning-based RAG system for financial document analysis, powered by **PageIndex**. It achieved a state-of-the-art [**98.7% accuracy**](https://vectify.ai/blog/Mafin2.5) on the [FinanceBench](https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.11944) benchmark, significantly outperforming traditional vector-based RAG systems.

PageIndex&#039;s hierarchical indexing and reasoning-driven retrieval enable precise navigation and extraction of relevant context from complex financial reports, such as SEC filings and earnings disclosures.

Explore the full [benchmark results](https://github.com/VectifyAI/Mafin2.5-FinanceBench) and our [blog post](https://vectify.ai/blog/Mafin2.5) for detailed comparisons and performance metrics.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/VectifyAI/Mafin2.5-FinanceBench&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/571aa074-d803-43c7-80c4-a04254b782a3&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---

# 🧭 Resources

* 🧪 [Cookbooks](https://docs.pageindex.ai/cookbook/vectorless-rag-pageindex): hands-on, runnable examples and advanced use cases.
* 📖 [Tutorials](https://docs.pageindex.ai/doc-search): practical guides and strategies, including *Document Search* and *Tree Search*.
* 📝 [Blog](https://pageindex.ai/blog): technical articles, research insights, and product updates.
* 🔌 [MCP setup](https://pageindex.ai/mcp#quick-setup) &amp; [API docs](https://docs.pageindex.ai/quickstart): integration details and configuration options.

---

# ⭐ Support Us
Please cite this work as:
```
Mingtian Zhang, Yu Tang and PageIndex Team,
&quot;PageIndex: Next-Generation Vectorless, Reasoning-based RAG&quot;,
PageIndex Blog, Sep 2025.
```

Or use the BibTeX citation:

```
@article{zhang2025pageindex,
  author = {Mingtian Zhang and Yu Tang and PageIndex Team},
  title = {PageIndex: Next-Generation Vectorless, Reasoning-based RAG},
  journal = {PageIndex Blog},
  year = {2025},
  month = {September},
  note = {https://pageindex.ai/blog/pageindex-intro},
}
```

Leave us a star 🌟 if you like our project. Thank you!  

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/eae4ff38-48ae-4a7c-b19f-eab81201d794&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### Connect with Us

[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/badge/Twitter-000000?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=x&amp;logoColor=white)](https://x.com/PageIndexAI)&amp;nbsp;
[![LinkedIn](https://img.shields.io/badge/LinkedIn-0077B5?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=linkedin&amp;logoColor=white)](https://www.linkedin.com/company/vectify-ai/)&amp;nbsp;
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-5865F2?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.com/invite/VuXuf29EUj)&amp;nbsp;
[![Contact Us](https://img.shields.io/badge/Contact_Us-3B82F6?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=envelope&amp;logoColor=white)](https://ii2abc2jejf.typeform.com/to/tK3AXl8T)

---

© 2025 [Vectify AI](https://vectify.ai)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[smittix/intercept]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/smittix/intercept</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/smittix/intercept</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[iNTERCEPT, a free and open-source platform that unites the best signal intelligence tools into a single, accessible interface.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/smittix/intercept">smittix/intercept</a></h1>
            <p>iNTERCEPT, a free and open-source platform that unites the best signal intelligence tools into a single, accessible interface.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,308</p>
            <p>Forks: 161</p>
            <p>Stars today: 76 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># INTERCEPT

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.9+-blue.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Python 3.9+&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache--2.0-green.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Apache 2.0 License&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/platform-macOS%20%7C%20Linux-lightgrey.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Platform&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
Support the developer of this open-source project 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/smittix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/assets/img/custom_images/orange_img.png&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Me A Coffee&quot; style=&quot;height: 41px !important;width: 174px !important;box-shadow: 0px 3px 2px 0px rgba(190, 190, 190, 0.5) !important;-webkit-box-shadow: 0px 3px 2px 0px rgba(190, 190, 190, 0.5) !important;&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Signal Intelligence Platform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  A web-based interface for software-defined radio tools.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;static/images/screenshots/intercept-main.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

---

## Features

- **Pager Decoding** - POCSAG/FLEX via rtl_fm + multimon-ng
- **433MHz Sensors** - Weather stations, TPMS, IoT devices via rtl_433
- **Sub-GHz Analyzer** - RF capture and protocol decoding for 300-928 MHz ISM bands via HackRF
- **Aircraft Tracking** - ADS-B via dump1090 with real-time map and radar
- **Vessel Tracking** - AIS ship tracking with VHF DSC distress monitoring
- **ACARS Messaging** - Aircraft datalink messages via acarsdec
- **VDL2** - VHF Data Link Mode 2 aircraft datalink decoding via dumpvdl2
- **Listening Post** - Wideband frequency scanner with real-time audio monitoring
- **Weather Satellites** - NOAA APT and Meteor LRPT image decoding via SatDump with auto-scheduler
- **WebSDR** - Remote HF/shortwave listening via KiwiSDR network
- **ISS SSTV** - Slow-scan TV image reception from the International Space Station
- **HF SSTV** - Terrestrial SSTV on shortwave frequencies (80m-10m, VHF, UHF)
- **APRS** - Amateur packet radio position reports and telemetry via direwolf
- **Satellite Tracking** - Pass prediction with polar plot and ground track map
- **Utility Meters** - Electric, gas, and water meter reading via rtlamr
- **ADS-B History** - Persistent aircraft history with reporting dashboard (Postgres optional)
- **WiFi Scanning** - Monitor mode reconnaissance via aircrack-ng
- **Bluetooth Scanning** - Device discovery and tracker detection (with Ubertooth support)
- **BT Locate** - SAR Bluetooth device location with GPS-tagged signal trail mapping and proximity alerts
- **GPS** - Real-time GPS position tracking with live map, speed, altitude, and satellite info
- **TSCM** - Counter-surveillance with RF baseline comparison and threat detection
- **Meshtastic** - LoRa mesh network integration
- **Space Weather** - Real-time solar and geomagnetic data from NOAA SWPC, NASA SDO, and HamQSL (no SDR required)
- **Spy Stations** - Number stations and diplomatic HF network database
- **Remote Agents** - Distributed SIGINT with remote sensor nodes
- **Offline Mode** - Bundled assets for air-gapped/field deployments

---

## Installation / Debian / Ubuntu / MacOS

**1. Clone and run:**
```bash
git clone https://github.com/smittix/intercept.git
cd intercept
./setup.sh
sudo -E venv/bin/python intercept.py
```

### Docker

```bash
git clone https://github.com/smittix/intercept.git
cd intercept
docker compose --profile basic up -d --build
```

&gt; **Note:** Docker requires privileged mode for USB SDR access. SDR devices are passed through via `/dev/bus/usb`.

#### Multi-Architecture Builds (amd64 + arm64)

Cross-compile on an x64 machine and push to a registry. This is much faster than building natively on an RPi.

```bash
# One-time setup on your x64 build machine
docker run --privileged --rm tonistiigi/binfmt --install all
docker buildx create --name intercept-builder --use --bootstrap

# Build and push for both architectures
REGISTRY=ghcr.io/youruser ./build-multiarch.sh --push

# On the RPi5, just pull and run
INTERCEPT_IMAGE=ghcr.io/youruser/intercept:latest docker compose --profile basic up -d
```

Build script options:

| Flag | Description |
|------|-------------|
| `--push` | Push to container registry |
| `--load` | Load into local Docker (single platform only) |
| `--arm64-only` | Build arm64 only (for RPi deployment) |
| `--amd64-only` | Build amd64 only |

Environment variables: `REGISTRY`, `IMAGE_NAME`, `IMAGE_TAG`

#### Using a Pre-built Image

If you&#039;ve pushed to a registry, you can skip building entirely on the target machine:

```bash
# Set in .env or export
INTERCEPT_IMAGE=ghcr.io/youruser/intercept:latest

# Then just run
docker compose --profile basic up -d
```

### ADS-B History (Optional)

The ADS-B history feature persists aircraft messages to Postgres for long-term analysis.

```bash
# Start with ADS-B history and Postgres
docker compose --profile history up -d
```

Set the following environment variables (for example in a `.env` file):

```bash
INTERCEPT_ADSB_HISTORY_ENABLED=true
INTERCEPT_ADSB_DB_HOST=adsb_db
INTERCEPT_ADSB_DB_PORT=5432
INTERCEPT_ADSB_DB_NAME=intercept_adsb
INTERCEPT_ADSB_DB_USER=intercept
INTERCEPT_ADSB_DB_PASSWORD=intercept
```

### Other ADS-B Settings

Set these as environment variables for either local installs or Docker:

| Variable | Default | Description |
|----------|---------|-------------|
| `INTERCEPT_ADSB_AUTO_START` | `false` | Auto-start ADS-B tracking when the dashboard loads |
| `INTERCEPT_SHARED_OBSERVER_LOCATION` | `true` | Share observer location across ADS-B/AIS/SSTV/Satellite modules |

**Local install example**

```bash
INTERCEPT_ADSB_AUTO_START=true \
INTERCEPT_SHARED_OBSERVER_LOCATION=false \
sudo -E venv/bin/python intercept.py
```

**Docker example (.env)**

```bash
INTERCEPT_ADSB_AUTO_START=true
INTERCEPT_SHARED_OBSERVER_LOCATION=false
```

To store Postgres data on external storage, set `PGDATA_PATH` (defaults to `./pgdata`):

```bash
PGDATA_PATH=/mnt/usbpi1/intercept/pgdata
```

Then open **/adsb/history** for the reporting dashboard.

### Open the Interface

After starting, open **http://localhost:5050** in your browser. The username and password is &lt;b&gt;admin&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;b&gt;admin&lt;/b&gt; 

The credentials can be changed in the ADMIN_USERNAME &amp; ADMIN_PASSWORD variables in config.py

---

## Hardware Requirements

| Hardware | Purpose | Price |
|----------|---------|-------|
| **RTL-SDR** | Required for all SDR features | ~$25-35 |
| **WiFi adapter** | Must support promiscuous (monitor) mode | ~$20-40 |
| **Bluetooth adapter** | Device scanning (usually built-in) | - |
| **GPS** | Any Linux supported GPS Unit | ~10 |

Most features work with a basic RTL-SDR dongle (RTL2832U + R820T2).

| :exclamation:  Not using an RTL-SDR Device?   |
|-----------------------------------------------
|Intercept supports any device that SoapySDR supports. You must however have the correct module for your device installed! For example if you have an SDRPlay device you&#039;d need to install soapysdr-module-sdrplay.

| :exclamation:  GPS Usage   |
|-----------------------------------------------
|gpsd is needed for real time location. Intercept automatically checks to see if you&#039;re running gpsd in the background when any maps are rendered.

---

## Discord Server

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/EyeksEJmWE&quot;&gt;Join our Discord&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


---

## Documentation

- [Usage Guide](docs/USAGE.md) - Detailed instructions for each mode
- [Distributed Agents](docs/DISTRIBUTED_AGENTS.md) - Remote sensor node deployment
- [Hardware Guide](docs/HARDWARE.md) - SDR hardware and advanced setup
- [Troubleshooting](docs/TROUBLESHOOTING.md) - Common issues and solutions
- [Security](docs/SECURITY.md) - Network security and best practices

---

## Disclaimer

This project was developed using AI as a coding partner, combining human direction with AI-assisted implementation. The goal: make Software Defined Radio more accessible by providing a clean, unified interface for common SDR tools.

**This software is for educational and authorized testing purposes only.**

- Only use with proper authorization
- Intercepting communications without consent may be illegal
- You are responsible for compliance with applicable laws

---

## License

Apache 2.0 License - see [LICENSE](LICENSE)

## Author

Created by **smittix** - [GitHub](https://github.com/smittix)

## Acknowledgments

[rtl-sdr](https://osmocom.org/projects/rtl-sdr/wiki) |
[multimon-ng](https://github.com/EliasOenal/multimon-ng) |
[rtl_433](https://github.com/merbanan/rtl_433) |
[dump1090](https://github.com/flightaware/dump1090) |
[AIS-catcher](https://github.com/jvde-github/AIS-catcher) |
[acarsdec](https://github.com/TLeconte/acarsdec) |
[direwolf](https://github.com/wb2osz/direwolf) |
[rtlamr](https://github.com/bemasher/rtlamr) |
[dumpvdl2](https://github.com/szpajder/dumpvdl2) |
[aircrack-ng](https://www.aircrack-ng.org/) |
[Leaflet.js](https://leafletjs.com/) |
[SatDump](https://github.com/SatDump/SatDump) |
[Celestrak](https://celestrak.org/) |
[Priyom.org](https://priyom.org/)










</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenBMB/ChatDev]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ChatDev 2.0: Dev All through LLM-powered Multi-Agent Collaboration]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev">OpenBMB/ChatDev</a></h1>
            <p>ChatDev 2.0: Dev All through LLM-powered Multi-Agent Collaboration</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 31,184</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,854</p>
            <p>Stars today: 47 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># ChatDev 2.0 - DevAll

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;frontend/public/media/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;DevAll Logo&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;A Zero-Code Multi-Agent Platform for Developing Everything&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  【&lt;a href=&quot;./README.md&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;./README-zh.md&quot;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt;】
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    【📚 &lt;a href=&quot;#developers&quot;&gt;Developers&lt;/a&gt; | 👥 &lt;a href=&quot;#primary-contributors&quot;&gt;Contributors&lt;/a&gt;｜⭐️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/chatdev1.0&quot;&gt;ChatDev 1.0 (Legacy)&lt;/a&gt;】
&lt;/p&gt;

## 📖 Overview
ChatDev has evolved from a specialized software development multi-agent system into a comprehensive multi-agent orchestration platform.

- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/main&quot;&gt;**ChatDev 2.0 (DevAll)**&lt;/a&gt; is a **Zero-Code Multi-Agent Platform** for &quot;Developing Everything&quot;. It empowers users to rapidly build and execute customized multi-agent systems through simple configuration. No coding is required—users can define agents, workflows, and tasks to orchestrate complex scenarios such as data visualization, 3D generation, and deep research.
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/chatdev1.0&quot;&gt;**ChatDev 1.0 (Legacy)**&lt;/a&gt; operates as a **Virtual Software Company**. It utilizes various intelligent agents (e.g., CEO, CTO, Programmer) participating in specialized functional seminars to automate the entire software development life cycle—including designing, coding, testing, and documenting. It serves as the foundational paradigm for communicative agent collaboration.

## 🎉 News
• **Jan 07, 2026: 🚀 We are excited to announce the official release of ChatDev 2.0 (DevAll)!** This version introduces a zero-code multi-agent orchestration platform. The classic ChatDev (v1.x) has been moved to the [`chatdev1.0`](https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/chatdev1.0) branch for maintenance. More details about ChatDev 2.0 can be found on [our official post](https://x.com/OpenBMB/status/2008916790399701335).

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Old News&lt;/summary&gt;

•Sep 24, 2025: 🎉 Our paper [Multi-Agent Collaboration via Evolving Orchestration](https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.19591) has been accepted to NeurIPS 2025. The implementation is available in the `puppeteer` branch of this repository.

•May 26, 2025: 🎉 We propose a novel puppeteer-style paradigm for multi-agent collaboration among large language model based agents. By leveraging a learnable central orchestrator optimized with reinforcement learning, our method dynamically activates and sequences agents to construct efficient, context-aware reasoning paths. This approach not only improves reasoning quality but also reduces computational costs, enabling scalable and adaptable multi-agent cooperation in complex tasks.
See our paper in [Multi-Agent Collaboration via Evolving Orchestration](https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.19591).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/puppeteer.png&#039; width=800&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

•June 25, 2024: 🎉To foster development in LLM-powered multi-agent collaboration🤖🤖 and related fields, the ChatDev team has curated a collection of seminal papers📄 presented in a [open-source](https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/main/MultiAgentEbook) interactive e-book📚 format. Now you can explore the latest advancements on the [Ebook Website](https://thinkwee.top/multiagent_ebook) and download the [paper list](https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/blob/main/MultiAgentEbook/papers.csv).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/ebook.png&#039; width=800&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
•June 12, 2024: We introduced Multi-Agent Collaboration Networks (MacNet) 🎉, which utilize directed acyclic graphs to facilitate effective task-oriented collaboration among agents through linguistic interactions 🤖🤖. MacNet supports co-operation across various topologies and among more than a thousand agents without exceeding context limits. More versatile and scalable, MacNet can be considered as a more advanced version of ChatDev&#039;s chain-shaped topology. Our preprint paper is available at [https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07155](https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07155). This technique has been incorporated into the [macnet](https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev/tree/macnet) branch, enhancing support for diverse organizational structures and offering richer solutions beyond software development (e.g., logical reasoning, data analysis, story generation, and more).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/macnet.png&#039; width=500&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• May 07, 2024, we introduced &quot;Iterative Experience Refinement&quot; (IER), a novel method where instructor and assistant agents enhance shortcut-oriented experiences to efficiently adapt to new tasks. This approach encompasses experience acquisition, utilization, propagation and elimination across a series of tasks and making the pricess shorter and efficient. Our preprint paper is available at https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04219, and this technique will soon be incorporated into ChatDev.
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/ier.png&#039; width=220&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• January 25, 2024: We have integrated Experiential Co-Learning Module into ChatDev. Please see the [Experiential Co-Learning Guide](wiki.md#co-tracking).

• December 28, 2023: We present Experiential Co-Learning, an innovative approach where instructor and assistant agents accumulate shortcut-oriented experiences to effectively solve new tasks, reducing repetitive errors and enhancing efficiency.  Check out our preprint paper at https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17025 and this technique will soon be integrated into ChatDev.
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/ecl.png&#039; width=860&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
• November 15, 2023: We launched ChatDev as a SaaS platform that enables software developers and innovative entrepreneurs to build software efficiently at a very low cost and remove the barrier to entry. Try it out at https://chatdev.modelbest.cn/.
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/saas.png&#039; width=560&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• November 2, 2023: ChatDev is now supported with a new feature: incremental development, which allows agents to develop upon existing codes. Try ```--config &quot;incremental&quot; --path &quot;[source_code_directory_path]&quot;``` to start it.
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/increment.png&#039; width=700&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• October 26, 2023: ChatDev is now supported with Docker for safe execution (thanks to contribution from [ManindraDeMel](https://github.com/ManindraDeMel)). Please see [Docker Start Guide](wiki.md#docker-start).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/docker.png&#039; width=400&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
• September 25, 2023: The **Git** mode is now available, enabling the programmer &lt;img src=&#039;visualizer/static/figures/programmer.png&#039; height=20&gt; to utilize Git for version control. To enable this feature, simply set ``&quot;git_management&quot;`` to ``&quot;True&quot;`` in ``ChatChainConfig.json``. See [guide](wiki.md#git-mode).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/github.png&#039; width=600&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• September 20, 2023: The **Human-Agent-Interaction** mode is now available! You can get involved with the ChatDev team by playing the role of reviewer &lt;img src=&#039;visualizer/static/figures/reviewer.png&#039; height=20&gt; and making suggestions to the programmer &lt;img src=&#039;visualizer/static/figures/programmer.png&#039; height=20&gt;;
  try ``python3 run.py --task [description_of_your_idea] --config &quot;Human&quot;``. See [guide](wiki.md#human-agent-interaction) and [example](WareHouse/Gomoku_HumanAgentInteraction_20230920135038).
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#039;./assets/Human_intro.png&#039; width=600&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

• September 1, 2023: The **Art** mode is available now! You can activate the designer agent &lt;img src=&#039;visualizer/static/figures/designer.png&#039; height=20&gt; to generate images used in the software;
  try ``python3 run.py --task [description_of_your_idea] --config &quot;Art&quot;``. See [guide](wiki.md#art) and [example](WareHouse/gomokugameArtExample_THUNLP_20230831122822).
  
• August 28, 2023: The system is publicly available.

• August 17, 2023: The v1.0.0 version was ready for release.

• July 30, 2023: Users can customize ChatChain, Phasea and Role settings. Additionally, both online Log mode and replay
  mode are now supported.

• July 16, 2023: The [preprint paper](https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.07924) associated with this project was published.

• June 30, 2023: The initial version of the ChatDev repository was released.
&lt;/details&gt;


## 🚀 Quick Start

### 📋 Prerequisites

*   **OS**: macOS / Linux / WSL / Windows
*   **Python**: 3.12+
*   **Node.js**: 18+
*   **Package Manager**: [uv](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/)

### 📦 Installation

1.  **Backend Dependencies** (Python managed by `uv`):
    ```bash
    uv sync
    ```

2.  **Frontend Dependencies** (Vite + Vue 3):
    ```bash
    cd frontend &amp;&amp; npm install
    ```

### 🔑 Configuration

*   **Environment Variables**:
    ```bash
    cp .env.example .env
    ```
*   **Model Keys**: Set `API_KEY` and `BASE_URL` in `.env` for your LLM provider.
*   **YAML placeholders**: Use `${VAR}`（e.g., `${API_KEY}`）in configuration files to reference these variables.

### ⚡️ Run the Application

#### Using Makefile (Recommended)

**Start both Backend and Frontent**:
```bash
make dev
```

&gt; Then access the Web Console at **[http://localhost:5173](http://localhost:5173)**.

#### Manual Commands

1.  **Start Backend**:
    ```bash
    # Run from the project root
    uv run python server_main.py --port 6400 --reload
    ```
    &gt; Remove `--reload` if output files (e.g., GameDev) trigger restarts, which interrupts tasks and loses progress.

2.  **Start Frontend**:
    ```bash
    cd frontend
    VITE_API_BASE_URL=http://localhost:6400 npm run dev
    ```
    &gt; Then access the Web Console at **[http://localhost:5173](http://localhost:5173)**. 
    
    
    &gt; **💡 Tip**: If the frontend fails to connect to the backend, the default port `6400` may already be occupied.
    &gt; Please switch both services to an available port, for example:
    &gt;
    &gt; * **Backend**: start with `--port 6401`
    &gt; * **Frontend**: set `VITE_API_BASE_URL=http://localhost:6401`

#### Utility Commands

*   **Help command**:
    ```bash
    make help
    ```

*   **Sync YAML workflows to frontend**:
    ```bash
    make sync
    ```
    Uploads all workflow files from `yaml_instance/` to the database.

*   **Validate all YAML workflows**:
    ```bash
    make validate-yamls
    ```
    Checks all YAML files for syntax and schema errors.

### 🐳 Run with Docker
Alternatively, you can run the entire application using Docker Compose. This method simplifies dependency management and provides a consistent environment.

1.  **Prerequisites**:
    *   [Docker](https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/) and [Docker Compose](https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/) installed.
    *   Ensure you have a `.env` file in the project root for your API keys.

2.  **Build and Run**:
    ```bash
    # From the project root
    docker compose up --build
    ```

3.  **Access**:
    *   **Backend**: `http://localhost:6400`
    *   **Frontend**: `http://localhost:5173`

&gt; The services will automatically restart if they crash, and local file changes will be reflected inside the containers for live development.

---

## 💡 How to Use

### 🖥️ Web Console

The DevAll interface provides a seamless experience for both construction and execution

*   **Tutorial**: Comprehensive step-by-step guides and documentation integrated directly into the platform to help you get started quickly.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/tutorial-en.png&quot;/&gt; 

*   **Workflow**: A visual canvas to design your multi-agent systems. Configure node parameters, define context flows, and orchestrate complex agent interactions with drag-and-drop ease.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/workflow.gif&quot;/&gt;

*   **Launch**: Initiate workflows, monitor real-time logs, inspect intermediate artifacts, and provide human-in-the-loop feedback.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/launch.gif&quot;/&gt;

### 🧰 Python SDK
For automation and batch processing, use our lightweight Python SDK to execute workflows programmatically and retrieve results directly.

```python
from runtime.sdk import run_workflow

# Execute a workflow and get the final node message
result = run_workflow(
    yaml_file=&quot;yaml_instance/demo.yaml&quot;,
    task_prompt=&quot;Summarize the attached document in one sentence.&quot;,
    attachments=[&quot;/path/to/document.pdf&quot;],
    variables={&quot;API_KEY&quot;: &quot;sk-xxxx&quot;} # Override .env variables if needed
)

if result.final_message:
    print(f&quot;Output: {result.final_message.text_content()}&quot;)
```

---

&lt;a id=&quot;developers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
## ⚙️ For Developers

**For secondary development and extensions, please proceed with this section.**

Extend DevAll with new nodes, providers, and tools.
The project is organized into a modular structure:
*   **Core Systems**: `server/` hosts the FastAPI backend, while `runtime/` manages agent abstraction and tool execution.
*   **Orchestration**: `workflow/` handles the multi-agent logic, driven by configurations in `entity/`.
*   **Frontend**: `frontend/` contains the Vue 3 Web Console.
*   **Extensibility**: `functions/` is the place for custom Python tools.

Relevant reference documentation:
*   **Getting Started**: [Start Guide](./docs/user_guide/en/index.md)
*   **Core Modules**: [Workflow Authoring](./docs/user_guide/en/workflow_authoring.md), [Memory](./docs/user_guide/en/modules/memory.md), and [Tooling](./docs/user_guide/en/modules/tooling/index.md)

---

## 🌟 Featured Workflows
We provide robust, out-of-the-box templates for common scenarios. All runnable workflow configs are located in `yaml_instance/`.
*   **Demos**: Files named `demo_*.yaml` showcase specific features or modules.
*   **Implementations**: Files named directly (e.g., `ChatDev_v1.yaml`) are full in-house or recreated workflows. As follows:

### 📋 Workflow Collection

| Category | Workflow                                                                                                    | Case | 
| :--- |:------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------| :--- | 
| **📈 Data Visualization** | `data_visualization_basic.yaml`&lt;br&gt;`data_visualization_enhanced.yaml`                                       | &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cases/data_analysis/data_analysis.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prompt: *&quot;Create 4–6 high-quality PNG charts for my large real-estate transactions dataset.&quot;* |
| **🛠️ 3D Generation**&lt;br&gt;*(Requires [Blender](https://www.blender.org/) &amp; [blender-mcp](https://github.com/ahujasid/blender-mcp))* | `blender_3d_builder_simple.yaml`&lt;br&gt;`blender_3d_builder_hub.yaml`&lt;br&gt;`blender_scientific_illustration.yaml` | &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cases/3d_generation/3d.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prompt: *&quot;Please build a Christmas tree.&quot;* |
| **🎮 Game Dev** | `GameDev_v1.yaml`&lt;br&gt;`ChatDev_v1.yaml`                                                                      | &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cases/game_development/game.gif&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prompt: *&quot;Please help me design and develop a Tank Battle game.&quot;* |
| **📚 Deep Research** | `deep_research_v1.yaml`                                                                                     | &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cases/deep_research/deep_research.gif&quot; width=&quot;85%&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prompt: *&quot;Research about recent advances in the field of LLM-based agent RL&quot;* |
| **🎓 Teach Video** | `teach_video.yaml` (Please run command `uv add manim` before running this workflow)                         | &lt;img src=&quot;assets/cases/video_generation/video.gif&quot; width=&quot;140%&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Prompt: *&quot;讲一下什么是凸优化&quot;* |

---

### 💡 Usage Guide
For those implementations, you can use the **Launch** tab to execute them.
1.  **Select**: Choose a workflow in the **Launch** tab.
2.  **Upload**: Upload necessary files (e.g., `.csv` for data analysis) if required.
3.  **Prompt**: Enter your request (e.g., *&quot;Visualize the sales trends&quot;* or *&quot;Design a snake game&quot;*).

---

## 🤝 Contributing

We welcome contributions from the community! Whether you&#039;re fixing bugs, adding new workflow templates, or sharing high-quality cases/artifacts produced by DevAll, your help is much appreciated. Feel free to contribute by submitting **Issues** or **Pull Requests**.

By contributing to DevAll, you&#039;ll be recognized in our **Contributors** list below. Check out our [Developer Guide](#developers) to get started!

### 👥 Contributors

#### Primary Contributors

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NA-Wen&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/NA-Wen.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;NA-Wen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zxrys&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/zxrys.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;zxrys&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swugi&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/swugi.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;swugi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huatl98&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huatl98.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;huatl98&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

#### Contributors
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shiowen&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/shiowen.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;shiowen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kilo2127&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/kilo2127.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;kilo2127&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AckerlyLau&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/AckerlyLau.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;AckerlyLau&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LaansDole&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/LaansDole.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;LaansDole&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zivkovicp&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/zivkovicp.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;zivkovicp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rainoeelmae&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/rainoeelmae.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;rainoeelmae&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/conprour&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/conprour.png?size=100&quot; width=&quot;64px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;conprour&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

## 🤝 Acknowledgments

&lt;a href=&quot;http://nlp.csai.tsinghua.edu.cn/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/thunlp.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://modelbest.cn/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/modelbest.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/AgentVerse/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/agentverse.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/RepoAgent&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/repoagent.png&quot;  height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.commanddash.io/agent?github=https://github.com/OpenBMB/ChatDev&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/CommandDash.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;www.teachmaster.cn&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/teachmaster.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OpenBMB/AppCopilot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/appcopilot.png&quot; height=50pt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## 🔎 Citation

```
@article{chatdev,
    title = {ChatDev: Communicative Agents for Software Development},
    author = {Chen Qian and Wei Liu and Hongzhang Liu and Nuo Chen and Yufan Dang and Jiahao Li and Cheng Yang and Weize Chen and Yusheng Su and Xin Cong and Juyuan Xu and Dahai Li and Zhiyuan Liu and Maosong Sun},
    journal = {arXiv preprint arXiv:2307.07924},
    url = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.07924},
    year = {2023}
}

@article{colearning,
    title = {Experiential Co-Learning of Software-Developing Agents},
    author = {Chen Qian and Yufan Dang and Jiahao Li and Wei Liu and Zihao Xie and Yifei Wang and Weize Chen and Cheng Yang and Xin Cong and Xiaoyin Che and Zhiyuan Liu and Maosong Sun},
    journal = {arXiv preprint arXiv:2312.17025},
    url = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.17025},
    year = {2023}
}

@article{macnet,
    title={Scaling Large-Language-Model-based Multi-Agent Collaboration},
    author={Chen Qian and Zihao Xie and Yifei Wang and Wei Liu and Yufan Dang a

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[anthropics/claude-code-security-review]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code-security-review</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code-security-review</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An AI-powered security review GitHub Action using Claude to analyze code changes for security vulnerabilities.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code-security-review">anthropics/claude-code-security-review</a></h1>
            <p>An AI-powered security review GitHub Action using Claude to analyze code changes for security vulnerabilities.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,264</p>
            <p>Forks: 258</p>
            <p>Stars today: 73 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Claude Code Security Reviewer

An AI-powered security review GitHub Action using Claude to analyze code changes for security vulnerabilities. This action provides intelligent, context-aware security analysis for pull requests using Anthropic&#039;s Claude Code tool for deep semantic security analysis. See our blog post [here](https://www.anthropic.com/news/automate-security-reviews-with-claude-code) for more details.

## Features

- **AI-Powered Analysis**: Uses Claude&#039;s advanced reasoning to detect security vulnerabilities with deep semantic understanding
- **Diff-Aware Scanning**: For PRs, only analyzes changed files
- **PR Comments**: Automatically comments on PRs with security findings
- **Contextual Understanding**: Goes beyond pattern matching to understand code semantics
- **Language Agnostic**: Works with any programming language
- **False Positive Filtering**: Advanced filtering to reduce noise and focus on real vulnerabilities

## Quick Start

Add this to your repository&#039;s `.github/workflows/security.yml`:

```yaml
name: Security Review

permissions:
  pull-requests: write  # Needed for leaving PR comments
  contents: read

on:
  pull_request:

jobs:
  security:
    runs-on: ubuntu-latest
    steps:
      - uses: actions/checkout@v4
        with:
          ref: ${{ github.event.pull_request.head.sha || github.sha }}
          fetch-depth: 2
      
      - uses: anthropics/claude-code-security-review@main
        with:
          comment-pr: true
          claude-api-key: ${{ secrets.CLAUDE_API_KEY }}
```

## Security Considerations

This action is not hardened against prompt injection attacks and should only be used to review trusted PRs. We recommend [configuring your repository](https://docs.github.com/en/repositories/managing-your-repositorys-settings-and-features/enabling-features-for-your-repository/managing-github-actions-settings-for-a-repository#controlling-changes-from-forks-to-workflows-in-public-repositories) to use the &quot;Require approval for all external contributors&quot; option to ensure workflows only run after a maintainer has reviewed the PR.

## Configuration Options

### Action Inputs

| Input | Description | Default | Required |
|-------|-------------|---------|----------|
| `claude-api-key` | Anthropic Claude API key for security analysis. &lt;br&gt;*Note*: This API key needs to be enabled for both the Claude API and Claude Code usage. | None | Yes |
| `comment-pr` | Whether to comment on PRs with findings | `true` | No |
| `upload-results` | Whether to upload results as artifacts | `true` | No |
| `exclude-directories` | Comma-separated list of directories to exclude from scanning | None | No |
| `claude-model` | Claude [model name](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/about-claude/models/overview#model-names) to use. Defaults to Opus 4.1. | `claude-opus-4-1-20250805` | No |
| `claudecode-timeout` | Timeout for ClaudeCode analysis in minutes | `20` | No |
| `run-every-commit` | Run ClaudeCode on every commit (skips cache check). Warning: May increase false positives on PRs with many commits. | `false` | No |
| `false-positive-filtering-instructions` | Path to custom false positive filtering instructions text file | None | No |
| `custom-security-scan-instructions` | Path to custom security scan instructions text file to append to audit prompt | None | No |

### Action Outputs

| Output | Description |
|--------|-------------|
| `findings-count` | Total number of security findings |
| `results-file` | Path to the results JSON file |

## How It Works

### Architecture

```
claudecode/
├── github_action_audit.py  # Main audit script for GitHub Actions
├── prompts.py              # Security audit prompt templates
├── findings_filter.py      # False positive filtering logic
├── claude_api_client.py    # Claude API client for false positive filtering
├── json_parser.py          # Robust JSON parsing utilities
├── requirements.txt        # Python dependencies
├── test_*.py               # Test suites
└── evals/                  # Eval tooling to test CC on arbitrary PRs
```

### Workflow

1. **PR Analysis**: When a pull request is opened, Claude analyzes the diff to understand what changed
2. **Contextual Review**: Claude examines the code changes in context, understanding the purpose and potential security implications
3. **Finding Generation**: Security issues are identified with detailed explanations, severity ratings, and remediation guidance
4. **False Positive Filtering**: Advanced filtering removes low-impact or false positive prone findings to reduce noise
5. **PR Comments**: Findings are posted as review comments on the specific lines of code

## Security Analysis Capabilities

### Types of Vulnerabilities Detected

- **Injection Attacks**: SQL injection, command injection, LDAP injection, XPath injection, NoSQL injection, XXE
- **Authentication &amp; Authorization**: Broken authentication, privilege escalation, insecure direct object references, bypass logic, session flaws
- **Data Exposure**: Hardcoded secrets, sensitive data logging, information disclosure, PII handling violations
- **Cryptographic Issues**: Weak algorithms, improper key management, insecure random number generation
- **Input Validation**: Missing validation, improper sanitization, buffer overflows
- **Business Logic Flaws**: Race conditions, time-of-check-time-of-use (TOCTOU) issues
- **Configuration Security**: Insecure defaults, missing security headers, permissive CORS
- **Supply Chain**: Vulnerable dependencies, typosquatting risks
- **Code Execution**: RCE via deserialization, pickle injection, eval injection
- **Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)**: Reflected, stored, and DOM-based XSS

### False Positive Filtering

The tool automatically excludes a variety of low-impact and false positive prone findings to focus on high-impact vulnerabilities:
- Denial of Service vulnerabilities
- Rate limiting concerns
- Memory/CPU exhaustion issues
- Generic input validation without proven impact
- Open redirect vulnerabilities

The false positive filtering can also be tuned as needed for a given project&#039;s security goals.

### Benefits Over Traditional SAST

- **Contextual Understanding**: Understands code semantics and intent, not just patterns
- **Lower False Positives**: AI-powered analysis reduces noise by understanding when code is actually vulnerable
- **Detailed Explanations**: Provides clear explanations of why something is a vulnerability and how to fix it
- **Adaptive Learning**: Can be customized with organization-specific security requirements

## Installation &amp; Setup

### GitHub Actions

Follow the Quick Start guide above. The action handles all dependencies automatically.

### Local Development

To run the security scanner locally against a specific PR, see the [evaluation framework documentation](claudecode/evals/README.md).

&lt;a id=&quot;security-review-slash-command&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Claude Code Integration: /security-review Command 

By default, Claude Code ships a `/security-review` [slash command](https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/claude-code/slash-commands) that provides the same security analysis capabilities as the GitHub Action workflow, but integrated directly into your Claude Code development environment. To use this, simply run `/security-review` to perform a comprehensive security review of all pending changes.

### Customizing the Command

The default `/security-review` command is designed to work well in most cases, but it can also be customized based on your specific security needs. To do so: 

1. Copy the [`security-review.md`](https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code-security-review/blob/main/.claude/commands/security-review.md?plain=1) file from this repository to your project&#039;s `.claude/commands/` folder. 
2. Edit `security-review.md` to customize the security analysis. For example, you could add additional organization-specific directions to the false positive filtering instructions. 

## Custom Scanning Configuration

It is also possible to configure custom scanning and false positive filtering instructions, see the [`docs/`](docs/) folder for more details.  

## Testing

Run the test suite to validate functionality:

```bash
cd claude-code-security-review
# Run all tests
pytest claudecode -v
```

## Support

For issues or questions:
- Open an issue in this repository
- Check the [GitHub Actions logs](https://docs.github.com/en/actions/monitoring-and-troubleshooting-workflows/viewing-workflow-run-history) for debugging information

## License

MIT License - see [LICENSE](LICENSE) file for details.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[datawhalechina/hello-agents]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[📚 《从零开始构建智能体》——从零开始的智能体原理与实践教程]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents">datawhalechina/hello-agents</a></h1>
            <p>📚 《从零开始构建智能体》——从零开始的智能体原理与实践教程</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 21,573</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,486</p>
            <p>Stars today: 187 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;./README_EN.md&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | 中文
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/images/hello-agents.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h1&gt;Hello-Agents&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;🤖 《从零开始构建智能体》&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/15520&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/15520&quot; alt=&quot;datawhalechina%2Fhello-agents | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;从基础理论到实际应用，全面掌握智能体系统的设计与实现&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/datawhalechina/Hello-Agents?style=flat&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub stars&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/datawhalechina/Hello-Agents?style=flat&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub forks&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-Chinese-brightgreen?style=flat&quot; alt=&quot;Language&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/datawhalechina/Hello-Agents&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/GitHub-Project-blue?style=flat&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Project&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://datawhalechina.github.io/hello-agents/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/在线阅读-Online%20Reading-green?style=flat&amp;logo=gitbook&quot; alt=&quot;Online Reading&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---

## 🎯 项目介绍

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;如果说 2024 年是&quot;百模大战&quot;的元年，那么 2025 年无疑开启了&quot;Agent 元年&quot;。技术的焦点正从训练更大的基础模型，转向构建更聪明的智能体应用。然而，当前系统性、重实践的教程却极度匮乏。为此，我们发起了 Hello-Agents 项目，希望能为社区提供一本从零开始、理论与实战并重的智能体系统构建指南。

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;Hello-Agents 是 Datawhale 社区的&lt;strong&gt;系统性智能体学习教程&lt;/strong&gt;。如今 Agent 构建主要分为两派，一派是 Dify，Coze，n8n 这类软件工程类 Agent，其本质是流程驱动的软件开发，LLM 作为数据处理的后端；另一派则是 AI 原生的 Agent，即真正以 AI 驱动的 Agent。本教程旨在带领大家深入理解并构建后者——真正的 AI Native Agent。教程将带领你穿透框架表象，从智能体的核心原理出发，深入其核心架构，理解其经典范式，并最终亲手构建起属于自己的多智能体应用。我们相信，最好的学习方式就是动手实践。希望这本教程能成为你探索智能体世界的起点，能够从一名大语言模型的&quot;使用者&quot;，蜕变为一名智能体系统的&quot;构建者&quot;。

## 📚 快速开始

### 在线阅读
**[🌐 点击这里开始在线阅读](https://datawhalechina.github.io/hello-agents/)** - 无需下载，随时随地学习

**[📖 Cookbook](https://book.heterocat.com.cn/)**

### 本地阅读
如果您希望在本地阅读或贡献内容，请参考下方的学习指南。

### ✨ 你将收获什么？

- 📖 &lt;strong&gt;Datawhale 开源免费&lt;/strong&gt; 完全免费学习本项目所有内容，与社区共同成长
- 🔍 &lt;strong&gt;理解核心原理&lt;/strong&gt; 深入理解智能体的概念、历史与经典范式
- 🏗️ &lt;strong&gt;亲手实现&lt;/strong&gt; 掌握热门低代码平台和智能体代码框架的使用
- 🛠️ &lt;strong&gt;自研框架[HelloAgents](https://github.com/jjyaoao/helloagents)&lt;/strong&gt; 基于 Openai 原生 API 从零构建一个自己的智能体框架
- ⚙️ &lt;strong&gt;掌握高级技能&lt;/strong&gt; 一步步实现上下文工程、Memory、协议、评估等系统性技术
- 🤝 &lt;strong&gt;模型训练&lt;/strong&gt; 掌握 Agentic RL，从 SFT 到 GRPO 的全流程实战训练 LLM
- 🚀 &lt;strong&gt;驱动真实案例&lt;/strong&gt; 实战开发智能旅行助手、赛博小镇等综合项目
- 📖 &lt;strong&gt;求职面试&lt;/strong&gt; 学习智能体求职相关面试问题

## 📖 内容导航

| 章节                                                                                        | 关键内容                                      | 状态 |
| ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | --------------------------------------------- | ---- |
| [前言](./docs/前言.md)                                                                      | 项目的缘起、背景及读者建议                    | ✅    |
| &lt;strong&gt;第一部分：智能体与语言模型基础&lt;/strong&gt;                                             |                                               |      |
| [第一章 初识智能体](./docs/chapter1/第一章%20初识智能体.md)                                 | 智能体定义、类型、范式与应用                  | ✅    |
| [第二章 智能体发展史](./docs/chapter2/第二章%20智能体发展史.md)                             | 从符号主义到 LLM 驱动的智能体演进             | ✅    |
| [第三章 大语言模型基础](./docs/chapter3/第三章%20大语言模型基础.md)                         | Transformer、提示、主流 LLM 及其局限          | ✅    |
| &lt;strong&gt;第二部分：构建你的大语言模型智能体&lt;/strong&gt;                                         |                                               |      |
| [第四章 智能体经典范式构建](./docs/chapter4/第四章%20智能体经典范式构建.md)                 | 手把手实现 ReAct、Plan-and-Solve、Reflection  | ✅    |
| [第五章 基于低代码平台的智能体搭建](./docs/chapter5/第五章%20基于低代码平台的智能体搭建.md) | 了解 Coze、Dify、n8n 等低代码智能体平台使用   | ✅    |
| [第六章 框架开发实践](./docs/chapter6/第六章%20框架开发实践.md)                             | AutoGen、AgentScope、LangGraph 等主流框架应用 | ✅    |
| [第七章 构建你的Agent框架](./docs/chapter7/第七章%20构建你的Agent框架.md)                   | 从 0 开始构建智能体框架                       | ✅    |
| &lt;strong&gt;第三部分：高级知识扩展&lt;/strong&gt;                                                     |                                               |      |
| [第八章 记忆与检索](./docs/chapter8/第八章%20记忆与检索.md)                                 | 记忆系统，RAG，存储                           | ✅    |
| [第九章 上下文工程](./docs/chapter9/第九章%20上下文工程.md)                                 | 持续交互的&quot;情境理解&quot;                          | ✅    |
| [第十章 智能体通信协议](./docs/chapter10/第十章%20智能体通信协议.md)                        | MCP、A2A、ANP 等协议解析                      | ✅    |
| [第十一章 Agentic-RL](./docs/chapter11/第十一章%20Agentic-RL.md)                            | 从 SFT 到 GRPO 的 LLM 训练实战                | ✅    |
| [第十二章 智能体性能评估](./docs/chapter12/第十二章%20智能体性能评估.md)                    | 核心指标、基准测试与评估框架                  | ✅    |
| &lt;strong&gt;第四部分：综合案例进阶&lt;/strong&gt;                                                     |                                               |      |
| [第十三章 智能旅行助手](./docs/chapter13/第十三章%20智能旅行助手.md)                        | MCP 与多智能体协作的真实世界应用              | ✅    |
| [第十四章 自动化深度研究智能体](./docs/chapter14/第十四章%20自动化深度研究智能体.md)        | DeepResearch Agent 复现与解析                 | ✅    |
| [第十五章 构建赛博小镇](./docs/chapter15/第十五章%20构建赛博小镇.md)                        | Agent 与游戏的结合，模拟社会动态              | ✅    |
| &lt;strong&gt;第五部分：毕业设计及未来展望&lt;/strong&gt;                                               |                                               |      |
| [第十六章 毕业设计](./docs/chapter16/第十六章%20毕业设计.md)                                | 构建属于你的完整多智能体应用                  | ✅    |

### 社区贡献精选 (Community Blog)

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;欢迎大家将在学习 Hello-Agents 或 Agent 相关技术中的独到见解、实践总结，以 PR 的形式贡献到社区精选。如果是独立于正文的内容，也可以投稿至 Extra-Chapter！&lt;strong&gt;期待你的第一次贡献！&lt;/strong&gt;

| 社区精选                                                                                                                                      | 内容总结                  |
| --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------- |
| [00-共创毕业设计](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Co-creation-projects)                                             | 社区共创毕业设计项目      |
| [01-Agent面试题总结](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra01-面试问题总结.md)                          | Agent 岗位相关面试问题    |
| [01-Agent面试题答案](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra01-参考答案.md)                              | 相关面试问题答案          |
| [02-上下文工程内容补充](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra02-上下文工程补充知识.md)                 | 上下文工程内容扩展        |
| [03-Dify智能体创建保姆级教程](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra03-Dify智能体创建保姆级操作流程.md) | Dify智能体创建保姆级教程  |
| [04-Hello-agents课程常见问题](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra04-DatawhaleFAQ.md)                 | Datawhale课程常见问题     |
| [05-Agent Skills与MCP对比解读](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra05-AgentSkills解读.md)             | Agent Skills与MCP技术对比 |
| [06-GUI Agent科普与实战](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra06-GUIAgent科普与实战.md)                | GUI Agent科普与多场景实战 |
| [07-环境配置](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra07-环境配置.md)                | 环境配置 |
| [08-如何写出好的Skill](https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/blob/main/Extra-Chapter/Extra08-如何写出好的Skill.md) | Skill 写作最佳实践 |

### PDF 版本下载

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;*&lt;strong&gt;本 Hello-Agents PDF 教程完全开源免费。为防止各类营销号加水印后贩卖给多智能体系统初学者，我们特地在 PDF 文件中预先添加了不影响阅读的 Datawhale 开源标志水印，敬请谅解～&lt;/strong&gt;*

&gt; *Hello-Agents PDF : https://github.com/datawhalechina/hello-agents/releases/tag/V1.0.0*  
&gt; *Hello-Agents PDF 国内下载地址 : https://www.datawhale.cn/learn/summary/239* 

## 💡 如何学习

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;欢迎你，未来的智能系统构建者！在开启这段激动人心的旅程之前，请允许我们给你一些清晰的指引。

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;本项目内容兼顾理论与实战，旨在帮助你系统性地掌握从单个智能体到多智能体系统的设计与开发全流程。因此，尤其适合有一定编程基础的 &lt;strong&gt;AI 开发者、软件工程师、在校学生&lt;/strong&gt; 以及对前沿 AI 技术抱有浓厚兴趣的 &lt;strong&gt;自学者&lt;/strong&gt;。在学习本项目之前，我们希望你具备基础的 Python 编程能力，并对大语言模型有基本的概念性了解（例如，知道如何通过 API 调用一个 LLM）。项目的重点是应用与构建，因此你无需具备深厚的算法或模型训练背景。

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;项目分为五大部分，每一部分都是通往下一阶段的坚实阶梯：

- &lt;strong&gt;第一部分：智能体与语言模型基础&lt;/strong&gt;（第一章～第三章），我们将从智能体的定义、类型与发展历史讲起，为你梳理&quot;智能体&quot;这一概念的来龙去脉。随后，我们会快速巩固大语言模型的核心知识，为你的实践之旅打下坚实的理论地基。

- &lt;strong&gt;第二部分：构建你的大语言模型智能体&lt;/strong&gt;（第四章～第七章），这是你动手实践的起点。你将亲手实现 ReAct 等经典范式，体验 Coze 等低代码平台的便捷，并掌握 Langgraph 等主流框架的应用。最终，我们还会带你从零开始构建一个属于自己的智能体框架，让你兼具“用轮子”与“造轮子”的能力。

- &lt;strong&gt;第三部分：高级知识扩展&lt;/strong&gt;（第八章～第十二章），在这一部分，你的智能体将“学会”思考与协作。我们将使用第二部分的自研框架，深入探索记忆与检索、上下文工程、Agent 训练等核心技术，并学习多智能体间的通信协议。最终，你将掌握评估智能体系统性能的专业方法。

- &lt;strong&gt;第四部分：综合案例进阶&lt;/strong&gt;（第十三章～第十五章），这里是理论与实践的交汇点。你将把所学融会贯通，亲手打造智能旅行助手、自动化深度研究智能体，乃至一个模拟社会动态的赛博小镇，在真实有趣的项目中淬炼你的构建能力。

- &lt;strong&gt;第五部分：毕业设计及未来展望&lt;/strong&gt;（第十六章），在旅程的终点，你将迎来一个毕业设计，构建一个完整的、属于你自己的多智能体应用，全面检验你的学习成果。我们还将与你一同展望智能体的未来，探索激动人心的前沿方向。


&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;智能体是一个飞速发展且极度依赖实践的领域。为了获得最佳的学习效果，我们在项目的`code`文件夹内提供了配套的全部代码，强烈建议你&lt;strong&gt;将理论与实践相结合&lt;/strong&gt;。请务必亲手运行、调试甚至修改项目里提供的每一份代码。欢迎你随时关注 Datawhale 以及其他 Agent 相关社区，当遇到问题时，你可以随时在本项目的 issue 区提问。

&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;现在，准备好进入智能体的奇妙世界了吗？让我们即刻启程！

## 下一步规划

- 视频课程陆续放出（将会更加细致，实践课带领大家从设计思路到实施，授人以鱼也授人以渔）
- 完善HelloAgents框架，开展Dev分支继续维护，兼容学习版本。
- 感谢大家助力2W Star! 达到3W Star将会更新续作，《从零开始训练智能体》，帮助每一个学习者掌握从零到一训练自定义场景智能体模型的能力。

## 🤝 如何贡献

我们是一个开放的开源社区，欢迎任何形式的贡献！

- 🐛 &lt;strong&gt;报告 Bug&lt;/strong&gt; - 发现内容或代码问题，请提交 Issue
- 💡 &lt;strong&gt;提出建议&lt;/strong&gt; - 对项目有好想法，欢迎发起讨论
- 📝 &lt;strong&gt;完善内容&lt;/strong&gt; - 帮助改进教程，提交你的 Pull Request
- ✍️ &lt;strong&gt;分享实践&lt;/strong&gt; - 在&quot;社区贡献精选&quot;中分享你的学习笔记和项目

## 🙏 致谢

### 核心贡献者
- [陈思州-项目负责人](https://github.com/jjyaoao) (Datawhale 成员, 全文写作和校对)
- [孙韬-联合发起者](https://github.com/fengju0213) (Datawhale 成员、CAMEL-AI, 第九章内容和校对)  
- [姜舒凡-联合发起者](https://github.com/Tsumugii24)（Datawhale 成员, 章节习题设计和校对）
- [黄佩林-Datawhale意向成员](https://github.com/HeteroCat) (Agent 开发工程师, 第五章内容贡献者)
- [曾鑫民-Agent工程师](https://github.com/fancyboi999) (牛客科技, 第十四章案例开发)
- [朱信忠-指导专家](https://xinzhongzhu.github.io/) (Datawhale首席科学家-浙江师范大学杭州人工智能研究院教授)
### Extra-Chapter 贡献者
- [WH](https://github.com/WHQAQ11) (内容贡献者)
- [周奥杰-DW贡献者团队](https://github.com/thunderbolt-fire) (西安交通大学, Extra02 内容贡献)
- [张宸旭-个人开发者](https://github.com/Tasselszcx)(帝国理工学院, Extra03 内容贡献)
- [黄宏晗-DW贡献者团队](https://github.com/XiaoMa-PM) (深圳大学, Extra04 内容贡献)
- [王大鹏-Datawhale成员](https://github.com/ditingdapeng) (高级研发工程师, Extra08 内容贡献)

### 特别感谢
- 感谢 [@Sm1les](https://github.com/Sm1les) 对本项目的帮助与支持
- 感谢所有为本项目做出贡献的开发者们 ❤️

&lt;div align=center style=&quot;margin-top: 30px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/datawhalechina/Hello-Agents/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=datawhalechina/Hello-Agents&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Star History

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/images/star-history-2026210.png&quot; alt=&quot;Datawhale&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;⭐ 如果这个项目对你有帮助，请给我们一个 Star！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 读者交流群

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./读者群二维码.png&quot; alt=&quot;读者群二维码&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;扫描二维码加入读者交流群，与更多学习者交流讨论&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 关于 Datawhale

&lt;div align=&#039;center&#039;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/images/datawhale.png&quot; alt=&quot;Datawhale&quot; width=&quot;30%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;扫描二维码关注 Datawhale 公众号，获取更多优质开源内容&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---

## 📜 开源协议

本作品采用[知识共享署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 4.0 国际许可协议](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/)进行许可。
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[wagtail/wagtail]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Django content management system focused on flexibility and user experience]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail">wagtail/wagtail</a></h1>
            <p>A Django content management system focused on flexibility and user experience</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,207</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,447</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;.github/wagtail.svg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;.github/wagtail-inverse.svg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;343&quot; src=&quot;.github/wagtail.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Wagtail&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/actions&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/workflows/Wagtail%20CI/badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/licenses/BSD-3-Clause&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-BSD-blue.svg&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/wagtail/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/wagtail.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Version&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/wagtail/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/dm/wagtail?logo=Downloads&quot; alt=&quot;Monthly downloads&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://fosstodon.org/@wagtail&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/mastodon/follow/109308882653647818?domain=https%3A%2F%2Ffosstodon.org&amp;style=social&quot; alt=&quot;Follow @wagtail@fosstodon.org&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

Wagtail is an open source content management system built on Django, with a strong community and commercial support. It&#039;s focused on user experience, and offers precise control for designers and developers.

![Wagtail screenshot](https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/wagtail/wagtail@main/.github/wagtail-screenshot-with-browser.png)

### 🔥 Features

-   A fast, attractive interface for authors
-   Complete control over front-end design and structure
-   Scales to millions of pages and thousands of editors
-   Fast out of the box, cache-friendly when you need it
-   Content API for &#039;headless&#039; sites with decoupled front-end
-   Runs on a Raspberry Pi or a multi-datacenter cloud platform
-   StreamField encourages flexible content without compromising structure
-   Powerful, integrated search, using Elasticsearch or PostgreSQL
-   Excellent support for images and embedded content
-   Multi-site and multi-language ready
-   Embraces and extends Django

Find out more at [wagtail.org](https://wagtail.org/).

### 👉 Getting started

Wagtail works with [Python 3](https://www.python.org/downloads/), on any platform.

To get started with using Wagtail, run the following in a [virtual environment](https://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/venv.html):

![Installing Wagtail](.github/install-animation.gif)

```sh
pip install wagtail
wagtail start mysite
cd mysite
pip install -r requirements.txt
python manage.py migrate
python manage.py createsuperuser
python manage.py runserver
```

For detailed installation and setup docs, see [the getting started tutorial](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/getting_started/tutorial.html).

### 👨‍👩‍👧‍👦 Who’s using it?

Wagtail is used by [NASA](https://www.nasa.gov/), [Google](https://www.google.com/), [Oxfam](https://www.oxfam.org/en), the [NHS](https://www.nhs.uk/), [Mozilla](https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/), [MIT](https://www.mit.edu/), the [Red Cross](https://www.icrc.org/en), [Salesforce](https://www.salesforce.com/), [NBC](https://www.nbc.com/), [BMW](https://www.bmw.com/en/index.html), and the US and UK governments. Add your own Wagtail site to [madewithwagtail.org](https://madewithwagtail.org).

### 📖 Documentation

[docs.wagtail.org](https://docs.wagtail.org/) is the full reference for Wagtail, and includes guides for developers, designers and editors, alongside [release notes](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/releases/) and our [roadmap](https://wagtail.org/roadmap/).

For those who are **new to Wagtail**, the [Zen of Wagtail](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/getting_started/the_zen_of_wagtail.html) will help you understand what Wagtail is, and what Wagtail is _not_.

**For developers** who are ready to jump in to their first Wagtail website the [Getting Started Tutorial](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/getting_started/tutorial.html) will guide you through creating and editing your first page.

**Do you have an existing Django project?** The [Wagtail Integration documentation](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/getting_started/integrating_into_django.html) is the best place to start.

### 📌 Compatibility

_(If you are reading this on GitHub, the details here may not be indicative of the current released version - please see [Compatible Django / Python versions](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/releases/upgrading.html#compatible-django-python-versions) in the Wagtail documentation.)_

Wagtail supports:

-   Django 5.2.x and 6.0.x
-   Python 3.10, 3.11, 3.12, 3.13, and 3.14
-   PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB and SQLite (with JSON1) as database backends

[Previous versions of Wagtail](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/stable/releases/upgrading.html#compatible-django-python-versions) additionally supported Python 2.7, 3.8 and earlier Django versions.

---

### 📢 Community Support

There is an active community of Wagtail users and developers responding to questions on [Stack Overflow](https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/wagtail). When posting questions, please read Stack Overflow&#039;s advice on [how to ask questions](https://stackoverflow.com/help/how-to-ask) and remember to tag your question &quot;wagtail&quot;.

For topics and discussions that do not fit Stack Overflow&#039;s question and answer format we have a [Slack workspace](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/wiki/Slack). Please respect the time and effort of volunteers by not asking the same question in multiple places.

[![Join slack community](.github/join-slack-community.png)](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/wiki/Slack)

Our [GitHub discussion boards](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/discussions) are open for sharing ideas and plans for the Wagtail project.

We maintain a curated list of third party packages, articles and other resources at [Awesome Wagtail](https://github.com/springload/awesome-wagtail).

### 🧑‍💼 Commercial Support

Wagtail is sponsored by [Torchbox](https://torchbox.com/). If you need help implementing or hosting Wagtail, please contact us: hello@torchbox.com. See also [madewithwagtail.org/developers/](https://madewithwagtail.org/developers/) for expert Wagtail developers around the world.

### 🔐 Security

We take the security of Wagtail, and related packages we maintain, seriously. If you have found a security issue with any of our projects please email us at [security@wagtail.org](mailto:security@wagtail.org) so we can work together to find and patch the issue. We appreciate responsible disclosure with any security related issues, so please contact us first before creating a GitHub issue.

If you want to send an encrypted email (optional), the public key ID for security@wagtail.org is 0xbed227b4daf93ff9, and this public key is available from most commonly-used keyservers.

### 🕒 Release schedule

Feature releases of Wagtail are released every three months. Selected releases are designated as Long Term Support (LTS) releases, and will receive maintenance updates for an extended period to address any security and data-loss related issues. For dates of past and upcoming releases and support periods, see [Release Schedule](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/wiki/Release-schedule).

#### 🕛 Nightly releases

To try out the latest features before a release, we also create builds from `main` every night. You can find instructions on how to install the latest nightly release at https://releases.wagtail.org/nightly/index.html

### 🙋🏽 Contributing

If you&#039;re a Python or Django developer, fork the repo and get stuck in! We have several developer focused channels on the [Slack workspace](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/wiki/Slack).

You might like to start by reviewing the [contributing guidelines](https://docs.wagtail.org/en/latest/contributing/index.html) and checking issues with the [good first issue](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/labels/good%20first%20issue) label.

We also welcome translations for Wagtail&#039;s interface. Translation work should be submitted through [Transifex](https://explore.transifex.com/torchbox/wagtail/).

### 🔓 License

[BSD](https://github.com/wagtail/wagtail/blob/main/LICENSE) - Free to use and modify for any purpose, including both open and closed-source code.

### 👏 Thanks

We thank the following organisations for their services used in Wagtail&#039;s development:

[![Browserstack](https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/wagtail/wagtail@main/.github/browserstack-logo.svg)](https://www.browserstack.com/)&lt;br&gt;
[BrowserStack](https://www.browserstack.com/) provides the project with free access to their live web-based browser testing tool, and automated Selenium cloud testing.

[![Assistiv Labs](https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/wagtail/wagtail@main/.github/assistivlabs-logo.png)](https://assistivlabs.com/)&lt;br&gt;
[Assistiv Labs](https://assistivlabs.com/) provides the project with unlimited access to their remote testing with assistive technologies.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix/metaflow]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Netflix/metaflow</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Netflix/metaflow</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Build, Manage and Deploy AI/ML Systems]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Netflix/metaflow">Netflix/metaflow</a></h1>
            <p>Build, Manage and Deploy AI/ML Systems</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,840</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,062</p>
            <p>Stars today: 22 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![Metaflow_Logo_Horizontal_FullColor_Ribbon_Dark_RGB](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/763451/89453116-96a57e00-d713-11ea-9fa6-82b29d4d6eff.png)

# Metaflow

[Metaflow](https://metaflow.org) is a human-centric framework designed to help scientists and engineers **build and manage real-life AI and ML systems**. Serving teams of all sizes and scale, Metaflow streamlines the entire development lifecycle—from rapid prototyping in notebooks to reliable, maintainable production deployments—enabling teams to iterate quickly and deliver robust systems efficiently.

Originally developed at [Netflix](https://netflixtechblog.com/open-sourcing-metaflow-a-human-centric-framework-for-data-science-fa72e04a5d9) and now supported by [Outerbounds](https://outerbounds.com), Metaflow is designed to boost the productivity for research and engineering teams working on [a wide variety of projects](https://netflixtechblog.com/supporting-diverse-ml-systems-at-netflix-2d2e6b6d205d), from classical statistics to state-of-the-art deep learning and foundation models. By unifying code, data, and compute at every stage, Metaflow ensures seamless, end-to-end management of real-world AI and ML systems.

Today, Metaflow powers thousands of AI and ML experiences across a diverse array of companies, large and small, including Amazon, Doordash, Dyson, Goldman Sachs, Ramp, and [many others](ADOPTERS.md). At Netflix alone, Metaflow supports over 3000 AI and ML projects, executes hundreds of millions of data-intensive high-performance compute jobs processing petabytes of data and manages tens of petabytes of models and artifacts for hundreds of users across its AI, ML, data science, and engineering teams.

## From prototype to production (and back)

Metaflow provides a simple and friendly pythonic [API](https://docs.metaflow.org) that covers foundational needs of AI and ML systems:
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/prototype-to-prod.png&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot;&gt;

1. [Rapid local prototyping](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/basics), [support for notebooks](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/managing-flows/notebook-runs), and built-in support for [experiment tracking, versioning](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/client) and [visualization](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/visualizing-results).
2. [Effortlessly scale horizontally and vertically in your cloud](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/remote-tasks/introduction), utilizing both CPUs and GPUs, with [fast data access](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/data) for running [massive embarrassingly parallel](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/basics#foreach) as well as [gang-scheduled](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/remote-tasks/distributed-computing) compute workloads [reliably](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/failures) and [efficiently](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/checkpoint/introduction).
3. [Easily manage dependencies](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/dependencies) and [deploy with one-click](https://docs.metaflow.org/production/introduction) to highly available production orchestrators with built in support for [reactive orchestration](https://docs.metaflow.org/production/event-triggering).

For full documentation, check out our [API Reference](https://docs.metaflow.org/api) or see our [Release Notes](https://github.com/Netflix/metaflow/releases) for the latest features and improvements. 


## Getting started

Getting up and running is easy. If you don&#039;t know where to start, [Metaflow sandbox](https://outerbounds.com/sandbox) will have you running and exploring in seconds.

### Installing Metaflow

To install Metaflow in your Python environment from [PyPI](https://pypi.org/project/metaflow/):

```sh
pip install metaflow
```
Alternatively, using [conda-forge](https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/metaflow):

```sh
conda install -c conda-forge metaflow
```

Once installed, a great way to get started is by following our [tutorial](https://docs.metaflow.org/getting-started/tutorials). It walks you through creating and running your first Metaflow flow step by step.  

For more details on Metaflow’s features and best practices, check out:
- [How Metaflow works](https://docs.metaflow.org/metaflow/basics)  
- [Additional resources](https://docs.metaflow.org/introduction/metaflow-resources)  

If you need help, don’t hesitate to reach out on our [Slack community](http://slack.outerbounds.co/)!


### Deploying infrastructure for Metaflow in your cloud
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/multicloud.png&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot;&gt;


While you can get started with Metaflow easily on your laptop, the main benefits of Metaflow lie in its ability to [scale out to external compute clusters](https://docs.metaflow.org/scaling/remote-tasks/introduction) 
and to [deploy to production-grade workflow orchestrators](https://docs.metaflow.org/production/introduction). To benefit from these features, follow this [guide](https://outerbounds.com/engineering/welcome/) to 
configure Metaflow and the infrastructure behind it appropriately.


## Get in touch
We&#039;d love to hear from you. Join our community [Slack workspace](http://slack.outerbounds.co/)!

## Contributing
We welcome contributions to Metaflow. Please see our [contribution guide](https://docs.metaflow.org/introduction/contributing-to-metaflow) for more details.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🚀 AI 全自动短视频引擎 | AI Fully Automated Short Video Engine]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video">AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video</a></h1>
            <p>🚀 AI 全自动短视频引擎 | AI Fully Automated Short Video Engine</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,539</p>
            <p>Forks: 419</p>
            <p>Stars today: 160 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;🎬 Pixelle-Video —— AI 全自动短视频引擎&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;README_EN.md&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;b&gt;中文&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1WzyGBnEVp/?vd_source=e7e7d4ca8db9a18c80f17a24a6582fca&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/🎥 视频教程-EA4C89&quot; alt=&quot;视频教程&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/releases&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/📦 Windows包-50C878&quot; alt=&quot;Windows整合包&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://aidc-ai.github.io/Pixelle-Video/zh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/📘 使用文档-4A90E2&quot; alt=&quot;使用文档&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/stargazers&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Stargazers&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/issues&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Issues&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/network/members&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Forks&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video.svg&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a42e7457-fcc8-40da-83fc-784c45a8b95d

&lt;br/&gt;

只需输入一个 **主题**，Pixelle-Video 就能自动完成：
- ✍️ 撰写视频文案  
- 🎨 生成 AI 配图/视频  
- 🗣️ 合成语音解说  
- 🎵 添加背景音乐  
- 🎬 一键合成视频  

**零门槛，零剪辑经验**，让视频创作成为一句话的事！


## 🖥️ Web 界面预览

![Web UI界面](resources/webui.png)


## 📋 最近更新

- ✅ **2026-01-26**: 新增「动作迁移」模块，上传参考视频和图片进行动作迁移
- ✅ **2026-01-14**: 新增「数字人口播」和「图生视频」流水线，新增多语言 TTS 音色支持
- ✅ **2026-01-06**: 新增 RunningHub 48G 显存机器调用支持
- ✅ **2025-12-28**: 支持 RunningHub 并发限制可配置，优化 LLM 返回结构化数据的逻辑
- ✅ **2025-12-17**: 支持 ComfyUI API Key 配置，支持 Nano Banana 模型调用，API 接口支持模板自定义参数
- ✅ **2025-12-10**: 侧边栏内置 FAQ，锁定 edge-tts 版本修复 TTS 服务不稳定问题
- ✅ **2025-12-08**: 支持固定脚本多种分割方式(段落/行/句子)，优化模板选择交互逻辑支持直接预览选择
- ✅ **2025-12-06**: 修复视频生成 API 返回 URL 路径处理，支持跨平台兼容
- ✅ **2025-12-05**: 新增 Windows 整合包下载，优化图片与视频反推工作流
- ✅ **2025-12-04**: 新增「自定义素材」功能，支持用户上传自己的照片和视频，AI 智能分析生成脚本
- ✅ **2025-11-18**: 优化 RunningHub 服务调用支持并行处理，新增历史记录页面，支持批量创建视频任务


## ✨ 功能亮点

- ✅ **全自动生成** - 输入主题，自动生成完整视频
- ✅ **AI 智能文案** - 根据主题智能创作解说词，无需自己写脚本
- ✅ **AI 生成配图** - 每句话都配上精美的 AI 插图
- ✅ **AI 生成视频** - 支持使用 AI 视频生成模型（如 WAN 2.1）创建动态视频内容
- ✅ **AI 生成语音** - 支持 Edge-TTS、Index-TTS 等众多主流 TTS 方案
- ✅ **背景音乐** - 支持添加 BGM，让视频更有氛围
- ✅ **视觉风格** - 多种模板可选，打造独特视频风格
- ✅ **灵活尺寸** - 支持竖屏、横屏等多种视频尺寸
- ✅ **多种 AI 模型** - 支持 GPT、通义千问、DeepSeek、Ollama 等
- ✅ **原子能力灵活组合** - 基于 ComfyUI 架构，可使用预置工作流，也可自定义任意能力（如替换生图模型为 FLUX、替换 TTS 为 ChatTTS 等）


## 📊 视频生成流程

Pixelle-Video 采用模块化设计，整个视频生成流程清晰简洁：

![视频生成流程图](resources/flow.png)

从输入文本到最终视频输出，整个流程简洁清晰：**文案生成 → 配图规划 → 逐帧处理 → 视频合成**

每个环节都支持灵活定制，可选择不同的 AI 模型、音频引擎、视觉风格等，满足个性化创作需求。


## 🎬 视频示例

以下是使用 Pixelle-Video 生成的实际案例，展示了不同主题和风格的视频效果：

### 📱 扩展模块视频展示

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;👤 数字人口播&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7c122563-c2e0-4dcd-a73c-25ba1d4fa2dd&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;韩语数字人口播&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🖼️ 图生视频&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/5b4eef17-07d0-4bde-9748-2ed68cc9888e&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;卡通视频&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💃 动作迁移&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7b1240bc-e965-434c-b343-118ec4793d4f&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;跳舞小猫&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


### 📱 竖屏视频展示

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🌄 人文纪实类 - 视频默认模版&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/e6716c1d-78de-453d-84c2-10873c8c595f&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;旅行路上的风景让人流连忘返&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔍 文化解构类 - 视频默认模版&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/f5de75f6-135a-4ab4-9f5f-079f649764d5&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Santa ID&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🔭 科学思辨类 - 视频默认模版&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/ceb8b0df-8331-4e1f-88e7-db5b295a1c1d&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;为什么我们还没有找到外星文明？&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🌱 个人成长类 - 克隆音色&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/1bad9a49-df83-4905-9cc8-9a7640e9c7d8&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;如何提升自己&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🧠 深度思考类 - 默认模板&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/663b705a-2aea-44bc-b266-4bb27aa255a8&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;如何理解反脆弱&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🏯 历史文化类 - 固定画面&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/56e0a018-fa99-47eb-a97f-fc2fa8915724&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;资治通鉴&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;☀️ 情感类 - 克隆音色&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4687df95-dd21-4a7b-b01e-f33a7b646644&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;冬日暖阳&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;📜 小说解说类 - 自创脚本&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d354465e-3fa8-40b4-93e9-61ad75ef0697&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;斗破苍穹&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;33%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🧬 知识科普类 - Qwen生图&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/8ac21768-41ce-4d41-acdd-e3dd3eb9725a&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;养生知识&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

### 🖥️ 横屏视频展示

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;💰 副业赚钱 - 电影模板&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/c9209d4e-73a6-4b82-aaad-cf102248c9e2&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;副业赚钱&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;🏛️ 历史解说 - 自定义模板&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a767c452-d5f1-4cff-bb34-b80fff0d4c3e&quot; controls width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;资治通鉴启示录&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&gt; 💡 **提示**: 这些视频都是通过输入一个主题关键词，由 AI 全自动生成的，无需任何视频剪辑经验！


&lt;div id=&quot;tutorial-start&quot; /&gt;


## 🚀 快速开始

### 🪟 Windows 一键整合包（推荐 Windows 用户使用）

**无需安装 Python、uv 或 ffmpeg，一键开箱即用！**

👉 **[下载 Windows 一键整合包](https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/releases/latest)**

1. 下载最新的 Windows 一键整合包并解压
2. 双击运行 `start.bat` 启动 Web 界面
3. 浏览器会自动打开 http://localhost:8501
4. 在「⚙️ 系统配置」中配置 LLM API 和图像生成服务
5. 开始生成视频！

&gt; 💡 **提示**: 整合包已包含所有依赖，无需手动安装任何环境。首次使用只需配置 API 密钥即可。


### 从源码安装（适合 macOS / Linux 用户或需要自定义的用户）

#### 前置环境依赖

在开始之前，需要先安装 Python 包管理器 `uv` 和视频处理工具 `ffmpeg`：

##### 安装 uv

请访问 uv 官方文档查看适合你系统的安装方法：  
👉 **[uv 安装指南](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/getting-started/installation/)**

安装完成后，在终端中运行 `uv --version` 验证安装成功。

##### 安装 ffmpeg

**macOS**
```bash
brew install ffmpeg
```

**Ubuntu / Debian**
```bash
sudo apt update
sudo apt install ffmpeg
```

**Windows**
- 下载地址：https://ffmpeg.org/download.html
- 下载后解压，将 `bin` 目录添加到系统环境变量 PATH 中

安装完成后，在终端中运行 `ffmpeg -version` 验证安装成功。


#### 第一步：下载项目

```bash
git clone https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video.git
cd Pixelle-Video
```

#### 第二步：启动 Web 界面

```bash
# 使用 uv 运行（推荐，会自动安装依赖）
uv run streamlit run web/app.py
```

浏览器会自动打开 http://localhost:8501

#### 第三步：在 Web 界面配置

首次使用时，展开「⚙️ 系统配置」面板，填写：
- **LLM 配置**: 选择 AI 模型（如通义千问、GPT 等）并填入 API Key
- **图像配置**: 如需生成图片，配置 ComfyUI 地址或 RunningHub API Key

配置好后点击「保存配置」，就可以开始生成视频了！

&lt;div id=&quot;tutorial-end&quot; /&gt;

## 💻 使用方法

打开 Web 界面后，你会看到三栏布局，下面详细讲解每个部分：


### ⚙️ 系统配置（首次必填）

首次使用时需要配置，点击展开「⚙️ 系统配置」面板：

#### 1. LLM 配置（大语言模型）
用于生成视频文案的 AI。

**快速选择预设**  
- 通过下拉菜单选择预设模型（通义千问、GPT-4o、DeepSeek 等）
- 选择后会自动填充 base_url 和 model
- 点击「🔑 获取 API Key」链接去注册并获取密钥

**手动配置**  
- API Key: 填入你的密钥
- Base URL: API 地址
- Model: 模型名称

#### 2. 图像配置
用于生成视频配图的 AI。

**本地部署（推荐）**  
- ComfyUI URL: 本地 ComfyUI 服务地址（默认 http://127.0.0.1:8188）
- 点击「测试连接」确认服务可用

**云端部署**  
- RunningHub API Key: 云端图像生成服务的密钥

配置完成后点击「保存配置」。


### 📝 内容输入（左侧栏）

#### 生成模式
- **AI 生成内容**: 输入主题，AI 自动创作文案
  - 适合：想快速生成视频，让 AI 写稿
  - 例如：「为什么要养成阅读习惯」
- **固定文案内容**: 直接输入完整文案，跳过 AI 创作
  - 适合：已有现成文案，直接生成视频

#### 背景音乐（BGM）
- **无 BGM**: 纯人声解说
- **内置音乐**: 选择预置的背景音乐（如 default.mp3）
- **自定义音乐**: 将你的音乐文件（MP3/WAV 等）放到 `bgm/` 文件夹
- 点击「试听 BGM」可以预览音乐


### 🎤 语音设置（中间栏）

#### TTS 工作流
- 从下拉菜单选择 TTS 工作流（支持 Edge-TTS、Index-TTS 等）
- 系统会自动扫描 `workflows/` 文件夹中的 TTS 工作流
- 如果懂 ComfyUI，可以自定义 TTS 工作流

#### 参考音频（可选）
- 上传参考音频文件用于声音克隆（支持 MP3/WAV/FLAC 等格式）
- 适用于支持声音克隆的 TTS 工作流（如 Index-TTS）
- 上传后可以直接试听

#### 预览功能
- 输入测试文本，点击「预览语音」即可试听效果
- 支持使用参考音频进行预览


### 🎨 视觉设置（中间栏）

#### 图像生成
决定 AI 生成什么风格的配图。

**ComfyUI 工作流**  
- 从下拉菜单选择图像生成工作流
- 支持本地部署（selfhost）和云端（RunningHub）工作流
- 默认使用 `image_flux.json`
- 如果懂 ComfyUI，可以放自己的工作流到 `workflows/` 文件夹

**图像尺寸**  
- 设置生成图像的宽度和高度（单位：像素）
- 默认 1024x1024，可根据需要调整
- 注意：不同的模型对尺寸有不同的限制

**提示词前缀（Prompt Prefix）**  
- 控制图像的整体风格（语言需要是英文的）
- 例如：Minimalist black-and-white matchstick figure style illustration, clean lines, simple sketch style
- 点击「预览风格」可以测试效果

#### 视频模板
决定视频画面的布局和设计。

**模板命名规范**  
- `static_*.html`: 静态模板（无需AI生成媒体，纯文字样式）
- `image_*.html`: 图片模板（使用AI生成的图片作为背景）
- `video_*.html`: 视频模板（使用AI生成的视频作为背景）

**使用方法**  
- 从下拉菜单选择模板，按尺寸分组显示（竖屏/横屏/方形）
- 点击「预览模板」可以自定义参数测试效果
- 如果懂 HTML，可以在 `templates/` 文件夹创建自己的模板
- 🔗 [查看所有模板效果图](https://aidc-ai.github.io/Pixelle-Video/zh/user-guide/templates/#_3)


### 🎬 生成视频（右侧栏）

#### 生成按钮
- 配置好所有参数后，点击「🎬 生成视频」
- 会显示实时进度（生成文案 → 生成配图 → 合成语音 → 合成视频）
- 生成完成后自动显示视频预览

#### 进度显示
- 实时显示当前步骤
- 例如：「分镜 3/5 - 生成插图」

#### 视频预览
- 生成完成后自动播放
- 显示视频时长、文件大小、分镜数等信息
- 视频文件保存在 `output/` 文件夹


### ❓ 常见问题

**Q: 第一次使用需要多久？**  
A: 生成时长取决于视频分镜数量、网络状况和 AI 推理速度，通常几分钟内即可完成。

**Q: 视频效果不满意怎么办？**  
A: 可以尝试：
1. 更换 LLM 模型（不同模型文案风格不同）
2. 调整图像尺寸和提示词前缀（改变配图风格）
3. 更换 TTS 工作流或上传参考音频（改变语音效果）
4. 尝试不同的视频模板和尺寸

**Q: 费用大概多少？**  
A: **本项目完全支持免费运行！**

- **完全免费方案**: LLM 使用 Ollama（本地运行）+ ComfyUI 本地部署 = 0 元
- **推荐方案**: LLM 使用通义千问（成本极低，性价比高）+ ComfyUI 本地部署
- **云端方案**: LLM 使用 OpenAI + 图像使用 RunningHub（费用较高但无需本地环境）

**选择建议**：本地有显卡建议完全免费方案，否则推荐使用通义千问（性价比高）


## 🤝 参考项目

Pixelle-Video 的设计受到以下优秀开源项目的启发：

- [Pixelle-MCP](https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-MCP) - ComfyUI MCP 服务器，让 AI 助手直接调用 ComfyUI
- [MoneyPrinterTurbo](https://github.com/harry0703/MoneyPrinterTurbo) - 优秀的视频生成工具
- [NarratoAI](https://github.com/linyqh/NarratoAI) - 影视解说自动化工具
- [MoneyPrinterPlus](https://github.com/ddean2009/MoneyPrinterPlus) - 视频创作平台
- [ComfyKit](https://github.com/puke3615/ComfyKit) - ComfyUI 工作流封装库

感谢这些项目的开源精神！🙏


## 💬 社区交流

扫描下方二维码加入我们的社区，获取最新动态和技术支持：

| 微信群 | Discord 社区 |
| ---- | ---- |
| &lt;img src=&quot;resources/wechat.png&quot; alt=&quot;微信交流群&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt; | &lt;img src=&quot;resources/discord.png&quot; alt=&quot;Discord 社区&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt; |


## 📢 反馈与支持

- 🐛 **遇到问题**: 提交 [Issue](https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/issues)
- 💡 **功能建议**: 提交 [Feature Request](https://github.com/AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video/issues)
- ⭐ **给个 Star**: 如果这个项目对你有帮助，欢迎给个 Star 支持一下！


## 📝 许可证

本项目采用 Apache 2.0 许可证，详情请查看 [LICENSE](LICENSE) 文件。


## ⭐ Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#AIDC-AI/Pixelle-Video&amp;Date)

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[zou-group/sleepfm-clinical]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/zou-group/sleepfm-clinical</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/zou-group/sleepfm-clinical</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/zou-group/sleepfm-clinical">zou-group/sleepfm-clinical</a></h1>
            <p></p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 554</p>
            <p>Forks: 106</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># SleepFM-Clinical

## 🔥 News &amp; Updates

### 📰 Publication
- **SleepFM** has been published in **Nature Medicine**  
  👉 https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-025-04133-4

### 🤖 Model Releases
- **Pretrained Base Model**  
  `sleepfm/checkpoints/model_base`
- **Finetuned Disease Prediction Model**  
  `sleepfm/checkpoints/model_diagnosis`
- **Finetuned Sleep Staging Model**  
  `sleepfm/checkpoints/model_sleep_staging`

### 📊 Dataset Release
- **Stanford Sleep Dataset**  
  Public release of the Stanford of data used to pretrain **SleepFM**  
  👉 https://bdsp.io/content/08vg8vqv2wdtwonc1ddy/1.0

### 🚀 Demos
- 📓 **End-to-End Inference Demo**  
  `notebooks/demo.ipynb`

## 📖 Introduction

Sleep is a fundamental biological process with broad implications for physical and mental health, yet its complex relationship with disease remains poorly understood. Polysomnography (PSG), the gold standard for sleep analysis, captures rich physiological signals but remains underutilized due to challenges in standardization, generalizability, and multimodal integration. To address these limitations, we developed SleepFM, a multimodal sleep foundation model trained with a novel contrastive learning approach that accommodates multiple PSG montages—the specific arrangements of electrodes and sensors used to record physiological signals during sleep. Trained on a curated dataset of over 585,000 hours of PSG recordings from approximately 65,000 participants across multiple cohorts, SleepFM produces latent sleep representations that capture the physiological and temporal structure of sleep and enable accurate prediction of future disease risk. SleepFM achieved a C-Index of at least 0.75 (Bonferroni-corrected p &lt; 0.01) for 130 conditions, including all-cause mortality (C-Index: 0.84), dementia (0.85), myocardial infarction (0.81), heart failure (0.80), chronic kidney disease (0.79), stroke (0.78), and atrial fibrillation (0.78). Moreover, the model demonstrates strong transfer learning performance on a dataset from the Sleep Heart Health Study (SHHS), a dataset that was excluded from pretraining, and performs competitively with specialized sleep-staging models such as U-Sleep and YASA on common sleep analysis tasks, achieving mean F1 scores of 0.70–0.78 for sleep staging and accuracies of 0.69 and 0.87 for classifying sleep apnea severity and presence. This work shows that foundation models can extract clinically meaningful features from multi-modal sleep recordings, enabling scalable, label-efficient analysis and disease prediction.

# 📖 Table of Contents
1. [Installation](#installation)
2. [Usage](#usage)
3. [Licence](#license)

&lt;a name=&quot;installation&quot;/&gt;

# 💿 Installation

Follow the steps below to set up an environment for running **SleepFM**.

We recommend using **Python 3.10**. All required packages and their specific versions are listed in the [requirements.txt](https://github.com/zou-group/sleepfm-clinical/blob/main/requirements.txt) file. Installing all dependencies should take only **2–3 minutes**.

### 🖥️ System Requirements

SleepFM was developed and tested on Linux systems with the following configuration:

- **GPU**: NVIDIA A40, A100, and RTX 2080 Ti
- **CUDA**: 12.4
- **CPU**: 8 cores recommended
- **RAM**: At least 32 GB
- **OS**: CentOS Linux 7.9.2009 (Core)

Although optimized for **A40/A100** GPUs, the model can be run on smaller GPUs (e.g., **RTX 2080 Ti**) by reducing the batch size. For smooth performance during preprocessing and training, we recommend using at least **8 CPU cores**.

### 🚀 Demo Run

This codebase includes a demo using the **MESA** dataset. On an **NVIDIA A40**, pretraining on MESA for one epoch takes approximately **1 hour**, and fine-tuning for one epoch takes about **1 minute**. Note that **MESA is significantly smaller** than the full dataset used in our main experiments.




```bash
git clone https://github.com/zou-group/sleepfm-clinical.git
cd sleepfm-clinical
conda env create -f env.yml
conda activate sleepfm_env
```

&lt;a name=&quot;usage&quot;/&gt;

# 👩‍💻 Usage

This codebase will serve as a framework that you can adapt to your dataset for pretraining and testing. Below, we outline the steps to pretrain and adapt the model on a publicly available dataset called [MESA](https://sleepdata.org/datasets/mesa). Please keep in mind that this dataset is small and will most likely not yield optimal results.

**Note**: Please make sure to download the dataset with in your local path, with dataset name, `mesa`. Later on, we will need this path. 

## Preprocessing Dataset

PSG files may be stored in different formats. Here, we specifically provide scripts to process .EDF file format.

- **Step 0:** `preprocessing/preprocessing.py`
  - This script converts .EDF file into .hdf5 files with is the format that the model will expect below. 


## Pretraining

Note that we provide with dataset split as json file here: `configs/dataset_split.json`. We also provide with different channel groups within a modality: `configs/channel_groups.json`.

- **Step 1:** `sleepfm/pipeline/pretrain.py`
  - This script has our main pretraining config. Its corresponding config file is inside `configs/config_set_transformer_contrastive.yaml`, where you will set all the parameters and data path. This step will roughly take about an hour for an epoch on `MESA`. 
- **Step 2:** `sleepfm/pipeline/generate_embeddings.py`
  - After pretraining our model, we want to generate the embeddings for train/valid/test so that we can train a model for downstream classification. We do sleep stage classification here. This step will roughly take few minutes on `MESA`. 

## Evaluation

Note: These evaluation results will not match the ones that we have in our paper as this is a small dataset. This step does not require GPU support. 

You should also have extracted the sleep stage labels, which should look like this:

```csv
Start,Stop,StageName,StageNumber
0.0,5190.0,Wake,0
0.0,5190.0,Wake,0,
0.0,5190.0,Wake,0
```

These labels files are stored inside a folder as such `&lt;path&gt;/mesa/mesa-sleep-0001.csv`. Note that `mesa-sleep-0001` is the filename that should correspond with the original `.EDF` file and `.hdf5` files. 

- **Step 3:** `sleepfm/pipelinefinetune_sleep_staging.py`
  - This will finetune the pretrained model on sleep stage classification task. Please make sure to check config `configs/config_finetune_sleep_events.yaml`. This step roughly takes less than a minute on `MESA`. 

- **Step 4:** `sleepfm/pipeline/evaluate_sleep_staging.py`
  - This will evaluate the model on test set. This step only takes few seconds on `MESA`.
 

For disease prediction task:

- **Step 3:** `sleepfm/pipeline/finetune_diagnosis_coxph.py`
  - This will finetune the pretrained model on disease prediction task, using CoxPH loss function. Note that you will need to provide your own data, and set up dataloaders. Please see corresponding config `sleepfm/configs/config_finetune_diagnosis_coxph.yaml`


## BibTeX

```bibtex
@article{thapa2026multimodal,
  title={A multimodal sleep foundation model for disease prediction},
  author={Thapa, Rahul and Kjaer, Magnus Ruud and He, Bryan and Covert, Ian and Moore IV, Hyatt and Hanif, Umaer and Ganjoo, Gauri and Westover, M Brandon and Jennum, Poul and Brink-Kjaer, Andreas and others},
  journal={Nature Medicine},
  pages={1--11},
  year={2026},
  publisher={Nature Publishing Group US New York}
}
```

## License

[MIT License](LICENSE)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[anthropics/skills]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/anthropics/skills</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/anthropics/skills</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Public repository for Agent Skills]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/anthropics/skills">anthropics/skills</a></h1>
            <p>Public repository for Agent Skills</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 74,843</p>
            <p>Forks: 7,721</p>
            <p>Stars today: 832 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&gt; **Note:** This repository contains Anthropic&#039;s implementation of skills for Claude. For information about the Agent Skills standard, see [agentskills.io](http://agentskills.io).

# Skills
Skills are folders of instructions, scripts, and resources that Claude loads dynamically to improve performance on specialized tasks. Skills teach Claude how to complete specific tasks in a repeatable way, whether that&#039;s creating documents with your company&#039;s brand guidelines, analyzing data using your organization&#039;s specific workflows, or automating personal tasks.

For more information, check out:
- [What are skills?](https://support.claude.com/en/articles/12512176-what-are-skills)
- [Using skills in Claude](https://support.claude.com/en/articles/12512180-using-skills-in-claude)
- [How to create custom skills](https://support.claude.com/en/articles/12512198-creating-custom-skills)
- [Equipping agents for the real world with Agent Skills](https://anthropic.com/engineering/equipping-agents-for-the-real-world-with-agent-skills)

# About This Repository

This repository contains skills that demonstrate what&#039;s possible with Claude&#039;s skills system. These skills range from creative applications (art, music, design) to technical tasks (testing web apps, MCP server generation) to enterprise workflows (communications, branding, etc.).

Each skill is self-contained in its own folder with a `SKILL.md` file containing the instructions and metadata that Claude uses. Browse through these skills to get inspiration for your own skills or to understand different patterns and approaches.

Many skills in this repo are open source (Apache 2.0). We&#039;ve also included the document creation &amp; editing skills that power [Claude&#039;s document capabilities](https://www.anthropic.com/news/create-files) under the hood in the [`skills/docx`](./skills/docx), [`skills/pdf`](./skills/pdf), [`skills/pptx`](./skills/pptx), and [`skills/xlsx`](./skills/xlsx) subfolders. These are source-available, not open source, but we wanted to share these with developers as a reference for more complex skills that are actively used in a production AI application.

## Disclaimer

**These skills are provided for demonstration and educational purposes only.** While some of these capabilities may be available in Claude, the implementations and behaviors you receive from Claude may differ from what is shown in these skills. These skills are meant to illustrate patterns and possibilities. Always test skills thoroughly in your own environment before relying on them for critical tasks.

# Skill Sets
- [./skills](./skills): Skill examples for Creative &amp; Design, Development &amp; Technical, Enterprise &amp; Communication, and Document Skills
- [./spec](./spec): The Agent Skills specification
- [./template](./template): Skill template

# Try in Claude Code, Claude.ai, and the API

## Claude Code
You can register this repository as a Claude Code Plugin marketplace by running the following command in Claude Code:
```
/plugin marketplace add anthropics/skills
```

Then, to install a specific set of skills:
1. Select `Browse and install plugins`
2. Select `anthropic-agent-skills`
3. Select `document-skills` or `example-skills`
4. Select `Install now`

Alternatively, directly install either Plugin via:
```
/plugin install document-skills@anthropic-agent-skills
/plugin install example-skills@anthropic-agent-skills
```

After installing the plugin, you can use the skill by just mentioning it. For instance, if you install the `document-skills` plugin from the marketplace, you can ask Claude Code to do something like: &quot;Use the PDF skill to extract the form fields from `path/to/some-file.pdf`&quot;

## Claude.ai

These example skills are all already available to paid plans in Claude.ai. 

To use any skill from this repository or upload custom skills, follow the instructions in [Using skills in Claude](https://support.claude.com/en/articles/12512180-using-skills-in-claude#h_a4222fa77b).

## Claude API

You can use Anthropic&#039;s pre-built skills, and upload custom skills, via the Claude API. See the [Skills API Quickstart](https://docs.claude.com/en/api/skills-guide#creating-a-skill) for more.

# Creating a Basic Skill

Skills are simple to create - just a folder with a `SKILL.md` file containing YAML frontmatter and instructions. You can use the **template-skill** in this repository as a starting point:

```markdown
---
name: my-skill-name
description: A clear description of what this skill does and when to use it
---

# My Skill Name

[Add your instructions here that Claude will follow when this skill is active]

## Examples
- Example usage 1
- Example usage 2

## Guidelines
- Guideline 1
- Guideline 2
```

The frontmatter requires only two fields:
- `name` - A unique identifier for your skill (lowercase, hyphens for spaces)
- `description` - A complete description of what the skill does and when to use it

The markdown content below contains the instructions, examples, and guidelines that Claude will follow. For more details, see [How to create custom skills](https://support.claude.com/en/articles/12512198-creating-custom-skills).

# Partner Skills

Skills are a great way to teach Claude how to get better at using specific pieces of software. As we see awesome example skills from partners, we may highlight some of them here:

- **Notion** - [Notion Skills for Claude](https://www.notion.so/notiondevs/Notion-Skills-for-Claude-28da4445d27180c7af1df7d8615723d0)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[sansan0/TrendRadar]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[⭐AI-driven public opinion & trend monitor with multi-platform aggregation, RSS, and smart alerts.🎯 告别信息过载，你的 AI 舆情监控助手与热点筛选工具！聚合多平台热点 + RSS 订阅，支持关键词精准筛选。AI 翻译 + AI 分析简报直推手机，也支持接入 MCP 架构，赋能 AI 自然语言对话分析、情感洞察与趋势预测等。支持 Docker ，数据本地/云端自持。集成微信/飞书/钉钉/Telegram/邮件/ntfy/bark/slack 等渠道智能推送。]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar">sansan0/TrendRadar</a></h1>
            <p>⭐AI-driven public opinion & trend monitor with multi-platform aggregation, RSS, and smart alerts.🎯 告别信息过载，你的 AI 舆情监控助手与热点筛选工具！聚合多平台热点 + RSS 订阅，支持关键词精准筛选。AI 翻译 + AI 分析简报直推手机，也支持接入 MCP 架构，赋能 AI 自然语言对话分析、情感洞察与趋势预测等。支持 Docker ，数据本地/云端自持。集成微信/飞书/钉钉/Telegram/邮件/ntfy/bark/slack 等渠道智能推送。</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 47,124</p>
            <p>Forks: 22,340</p>
            <p>Stars today: 134 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;trendradar&quot;&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar&quot; title=&quot;TrendRadar&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/_image/banner.webp&quot; alt=&quot;TrendRadar Banner&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

最快&lt;strong&gt;30秒&lt;/strong&gt;部署的热点助手 —— 告别无效刷屏，只看真正关心的新闻资讯

&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/14726&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/14726&quot; alt=&quot;sansan0%2FTrendRadar | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;


[![GitHub Stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/sansan0/TrendRadar?style=flat-square&amp;logo=github&amp;color=yellow)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar/stargazers)
[![GitHub Forks](https://img.shields.io/github/forks/sansan0/TrendRadar?style=flat-square&amp;logo=github&amp;color=blue)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar/network/members)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-GPL--3.0-blue.svg?style=flat-square)](LICENSE)
[![Version](https://img.shields.io/badge/version-v6.0.0-blue.svg)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar)
[![MCP](https://img.shields.io/badge/MCP-v4.0.0-green.svg)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar)
[![RSS](https://img.shields.io/badge/RSS-订阅源支持-orange.svg?style=flat-square&amp;logo=rss&amp;logoColor=white)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar)
[![AI翻译](https://img.shields.io/badge/AI-多语言推送-purple.svg?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar)

[![企业微信通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/企业微信-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://work.weixin.qq.com/)
[![个人微信通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/个人微信-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://weixin.qq.com/)
[![Telegram通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/Telegram-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://telegram.org/)
[![dingtalk通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/钉钉-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](#)
[![飞书通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/飞书-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://www.feishu.cn/)
[![邮件通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/Email-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](#)
[![ntfy通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/ntfy-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/binwiederhier/ntfy)
[![Bark通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/Bark-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/Finb/Bark)
[![Slack通知](https://img.shields.io/badge/Slack-通知-00D4AA?style=flat-square)](https://slack.com/)
[![通用Webhook](https://img.shields.io/badge/通用-Webhook-607D8B?style=flat-square&amp;logo=webhook&amp;logoColor=white)](#)


[![GitHub Actions](https://img.shields.io/badge/GitHub_Actions-自动化-2088FF?style=flat-square&amp;logo=github-actions&amp;logoColor=white)](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar)
[![GitHub Pages](https://img.shields.io/badge/GitHub_Pages-部署-4285F4?style=flat-square&amp;logo=github&amp;logoColor=white)](https://sansan0.github.io/TrendRadar)
[![Docker](https://img.shields.io/badge/Docker-部署-2496ED?style=flat-square&amp;logo=docker&amp;logoColor=white)](https://hub.docker.com/r/wantcat/trendradar)
[![MCP Support](https://img.shields.io/badge/MCP-AI分析支持-FF6B6B?style=flat-square&amp;logo=ai&amp;logoColor=white)](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/)
[![AI分析推送](https://img.shields.io/badge/AI-分析推送-FF6B6B?style=flat-square&amp;logo=openai&amp;logoColor=white)](#)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

**中文** | **[English](README-EN.md)**

&lt;/div&gt;

&gt; 本项目以轻量，易部署为目标

&lt;br&gt;

## 📑 快速导航

&gt; 💡 **点击下方链接**可快速跳转到对应章节。部署推荐从「**快速开始**」入手，需要详细自定义请看「**配置详解**」

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

|   |   |   |
|:---:|:---:|:---:|
| [🚀 **快速开始**](#-快速开始) | [AI 智能分析](#-ai-智能分析) | [⚙️ **配置详解**](#配置详解) |
| [Docker部署](#6-docker-部署) | [MCP客户端](#-mcp-客户端) | [📝 **更新日志**](#-更新日志) |
| [🎯 **核心功能**](#-核心功能) | [☕ **支持项目**](#-支持项目) | [📚 **项目相关**](#-项目相关) |

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

- 感谢**为项目点 star** 的观众们，**fork** 你所欲也，**star** 我所欲也，两者得兼😍是对开源精神最好的支持

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;👉 点击展开：&lt;strong&gt;致谢名单&lt;/strong&gt; (天使轮荣誉榜 🔥73+🔥 位)&lt;/summary&gt;

### 早期支持者致谢

&gt; 💡 **特别说明**：
&gt;
&gt; 1. **关于名单**：下方表格记录了项目起步阶段（天使轮）的支持者。因早期人工统计繁琐，**难免存在疏漏或记录不全的情况，如有遗漏，实非本意，万望海涵**。
&gt; 2. **未来规划**：为了将有限的精力回归代码与功能迭代，**即日起不再人工维护此名单**。
&gt;
&gt; 无论名字是否上榜，你们的每一份支持都是 TrendRadar 能够走到今天的基石。🙏

### 基础设施支持

感谢 **GitHub** 免费提供的基础设施，这是本项目得以**一键 fork**便捷运行的最大前提。

### 数据支持

本项目使用 [newsnow](https://github.com/ourongxing/newsnow) 项目的 API 获取多平台数据，特别感谢作者提供的服务。

经联系，作者表示无需担心服务器压力，但这是基于他的善意和信任。请大家：
- **前往 [newsnow 项目](https://github.com/ourongxing/newsnow) 点 star 支持**
- Docker 部署时，请合理控制推送频率，勿竭泽而渔

### 推广助力

&gt; 感谢以下平台和个人的推荐(按时间排列)

- [小众软件](https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/fvutkJ_NPUelSW9OGK39aA) - 开源软件推荐平台
- [LinuxDo 社区](https://linux.do/) - 技术爱好者的聚集地
- [阮一峰周刊](https://github.com/ruanyf/weekly) - 技术圈有影响力的周刊

### 观众支持

&gt; 感谢**给予资金支持**的朋友们，你们的慷慨已化身为键盘旁的零食饮料，陪伴着项目的每一次迭代。
&gt;
&gt; **关于&quot;一元点赞&quot;的回归**：
&gt; 随着 v5.0.0 版本的发布，项目迈入了一个新的阶段。为了支持日益增长的 API 成本和咖啡因消耗，&quot;一元点赞&quot;通道现已重新开启。你的每一份心意，都将转化为代码世界里的 Token 和动力。🚀 [前往支持](#-支持项目)

|           点赞人            |  金额  |  日期  |             备注             |
| :-------------------------: | :----: | :----: | :-----------------------: |
|           D*5          |  1.8 * 3 | 2025.11.24  |    | 
|           *鬼          |  1 | 2025.11.17  |    | 
|           *超          |  10 | 2025.11.17  |    | 
|           R*w          |  10 | 2025.11.17  | 这 agent 做的牛逼啊,兄弟    | 
|           J*o          |  1 | 2025.11.17  | 感谢开源,祝大佬事业有成    | 
|           *晨          |  8.88  | 2025.11.16  | 项目不错,研究学习中    | 
|           *海          |  1  | 2025.11.15  |    | 
|           *德          |  1.99  | 2025.11.15  |    | 
|           *疏          |  8.8  | 2025.11.14  |  感谢开源，项目很棒，支持一下   | 
|           M*e          |  10  | 2025.11.14  |  开源不易，大佬辛苦了   | 
|           **柯          |  1  | 2025.11.14  |     | 
|           *云          |  88  | 2025.11.13  |    好项目，感谢开源  | 
|           *W          |  6  | 2025.11.13  |      | 
|           *凯          |  1  | 2025.11.13  |      | 
|           对*.          |  1  | 2025.11.13  |    Thanks for your TrendRadar  | 
|           s*y          |  1  | 2025.11.13  |      | 
|           **翔          |  10  | 2025.11.13  |   好项目，相见恨晚，感谢开源！     | 
|           *韦          |  9.9  | 2025.11.13  |   TrendRadar超赞，请老师喝咖啡~     | 
|           h*p          |  5  | 2025.11.12  |   支持中国开源力量，加油！     | 
|           c*r          |  6  | 2025.11.12  |        | 
|           a*n          |  5  | 2025.11.12  |        | 
|           。*c          |  1  | 2025.11.12  |    感谢开源分享    | 
|           *记          |  1  | 2025.11.11  |        | 
|           *主          |  1  | 2025.11.10  |        | 
|           *了          |  10  | 2025.11.09  |        | 
|           *杰          |  5  | 2025.11.08  |        | 
|           *点          |  8.80  | 2025.11.07  |   开发不易，支持一下。     | 
|           Q*Q          |  6.66  | 2025.11.07  |   感谢开源！     | 
|           C*e          |  1  | 2025.11.05  |        | 
|           Peter Fan          |  20  | 2025.10.29  |        | 
|           M*n          |  1  | 2025.10.27  |      感谢开源  | 
|           *许          |  8.88  | 2025.10.23  |      老师 小白一枚，摸了几天了还没整起来，求教  | 
|           Eason           |  1  | 2025.10.22  |      还没整明白，但你在做好事  | 
|           P*n           |  1  | 2025.10.20  |          |
|           *杰           |  1  | 2025.10.19  |          |
|           *徐           |  1  | 2025.10.18  |          |
|           *志           |  1  | 2025.10.17  |          |
|           *😀           |  10  | 2025.10.16  |     点赞     |
|           **杰           |  10  | 2025.10.16  |          |
|           *啸           |  10  | 2025.10.16  |          |
|           *纪           |  5  | 2025.10.14  | TrendRadar         |
|           J*d           |  1  | 2025.10.14  | 谢谢你的工具，很好玩...          |
|           *H           |  1  | 2025.10.14  |           |
|           那*O           |  10  | 2025.10.13  |           |
|           *圆           |  1  | 2025.10.13  |           |
|           P*g           |  6  | 2025.10.13  |           |
|           Ocean           |  20  | 2025.10.12  |  ...真的太棒了！！！小白级别也能直接用...         |
|           **培           |  5.2  | 2025.10.2  |  github-yzyf1312:开源万岁         |
|           *椿           |  3  | 2025.9.23  |  加油，很不错         |
|           *🍍           |  10  | 2025.9.21  |           |
|           E*f           |  1  | 2025.9.20  |           |
|           *记            |  1  | 2025.9.20  |           |
|           z*u            |  2  | 2025.9.19  |           |
|           **昊            |  5  | 2025.9.17  |           |
|           *号            |  1  | 2025.9.15  |           |
|           T*T            |  2  | 2025.9.15  |  点赞         |
|           *家            |  10  | 2025.9.10  |           |
|           *X            |  1.11  | 2025.9.3  |           |
|           *飙            |  20  | 2025.8.31  |  来自老童谢谢         |
|           *下            |  1  | 2025.8.30  |           |
|           2*D            |  88  | 2025.8.13 下午 |           |
|           2*D            |  1  | 2025.8.13 上午 |           |
|           S*o            |  1  | 2025.8.05 |   支持一下        |
|           *侠            |  10  | 2025.8.04 |           |
|           x*x            |  2  | 2025.8.03 |  trendRadar 好项目 点赞          |
|           *远            |  1  | 2025.8.01 |            |
|           *邪            |  5  | 2025.8.01 |            |
|           *梦            |  0.1  | 2025.7.30 |            |
|           **龙            |  10  | 2025.7.29 |      支持一下      |


&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

## 🪄 赞助商

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&gt; **虚位以待**

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;-支持项目&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

### ❤️ 觉得好用？支持一下

&gt; 若 TrendRadar 曾为你捕捉价值，不妨为它注入动力，助其持续进化
&gt;
&gt; 金额随意，1 元也是对开源的鼓励。欢迎在赞赏时备注留言 (´▽`ʃ♡ƪ)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

| 微信赞赏 | 支付宝赞赏 |
|:---:|:---:|
| &lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-1258574687.cos.ap-shanghai.myqcloud.com/img/%2F2025%2F07%2F17%2F2ae0a88d98079f7e876c2b4dc85233c6-9e8025.JPG&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;微信赞赏&quot;&gt; | &lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-1258574687.cos.ap-shanghai.myqcloud.com/img/%2F2025%2F07%2F17%2F1ed4f20ab8e35be51f8e84c94e6e239b4-fe4947.JPG&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;支付宝赞赏&quot;&gt; |

&lt;/div&gt;


### 🤝 二次开发与引用

如果你在项目中使用或借鉴了本项目的思路、核心代码，**非常欢迎**在 README 或文档中注明来源并附上本仓库链接。

这将有助于项目的持续维护和社区发展，感谢你的尊重与支持！❤️


### 💬 交流与反馈

- **GitHub Issues**：适合具体的技术问题。提问时请提供完整信息（截图、错误日志等），有助于快速定位。
- **公众号交流**：建议优先在相关文章下的留言区交流。若需后台提问，**先点赞/推荐**文章是最好的“敲门砖”，我在后台都能感受到这份心意哟 (´▽`ʃ♡ƪ)。

&gt; **友情提示**：        
&gt; 本项目为开源分享，非商业产品。把作者当朋友而非客服，沟通效率会更高哦！     

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

|公众号关注 |
|:---:|
| &lt;img src=&quot;_image/weixin.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; title=&quot;硅基茶水间&quot;/&gt; |

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

## 📝 更新日志

&gt; **📌 查看最新更新**：**[原仓库更新日志](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar?tab=readme-ov-file#-更新日志)** ：
- **提示**：建议查看【历史更新】，明确具体的【功能内容】


### 2026/02/09 - v6.0.0

&gt; **Breaking Change**：配置文件升级（config.yaml 2.0.0），旧版 `push_window` 和 `analysis_window` 配置不再兼容，请参考新版 config.yaml 迁移

- **统一调度系统**：新增 `timeline.yaml`，用一套配置控制「什么时间采集 / 推送 / AI 分析」
- **5 种预设模板**：`always_on`（全天候，默认）、`morning_evening`（早晚汇总）、`office_hours`（办公时间）、`night_owl`（夜猫子）、`custom`（自定义）；也支持在 `presets:` 下新增自己的模板，只要 key 不重复，然后在 config.yaml 里填你的模板名即可
- **灵活的时间段配置**：支持工作日/周末差异化、跨午夜时间段、per-period once 去重
- **可视化配置编辑器**：
  - 新增 `timeline.yaml` 编辑标签页，与 config.yaml / frequency_words.txt 并列
  - 预设模式卡片选择：点击即切换，自动同步 config.yaml 的 `schedule.preset`
  - 周视图时间线：7 天 × 24 小时水平条，用颜色区分推送/分析/采集状态
  - 可交互控件：开关、下拉框、时间选择器，右侧修改实时同步到左侧 YAML
  - 周映射下拉选择：根据日计划动态填充，拖拉点击即可完成调度配置
- **AI 提示词稳定性优化**（ai_analysis_prompt.txt v2.0.0）：
  - 格式规范独立说明：将换行/标签/序号/禁止事项从 JSON value 中抽出，作为独立章节
  - JSON 模板简化：字段描述缩短为一句话 + 字数限制，减少 AI 输出格式混乱
  - 去除 system prompt 中的 Markdown 格式，与&quot;禁止 Markdown&quot;指令保持一致
  - 所有 JSON 字段声明为可选，缺少任何字段不会报错，增强容错性
- **新增独立展示区 AI 概括分析**（`ai_analysis.include_standalone`）：
  - 新增独立开关，开启后 AI 对每个 standalone 源生成核心概括
  - AI 分析与推送展示解耦：无需开启独立展示区的推送显示，AI 也可独立分析完整热榜数据
  - 支持热榜平台和 RSS 源，含排名/时间/轨迹数据
  - 轨迹分析与 `include_rank_timeline` 联动：开启时利用轨迹数据做深度趋势分析，关闭时基于排名做简要判断
  - 新增 `standalone_summaries` JSON 字段（独立源点速览），所有推送渠道均已适配渲染


### 2026/02/09 - mcp-v4.0.0

- **🔥 AI 消息直推所有渠道**：让 AI 写好的内容一键推送到飞书、钉钉、Telegram、邮件等 9 个渠道，Markdown 自动适配各平台格式，不用操心格式差异
- **新增格式化策略指南**：新增 `get_channel_format_guide` 工具，告诉 AI 每个渠道支持什么格式、有什么限制，生成的内容排版更好看
- **智能分批发送**：超长消息自动按各渠道字节限制拆分（飞书 30KB、钉钉 20KB 等），配置读取自 config.yaml
- **修复渠道误检测**：ntfy 不再因为默认地址被误报为&quot;已配置&quot;
- **代码复用优化**：批次处理函数直接复用 trendradar 核心模块，不重复造轮子


&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;👉 点击展开：&lt;strong&gt;历史更新&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;


### 2026/01/28 - v5.5.0

&gt; 和 mcp 功能一样, 这个小工具我也不新开一个仓库维护了, 反正纯前端, 都搁一起吧

- 增加 trendradar 的可视化配置编辑器


### 2026/02/02 - mcp-v3.2.0

- **新增 read_article 工具**：通过 Jina AI Reader 读取单篇文章正文（Markdown 格式）
- **新增 read_articles_batch 工具**：批量读取多篇文章（最多 5 篇，自动限速）
- **推荐工作流**：`search_news(query=&quot;关键词&quot;, include_url=True)` → `read_article(url=...)` 读取正文
- **文档更新**：README-MCP-FAQ.md 和 README-MCP-FAQ-EN.md 新增 Q19-Q20 文章读取相关说明


### 2026/01/10 - mcp-v3.0.0~v3.1.5

- **Breaking Change**：所有工具返回值统一为 `{success, summary, data, error}` 结构
- **异步一致性**：所有 21 个工具函数使用 `asyncio.to_thread()` 包装同步调用
- **MCP Resources**：新增 4 个资源（platforms、rss-feeds、available-dates、keywords）
- **RSS 增强**：`get_latest_rss` 支持多日查询（days 参数），跨日期 URL 去重
- **正则匹配修复**：`get_trending_topics` 支持 `/pattern/` 正则语法和 `display_name`
- **缓存优化**：新增 `make_cache_key()` 函数，参数排序+MD5 哈希确保一致性
- **新增 check_version 工具**：支持同时检查 TrendRadar 和 MCP Server 版本更新


### 2026/01/23 - v5.4.0

- 增加 AI 分析模式的独立控制功能，可选 follow_report | daily | current | incremental 
- 新增 AI 分析时间窗口控制，支持自定义运行段及每日频次限制
- 增加配置文件版本管理功能
- 修复若干bug


### 2026/01/19 - v5.3.0

&gt; **重大重构：AI 模块迁移至 LiteLLM**

- **统一 AI 接口**：使用 LiteLLM 替代手动实现，支持 100+ AI 提供商
- **简化配置**：移除 `provider` 字段，改用 `model: &quot;provider/model_name&quot;` 格式
- **新增功能**：自动重试 (`num_retries`)、备用模型 (`fallback_models`)
- **配置变更**：
  - `ai.provider` → 移除（已合并到 model）
  - `ai.base_url` → `ai.api_base`
  - `AI_PROVIDER` 环境变量 → 移除
  - `AI_BASE_URL` 环境变量 → `AI_API_BASE`
- **模型格式示例**：
  - DeepSeek: `deepseek/deepseek-chat`
  - OpenAI: `openai/gpt-4o`
  - Gemini: `gemini/gemini-2.5-flash`
  - Anthropic: `anthropic/claude-3-5-sonnet`

### 2026/01/17 - v5.2.0

&gt; 主要见 config.yaml 描述

**🌐 AI 翻译功能**

- **多语言翻译**：支持将推送内容翻译为任意语言
- **批量翻译**：智能批量处理，减少 API 调用次数
- **自定义提示词**：支持自定义翻译风格

**🔧 配置架构优化**

- **AI 模型配置独立**：分析和翻译共享模型配置
- **区域开关统一**：统一管理推送区域显示
- **区域排序自定义**：支持自定义各区域的显示顺序

**✨ AI 分析增强**

- **AI 分析嵌入 HTML**：分析结果直接嵌入 HTML 报告，邮件通知直接使用
- **富样式 AI 区块**：渐变蓝色背景卡片式布局，清晰分隔各分析维度
- **排名时间线支持**：AI 可获取每条新闻在每个抓取时间点的精确排名
- **板块重组 (7→4)**：整合为核心热点态势、舆论风向争议、异动与弱信号、研判策略建议

**🔧 多模型适配**

- **通用参数透传**：支持向 API 透传任意高级参数
- **Gemini 适配**：原生参数支持，内置安全策略放宽

**🐛 Bug 修复**

- 修复若干已知问题，提升系统稳定性

### 2026/01/10 - v5.0.0

&gt; **开发小插曲**：
&gt; 致敬那个陪伴我两年多、却在刚续费后反手弹出 `&quot;This organization has been disabled&quot;` 的某 C 厂模型

**✨ 推送内容&quot;五大板块&quot;重构**

本次更新对推送消息进行了区域化重构，现在推送内容清晰地划分为五大核心板块：

1.  **📊 热榜新闻**：根据你的关键词精准筛选后的全网热点聚合。
2.  **📰 RSS 订阅**：你的个性化订阅源内容，支持按关键词分组。
3.  **🆕 本次新增**：实时捕捉自上次运行以来的全新热点（带 🆕 标记）。
4.  **📋 独立展示区**：指定平台的完整热榜或 RSS 源展示，**完全不受关键词过滤限制**。
5.  **✨ AI 分析板块**：由 AI 驱动的深度洞察，包含趋势概述、热度走势及**极其重要**的情感倾向分析。

**✨ AI 智能分析推送功能**

- **AI 分析集成**：使用 AI 大模型对推送内容进行深度分析，自动生成热点趋势概述、关键词热度分析、跨平台关联、潜在影响评估等
- **情感倾向分析**：新增深度情感识别，精准捕捉舆论的正负面、争议或担忧情绪
- **多 AI 提供商支持**：支持 DeepSeek（默认，性价比高）、OpenAI、Google Gemini 及任意 OpenAI 兼容接口
- **两种推送模式**：`only_analysis`（仅 AI 分析）、`both`（两者都推送）
- **自定义提示词**：通过 `config/ai_analysis_prompt.txt` 文件自定义 AI 分析角色和输出格式
- **多维度数据分析**：AI 可分析排名变化、热度持续时间、跨平台表现、趋势预测等

**📋 独立展示区功能**

- **完整热榜展示**：指定平台的完整热榜单独展示，不受关键词过滤影响
- **RSS 独立展示**：RSS 源内容可完整展示，适合内容较少的订阅源
- **灵活配置**：支持配置展示平台列表、RSS 源列表、最大展示条数

**📊 推送体验重构**

- **排版升级**：重新设计并统一各渠道统计头部，强化区块组织，消息层次一目了然
- **配置简化**：优化飞书等通知渠道的配置逻辑，上手更简单
- **热度趋势箭头**：新增 🔺(上升)、🔻(下降)、➖(持平) 趋势标识，直观展示热度变化
- **通用 Webhook**：支持自定义 Webhook URL 和 JSON 模板，轻松适配 Discord、Matrix、IFTTT 等任意平台

**🔧 配置优化**

- **频率词配置增强**：新增 `[组别名]` 语法，支持 `#` 注释行，配置更清晰（感谢 [@songge8](https://github.com/sansan0/TrendRadar/issues/752) 提出的建议）
- **环境变量支持**：AI 分析相关配置支持环境变量覆盖（`AI_API_KEY`、`AI_PROVIDER` 等）

&gt; 💡 详细配置教程见 [让 AI 帮我分析热点](#12-让-ai-帮我分析热点)


### 2026/01/02 - v4.7.0

- **修复 RSS HTML 显示**：修复 RSS 数据格式不匹配导致的渲染问题，现在按关键词分组正确显示
- **新增正则表达式语法**：关键词配置支持 `/pattern/` 正则语法，解决英文子字符串误匹配问题（如 `ai` 匹配 `training`）[📖 查看语法详解](#关键词基础语法)
- **新增显示名称语法**：使用 `=&gt; 备注` 给复杂的正则表达式起个好记的名字，推送消息显示更清晰（如 `/\bai\b/ =&gt; AI相关`）
- **不会写正则？** README 新增 AI 生成正则的引导，告诉 ChatGPT/Gemini/DeepSeek 你想匹配什么，让 AI 帮你写


### 2025/12/30 - mcp-v2.0.0

- **架构调整**：移除 TXT 支持，统一使用 SQLite 数据库
- **RSS 查询**：新增 `get_latest_rss`、`search_rss`、`get_rss_feeds_status`
- **统一搜索**：`search_news` 支持 `include_rss` 参数同时搜索热榜和 RSS


### 2026/01/01 - v4.6.0

- **修复 RSS HTML 显示**：将 RSS 内容合并到热榜 HTML 页面，按源分组显示
- **新增 display_mode 配置**：支持 `keyword`（按关键词分组）和 `platform`（按平台分组）两种显示模式


### 2025/12/30 - v4.5.0

- **RSS 订阅源支持**：新增 RSS/Atom 抓取，按关键词分组统计（与热榜格式一致）
- **存储结构重构**：扁平化目录结构 `output/{type}/{date}.db`
- **统一排序配置**：`sort_by_position_first` 同时影响热榜和 RSS
- **配置结构重构**：`config.yaml` 重新组织为 7 个逻辑分组（app、report、notification、storage、platforms、rss、advanced），配置路径更清晰


### 2025/12/26 - mcp-v1.2.0

  **MCP 模块更新 - 优化工具集，新增聚合对比功能，合并冗余工具:**
  - 新增 `aggregate_news` 工具 - 跨平台新闻去重聚合
  - 新增 `compare_periods` 工具 - 时期对比分析（周环比/月环比）
  - 合并 `find_similar_news` + `search_related_news_history` → `find_related_news`
  - 增强 `get_trending_topics` - 新增 `auto_extract` 模式自动提取热点
  - 修复若干bug
  - 同步更新 README-MCP-FAQ.md 文档的中英文版 (Q1-Q18)


### 2025/12/20 - v4.0.3

- 新增 URL 标准化功能，解决微博等平台因动态参数（如 `band_rank`）导致的重复推送问题
- 修复增量模式检测逻辑，正确识别历史标题


### 2025/12/17 - v4.0.1

- StorageManager 添加推送记录代理方法
- S3 客户端切换至 virtual-hosted style 以提升兼容性（支持腾讯云 COS 等更多服务）


### 2025/12/13 - mcp-v1.1.0

  **MCP 模块更新:**
  - 适配 v4.0.0，同时也兼容 v3.x 的数据
  - 新增存储同步工具：`sync_from_remote`、`get_storage_status`、`list_available_dates`


### 2025/12/13 - v4.0.0

**🎉 重大更新：全面重构存储和核心架构**

- **多存储后端支持**：引入全新的存储模块，支持本地 SQLite 和远程云存储（S3 兼容协议，例如 Cloudflare R2），适应 GitHub Actions、Docker 和本地环境。
- **数据库结构优化**：重构 SQLite 数据库表结构，提升数据效率和查询能力。
- **核心代码模块化**：将主程序逻辑拆分为 trendradar 包的多个模块，显著提升代码可维护性。
- **增强功能**：实现日期格式标准化、数据保留策略、时区配置支持、时间显示优化，并修复远程存储数据持久化问题，确保数据合并的准确性。
- **清理和兼容**：移除了大部分历史兼容代码，统一了数据存储和读取方式。


### 2025/12/03 - v3.5.0

**🎉 核心功能增强**

1. **多账号推送支持**
   - 所有推送渠道（飞书、钉钉、企业微信、Telegram、ntfy、Bark、Slack）支持多账号配置
   - 使用分号 `;` 分隔多个账号，例如：`FEISHU_WEBHOOK_URL=url1;url2`
   - 自动验证配对配置（如 Telegram 的 token 和 chat_id）数量一致性

2. **推送区域配置**
   - 通过 `display.region_order` 自定义各区域的显示顺序（v5.2.0 替代原 `reverse_content_order`）
   - 通过 `display.regions` 控制各区域是否显示（热榜、新增热点、RSS、独立展示区、AI 分析）

3. **全局过滤关键词**
   - 新增 `[GLOBAL_FILTER]` 区域标记，支持全局过滤不想看到的内容
   - 适用场景：过滤广告、营销、低质内容等

**🐳 Docker 双路径 HTML 生成优化**

- **问题修复**：解决 Docker 环境下 `index.html` 无法同步到宿主机的问题
- **双路径生成**：当日汇总 HTML 同时生成到两个位置
  - `index.html`（项目根目录）：供 GitHub Pages 访问
  - `output/index.html`：通过 Docker Volume 挂载，宿主机可直接访问
- **兼容性**：确保 Docker、GitHub Actions、本地运行环境均能正常访问网页版报告

**🐳 Docker MCP 镜像支持**

- 新增独立的 MCP 服务镜像 `wantcat/trendradar-mcp`
- 支持 Docker 部署 AI 分析功能，通过 HTTP 接口（端口 3333）提供服务
- 双容器架构：新闻推送服务与 MCP 服务独立运行，可分别扩展和重启
- 详见 [Docker 部署 - MCP 服务](#6-docker-部署)

**🌐 Web 服务器支持**

- 新增内置 Web 服务器，支持通过浏览器访问生成的报告
- 通过 `manage.py` 命令控制启动/停止：`docker exec -it trendradar python manage.py start_webserver`
- 访问地址：`http://localhost:8080`（端口可配置）
- 安全特性：静态文件服务、目录限制、本地访问
- 支持自动启动和手动控制两种模式

**📖 文档优化**

- 新增 [推送内容怎么显示？](#7-推送内容怎么显示) 章节：自定义推送样式和内容
- 新增 [什么时候给我推送？](#8-什么时候给我推送) 章节：设置推送时间段
- 新增 [多久运行一次？](#9-多久运行一次) 章节：设置自动运行频率
- 新增 [推送到多个群/设备](#10-推送到多个群设备) 章节：同时推送给多个接收者
- 优化各配置章节：统一添加&quot;配置位置&quot;说明
- 简化快速开始配置说明：三个核心文件一目了然
- 优化 [Docker 部署](#6-docker-部署) 章节：新增镜像说明、推荐 git clone 部署、重组部署方式

**🔧 升级说明**：
- **GitHub Fork 用户**：更新 `main.py`、`config/config.yaml`（新增多账号推送支持，无需修改现有配置）
- **多账号推送**：新功能，默认不启用，现有单账号配置不受影响


### 2025/11/26 - mcp-v1.0.3

  **MCP 模块更新:**
  - 新增日期解析工具 resolve_date_range,解决 AI 模型计算日期不一致的问题
  - 支持自然语言日期表达式解析(本周、最近7天、上月等)
  - 工具总数从 13 个增加到 14 个


### 2025/11/28 - v3.4.1

**🔧 格式优化**

1. **Bark 推送增强**
   - Bark 现支持 Markdown 渲染
   - 启用原生 Markdown 格式：粗体、链接、列表、代码块等
   - 移除纯文本转换，充分利用 Bark 原生渲染能力

2. **Slack 格式精准化**
   - 使用专用 mrkdwn 格式处理分批内容
   - 提升字节大小估算准确性（避免消息超限）
   - 优化链接格式：`&lt;url|text&gt;` 和加粗语法：`*text*`

3. **性能提升**
   - 格式转换在分批过程中完成，避免二次处理
   - 准确估算消息大小，减少发送失败率

**🔧 升级说明**：
- **GitHub Fork 用户**：更新 `main.py`，`config.yaml`


### 2025/11/25 - v3.4.0

**🎉 新增 Slack 推送支持**

1. **团队协作推送渠道**
   - 支持 Slack Incoming Webhooks（全球流行的团队协作工具）
   - 消息集中管理，适合团队共享热点资讯
   - 支持 mrkdwn 格式（粗体、链接等）

2. **多种部署方式**
   - GitHub Actions：配置 `SLACK_WEBHOOK_URL` Secret
   - Docker：环境变量 `SLACK_WEBHOOK_URL`
   - 本地运行：`config/config.yaml` 配置文件


&gt; 📖 **详细配置教程**：[快速开始 - Slack 推送](#-快速开始)

- 优化 setup-windows.bat 和 setup-windows-en.bat 一键安装 MCP 的体验

**🔧 升级说明**：
- **GitHub Fork 用户**：更新 `main.py`、`config/config.yaml`、`.github/workflows/crawler.yml`


### 2025/11/24 - v3.3.0

**🎉 新增 B

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NevaMind-AI/memU]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/NevaMind-AI/memU</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/NevaMind-AI/memU</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Memory for 24/7 proactive agents like openclaw (moltbot, clawdbot).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/NevaMind-AI/memU">NevaMind-AI/memU</a></h1>
            <p>Memory for 24/7 proactive agents like openclaw (moltbot, clawdbot).</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,458</p>
            <p>Forks: 781</p>
            <p>Stars today: 508 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![MemU Banner](assets/banner.png)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# memU

### 24/7 Always-On Proactive Memory for AI Agents

[![PyPI version](https://badge.fury.io/py/memu-py.svg)](https://badge.fury.io/py/memu-py)
[![License: Apache 2.0](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache%202.0-blue.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2.0)
[![Python 3.13+](https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3.13+-blue.svg)](https://www.python.org/downloads/)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join%20Chat-5865F2?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/memu)
[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/badge/Twitter-Follow-1DA1F2?logo=x&amp;logoColor=white)](https://x.com/memU_ai)

&lt;a href=&quot;https://trendshift.io/repositories/17374&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/17374&quot; alt=&quot;NevaMind-AI%2FmemU | Trendshift&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 55px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;55&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

**[English](readme/README_en.md) | [中文](readme/README_zh.md) | [日本語](readme/README_ja.md) | [한국어](readme/README_ko.md) | [Español](readme/README_es.md) | [Français](readme/README_fr.md)**

&lt;/div&gt;

---

memU is a memory framework built for **24/7 proactive agents**.
It is designed for long-running use and greatly **reduces the LLM token cost** of keeping agents always online, making always-on, evolving agents practical in production systems.
memU **continuously captures and understands user intent**. Even without a command, the agent can tell what you are about to do and act on it by itself.

---

## 🤖 [OpenClaw (Moltbot, Clawdbot) Alternative](https://memu.bot)

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/NevaMind-AI/memU/blob/main/assets/memUbot.png&quot; /&gt;

- **Download-and-use and simple** to get started.
- Builds long-term memory to **understand user intent** and act proactively.
- **Cuts LLM token cost** with smaller context.

Try now: [memU bot](https://memu.bot)

---

## 🗃️ Memory as File System, File System as Memory

memU treats **memory like a file system**—structured, hierarchical, and instantly accessible.

| File System | memU Memory |
|-------------|-------------|
| 📁 Folders | 🏷️ Categories (auto-organized topics) |
| 📄 Files | 🧠 Memory Items (extracted facts, preferences, skills) |
| 🔗 Symlinks | 🔄 Cross-references (related memories linked) |
| 📂 Mount points | 📥 Resources (conversations, documents, images) |

**Why this matters:**
- **Navigate memories** like browsing directories—drill down from broad categories to specific facts
- **Mount new knowledge** instantly—conversations and documents become queryable memory
- **Cross-link everything**—memories reference each other, building a connected knowledge graph
- **Persistent &amp; portable**—export, backup, and transfer memory like files

```
memory/
├── preferences/
│   ├── communication_style.md
│   └── topic_interests.md
├── relationships/
│   ├── contacts/
│   └── interaction_history/
├── knowledge/
│   ├── domain_expertise/
│   └── learned_skills/
└── context/
    ├── recent_conversations/
    └── pending_tasks/
```

Just as a file system turns raw bytes into organized data, memU transforms raw interactions into **structured, searchable, proactive intelligence**.

---

## ⭐️ Star the repository

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/NevaMind-AI/memU/blob/main/assets/star.gif&quot; /&gt;
If you find memU useful or interesting, a GitHub Star ⭐️ would be greatly appreciated.

---


## ✨ Core Features

| Capability | Description |
|------------|-------------|
| 🤖 **24/7 Proactive Agent** | Always-on memory agent that works continuously in the background—never sleeps, never forgets |
| 🎯 **User Intention Capture** | Understands and remembers user goals, preferences, and context across sessions automatically |
| 💰 **Cost Efficient** | Reduces long-running token costs by caching insights and avoiding redundant LLM calls |
---

## 🔄 How Proactive Memory Works

```bash

cd examples/proactive
python proactive.py

```

---

### Proactive Memory Lifecycle
```
┌──────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┐
│                                         USER QUERY                                               │
└──────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┘
                 │                                                           │
                 ▼                                                           ▼
┌────────────────────────────────────────┐         ┌────────────────────────────────────────────────┐
│         🤖 MAIN AGENT                  │         │              🧠 MEMU BOT                       │
│                                        │         │                                                │
│  Handle user queries &amp; execute tasks   │  ◄───►  │  Monitor, memorize &amp; proactive intelligence   │
├────────────────────────────────────────┤         ├────────────────────────────────────────────────┤
│                                        │         │                                                │
│  ┌──────────────────────────────────┐  │         │  ┌──────────────────────────────────────────┐  │
│  │  1. RECEIVE USER INPUT           │  │         │  │  1. MONITOR INPUT/OUTPUT                 │  │
│  │     Parse query, understand      │  │   ───►  │  │     Observe agent interactions           │  │
│  │     context and intent           │  │         │  │     Track conversation flow              │  │
│  └──────────────────────────────────┘  │         │  └──────────────────────────────────────────┘  │
│                 │                      │         │                    │                           │
│                 ▼                      │         │                    ▼                           │
│  ┌──────────────────────────────────┐  │         │  ┌──────────────────────────────────────────┐  │
│  │  2. PLAN &amp; EXECUTE               │  │         │  │  2. MEMORIZE &amp; EXTRACT                   │  │
│  │     Break down tasks             │  │   ◄───  │  │     Store insights, facts, preferences   │  │
│  │     Call tools, retrieve data    │  │  inject │  │     Extract skills &amp; knowledge           │  │
│  │     Generate responses           │  │  memory │  │     Update user profile                  │  │
│  └──────────────────────────────────┘  │         │  └──────────────────────────────────────────┘  │
│                 │                      │         │                    │                           │
│                 ▼                      │         │                    ▼                           │
│  ┌──────────────────────────────────┐  │         │  ┌──────────────────────────────────────────┐  │
│  │  3. RESPOND TO USER              │  │         │  │  3. PREDICT USER INTENT                  │  │
│  │     Deliver answer/result        │  │   ───►  │  │     Anticipate next steps                │  │
│  │     Continue conversation        │  │         │  │     Identify upcoming needs              │  │
│  └──────────────────────────────────┘  │         │  └──────────────────────────────────────────┘  │
│                 │                      │         │                    │                           │
│                 ▼                      │         │                    ▼                           │
│  ┌──────────────────────────────────┐  │         │  ┌──────────────────────────────────────────┐  │
│  │  4. LOOP                         │  │         │  │  4. RUN PROACTIVE TASKS                  │  │
│  │     Wait for next user input     │  │   ◄───  │  │     Pre-fetch relevant context           │  │
│  │     or proactive suggestions     │  │  suggest│  │     Prepare recommendations              │  │
│  └──────────────────────────────────┘  │         │  │     Update todolist autonomously         │  │
│                                        │         │  └──────────────────────────────────────────┘  │
└────────────────────────────────────────┘         └────────────────────────────────────────────────┘
                 │                                                           │
                 └───────────────────────────┬───────────────────────────────┘
                                             ▼
                              ┌──────────────────────────────┐
                              │     CONTINUOUS SYNC LOOP     │
                              │  Agent ◄──► MemU Bot ◄──► DB │
                              └──────────────────────────────┘
```

---

## 🎯 Proactive Use Cases

### 1. **Information Recommendation**
*Agent monitors interests and proactively surfaces relevant content*
```python
# User has been researching AI topics
MemU tracks: reading history, saved articles, search queries

# When new content arrives:
Agent: &quot;I found 3 new papers on RAG optimization that align with
        your recent research on retrieval systems. One author
        (Dr. Chen) you&#039;ve cited before published yesterday.&quot;

# Proactive behaviors:
- Learns topic preferences from browsing patterns
- Tracks author/source credibility preferences
- Filters noise based on engagement history
- Times recommendations for optimal attention
```

### 2. **Email Management**
*Agent learns communication patterns and handles routine correspondence*
```python
# MemU observes email patterns over time:
- Response templates for common scenarios
- Priority contacts and urgent keywords
- Scheduling preferences and availability
- Writing style and tone variations

# Proactive email assistance:
Agent: &quot;You have 12 new emails. I&#039;ve drafted responses for 3 routine
        requests and flagged 2 urgent items from your priority contacts.
        Should I also reschedule tomorrow&#039;s meeting based on the
        conflict John mentioned?&quot;

# Autonomous actions:
✓ Draft context-aware replies
✓ Categorize and prioritize inbox
✓ Detect scheduling conflicts
✓ Summarize long threads with key decisions
```

### 3. **Trading &amp; Financial Monitoring**
*Agent tracks market context and user investment behavior*
```python
# MemU learns trading preferences:
- Risk tolerance from historical decisions
- Preferred sectors and asset classes
- Response patterns to market events
- Portfolio rebalancing triggers

# Proactive alerts:
Agent: &quot;NVDA dropped 5% in after-hours trading. Based on your past
        behavior, you typically buy tech dips above 3%. Your current
        allocation allows for $2,000 additional exposure while
        maintaining your 70/30 equity-bond target.&quot;

# Continuous monitoring:
- Track price alerts tied to user-defined thresholds
- Correlate news events with portfolio impact
- Learn from executed vs. ignored recommendations
- Anticipate tax-loss harvesting opportunities
```


...

---

## 🗂️ Hierarchical Memory Architecture

MemU&#039;s three-layer system enables both **reactive queries** and **proactive context loading**:

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;structure&quot; src=&quot;assets/structure.png&quot; /&gt;

| Layer | Reactive Use | Proactive Use |
|-------|--------------|---------------|
| **Resource** | Direct access to original data | Background monitoring for new patterns |
| **Item** | Targeted fact retrieval | Real-time extraction from ongoing interactions |
| **Category** | Summary-level overview | Automatic context assembly for anticipation |

**Proactive Benefits:**
- **Auto-categorization**: New memories self-organize into topics
- **Pattern Detection**: System identifies recurring themes
- **Context Prediction**: Anticipates what information will be needed next

---

## 🚀 Quick Start

### Option 1: Cloud Version

Experience proactive memory instantly:

👉 **[memu.so](https://memu.so)** - Hosted service with 7×24 continuous learning

For enterprise deployment with custom proactive workflows, contact **info@nevamind.ai**

#### Cloud API (v3)

| Base URL | `https://api.memu.so` |
|----------|----------------------|
| Auth | `Authorization: Bearer YOUR_API_KEY` |

| Method | Endpoint | Description |
|--------|----------|-------------|
| `POST` | `/api/v3/memory/memorize` | Register continuous learning task |
| `GET` | `/api/v3/memory/memorize/status/{task_id}` | Check real-time processing status |
| `POST` | `/api/v3/memory/categories` | List auto-generated categories |
| `POST` | `/api/v3/memory/retrieve` | Query memory (supports proactive context loading) |

📚 **[Full API Documentation](https://memu.pro/docs#cloud-version)**

---

### Option 2: Self-Hosted

#### Installation
```bash
pip install -e .
```

#### Basic Example

&gt; **Requirements**: Python 3.13+ and an OpenAI API key

**Test Continuous Learning** (in-memory):
```bash
export OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key
cd tests
python test_inmemory.py
```

**Test with Persistent Storage** (PostgreSQL):
```bash
# Start PostgreSQL with pgvector
docker run -d \
  --name memu-postgres \
  -e POSTGRES_USER=postgres \
  -e POSTGRES_PASSWORD=postgres \
  -e POSTGRES_DB=memu \
  -p 5432:5432 \
  pgvector/pgvector:pg16

# Run continuous learning test
export OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key
cd tests
python test_postgres.py
```

Both examples demonstrate **proactive memory workflows**:
1. **Continuous Ingestion**: Process multiple files sequentially
2. **Auto-Extraction**: Immediate memory creation
3. **Proactive Retrieval**: Context-aware memory surfacing

See [`tests/test_inmemory.py`](tests/test_inmemory.py) and [`tests/test_postgres.py`](tests/test_postgres.py) for implementation details.

---

### Custom LLM and Embedding Providers

MemU supports custom LLM and embedding providers beyond OpenAI. Configure them via `llm_profiles`:
```python
from memu import MemUService

service = MemUService(
    llm_profiles={
        # Default profile for LLM operations
        &quot;default&quot;: {
            &quot;base_url&quot;: &quot;https://dashscope.aliyuncs.com/compatible-mode/v1&quot;,
            &quot;api_key&quot;: &quot;your_api_key&quot;,
            &quot;chat_model&quot;: &quot;qwen3-max&quot;,
            &quot;client_backend&quot;: &quot;sdk&quot;  # &quot;sdk&quot; or &quot;http&quot;
        },
        # Separate profile for embeddings
        &quot;embedding&quot;: {
            &quot;base_url&quot;: &quot;https://api.voyageai.com/v1&quot;,
            &quot;api_key&quot;: &quot;your_voyage_api_key&quot;,
            &quot;embed_model&quot;: &quot;voyage-3.5-lite&quot;
        }
    },
    # ... other configuration
)
```

---

### OpenRouter Integration

MemU supports [OpenRouter](https://openrouter.ai) as a model provider, giving you access to multiple LLM providers through a single API.

#### Configuration
```python
from memu import MemoryService

service = MemoryService(
    llm_profiles={
        &quot;default&quot;: {
            &quot;provider&quot;: &quot;openrouter&quot;,
            &quot;client_backend&quot;: &quot;httpx&quot;,
            &quot;base_url&quot;: &quot;https://openrouter.ai&quot;,
            &quot;api_key&quot;: &quot;your_openrouter_api_key&quot;,
            &quot;chat_model&quot;: &quot;anthropic/claude-3.5-sonnet&quot;,  # Any OpenRouter model
            &quot;embed_model&quot;: &quot;openai/text-embedding-3-small&quot;,  # Embedding model
        },
    },
    database_config={
        &quot;metadata_store&quot;: {&quot;provider&quot;: &quot;inmemory&quot;},
    },
)
```

#### Environment Variables

| Variable | Description |
|----------|-------------|
| `OPENROUTER_API_KEY` | Your OpenRouter API key from [openrouter.ai/keys](https://openrouter.ai/keys) |

#### Supported Features

| Feature | Status | Notes |
|---------|--------|-------|
| Chat Completions | Supported | Works with any OpenRouter chat model |
| Embeddings | Supported | Use OpenAI embedding models via OpenRouter |
| Vision | Supported | Use vision-capable models (e.g., `openai/gpt-4o`) |

#### Running OpenRouter Tests
```bash
export OPENROUTER_API_KEY=your_api_key

# Full workflow test (memorize + retrieve)
python tests/test_openrouter.py

# Embedding-specific tests
python tests/test_openrouter_embedding.py

# Vision-specific tests
python tests/test_openrouter_vision.py
```

See [`examples/example_4_openrouter_memory.py`](examples/example_4_openrouter_memory.py) for a complete working example.

---

## 📖 Core APIs

### `memorize()` - Continuous Learning Pipeline

Processes inputs in real-time and immediately updates memory:

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;memorize&quot; src=&quot;assets/memorize.png&quot; /&gt;

```python
result = await service.memorize(
    resource_url=&quot;path/to/file.json&quot;,  # File path or URL
    modality=&quot;conversation&quot;,            # conversation | document | image | video | audio
    user={&quot;user_id&quot;: &quot;123&quot;}             # Optional: scope to a user
)

# Returns immediately with extracted memory:
{
    &quot;resource&quot;: {...},      # Stored resource metadata
    &quot;items&quot;: [...],         # Extracted memory items (available instantly)
    &quot;categories&quot;: [...]     # Auto-updated category structure
}
```

**Proactive Features:**
- Zero-delay processing—memories available immediately
- Automatic categorization without manual tagging
- Cross-reference with existing memories for pattern detection

### `retrieve()` - Dual-Mode Intelligence

MemU supports both **proactive context loading** and **reactive querying**:

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;retrieve&quot; src=&quot;assets/retrieve.png&quot; /&gt;

#### RAG-based Retrieval (`method=&quot;rag&quot;`)

Fast **proactive context assembly** using embeddings:

- ✅ **Instant context**: Sub-second memory surfacing
- ✅ **Background monitoring**: Can run continuously without LLM costs
- ✅ **Similarity scoring**: Identifies most relevant memories automatically

#### LLM-based Retrieval (`method=&quot;llm&quot;`)

Deep **anticipatory reasoning** for complex contexts:

- ✅ **Intent prediction**: LLM infers what user needs before they ask
- ✅ **Query evolution**: Automatically refines search as context develops
- ✅ **Early termination**: Stops when sufficient context is gathered

#### Comparison

| Aspect | RAG (Fast Context) | LLM (Deep Reasoning) |
|--------|-------------------|---------------------|
| **Speed** | ⚡ Milliseconds | 🐢 Seconds |
| **Cost** | 💰 Embedding only | 💰💰 LLM inference |
| **Proactive use** | Continuous monitoring | Triggered context loading |
| **Best for** | Real-time suggestions | Complex anticipation |

#### Usage
```python
# Proactive retrieval with context history
result = await service.retrieve(
    queries=[
        {&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: {&quot;text&quot;: &quot;What are their preferences?&quot;}},
        {&quot;role&quot;: &quot;user&quot;, &quot;content&quot;: {&quot;text&quot;: &quot;Tell me about work habits&quot;}}
    ],
    where={&quot;user_id&quot;: &quot;123&quot;},  # Optional: scope filter
    method=&quot;rag&quot;  # or &quot;llm&quot; for deeper reasoning
)

# Returns context-aware results:
{
    &quot;categories&quot;: [...],     # Relevant topic areas (auto-prioritized)
    &quot;items&quot;: [...],          # Specific memory facts
    &quot;resources&quot;: [...],      # Original sources for traceability
    &quot;next_step_query&quot;: &quot;...&quot; # Predicted follow-up context
}
```

**Proactive Filtering**: Use `where` to scope continuous monitoring:
- `where={&quot;user_id&quot;: &quot;123&quot;}` - User-specific context
- `where={&quot;agent_id__in&quot;: [&quot;1&quot;, &quot;2&quot;]}` - Multi-agent coordination
- Omit `where` for global context awareness

---

## 💡 Proactive Scenarios

### Example 1: Always-Learning Assistant

Continuously learns from every interaction without explicit memory commands:
```bash
export OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key
python examples/example_1_conversation_memory.py
```

**Proactive Behavior:**
- Automatically extracts preferences from casual mentions
- Builds relationship models from interaction patterns
- Surfaces relevant context in future conversations
- Adapts communication style based on learned preferences

**Best for:** Personal AI assistants, customer support that remembers, social chatbots

---

### Example 2: Self-Improving Agent

Learns from execution logs and proactively suggests optimizations:
```bash
export OPENAI_API_KEY=your_api_key
python examples/example_2_skill_extraction.py
```

**Proactive Behavior:**
- Monitors agent actions and outcomes continuously
- Identifies patterns in successes and failures
- Auto-generates skill guides from experience
- Proactively suggests strategies for similar future tasks

**Best for:** DevOps automation, agent self-improvement, knowledge capture

---

### Example 3: Multimodal Context Builder

Unifies memory across different input types for comprehensive context:
```bash
export OPENAI

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Python sample codes and documents about Autonomous vehicle control algorithm. This project can be used as a technical guide book to study the algorithms and the software architectures for beginners.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide">ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide</a></h1>
            <p>Python sample codes and documents about Autonomous vehicle control algorithm. This project can be used as a technical guide book to study the algorithms and the software architectures for beginners.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,398</p>
            <p>Forks: 209</p>
            <p>Stars today: 43 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide
[![Linux_CI](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/Linux_CI.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/Linux_CI.yml) [![Windows_CI](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/Windows_CI.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/Windows_CI.yml) [![MacOS_CI](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/MacOS_CI.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousDrivingSamplePrograms/actions/workflows/MacOS_CI.yml) [![CodeFactor](https://www.codefactor.io/repository/github/shisatoyano/autonomousvehiclecontrolbeginnersguide/badge)](https://www.codefactor.io/repository/github/shisatoyano/autonomousvehiclecontrolbeginnersguide)  

Python sample codes and documents about Autonomous vehicle control algorithm. This project can be used as a technical guide book to study the algorithms and the software architectures for beginners.  

![](src/simulations/mapping/ndt_map_construction/ndt_map_construction.gif)  


## Table of Contents
* [What is this?](#what-is-this)
* [Goal of this project](#goal-of-this-project)
* [Requirements](#requirements)
* [How to use](#how-to-use)
* [Examples of Simulation](#examples-of-simulation)
    * [Localization](#localization)
        * [Extended Kalman Filter Localization](#extended-kalman-filter-localization)
        * [Unscented Kalman Filter Localization](#unscented-kalman-filter-localization)
        * [Particle Filter Localization](#particle-filter-localization)
    * [Mapping](#mapping)
        * [Binary Occupancy Grid Map](#binary-occupancy-grid-map)
        * [Cost Map](#cost-map)
        * [Potential Field Map](#potential-field-map)
        * [NDT Map](#ndt-map)
    * [Path Planning](#path-planning)
        * [A*](#a)
        * [Bidirectional A*](#bidirectional-a)
        * [Hybrid A*](#hybrid-a)
        * [Dijkstra](#dijkstra)
        * [RRT](#rrt)
        * [Bidirectional RRT*](#bidirectional-rrt)
        * [RRT*](#rrt-star)
        * [Informed RRT*](#informed-rrt)
    * [Path Tracking](#path-tracking)
        * [Pure pursuit Path Tracking](#pure-pursuit-path-tracking)
        * [Adaptive Pure pursuit Path Tracking](#adaptive-pure-pursuit-path-tracking)
        * [Rear wheel feedback Path Tracking](#rear-wheel-feedback-path-tracking)
        * [LQR(Linear Quadratic Regulator) Path Tracking](#lqrlinear-quadratic-regulator-path-tracking)
        * [Stanley steering control Path tracking](#stanley-steering-control-path-tracking)
        * [MPPI Path Tracking](#mppi-path-tracking)
    * [Perception](#perception)
        * [Rectangle fitting Detection](#rectangle-fitting-detection)
        * [Sensor&#039;s Extrinsic Parameters Estimation](#sensors-extrinsic-parameters-estimation)
* [Documents](#documents)
* [License](#license)
* [Use Case](#use-case)
* [Contribution](#contribution)
* [Author](#author)


## What is this?
This is a sample codes collections about Autonomous vehicle control algorithm. Each source codes are implemented with Python to help your understanding. You can fork this repository and use for studying, education or work freely.  


## Goal of this project
I want to release my own technical book about Autonomous Vehicle algorithms in the future. The book will include all of codes and documents in this repository as contents.  


## Requirements
Please satisfy with the following requirements on native or VM Linux in advance.  
For running each sample codes:  
* [Python 3.13.x](https://www.python.org/)
* [Matplotlib](https://matplotlib.org/)
* [NumPy](https://numpy.org/)
* [SciPy](https://scipy.org/)

For development:
* [pytest](https://docs.pytest.org/en/7.4.x/) (for unit tests)
* [pytest-cov](https://github.com/pytest-dev/pytest-cov) (for coverage measurement)

For setting up the environment with Docker:
* [VS Code](https://code.visualstudio.com/)
* [Docker](https://www.docker.com/)


## How to use
1. Clone this repository  
    ```bash
    $ git clone https://github.com/ShisatoYano/AutonomousVehicleControlBeginnersGuide
    ```

2. Set up the environment for running each codes
    * Set up with Docker on WSL:
        * Before cloning thi repo, [install Docker](https://docs.docker.com/desktop/install/linux-install/) in advance
        * Clone this repo following the above Step 1
        * Open this repo&#039;s folder by VSCode
        * [Create Dev Container](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/devcontainers/create-dev-container)
        * And then, all required libraries are installed automatically
3. Execute unit tests to confirm the environment were installed successfully
    ```bash
    $ . run_test_suites.sh
    ```
4. Execute a python script at src/simulations directory
    * For example, when you want to execute localization simulation of Extended Kalman Filter:
        ```bash
        $ python src/simulations/localization/extended_kalman_filter_localization/extended_kalman_filter_localization.py
        ```
5. Add star to this repository if you like it!!


## Examples of Simulation
### Localization
#### Extended Kalman Filter Localization
![](src/simulations/localization/extended_kalman_filter_localization/extended_kalman_filter_localization.gif)  
#### Unscented Kalman Filter Localization
![](src/simulations/localization/unscented_kalman_filter_localization/unscented_kalman_filter_localization.gif)  
#### Particle Filter Localization
![](src/simulations/localization/particle_filter_localization/particle_filter_localization.gif)  
### Mapping
#### Binary Occupancy Grid Map
![](src/simulations/mapping/binary_grid_map_construction/binary_grid_map_construction.gif)  
#### Cost Map
![](src/simulations/mapping/cost_grid_map_construction/cost_grid_map_construction.gif)  
#### Potential Field Map
![](src/simulations/mapping/potential_field_map_construction/potential_field_demo.gif)   
#### NDT Map
![](src/simulations/mapping/ndt_map_construction/ndt_map_construction.gif)  
### Path Planning
#### A*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/astar_path_planning/astar_search.gif)  
#### Bidirectional A*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/astar_bidirectional_path_planning/astar_bidirectional_search.gif)  
#### Hybrid A*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/astar_hybrid_path_planning/astar_hybrid_search.gif)  
#### Dijkstra
Planning(Reduce frames by sampling every nth node to prevent memory exhaustion)  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/dijkstra_path_planning/dijkstra_search.gif)  
#### RRT
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_path_planning/rrt_search.gif)  
Navigation  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_path_planning/rrt_navigate.gif)  
#### Bidirectional RRT*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_star_bidirectional_path_planning/rrt_star_bidirectional_search.gif)  
Navigation  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_star_bidirectional_path_planning/rrt_star_bidirectional_navigate.gif)  
#### RRT*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_star_path_planning/rrt_star_search.gif)  
Navigation  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/rrt_star_path_planning/rrt_star_navigate.gif)  
#### Informed RRT*
Planning  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/informed_rrt_star_path_planning/informed_rrt_star_search.gif)  
Navigation  
![](src/simulations/path_planning/informed_rrt_star_path_planning/informed_rrt_star_navigate.gif)  
### Path Tracking
#### Pure pursuit Path Tracking
![](src/simulations/path_tracking/pure_pursuit_path_tracking/pure_pursuit_path_tracking.gif)  
#### Adaptive Pure pursuit Path Tracking
![](src/simulations/path_tracking/adaptive_pure_pursuit_path_tracking/adaptive_pure_pursuit_path_tracking.gif)  
#### Rear wheel feedback Path Tracking
![](src/simulations//path_tracking/rear_wheel_feedback_tracking/rear_wheel_feedback_tracking.gif)  
#### LQR(Linear Quadratic Regulator) Path Tracking
![](src/simulations/path_tracking/lqr_path_tracking/lqr_path_tracking.gif)  
#### Stanley steering control Path Tracking
![](src/simulations/path_tracking/stanley_path_tracking/stanley_path_tracking.gif)  
#### MPPI Path Tracking
![](src/simulations/path_tracking/mppi_path_tracking/mppi_path_tracking.gif)  
### Perception
#### Rectangle fitting Detection
![](src/simulations/perception/point_cloud_rectangle_fitting/point_cloud_rectangle_fitting.gif)  
#### Sensor&#039;s Extrinsic Parameters Estimation
Estimation by Unscented Kalman Filter  
![](src/simulations/perception/sensor_auto_calibration/sensor_auto_calibration.gif)  


## Documents
Design documents of each Python programs are prepared here. The documents are still not completed. They have been being updated. If you found any problems in them, please tell me by creating an issue.  
[Documents link](/doc/DESIGN_DOCUMENT.md)  


## License
MIT  


## Use Case
I started this project to study an algorithm and software development for Autonomous Vehicle system by myself. You can also use this repo for your own studying, education, researching and development.  

If this project helps your task, please let me know by creating a issue.  
Any paper, animation, video as your output, always welcome!! It will encourage me to continue this project.  

Your comment and output is added to [this list of user comments](/USERS_COMMENTS.md).  


## Contribution
Any contribution by creating an issue or sending a pull request is welcome!! Please check [this document about how to contribute](/HOWTOCONTRIBUTE.md).  


## Author
[Shisato Yano](https://github.com/ShisatoYano)  
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[business-science/ai-data-science-team]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An AI-powered data science team of agents to help you perform common data science tasks 10X faster.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team">business-science/ai-data-science-team</a></h1>
            <p>An AI-powered data science team of agents to help you perform common data science tasks 10X faster.</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,945</p>
            <p>Forks: 850</p>
            <p>Stars today: 93 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./img/ai_data_science_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;AI Data Science Team&quot; width=&quot;360&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;AI Data Science Team + AI Pipeline Studio&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/ai-data-science-team&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/ai-data-science-team.svg?style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;PyPI&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/ai-data-science-team.svg?style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;versions&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/business-science/ai-data-science-team.svg?style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;license&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Repo stars&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/business-science/ai-data-science-team?style=for-the-badge&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

# AI Data Science Team

AI Data Science Team is a Python library of specialized agents for common data science workflows, plus a flagship app: **AI Pipeline Studio**. The Studio turns your work into a visual, reproducible pipeline, while the AI team handles data loading, cleaning, visualization, and modeling.

**Status:** Beta. Breaking changes may occur until 0.1.0.

[**Please ⭐ us on GitHub (it takes 2 seconds and means a lot).**](https://github.com/business-science/ai-data-science-team)

## AI Pipeline Studio (Flagship App)

AI Pipeline Studio is the main example of the AI Data Science Team in action.

![AI Pipeline Studio](/img/apps/ai_pipeline_studio_app.jpg)

Highlights:
- Pipeline-first workspace: Visual Editor, Table, Chart, EDA, Code, Model, Predictions, MLflow
- Manual + AI steps with lineage and reproducible scripts
- Multi-dataset handling and merge workflows
- Project saves: metadata-only or full-data
- Storage footprint controls and rehydrate workflows

Run it:
```bash
streamlit run apps/ai-pipeline-studio-app/app.py
```

Full app docs: `apps/ai-pipeline-studio-app/README.md`

## Quickstart

### Requirements
- Python 3.10+
- OpenAI API key (or Ollama for local models)

### Install the app and library
Clone the repo and install in editable mode:
```bash
pip install -e .
```

### Run the AI Pipeline Studio app
```bash
streamlit run apps/ai-pipeline-studio-app/app.py
```

## Library Overview

The repository includes both the **AI Pipeline Studio** app and the underlying **AI Data Science Team** library. The library provides agent building blocks and multi-agent workflows for:
- Data loading and inspection
- Cleaning, wrangling, and feature engineering
- Visualization and EDA
- Modeling and evaluation (H2O + MLflow tools)
- SQL database interaction

### Agents (Snapshot)

Agent examples live in `examples/`. Notable agents:
- Data Loader Tools Agent
- Data Wrangling Agent
- Data Cleaning Agent
- Data Visualization Agent
- EDA Tools Agent
- Feature Engineering Agent
- SQL Database Agent
- H2O ML Agent
- MLflow Tools Agent
- Multi-agent workflows (e.g., Pandas Data Analyst, SQL Data Analyst)
- Supervisor Agent (oversees other agents)
- Custom tools for data science tasks

## Apps

See all apps in `apps/`. Notable apps:
- AI Pipeline Studio: `apps/ai-pipeline-studio-app/`
- EDA Explorer App: `apps/exploratory-copilot-app/`
- Pandas Data Analyst App: `apps/pandas-data-analyst-app/`

## Use OpenAI

```python
from langchain_openai import ChatOpenAI
llm = ChatOpenAI(
    model_name=&quot;gpt-4.1-mini&quot;,
)
```

## Use Ollama (Local LLM)

```bash
ollama serve
ollama pull llama3.1:8b
```

```python
from langchain_ollama import ChatOllama

llm = ChatOllama(
    model=&quot;llama3.1:8b&quot;,
)
```

## Next-Gen AI Agentic Workshop

Want to learn how to build AI agents and AI apps for real data science workflows? Join my next‑gen AI workshop:
https://learn.business-science.io/ai-register
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mihail911/modern-software-dev-assignments]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mihail911/modern-software-dev-assignments</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mihail911/modern-software-dev-assignments</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:08:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Assignments for CS146S: The Modern Software Dev (Stanford University Fall 2025)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mihail911/modern-software-dev-assignments">mihail911/modern-software-dev-assignments</a></h1>
            <p>Assignments for CS146S: The Modern Software Dev (Stanford University Fall 2025)</p>
            <p>Language: Python</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,195</p>
            <p>Forks: 512</p>
            <p>Stars today: 131 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Assignments for CS146S: The Modern Software Developer

This is the home of the assignments for [CS146S: The Modern Software Developer](https://themodernsoftware.dev), taught at Stanford University fall 2025.

## Repo Setup
These steps work with Python 3.12.

1. Install Anaconda
   - Download and install: [Anaconda Individual Edition](https://www.anaconda.com/download)
   - Open a new terminal so `conda` is on your `PATH`.

2. Create and activate a Conda environment (Python 3.12)
   ```bash
   conda create -n cs146s python=3.12 -y
   conda activate cs146s
   ```

3. Install Poetry
   ```bash
   curl -sSL https://install.python-poetry.org | python -
   ```

4. Install project dependencies with Poetry (inside the activated Conda env)
   From the repository root:
   ```bash
   poetry install --no-interaction
   ```</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Python</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>