<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for rust - Rust Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for rust.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[bevyengine/bevy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A refreshingly simple data-driven game engine built in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy">bevyengine/bevy</a></h1>
            <p>A refreshingly simple data-driven game engine built in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 38,987</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,836</p>
            <p>Stars today: 21 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># [![Bevy](assets/branding/bevy_logo_light_dark_and_dimmed.svg)](https://bevyengine.org)

[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT%2FApache-blue.svg)](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy#license)
[![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/bevy.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/bevy)
[![Downloads](https://img.shields.io/crates/d/bevy.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/bevy)
[![Docs](https://docs.rs/bevy/badge.svg)](https://docs.rs/bevy/latest/bevy/)
[![CI](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/workflows/CI/badge.svg)](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/actions)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/691052431525675048.svg?label=&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;color=7389D8&amp;labelColor=6A7EC2)](https://discord.gg/bevy)

## What is Bevy?

Bevy is a refreshingly simple data-driven game engine built in Rust. It is free and open-source forever!

## WARNING

Bevy is still in the early stages of development. Important features are missing. Documentation is sparse. A new version of Bevy containing breaking changes to the API is released [approximately once every 3 months](https://bevyengine.org/news/bevy-0-6/#the-train-release-schedule). We provide [migration guides](https://bevyengine.org/learn/migration-guides/), but we can&#039;t guarantee migrations will always be easy. Use only if you are willing to work in this environment.

**MSRV:** Bevy relies heavily on improvements in the Rust language and compiler.
As a result, the Minimum Supported Rust Version (MSRV) is generally close to &quot;the latest stable release&quot; of Rust.

## Design Goals

* **Capable**: Offer a complete 2D and 3D feature set
* **Simple**: Easy for newbies to pick up, but infinitely flexible for power users
* **Data Focused**: Data-oriented architecture using the Entity Component System paradigm
* **Modular**: Use only what you need. Replace what you don&#039;t like
* **Fast**: App logic should run quickly, and when possible, in parallel
* **Productive**: Changes should compile quickly ... waiting isn&#039;t fun

## About

* **[Features](https://bevyengine.org):** A quick overview of Bevy&#039;s features.
* **[News](https://bevyengine.org/news/)**: A development blog that covers our progress, plans and shiny new features.

## Docs

* **[Quick Start Guide](https://bevyengine.org/learn/quick-start/introduction):** Bevy&#039;s official Quick Start Guide. The best place to start learning Bevy.
* **[Bevy Rust API Docs](https://docs.rs/bevy):** Bevy&#039;s Rust API docs, which are automatically generated from the doc comments in this repo.
* **[Official Examples](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/tree/latest/examples):** Bevy&#039;s dedicated, runnable examples, which are great for digging into specific concepts.
* **[Community-Made Learning Resources](https://bevyengine.org/assets/#learning)**: More tutorials, documentation, and examples made by the Bevy community.

## Community

Before contributing or participating in discussions with the community, you should familiarize yourself with our [**Code of Conduct**](./CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md).

* **[Discord](https://discord.gg/bevy):** Bevy&#039;s official discord server.
* **[Reddit](https://reddit.com/r/bevy):** Bevy&#039;s official subreddit.
* **[GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/discussions):** The best place for questions about Bevy, answered right here!
* **[Bevy Assets](https://bevyengine.org/assets/):** A collection of awesome Bevy projects, tools, plugins and learning materials.

### Contributing

If you&#039;d like to help build Bevy, check out the **[Contributor&#039;s Guide](https://bevyengine.org/learn/contribute/introduction)**.
For simple problems, feel free to [open an issue](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/issues) or
[PR](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/pulls) and tackle it yourself!

For more complex architecture decisions and experimental mad science, please open an [RFC](https://github.com/bevyengine/rfcs) (Request For Comments) so we can brainstorm together effectively!

## Getting Started

We recommend checking out the [Quick Start Guide](https://bevyengine.org/learn/quick-start/introduction) for a brief introduction.

Follow the [Setup guide](https://bevyengine.org/learn/quick-start/getting-started/setup) to ensure your development environment is set up correctly.
Once set up, you can quickly try out the [examples](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/tree/latest/examples) by cloning this repo and running the following commands:

```sh
# Switch to the correct version (latest release, default is main development branch)
git checkout latest
# Runs the &quot;breakout&quot; example
cargo run --example breakout
```

To draw a window with standard functionality enabled, use:

```rust
use bevy::prelude::*;

fn main(){
  App::new()
    .add_plugins(DefaultPlugins)
    .run();
}
```

### Fast Compiles

Bevy can be built just fine using default configuration on stable Rust. However for really fast iterative compiles, you should enable the &quot;fast compiles&quot; setup by [following the instructions here](https://bevyengine.org/learn/quick-start/getting-started/setup).

## [Bevy Cargo Features][cargo_features]

This [list][cargo_features] outlines the different cargo features supported by Bevy. These allow you to customize the Bevy feature set for your use-case.

[cargo_features]: docs/cargo_features.md

## Thanks

Bevy is the result of the hard work of many people. A huge thanks to all Bevy contributors, the many open source projects that have come before us, the [Rust gamedev ecosystem](https://arewegameyet.rs/), and the many libraries we build on.

A huge thanks to Bevy&#039;s [generous sponsors](https://bevyengine.org). Bevy will always be free and open source, but it isn&#039;t free to make. Please consider [sponsoring our work](https://bevyengine.org/donate/) if you like what we&#039;re building.

&lt;!-- This next line need to stay exactly as is. It is required for BrowserStack sponsorship. --&gt;
This project is tested with BrowserStack.

## License

Bevy is free, open source and permissively licensed!
Except where noted (below and/or in individual files), all code in this repository is dual-licensed under either:

* MIT License ([LICENSE-MIT](LICENSE-MIT) or [http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT](http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT))
* Apache License, Version 2.0 ([LICENSE-APACHE](LICENSE-APACHE) or [http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0](http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0))

at your option.
This means you can select the license you prefer!
This dual-licensing approach is the de-facto standard in the Rust ecosystem and there are [very good reasons](https://github.com/bevyengine/bevy/issues/2373) to include both.

Some of the engine&#039;s code carries additional copyright notices and license terms due to their external origins.
These are generally BSD-like, but exact details vary by crate:
If the README of a crate contains a &#039;License&#039; header (or similar), the additional copyright notices and license terms applicable to that crate will be listed.
The above licensing requirement still applies to contributions to those crates, and sections of those crates will carry those license terms.
The [license](https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/reference/manifest.html#the-license-and-license-file-fields) field of each crate will also reflect this.
For example, [`bevy_mikktspace`](./crates/bevy_mikktspace/README.md#license-agreement) has code under the Zlib license (as well as a copyright notice when choosing the MIT license).

The [assets](assets) included in this repository (for our [examples](./examples/README.md)) typically fall under different open licenses.
These will not be included in your game (unless copied in by you), and they are not distributed in the published bevy crates.
See [CREDITS.md](CREDITS.md) for the details of the licenses of those files.

### Your contributions

Unless you explicitly state otherwise,
any contribution intentionally submitted for inclusion in the work by you,
as defined in the Apache-2.0 license,
shall be dual licensed as above,
without any additional terms or conditions.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[solana-labs/solana]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/solana-labs/solana</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/solana-labs/solana</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Web-Scale Blockchain for fast, secure, scalable, decentralized apps and marketplaces.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/solana-labs/solana">solana-labs/solana</a></h1>
            <p>Web-Scale Blockchain for fast, secure, scalable, decentralized apps and marketplaces.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,035</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,752</p>
            <p>Stars today: 1 star today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># PLEASE READ: This repo is now a public archive

This repo still exists in archived form, feel free to fork any reference
implementations it still contains.

See Agave, the Solana validator implementation from Anza: https://github.com/anza-xyz/agave

---

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://solana.com&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Solana&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/IKyzQ6T.png&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

[![Solana crate](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/solana-core.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/solana-core)
[![Solana documentation](https://docs.rs/solana-core/badge.svg)](https://docs.rs/solana-core)
[![Build status](https://badge.buildkite.com/8cc350de251d61483db98bdfc895b9ea0ac8ffa4a32ee850ed.svg?branch=master)](https://buildkite.com/solana-labs/solana/builds?branch=master)
[![codecov](https://codecov.io/gh/solana-labs/solana/branch/master/graph/badge.svg)](https://codecov.io/gh/solana-labs/solana)

# Building

## **1. Install rustc, cargo and rustfmt.**

```bash
$ curl https://sh.rustup.rs -sSf | sh
$ source $HOME/.cargo/env
$ rustup component add rustfmt
```

When building the master branch, please make sure you are using the latest stable rust version by running:

```bash
$ rustup update
```

When building a specific release branch, you should check the rust version in `ci/rust-version.sh` and if necessary, install that version by running:

```bash
$ rustup install VERSION
```

Note that if this is not the latest rust version on your machine, cargo commands may require an [override](https://rust-lang.github.io/rustup/overrides.html) in order to use the correct version.

On Linux systems you may need to install libssl-dev, pkg-config, zlib1g-dev, protobuf etc.

On Ubuntu:

```bash
$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install libssl-dev libudev-dev pkg-config zlib1g-dev llvm clang cmake make libprotobuf-dev protobuf-compiler
```

On Fedora:

```bash
$ sudo dnf install openssl-devel systemd-devel pkg-config zlib-devel llvm clang cmake make protobuf-devel protobuf-compiler perl-core
```

## **2. Download the source code.**

```bash
$ git clone https://github.com/solana-labs/solana.git
$ cd solana
```

## **3. Build.**

```bash
$ ./cargo build
```

# Testing

**Run the test suite:**

```bash
$ ./cargo test
```

### Starting a local testnet

Start your own testnet locally, instructions are in the [online docs](https://docs.solanalabs.com/clusters/benchmark).

### Accessing the remote development cluster

- `devnet` - stable public cluster for development accessible via
  devnet.solana.com. Runs 24/7. Learn more about the [public clusters](https://docs.solanalabs.com/clusters)

# Benchmarking

First, install the nightly build of rustc. `cargo bench` requires the use of the
unstable features only available in the nightly build.

```bash
$ rustup install nightly
```

Run the benchmarks:

```bash
$ cargo +nightly bench
```

# Release Process

The release process for this project is described [here](RELEASE.md).

# Code coverage

To generate code coverage statistics:

```bash
$ scripts/coverage.sh
$ open target/cov/lcov-local/index.html
```

Why coverage? While most see coverage as a code quality metric, we see it primarily as a developer
productivity metric. When a developer makes a change to the codebase, presumably it&#039;s a _solution_ to
some problem. Our unit-test suite is how we encode the set of _problems_ the codebase solves. Running
the test suite should indicate that your change didn&#039;t _infringe_ on anyone else&#039;s solutions. Adding a
test _protects_ your solution from future changes. Say you don&#039;t understand why a line of code exists,
try deleting it and running the unit-tests. The nearest test failure should tell you what problem
was solved by that code. If no test fails, go ahead and submit a Pull Request that asks, &quot;what
problem is solved by this code?&quot; On the other hand, if a test does fail and you can think of a
better way to solve the same problem, a Pull Request with your solution would most certainly be
welcome! Likewise, if rewriting a test can better communicate what code it&#039;s protecting, please
send us that patch!

# Disclaimer

All claims, content, designs, algorithms, estimates, roadmaps,
specifications, and performance measurements described in this project
are done with the Solana Labs, Inc. (“SL”) good faith efforts. It is up to
the reader to check and validate their accuracy and truthfulness.
Furthermore, nothing in this project constitutes a solicitation for
investment.

Any content produced by SL or developer resources that SL provides are
for educational and inspirational purposes only. SL does not encourage,
induce or sanction the deployment, integration or use of any such
applications (including the code comprising the Solana blockchain
protocol) in violation of applicable laws or regulations and hereby
prohibits any such deployment, integration or use. This includes the use of
any such applications by the reader (a) in violation of export control
or sanctions laws of the United States or any other applicable
jurisdiction, (b) if the reader is located in or ordinarily resident in
a country or territory subject to comprehensive sanctions administered
by the U.S. Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC), or (c) if the
reader is or is working on behalf of a Specially Designated National
(SDN) or a person subject to similar blocking or denied party
prohibitions.

The reader should be aware that U.S. export control and sanctions laws prohibit
U.S. persons (and other persons that are subject to such laws) from transacting
with persons in certain countries and territories or that are on the SDN list.
Accordingly, there is a risk to individuals that other persons using any of the
code contained in this repo, or a derivation thereof, may be sanctioned persons
and that transactions with such persons would be a violation of U.S. export
controls and sanctions law.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[huggingface/candle]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/huggingface/candle</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/huggingface/candle</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Minimalist ML framework for Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/candle">huggingface/candle</a></h1>
            <p>Minimalist ML framework for Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 17,013</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,080</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># candle
[![discord server](https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/hugging-face-879548962464493619)](https://discord.gg/hugging-face-879548962464493619)
[![Latest version](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/candle-core.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/candle-core)
[![Documentation](https://docs.rs/candle-core/badge.svg)](https://docs.rs/candle-core)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/base-org/node?color=blue)](https://github.com/huggingface/candle/blob/main/LICENSE-MIT)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%202.0-blue?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/huggingface/candle/blob/main/LICENSE-APACHE)

Candle is a minimalist ML framework for Rust with a focus on performance (including GPU support) 
and ease of use. Try our online demos: 
[whisper](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-whisper),
[LLaMA2](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-llama2),
[T5](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-T5-Generation-Wasm),
[yolo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-yolo),
[Segment
Anything](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/candle-segment-anything-wasm).

## Get started

Make sure that you have [`candle-core`](https://github.com/huggingface/candle/tree/main/candle-core) correctly installed as described in [**Installation**](https://huggingface.github.io/candle/guide/installation.html).

Let&#039;s see how to run a simple matrix multiplication.
Write the following to your `myapp/src/main.rs` file:
```rust
use candle_core::{Device, Tensor};

fn main() -&gt; Result&lt;(), Box&lt;dyn std::error::Error&gt;&gt; {
    let device = Device::Cpu;

    let a = Tensor::randn(0f32, 1., (2, 3), &amp;device)?;
    let b = Tensor::randn(0f32, 1., (3, 4), &amp;device)?;

    let c = a.matmul(&amp;b)?;
    println!(&quot;{c}&quot;);
    Ok(())
}
```

`cargo run` should display a tensor of shape `Tensor[[2, 4], f32]`.


Having installed `candle` with Cuda support, simply define the `device` to be on GPU:

```diff
- let device = Device::Cpu;
+ let device = Device::new_cuda(0)?;
```

For more advanced examples, please have a look at the following section.

## Check out our examples

These online demos run entirely in your browser:
- [yolo](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-yolo): pose estimation and
  object recognition.
- [whisper](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-whisper): speech recognition.
- [LLaMA2](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-llama2): text generation.
- [T5](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-T5-Generation-Wasm): text generation.
- [Phi-1.5, and Phi-2](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-Phi-1.5-Wasm): text generation.
- [Segment Anything Model](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/candle-segment-anything-wasm): Image segmentation.
- [BLIP](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-BLIP-Image-Captioning): image captioning.

We also provide a some command line based examples using state of the art models:

- [LLaMA v1, v2, and v3](./candle-examples/examples/llama/): general LLM, includes
  the SOLAR-10.7B variant.
- [Falcon](./candle-examples/examples/falcon/): general LLM.
- [Codegeex4](./candle-examples/examples/codegeex4-9b/): Code completion,code interpreter,web search,fuction calling,repository-level
- [GLM4](./candle-examples/examples/glm4/): Open Multilingual Multimodal Chat LMs by THUDM
- [Gemma v1 and v2](./candle-examples/examples/gemma/): 2b and 7b+/9b general LLMs from Google Deepmind.
- [RecurrentGemma](./candle-examples/examples/recurrent-gemma/): 2b and 7b
  Griffin based models from Google that mix attention with a RNN like state.
- [Phi-1, Phi-1.5, Phi-2, and Phi-3](./candle-examples/examples/phi/): 1.3b,
  2.7b, and 3.8b general LLMs with performance on par with 7b models.
- [StableLM-3B-4E1T](./candle-examples/examples/stable-lm/): a 3b general LLM
  pre-trained on 1T tokens of English and code datasets. Also supports
  StableLM-2, a 1.6b LLM trained on 2T tokens, as well as the code variants.
- [Mamba](./candle-examples/examples/mamba/): an inference only
  implementation of the Mamba state space model.
- [Mistral7b-v0.1](./candle-examples/examples/mistral/): a 7b general LLM with
  better performance than all publicly available 13b models as of 2023-09-28.
- [Mixtral8x7b-v0.1](./candle-examples/examples/mixtral/): a sparse mixture of
  experts 8x7b general LLM with better performance than a Llama 2 70B model with
  much faster inference.
- [StarCoder](./candle-examples/examples/bigcode/) and
  [StarCoder2](./candle-examples/examples/starcoder2/): LLM specialized to code generation.
- [Qwen1.5](./candle-examples/examples/qwen/): Bilingual (English/Chinese) LLMs.
- [RWKV v5 and v6](./candle-examples/examples/rwkv/): An RNN with transformer level LLM
  performance.
- [Replit-code-v1.5](./candle-examples/examples/replit-code/): a 3.3b LLM specialized for code completion.
- [Yi-6B / Yi-34B](./candle-examples/examples/yi/): two bilingual
  (English/Chinese) general LLMs with 6b and 34b parameters.
- [Quantized LLaMA](./candle-examples/examples/quantized/): quantized version of
  the LLaMA model using the same quantization techniques as
  [llama.cpp](https://github.com/ggerganov/llama.cpp).

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/quantized/assets/aoc.gif&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;
  
- [Stable Diffusion](./candle-examples/examples/stable-diffusion/): text to
  image generative model, support for the 1.5, 2.1, SDXL 1.0 and Turbo versions.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/stable-diffusion/assets/stable-diffusion-xl.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;

- [Wuerstchen](./candle-examples/examples/wuerstchen/): another text to
  image generative model.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/wuerstchen/assets/cat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;

- [yolo-v3](./candle-examples/examples/yolo-v3/) and
  [yolo-v8](./candle-examples/examples/yolo-v8/): object detection and pose
  estimation models.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/yolo-v8/assets/bike.od.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/yolo-v8/assets/bike.pose.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;
- [segment-anything](./candle-examples/examples/segment-anything/): image
  segmentation model with prompt.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/candle/raw/main/candle-examples/examples/segment-anything/assets/sam_merged.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot;&gt;

- [SegFormer](./candle-examples/examples/segformer/): transformer based semantic segmentation model.
- [Whisper](./candle-examples/examples/whisper/): speech recognition model.
- [EnCodec](./candle-examples/examples/encodec/): high-quality audio compression
  model using residual vector quantization.
- [MetaVoice](./candle-examples/examples/metavoice/): foundational model for
  text-to-speech.
- [Parler-TTS](./candle-examples/examples/parler-tts/): large text-to-speech
  model.
- [T5](./candle-examples/examples/t5), [Bert](./candle-examples/examples/bert/),
  [JinaBert](./candle-examples/examples/jina-bert/) : useful for sentence embeddings.
- [DINOv2](./candle-examples/examples/dinov2/): computer vision model trained
  using self-supervision (can be used for imagenet classification, depth
  evaluation, segmentation).
- [VGG](./candle-examples/examples/vgg/),
  [RepVGG](./candle-examples/examples/repvgg): computer vision models.
- [BLIP](./candle-examples/examples/blip/): image to text model, can be used to
  generate captions for an image.
- [CLIP](./candle-examples/examples/clip/): multi-model vision and language
  model.
- [TrOCR](./candle-examples/examples/trocr/): a transformer OCR model, with
  dedicated submodels for hand-writing and printed recognition.
- [Marian-MT](./candle-examples/examples/marian-mt/): neural machine translation
  model, generates the translated text from the input text.
- [Moondream](./candle-examples/examples/moondream/): tiny computer-vision model 
  that can answer real-world questions about images.

Run them using commands like:
```
cargo run --example quantized --release
```

In order to use **CUDA** add `--features cuda` to the example command line. If
you have cuDNN installed, use `--features cudnn` for even more speedups.

There are also some wasm examples for whisper and
[llama2.c](https://github.com/karpathy/llama2.c). You can either build them with
`trunk` or try them online:
[whisper](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-whisper),
[llama2](https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-llama2),
[T5](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-T5-Generation-Wasm),
[Phi-1.5, and Phi-2](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/Candle-Phi-1.5-Wasm),
[Segment Anything Model](https://huggingface.co/spaces/radames/candle-segment-anything-wasm).

For LLaMA2, run the following command to retrieve the weight files and start a
test server:
```bash
cd candle-wasm-examples/llama2-c
wget https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-llama2/resolve/main/model.bin
wget https://huggingface.co/spaces/lmz/candle-llama2/resolve/main/tokenizer.json
trunk serve --release --port 8081
```
And then head over to
[http://localhost:8081/](http://localhost:8081/).

&lt;!--- ANCHOR: useful_libraries ---&gt;

## Useful External Resources
- [`candle-tutorial`](https://github.com/ToluClassics/candle-tutorial): A
  very detailed tutorial showing how to convert a PyTorch model to Candle.
- [`candle-lora`](https://github.com/EricLBuehler/candle-lora): Efficient and
  ergonomic LoRA implementation for Candle. `candle-lora` has      
  out-of-the-box LoRA support for many models from Candle, which can be found
  [here](https://github.com/EricLBuehler/candle-lora/tree/master/candle-lora-transformers/examples).
- [`optimisers`](https://github.com/KGrewal1/optimisers): A collection of optimisers
  including SGD with momentum, AdaGrad, AdaDelta, AdaMax, NAdam, RAdam, and RMSprop.
- [`candle-vllm`](https://github.com/EricLBuehler/candle-vllm): Efficient platform for inference and
  serving local LLMs including an OpenAI compatible API server.
- [`candle-ext`](https://github.com/mokeyish/candle-ext): An extension library to Candle that provides PyTorch functions not currently available in Candle.
- [`candle-coursera-ml`](https://github.com/vishpat/candle-coursera-ml): Implementation of ML algorithms from Coursera&#039;s [Machine Learning Specialization](https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning-introduction) course.
- [`kalosm`](https://github.com/floneum/floneum/tree/master/interfaces/kalosm): A multi-modal meta-framework in Rust for interfacing with local pre-trained models with support for controlled generation, custom samplers, in-memory vector databases, audio transcription, and more.
- [`candle-sampling`](https://github.com/EricLBuehler/candle-sampling): Sampling techniques for Candle.
- [`gpt-from-scratch-rs`](https://github.com/jeroenvlek/gpt-from-scratch-rs): A port of Andrej Karpathy&#039;s _Let&#039;s build GPT_ tutorial on YouTube showcasing the Candle API on a toy problem.
- [`candle-einops`](https://github.com/tomsanbear/candle-einops): A pure rust implementation of the python [einops](https://github.com/arogozhnikov/einops) library.
- [`atoma-infer`](https://github.com/atoma-network/atoma-infer): A Rust library for fast inference at scale, leveraging FlashAttention2 for efficient attention computation, PagedAttention for efficient KV-cache memory management, and multi-GPU support. It is OpenAI api compatible.
- [`llms-from-scratch-rs`](https://github.com/nerdai/llms-from-scratch-rs): A comprehensive Rust translation of the code from Sebastian Raschka&#039;s Build an LLM from Scratch book.

If you have an addition to this list, please submit a pull request.

&lt;!--- ANCHOR_END: useful_libraries ---&gt;

&lt;!--- ANCHOR: features ---&gt;

## Features

- Simple syntax, looks and feels like PyTorch.
    - Model training.
    - Embed user-defined ops/kernels, such as [flash-attention v2](https://github.com/huggingface/candle/blob/89ba005962495f2bfbda286e185e9c3c7f5300a3/candle-flash-attn/src/lib.rs#L152).
- Backends.
    - Optimized CPU backend with optional MKL support for x86 and Accelerate for macs.
    - CUDA backend for efficiently running on GPUs, multiple GPU distribution via NCCL.
    - WASM support, run your models in a browser.
- Included models.
    - Language Models.
        - LLaMA v1, v2, and v3 with variants such as SOLAR-10.7B.
        - Falcon.
        - StarCoder, StarCoder2.
        - Phi 1, 1.5, 2, and 3.
        - Mamba, Minimal Mamba
        - Gemma v1 2b and 7b+, v2 2b and 9b.
        - Mistral 7b v0.1.
        - Mixtral 8x7b v0.1.
        - StableLM-3B-4E1T, StableLM-2-1.6B, Stable-Code-3B.
        - Replit-code-v1.5-3B.
        - Bert.
        - Yi-6B and Yi-34B.
        - Qwen1.5, Qwen1.5 MoE.
        - RWKV v5 and v6.
    - Quantized LLMs.
        - Llama 7b, 13b, 70b, as well as the chat and code variants.
        - Mistral 7b, and 7b instruct.
        - Mixtral 8x7b.
        - Zephyr 7b a and b (Mistral-7b based).
        - OpenChat 3.5 (Mistral-7b based).
    - Text to text.
        - T5 and its variants: FlanT5, UL2, MADLAD400 (translation), CoEdit (Grammar correction).
        - Marian MT (Machine Translation).
    - Text to image.
        - Stable Diffusion v1.5, v2.1, XL v1.0.
        - Wurstchen v2.
    - Image to text.
        - BLIP.
        - TrOCR.
    - Audio.
        - Whisper, multi-lingual speech-to-text.
        - EnCodec, audio compression model.
        - MetaVoice-1B, text-to-speech model.
        - Parler-TTS, text-to-speech model.
    - Computer Vision Models.
        - DINOv2, ConvMixer, EfficientNet, ResNet, ViT, VGG, RepVGG, ConvNeXT,
          ConvNeXTv2, MobileOne, EfficientVit (MSRA), MobileNetv4, Hiera, FastViT.
        - yolo-v3, yolo-v8.
        - Segment-Anything Model (SAM).
        - SegFormer.
- File formats: load models from safetensors, npz, ggml, or PyTorch files.
- Serverless (on CPU), small and fast deployments.
- Quantization support using the llama.cpp quantized types.

&lt;!--- ANCHOR_END: features ---&gt;

## How to use

&lt;!--- ANCHOR: cheatsheet ---&gt;
Cheatsheet:

|            | Using PyTorch                            | Using Candle                                                     |
|------------|------------------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------|
| Creation   | `torch.Tensor([[1, 2], [3, 4]])`         | `Tensor::new(&amp;[[1f32, 2.], [3., 4.]], &amp;Device::Cpu)?`           |
| Creation   | `torch.zeros((2, 2))`                    | `Tensor::zeros((2, 2), DType::F32, &amp;Device::Cpu)?`               |
| Indexing   | `tensor[:, :4]`                          | `tensor.i((.., ..4))?`                                           |
| Operations | `tensor.view((2, 2))`                    | `tensor.reshape((2, 2))?`                                        |
| Operations | `a.matmul(b)`                            | `a.matmul(&amp;b)?`                                                  |
| Arithmetic | `a + b`                                  | `&amp;a + &amp;b`                                                        |
| Device     | `tensor.to(device=&quot;cuda&quot;)`               | `tensor.to_device(&amp;Device::new_cuda(0)?)?`                            |
| Dtype      | `tensor.to(dtype=torch.float16)`         | `tensor.to_dtype(&amp;DType::F16)?`                                  |
| Saving     | `torch.save({&quot;A&quot;: A}, &quot;model.bin&quot;)`      | `candle::safetensors::save(&amp;HashMap::from([(&quot;A&quot;, A)]), &quot;model.safetensors&quot;)?` |
| Loading    | `weights = torch.load(&quot;model.bin&quot;)`      | `candle::safetensors::load(&quot;model.safetensors&quot;, &amp;device)`        |

&lt;!--- ANCHOR_END: cheatsheet ---&gt;


## Structure

- [candle-core](./candle-core): Core ops, devices, and `Tensor` struct definition
- [candle-nn](./candle-nn/): Tools to build real models
- [candle-examples](./candle-examples/): Examples of using the library in realistic settings
- [candle-kernels](./candle-kernels/): CUDA custom kernels
- [candle-datasets](./candle-datasets/): Datasets and data loaders.
- [candle-transformers](./candle-transformers): transformers-related utilities.
- [candle-flash-attn](./candle-flash-attn): Flash attention v2 layer.
- [candle-onnx](./candle-onnx/): ONNX model evaluation.

## FAQ

### Why should I use Candle?

Candle&#039;s core goal is to *make serverless inference possible*. Full machine learning frameworks like PyTorch
are very large, which makes creating instances on a cluster slow. Candle allows deployment of lightweight
binaries.

Secondly, Candle lets you *remove Python* from production workloads. Python overhead can seriously hurt performance,
and the [GIL](https://www.backblaze.com/blog/the-python-gil-past-present-and-future/) is a notorious source of headaches.

Finally, Rust is cool! A lot of the HF ecosystem already has Rust crates, like [safetensors](https://github.com/huggingface/safetensors) and [tokenizers](https://github.com/huggingface/tokenizers).


### Other ML frameworks

- [dfdx](https://github.com/coreylowman/dfdx) is a formidable crate, with shapes being included
  in types. This prevents a lot of headaches by getting the compiler to complain about shape mismatches right off the bat.
  However, we found that some features still require nightly, and writing code can be a bit daunting for non rust experts.

  We&#039;re leveraging and contributing to other core crates for the runtime so hopefully both crates can benefit from each
  other.

- [burn](https://github.com/burn-rs/burn) is a general crate that can leverage multiple backends so you can choose the best
  engine for your workload.

- [tch-rs](https://github.com/LaurentMazare/tch-rs.git) Bindings to the torch library in Rust. Extremely versatile, but they 
  bring in the entire torch library into the runtime. The main contributor of `tch-rs` is also involved in the development
  of `candle`.

### Common Errors

#### Missing symbols when compiling with the mkl feature.

If you get some missing symbols when compiling binaries/tests using the mkl
or accelerate features, e.g. for mkl you get:
```
  = note: /usr/bin/ld: (....o): in function `blas::sgemm&#039;:
          .../blas-0.22.0/src/lib.rs:1944: undefined reference to `sgemm_&#039; collect2: error: ld returned 1 exit status

  = note: some `extern` functions couldn&#039;t be found; some native libraries may need to be installed or have their path specified
  = note: use the `-l` flag to specify native libraries to link
  = note: use the `cargo:rustc-link-lib` directive to specify the native libraries to link with Cargo
```
or for accelerate:
```
Undefined symbols for architecture arm64:
            &quot;_dgemm_&quot;, referenced from:
                candle_core::accelerate::dgemm::h1b71a038552bcabe in libcandle_core...
            &quot;_sgemm_&quot;, referenced from:
                candle_core::accelerate::sgemm::h2cf21c592cba3c47 in libcandle_core...
          ld: symbol(s) not found for architecture arm64
```

This is likely due to a missing linker flag that was needed to enable the mkl library. You
can try adding the following for mkl at the top of your binary:
```rust
extern crate intel_mkl_src;
```
or for accelerate:
```rust
extern crate accelerate_src;
```

#### Cannot run the LLaMA examples: access to source requires login credentials

```
Error: request error: https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-2-7b-hf/resolve/main/tokenizer.json: status code 401
```

This is likely because you&#039;re not permissioned for the LLaMA-v2 model. To fix
this, you have to register on the huggingface-hub, accept the [LLaMA-v2 model
conditions](https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-2-7b-hf), and set up your
authentication token. See issue
[#350](https://github.com/huggingface/candle/issues/350) for more details.

#### Missing cute/cutlass headers when compiling flash-attn

```
  In file included from kernels/flash_fwd_launch_template.h:11:0,
                   from kernels/flash_fwd_hdim224_fp16_sm80.cu:5:
  kernels/flash_fwd_kernel.h:8:10: fatal error: cute/algorithm/copy.hpp: No such file or directory
   #include

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iced-rs/iced]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/iced-rs/iced</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/iced-rs/iced</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A cross-platform GUI library for Rust, inspired by Elm]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/iced-rs/iced">iced-rs/iced</a></h1>
            <p>A cross-platform GUI library for Rust, inspired by Elm</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 26,258</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,276</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;docs/logo.svg&quot; width=&quot;140px&quot; /&gt;

# Iced

[![Documentation](https://docs.rs/iced/badge.svg)][documentation]
[![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/iced.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/iced)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/crates/l/iced.svg)](https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/blob/master/LICENSE)
[![Downloads](https://img.shields.io/crates/d/iced.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/iced)
[![Test Status](https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/iced-rs/iced/test.yml?branch=master&amp;event=push&amp;label=test)](https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/actions)
[![Discourse](https://img.shields.io/badge/dynamic/json?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdiscourse.iced.rs%2Fsite%2Fstatistics.json&amp;query=%24.users_count&amp;suffix=%20users&amp;label=discourse&amp;color=5e7ce2)](https://discourse.iced.rs/)
[![Discord Server](https://img.shields.io/discord/628993209984614400?label=&amp;labelColor=6A7EC2&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;color=7389D8)](https://discord.gg/3xZJ65GAhd)

A cross-platform GUI library for Rust focused on simplicity and type-safety.
Inspired by [Elm].

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/squidowl/halloy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://iced.rs/showcase/halloy.gif&quot; width=&quot;460px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hecrj/icebreaker&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://iced.rs/showcase/icebreaker.gif&quot; width=&quot;360px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

## Features

* Simple, easy-to-use, batteries-included API
* Type-safe, reactive programming model
* [Cross-platform support] (Windows, macOS, Linux, and the Web)
* Responsive layout
* Built-in widgets (including [text inputs], [scrollables], and more!)
* Custom widget support (create your own!)
* [Debug overlay with performance metrics]
* First-class support for async actions (use futures!)
* Modular ecosystem split into reusable parts:
  * A [renderer-agnostic native runtime] enabling integration with existing systems
  * Two built-in renderers leveraging [`wgpu`] and [`tiny-skia`]
    * [`iced_wgpu`] supporting Vulkan, Metal and DX12
    * [`iced_tiny_skia`] offering a software alternative as a fallback
  * A [windowing shell]

__Iced is currently experimental software.__ [Take a look at the roadmap] and
[check out the issues].

[Cross-platform support]: https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iced-rs/iced/master/docs/images/todos_desktop.jpg
[text inputs]: https://iced.rs/examples/text_input.mp4
[scrollables]: https://iced.rs/examples/scrollable.mp4
[Debug overlay with performance metrics]: https://iced.rs/examples/debug.mp4
[renderer-agnostic native runtime]: runtime/
[`wgpu`]: https://github.com/gfx-rs/wgpu
[`tiny-skia`]: https://github.com/RazrFalcon/tiny-skia
[`iced_wgpu`]: wgpu/
[`iced_tiny_skia`]: tiny_skia/
[windowing shell]: winit/
[Take a look at the roadmap]: ROADMAP.md
[check out the issues]: https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/issues

## Overview

Inspired by [The Elm Architecture], Iced expects you to split user interfaces
into four different concepts:

* __State__ — the state of your application
* __Messages__ — user interactions or meaningful events that you care
  about
* __View logic__ — a way to display your __state__ as widgets that
  may produce __messages__ on user interaction
* __Update logic__ — a way to react to __messages__ and update your
  __state__

We can build something to see how this works! Let&#039;s say we want a simple counter
that can be incremented and decremented using two buttons.

We start by modelling the __state__ of our application:

```rust
#[derive(Default)]
struct Counter {
    value: i32,
}
```

Next, we need to define the possible user interactions of our counter:
the button presses. These interactions are our __messages__:

```rust
#[derive(Debug, Clone, Copy)]
pub enum Message {
    Increment,
    Decrement,
}
```

Now, let&#039;s show the actual counter by putting it all together in our
__view logic__:

```rust
use iced::widget::{button, column, text, Column};

impl Counter {
    pub fn view(&amp;self) -&gt; Column&lt;Message&gt; {
        // We use a column: a simple vertical layout
        column![
            // The increment button. We tell it to produce an
            // `Increment` message when pressed
            button(&quot;+&quot;).on_press(Message::Increment),

            // We show the value of the counter here
            text(self.value).size(50),

            // The decrement button. We tell it to produce a
            // `Decrement` message when pressed
            button(&quot;-&quot;).on_press(Message::Decrement),
        ]
    }
}
```

Finally, we need to be able to react to any produced __messages__ and change our
__state__ accordingly in our __update logic__:

```rust
impl Counter {
    // ...

    pub fn update(&amp;mut self, message: Message) {
        match message {
            Message::Increment =&gt; {
                self.value += 1;
            }
            Message::Decrement =&gt; {
                self.value -= 1;
            }
        }
    }
}
```

And that&#039;s everything! We just wrote a whole user interface. Let&#039;s run it:

```rust
fn main() -&gt; iced::Result {
    iced::run(&quot;A cool counter&quot;, Counter::update, Counter::view)
}
```

Iced will automatically:

  1. Take the result of our __view logic__ and layout its widgets.
  1. Process events from our system and produce __messages__ for our
     __update logic__.
  1. Draw the resulting user interface.

Read the [book], the [documentation], and the [examples] to learn more!

## Implementation details

Iced was originally born as an attempt at bringing the simplicity of [Elm] and
[The Elm Architecture] into [Coffee], a 2D game library I am working on.

The core of the library was implemented during May 2019 in [this pull request].
[The first alpha version] was eventually released as
[a renderer-agnostic GUI library]. The library did not provide a renderer and
implemented the current [tour example] on top of [`ggez`], a game library.

Since then, the focus has shifted towards providing a batteries-included,
end-user-oriented GUI library, while keeping the ecosystem modular.

[this pull request]: https://github.com/hecrj/coffee/pull/35
[The first alpha version]: https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/tree/0.1.0-alpha
[a renderer-agnostic GUI library]: https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/czzjnv/iced_a_rendereragnostic_gui_library_focused_on/
[tour example]: examples/README.md#tour
[`ggez`]: https://github.com/ggez/ggez

## Contributing / Feedback

If you want to contribute, please read our [contributing guidelines] for more details.

Feedback is also welcome! You can create a new topic in [our Discourse forum] or
come chat to [our Discord server].

## Sponsors

The development of Iced is sponsored by the [Cryptowatch] team at [Kraken.com]

[book]: https://book.iced.rs/
[documentation]: https://docs.rs/iced/
[examples]: https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/tree/master/examples#examples
[Coffee]: https://github.com/hecrj/coffee
[Elm]: https://elm-lang.org/
[The Elm Architecture]: https://guide.elm-lang.org/architecture/
[the current issues]: https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/issues
[contributing guidelines]: https://github.com/iced-rs/iced/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md
[our Discourse forum]: https://discourse.iced.rs/
[our Discord server]: https://discord.gg/3xZJ65GAhd
[Cryptowatch]: https://cryptowat.ch/charts
[Kraken.com]: https://kraken.com/
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[embassy-rs/embassy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Modern embedded framework, using Rust and async.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy">embassy-rs/embassy</a></h1>
            <p>Modern embedded framework, using Rust and async.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,595</p>
            <p>Forks: 984</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Embassy

Embassy is the next-generation framework for embedded applications. Write safe, correct and energy-efficient embedded code faster, using the Rust programming language, its async facilities, and the Embassy libraries.

## &lt;a href=&quot;https://embassy.dev/book/index.html&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/&quot;&gt;API reference&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://embassy.dev/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#embassy-rs:matrix.org&quot;&gt;Chat&lt;/a&gt;
## Rust + async ❤️ embedded

The Rust programming language is blazingly fast and memory-efficient, with no runtime, garbage collector or OS. It catches a wide variety of bugs at compile time, thanks to its full memory- and thread-safety, and expressive type system. 

Rust&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang.github.io/async-book/&quot;&gt;async/await&lt;/a&gt; allows for unprecedentedly easy and efficient multitasking in embedded systems. Tasks get transformed at compile time into state machines that get run cooperatively. It requires no dynamic memory allocation, and runs on a single stack,  so no per-task stack size tuning is required. It obsoletes the need for a traditional RTOS with kernel context switching, and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tweedegolf.nl/en/blog/65/async-rust-vs-rtos-showdown&quot;&gt;faster and smaller than one!&lt;/a&gt;

## Batteries included

- **Hardware Abstraction Layers** - HALs implement safe, idiomatic Rust APIs to use the hardware capabilities, so raw register manipulation is not needed. The Embassy project maintains HALs for select hardware, but you can still use HALs from other projects with Embassy.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-stm32/&quot;&gt;embassy-stm32&lt;/a&gt;, for all STM32 microcontroller families.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-nrf/&quot;&gt;embassy-nrf&lt;/a&gt;, for the Nordic Semiconductor nRF52, nRF53, nRF54 and nRF91 series.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-rp/&quot;&gt;embassy-rp&lt;/a&gt;, for the Raspberry Pi RP2040 and RP23xx microcontrollers.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-mspm0/&quot;&gt;embassy-mspm0&lt;/a&gt;, for the Texas Instruments MSPM0 microcontrollers.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/esp-rs&quot;&gt;esp-rs&lt;/a&gt;, for the Espressif Systems ESP32 series of chips.
    - Embassy HAL support for Espressif chips, as well as Async WiFi, Bluetooth and ESP-NOW,  is being developed in the [esp-rs/esp-hal](https://github.com/esp-rs/esp-hal) repository.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ch32-rs/ch32-hal&quot;&gt;ch32-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the WCH 32-bit RISC-V(CH32V) series of chips.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AlexCharlton/mpfs-hal&quot;&gt;mpfs-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the Microchip PolarFire SoC.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/py32-rs/py32-hal&quot;&gt;py32-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the Puya Semiconductor PY32 series of microcontrollers.

- **Time that Just Works** - 
No more messing with hardware timers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-time&quot;&gt;embassy_time&lt;/a&gt; provides Instant, Duration and Timer types that are globally available and never overflow.

- **Real-time ready** - 
Tasks on the same async executor run cooperatively, but you can create multiple executors with different priorities, so that higher priority tasks preempt lower priority ones. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/blob/master/examples/nrf52840/src/bin/multiprio.rs&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;.

- **Low-power ready** - 
Easily build devices with years of battery life. The async executor automatically puts the core to sleep when there&#039;s no work to do. Tasks are woken by interrupts, there is no busy-loop polling while waiting.
 
- **Networking** - 
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-net/&quot;&gt;embassy-net&lt;/a&gt; network stack implements extensive networking functionality, including Ethernet, IP, TCP, UDP, ICMP and DHCP. Async drastically simplifies managing timeouts and serving multiple connections concurrently.

- **Bluetooth**
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/trouble&quot;&gt;trouble&lt;/a&gt; crate provides a Bluetooth Low Energy 4.x and 5.x Host that runs on any microcontroller implementing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/bt-hci&quot;&gt;bt-hci&lt;/a&gt; traits (currently `nRF52`, `rp2040`, `rp23xx` and `esp32` and `serial` controllers are supported).
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/nrf-softdevice&quot;&gt;nrf-softdevice&lt;/a&gt; crate provides Bluetooth Low Energy 4.x and 5.x support for nRF52 microcontrollers.
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/tree/main/embassy-stm32-wpan&quot;&gt;embassy-stm32-wpan&lt;/a&gt; crate provides Bluetooth Low Energy 5.x support for stm32wb microcontrollers.

- **LoRa** - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lora-rs/lora-rs&quot;&gt;lora-rs&lt;/a&gt; project provides an async LoRa and LoRaWAN stack that works well on Embassy.

- **USB** - 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-usb/&quot;&gt;embassy-usb&lt;/a&gt; implements a device-side USB stack. Implementations for common classes such as USB serial (CDC ACM) and USB HID are available, and a rich builder API allows building your own.

- **Bootloader and DFU** - 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/tree/master/embassy-boot&quot;&gt;embassy-boot&lt;/a&gt; is a lightweight bootloader supporting firmware application upgrades in a power-fail-safe way, with trial boots and rollbacks.


## Sneak peek

```rust,ignore
use defmt::info;
use embassy_executor::Spawner;
use embassy_time::{Duration, Timer};
use embassy_nrf::gpio::{AnyPin, Input, Level, Output, OutputDrive, Pin, Pull};
use embassy_nrf::{Peri, Peripherals};

// Declare async tasks
#[embassy_executor::task]
async fn blink(pin: Peri&lt;&#039;static, AnyPin&gt;) {
    let mut led = Output::new(pin, Level::Low, OutputDrive::Standard);

    loop {
        // Timekeeping is globally available, no need to mess with hardware timers.
        led.set_high();
        Timer::after_millis(150).await;
        led.set_low();
        Timer::after_millis(150).await;
    }
}

// Main is itself an async task as well.
#[embassy_executor::main]
async fn main(spawner: Spawner) {
    let p = embassy_nrf::init(Default::default());

    // Spawned tasks run in the background, concurrently.
    spawner.spawn(blink(p.P0_13.into())).unwrap();

    let mut button = Input::new(p.P0_11, Pull::Up);
    loop {
        // Asynchronously wait for GPIO events, allowing other tasks
        // to run, or the core to sleep.
        button.wait_for_low().await;
        info!(&quot;Button pressed!&quot;);
        button.wait_for_high().await;
        info!(&quot;Button released!&quot;);
    }
}
```

## Examples

Examples are found in the `examples/` folder separated by the chip manufacturer they are designed to run on. For example:

*   `examples/nrf52840` run on the `nrf52840-dk` board (PCA10056) but should be easily adaptable to other nRF52 chips and boards.
*   `examples/nrf5340` run on the `nrf5340-dk` board (PCA10095).
*   `examples/stm32xx` for the various STM32 families.
*   `examples/rp` are for the RP2040 chip.
*   `examples/std` are designed to run locally on your PC.

### Running examples

- Install `probe-rs` following the instructions at &lt;https://probe.rs&gt;.
- Change directory to the sample&#039;s base directory. For example:

```bash
cd examples/nrf52840
```

- Ensure `Cargo.toml` sets the right feature for the name of the chip you are programming.
  If this name is incorrect, the example may fail to run or immediately crash
  after being programmed.

- Ensure `.cargo/config.toml` contains the name of the chip you are programming.

- Run the example

For example:

```bash
cargo run --release --bin blinky
```

For more help getting started, see [Getting Started][1] and [Running the Examples][2].

## Developing Embassy with Rust Analyzer based editors

The [Rust Analyzer](https://rust-analyzer.github.io/) is used by [Visual Studio Code](https://code.visualstudio.com/)
and others. Given the multiple targets that Embassy serves, there is no Cargo workspace file. Instead, the Rust Analyzer
must be told of the target project to work with. In the case of Visual Studio Code,
please refer to the `.vscode/settings.json` file&#039;s `rust-analyzer.linkedProjects`setting.

## Minimum supported Rust version (MSRV)

Embassy is guaranteed to compile on stable Rust 1.75 and up. It *might*
compile with older versions but that may change in any new patch release.

## Why the name?

EMBedded ASYnc! :)

## License

Embassy is licensed under either of

- Apache License, Version 2.0 ([LICENSE-APACHE](LICENSE-APACHE) or
  &lt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&gt;)
- MIT license ([LICENSE-MIT](LICENSE-MIT) or &lt;http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&gt;)

at your option.

## Contribution

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted
for inclusion in the work by you, as defined in the Apache-2.0 license, shall be
dual licensed as above, without any additional terms or conditions.

[1]: https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/wiki/Getting-Started
[2]: https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/wiki/Running-the-Examples
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ankitects/anki]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ankitects/anki</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ankitects/anki</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Anki's shared backend and web components, and the Qt frontend]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ankitects/anki">ankitects/anki</a></h1>
            <p>Anki's shared backend and web components, and the Qt frontend</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,814</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,286</p>
            <p>Stars today: 17 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Anki

[![Build status](https://badge.buildkite.com/c9edf020a4aec976f9835e54751cc5409d843adbb66d043bd3.svg?branch=main)](https://buildkite.com/ankitects/anki-ci)

This repo contains the source code for the computer version of
[Anki](https://apps.ankiweb.net).

# About

Anki is a spaced repetition program. Please see the [website](https://apps.ankiweb.net) to learn more.

# Getting Started

### Anki Betas

If you&#039;d like to try development builds of Anki but don&#039;t feel comfortable
building the code, please see [Anki betas](https://betas.ankiweb.net/)

### Developing

For more information on building and developing, please see [Development](./docs/development.md).

### Contributing

Want to contribute to Anki? Check out the [Contribution Guidelines](./docs/contributing.md).

### Anki Contributors

[CONTRIBUTORS](./CONTRIBUTORS)

# License

Anki&#039;s license: [LICENSE](./LICENSE)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FractalFir/rustc_codegen_clr]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/FractalFir/rustc_codegen_clr</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/FractalFir/rustc_codegen_clr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Rust compiler backend targeting CIL(.NET IR) and C.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/FractalFir/rustc_codegen_clr">FractalFir/rustc_codegen_clr</a></h1>
            <p>A Rust compiler backend targeting CIL(.NET IR) and C.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,857</p>
            <p>Forks: 46</p>
            <p>Stars today: 13 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># rustc_codegen_clr 

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; This project is still early in its developement. Bugs, crashes and miscompilations are expected. DO NOT USE IT FOR ANYTHING SERIOUS.

`rustc_codegen_clr` is an experimental Rust compiler backend(plugin), which allows you to transpile Rust into .NET assebmlies, or C source files. 

The end goal of the project is allowing Rust to be used in places where it could not be used before. 

## .NET Interop layer

The project aims to provide a way to easily use Rust libraries in .NET. It comes with a Rust/.NET interop layer, which allows you to easily interact with .NET code from Rust:

```
use mychorizza::*;
fn main(){
    // Alocate a new GC-managed string builder
    let stringBuilder = StringBuilder::empty();
    // You can easily operate on GC-managed types
    mstring.AppendChar(&#039;H&#039;);
    mstring.AppendChar(&#039;i&#039;);
    mstring.AppendChar(&#039;.&#039;);
}
```
This should allow you to integrate Rust code with exisitng .NET codebases, and should allow you to use .NET-specific libraries or APIs from Rust.

The project will also include support for defining .NET classes from Rust, allowing .NET code to easily call Rust.
This is currently heavily WIP, and any feedback is appreciated.
```
// Early WIP syntax, subject to change.
dotnet_typedef! {
  class MyClass inherits [Some::External::Assebmly]SomeNamespace::SomeClass{
    virtual fn ToString(_this:MyClass)-&gt;MString{
      &quot;I am a class defined in Rust!&quot;.into_managed()
    },
  }
}
```

With this approach, the classes and APIs exposed to .NET can be easily used from other .NET languages, like F# or C#. The safety of this glue layer can be checked by the Rust compiler, which should make interop issues much less likely.

## C support

While .NET is the main focus of my work, this project can also be used to compile Rust to C, by setting the `C_MODE` enviroment flag to `1`.

This may seem like a strange and unrelated feature, but the project was written in such a way that this is not only possible, but relatively easy.

My representation of .NETs IR maps nicely to C, which means that I was able to add support for compiling Rust to C in 2-3K LOC. Almost all of the codebase is reused, with the C and .NET specific code only 
present in the very last stage of compilation.

This means that, instead of having to maintain 2 separate projects, I can maintain one project. Bug fixes to the .NET side of things also fix C bugs. 
Because of that, the support for C in the project is almost as good as support for .NET

## Current state of the project

The project currently supports most Rust features (except proc macros), but it is not bug-free. It can compile a mostly working version of Rust std, but there are many minor bugs make such `std` not 100% functional.

Most components of `std` are about 95% working in .NET, and 80% working in C.
So, you *can* compile a lot of existing Rust code, but it may not necessarily *work*.

## Supported C compilers

Currently, the GCC and clang C compilers are supported, with partial support for `tcc` and `sdcc`.
For obvious reasons, I am unable to add support for any C propietary compilers which are not free to use.
However, if you have access to such a compiler, I can assist you in adding support for it.

| Compiler | Status |
| GCC | Fully Supported &amp; regularly tested |
| Clang | Fully Supported &amp; regularly tested |
| TCC | Partially supported - issues with TLS / multithreading |
| SDCC | Partailly supported - no atomics, no statics / constants larger than 8 bytes supported |
| CompCert | Partailly supported(no known issues), not tested! |

### core, std, and alloc uint tests.

.NET

| Name | Pass	| Faliure	| Crash \ Timeout| OK precentage
|--------------------|--------|-------|-------|------|
| Core tests |	1764	| 48	| 20	| 96.29% |
| Alloc tests | 	616	|8 |	40 |	92.77% |
| Alloc benches	| 464	| 0	| 0 |	100.00% |
| Test Harness tests |	57 |	0	| 100.00% |
| std tests	| 931 | 43 | 64 |	89.69% |
| Core benches	| 491 | 1| | 98.99% |

C

| Name | Pass	| Faliure| Crash \ Timeout | OK precentage
|--------------------|--------|------|-------|------|
| Core tests |	1712	| 71 | 8 | 95.59%|

## FAQ

### Q: What is it?

**A**: *This is a compiler backend for rustc, which targets the `.NET` platform and runtime; this would enable you to use some Rust libraries from C#/F#, with little effort.*

### Q: Is Rust&#039;s memory management useless in .NET?

**A**: *Rust code typically uses the stack more than the heap, which can speed up code running within the CLR runtime. Heap-allocated objects are allocated from unmanaged (non-GC) memory and are allocated and freed in the same way as in Rust.*

### Q: Is this useless since I can already load shared libraries from C#?

**A**: *The Rust APIs this codegen exposes to C#/F# code are only slightly easier to use than those exposed by a .so or .dll Rust library. Interop still requires some effort, but the Rust code is bundled with everything else. Types used from C# are guaranteed to be the same as those in C#, preventing mismatch issues. All types can be safely sent between Rust and C#, with exactly the same layout. Additionally, since all Rust code compiled with this codegen can be bundled with C#/F# code, you no longer need to ship different versions of the library for different architectures. Any architecture supported by CLR works out of the box, using the exact same assembly.*

*You can also avoid the cost of switching between code running within and outside the runtime. This cost is not unbearable, but it is not easily eliminated, and reducing it can have safety penalties. In this case, all code runs within the runtime, meaning there is no transition between code running inside and outside the runtime.*

*Compiling Rust to CLR can potentially improve JIT optimization. Since the CLR&#039;s JIT now sees all the code, it can make better decisions about optimization, resulting in faster code.*

### Q: Compatibility?

**A**: *`rustc_codegen_clr` is only tested on Linux x86_64, with the CoreCLR runtime (more commonly known as simply the .NET runtime), on .NET 8. It should work on other platforms, but it is not guaranteed.*

### Q: What about Mono?

**A**: *The support for the Mono runtime is not as good as it could be. Due to not supported features and differences, 128-bit integers and checked 64-bit integer arithmetic are not supported on Mono.*
*Aligned allocators(__rust_alloc) and certain intrinsics are also not supported. I plan to expand support for Mono, but my resources are limited.*

### Q: Are there any issues?

**A**: *While the backend is extensively tested, it is still far from perfect, and there are still many edge cases that may break this backend.*
**A**: *Currently, there are no .NET-specific versions of `std` or .NET specific target triples. This means that you will need separate .NET assemblies for each OS.*

## Licensing

`rustc_codegen_clr` is dual licensed under MIT license or Apache License, Version 2.0.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[alacritty/alacritty]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A cross-platform, OpenGL terminal emulator.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty">alacritty/alacritty</a></h1>
            <p>A cross-platform, OpenGL terminal emulator.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 58,327</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,097</p>
            <p>Stars today: 19 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;200&quot; alt=&quot;Alacritty Logo&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alacritty/alacritty/master/extra/logo/compat/alacritty-term%2Bscanlines.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Alacritty - A fast, cross-platform, OpenGL terminal emulator&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Alacritty - A fast, cross-platform, OpenGL terminal emulator&quot;
       src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alacritty/alacritty/master/extra/promo/alacritty-readme.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## About

Alacritty is a modern terminal emulator that comes with sensible defaults, but
allows for extensive [configuration](#configuration). By integrating with other
applications, rather than reimplementing their functionality, it manages to
provide a flexible set of [features](./docs/features.md) with high performance.
The supported platforms currently consist of BSD, Linux, macOS and Windows.

The software is considered to be at a **beta** level of readiness; there are
a few missing features and bugs to be fixed, but it is already used by many as
a daily driver.

Precompiled binaries are available from the [GitHub releases page](https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty/releases).

Join [`#alacritty`] on libera.chat if you have questions or looking for a quick help.

[`#alacritty`]: https://web.libera.chat/gamja/?channels=#alacritty

## Features

You can find an overview over the features available in Alacritty [here](./docs/features.md).

## Further information

- [Announcing Alacritty, a GPU-Accelerated Terminal Emulator](https://jwilm.io/blog/announcing-alacritty/) January 6, 2017
- [A talk about Alacritty at the Rust Meetup January 2017](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qHOdYO3WUTk) January 19, 2017
- [Alacritty Lands Scrollback, Publishes Benchmarks](https://jwilm.io/blog/alacritty-lands-scrollback/) September 17, 2018

## Installation

Alacritty can be installed by using various package managers on Linux, BSD,
macOS and Windows.

Prebuilt binaries for macOS and Windows can also be downloaded from the
[GitHub releases page](https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty/releases).

For everyone else, the detailed instructions to install Alacritty can be found
[here](INSTALL.md).

### Requirements

- At least OpenGL ES 2.0
- [Windows] ConPTY support (Windows 10 version 1809 or higher)

## Configuration

You can find the documentation for Alacritty&#039;s configuration in `man 5
alacritty`, or by looking at [the website] if you do not have the manpages
installed.

[the website]: https://alacritty.org/config-alacritty.html

Alacritty doesn&#039;t create the config file for you, but it looks for one in the
following locations:

1. `$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/alacritty/alacritty.toml`
2. `$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/alacritty.toml`
3. `$HOME/.config/alacritty/alacritty.toml`
4. `$HOME/.alacritty.toml`

On Windows, the config file will be looked for in:

* `%APPDATA%\alacritty\alacritty.toml`

## Contributing

A guideline about contributing to Alacritty can be found in the
[`CONTRIBUTING.md`](CONTRIBUTING.md) file.

## FAQ

**_Is it really the fastest terminal emulator?_**

Benchmarking terminal emulators is complicated. Alacritty uses
[vtebench](https://github.com/alacritty/vtebench) to quantify terminal emulator
throughput and manages to consistently score better than the competition using
it. If you have found an example where this is not the case, please report a
bug.

Other aspects like latency or framerate and frame consistency are more difficult
to quantify. Some terminal emulators also intentionally slow down to save
resources, which might be preferred by some users.

If you have doubts about Alacritty&#039;s performance or usability, the best way to
quantify terminal emulators is always to test them with **your** specific
usecases.

**_Why isn&#039;t feature X implemented?_**

Alacritty has many great features, but not every feature from every other
terminal. This could be for a number of reasons, but sometimes it&#039;s just not a
good fit for Alacritty. This means you won&#039;t find things like tabs or splits
(which are best left to a window manager or [terminal multiplexer][tmux]) nor
niceties like a GUI config editor.

[tmux]: https://github.com/tmux/tmux

## License

Alacritty is released under the [Apache License, Version 2.0].

[Apache License, Version 2.0]: https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty/blob/master/LICENSE-APACHE
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[wezterm/wezterm]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by @wez and implemented in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm">wezterm/wezterm</a></h1>
            <p>A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by @wez and implemented in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 19,933</p>
            <p>Forks: 887</p>
            <p>Stars today: 16 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Wez&#039;s Terminal

&lt;img height=&quot;128&quot; alt=&quot;WezTerm Icon&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wezterm/wezterm/main/assets/icon/wezterm-icon.svg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; *A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wez&quot;&gt;@wez&lt;/a&gt; and implemented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;*

User facing docs and guide at: https://wezterm.org/

![Screenshot](docs/screenshots/two.png)

*Screenshot of wezterm on macOS, running vim*

## Installation

https://wezterm.org/installation

## Getting help

This is a spare time project, so please bear with me.  There are a couple of channels for support:

* You can use the [GitHub issue tracker](https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm/issues) to see if someone else has a similar issue, or to file a new one.
* Start or join a thread in our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm/discussions); if you have general
  questions or want to chat with other wezterm users, you&#039;re welcome here!
* There is a [Matrix room via Element.io](https://app.element.io/#/room/#wezterm:matrix.org)
  for (potentially!) real time discussions.

The GitHub Discussions and Element/Gitter rooms are better suited for questions
than bug reports, but don&#039;t be afraid to use whichever you are most comfortable
using and we&#039;ll work it out.

## Supporting the Project

If you use and like WezTerm, please consider sponsoring it: your support helps
to cover the fees required to maintain the project and to validate the time
spent working on it!

[Read more about sponsoring](https://wezterm.org/sponsor.html).

* [![Sponsor WezTerm](https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/wez?label=Sponsor%20WezTerm&amp;logo=github&amp;style=for-the-badge)](https://github.com/sponsors/wez)
* [Patreon](https://patreon.com/WezFurlong)
* [Ko-Fi](https://ko-fi.com/wezfurlong)
* [Liberapay](https://liberapay.com/wez)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[emilk/egui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/emilk/egui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/emilk/egui</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[egui: an easy-to-use immediate mode GUI in Rust that runs on both web and native]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/emilk/egui">emilk/egui</a></h1>
            <p>egui: an easy-to-use immediate mode GUI in Rust that runs on both web and native</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 24,404</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,717</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># 🖌 egui: an easy-to-use GUI in pure Rust

[&lt;img alt=&quot;github&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/github-emilk/egui-8da0cb?logo=github&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;&gt;](https://github.com/emilk/egui)
[![Latest version](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/egui.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/egui)
[![Documentation](https://docs.rs/egui/badge.svg)](https://docs.rs/egui)
[![unsafe forbidden](https://img.shields.io/badge/unsafe-forbidden-success.svg)](https://github.com/rust-secure-code/safety-dance/)
[![Build Status](https://github.com/emilk/egui/workflows/Rust/badge.svg)](https://github.com/emilk/egui/actions/workflows/rust.yml)
[![MIT](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg)](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/LICENSE-MIT)
[![Apache](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache-blue.svg)](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/LICENSE-APACHE)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/900275882684477440?label=egui%20discord)](https://discord.gg/JFcEma9bJq)


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rerun.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/78e79463-4357-461b-bbd1-31aa5ef5e1a2&quot; width=&quot;250&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

egui development is sponsored by [Rerun](https://www.rerun.io/), a startup building&lt;br&gt;
an SDK for visualizing streams of multimodal data.
&lt;/div&gt;

---

👉 [Click to run the web demo](https://www.egui.rs/#demo) 👈

egui (pronounced &quot;e-gooey&quot;) is a simple, fast, and highly portable immediate mode GUI library for Rust. egui runs on the web, natively, and [in your favorite game engine](#integrations).

egui aims to be the easiest-to-use Rust GUI library, and the simplest way to make a web app in Rust.

egui can be used anywhere you can draw textured triangles, which means you can easily integrate it into your game engine of choice.

[`eframe`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe) is the official egui framework, which supports writing apps for Web, Linux, Mac, Windows, and Android.


## Example

``` rust
ui.heading(&quot;My egui Application&quot;);
ui.horizontal(|ui| {
    ui.label(&quot;Your name: &quot;);
    ui.text_edit_singleline(&amp;mut name);
});
ui.add(egui::Slider::new(&amp;mut age, 0..=120).text(&quot;age&quot;));
if ui.button(&quot;Increment&quot;).clicked() {
    age += 1;
}
ui.label(format!(&quot;Hello &#039;{name}&#039;, age {age}&quot;));
ui.image(egui::include_image!(&quot;ferris.png&quot;));
```

&lt;img alt=&quot;Dark mode&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/3b446d29-99d8-4c82-86bb-4d8ef0516017&quot;&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;img alt=&quot;Light mode&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a5e7da93-89a8-4ba0-86b8-0fa2228a4f62&quot; height=&quot;278&quot;&gt;

## Sections:

* [Example](#example)
* [Quick start](#quick-start)
* [Demo](#demo)
* [Goals](#goals)
* [State / features](#state)
* [Dependencies](#dependencies)
* [Who is egui for?](#who-is-egui-for)
* [Integrations](#integrations)
* [Why immediate mode](#why-immediate-mode)
* [FAQ](#faq)
* [Other](#other)
* [Credits](#credits)

([egui 的中文翻译文档 / chinese translation](https://github.com/Re-Ch-Love/egui-doc-cn/blob/main/README_zh-hans.md))


## Quick start

There are simple examples in [the `examples/` folder](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/examples/). If you want to write a web app, then go to &lt;https://github.com/emilk/eframe_template/&gt; and follow the instructions. The official docs are at &lt;https://docs.rs/egui&gt;. For inspiration and more examples, check out the [the egui web demo](https://www.egui.rs/#demo) and follow the links in it to its source code.

If you want to integrate egui into an existing engine, go to the [Integrations](#integrations) section.

If you have questions, use [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/emilk/egui/discussions). There is also [an egui discord server](https://discord.gg/JFcEma9bJq). If you want to contribute to egui, please read the [Contributing Guidelines](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Demo

[Click to run egui web demo](https://www.egui.rs/#demo) (works in any browser with Wasm and WebGL support). Uses [`eframe`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe).

To test the demo app locally, run `cargo run --release -p egui_demo_app`.

The native backend is [`egui_glow`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/egui_glow) (using [`glow`](https://crates.io/crates/glow)) and should work out-of-the-box on Mac and Windows, but on Linux you need to first run:

`sudo apt-get install -y libclang-dev libgtk-3-dev libxcb-render0-dev libxcb-shape0-dev libxcb-xfixes0-dev libxkbcommon-dev libssl-dev`

On Fedora Rawhide you need to run:

`dnf install clang clang-devel clang-tools-extra libxkbcommon-devel pkg-config openssl-devel libxcb-devel gtk3-devel atk fontconfig-devel`

**NOTE**: This is just for the demo app - egui itself is completely platform agnostic!

## Goals

* The easiest to use GUI library
* Responsive: target 60 Hz in debug build
* Friendly: difficult to make mistakes, and shouldn&#039;t panic
* Portable: the same code works on the web and as a native app
* Easy to integrate into any environment
* A simple 2D graphics API for custom painting ([`epaint`](https://docs.rs/epaint)).
* Pure immediate mode: no callbacks
* Extensible: [easy to write your own widgets for egui](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/crates/egui_demo_lib/src/demo/toggle_switch.rs)
* Modular: You should be able to use small parts of egui and combine them in new ways
* Safe: there is no `unsafe` code in egui
* Minimal dependencies

egui is *not* a framework. egui is a library you call into, not an environment you program for.

**NOTE**: egui does not claim to have reached all these goals yet! egui is still work in progress.

### Non-goals

* Become the most powerful GUI library
* Native looking interface

## State

egui is in active development. It works well for what it does, but it lacks many features and the interfaces are still in flux. New releases will have breaking changes.

Still, egui can be used to create professional looking applications, like [the Rerun Viewer](https://app.rerun.io/).

### Features

* Widgets: label, text button, hyperlink, checkbox, radio button, slider, draggable value, text editing, color picker, spinner
* Images
* Layouts: horizontal, vertical, columns, automatic wrapping
* Text editing: multiline, copy/paste, undo, emoji supports
* Windows: move, resize, name, minimize and close. Automatically sized and positioned.
* Regions: resizing, vertical scrolling, collapsing headers (sections), panels
* Rendering: Anti-aliased rendering of lines, circles, text and convex polygons.
* Tooltips on hover
* Accessibility via [AccessKit](https://accesskit.dev/)
* Label text selection
* And more!

Check out the [3rd party egui crates wiki](https://github.com/emilk/egui/wiki/3rd-party-egui-crates) for even more
widgets and features, maintained by the community.

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/13e73b76-e456-42bd-8ec9-220802834268&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;

Light Theme:

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/2e38972c-a444-4894-b32f-47a2719cf369&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;

## Dependencies
`egui` has a minimal set of default dependencies:

* [`ab_glyph`](https://crates.io/crates/ab_glyph)
* [`ahash`](https://crates.io/crates/ahash)
* [`bitflags`](https://crates.io/crates/bitflags)
* [`nohash-hasher`](https://crates.io/crates/nohash-hasher)
* [`parking_lot`](https://crates.io/crates/parking_lot)

Heavier dependencies are kept out of `egui`, even as opt-in.
All code in `egui` is Wasm-friendly (even outside a browser).

To load images into `egui` you can use the official [`egui_extras`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/egui_extras) crate.

[`eframe`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe) on the other hand has a lot of dependencies, including [`winit`](https://crates.io/crates/winit), [`image`](https://crates.io/crates/image), graphics crates, clipboard crates, etc,

## Who is egui for?

egui aims to be the best choice when you want a simple way to create a GUI, or you want to add a GUI to a game engine.

If you are not using Rust, egui is not for you. If you want a GUI that looks native, egui is not for you. If you want something that doesn&#039;t break when you upgrade it, egui isn&#039;t for you (yet).

But if you are writing something interactive in Rust that needs a simple GUI, egui may be for you.


## Integrations

egui is built to be easy to integrate into any existing game engine or platform you are working on.
egui itself doesn&#039;t know or care on what OS it is running or how to render things to the screen - that is the job of the egui integration.

An integration needs to do the following each frame:

* **Input**: Gather input (mouse, touches, keyboard, screen size, etc) and give it to egui
* Call into the application GUI code
* **Output**: Handle egui output (cursor changes, paste, texture allocations, …)
* **Painting**: Render the triangle mesh egui produces (see [OpenGL example](https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/crates/egui_glow/src/painter.rs))

### Official integrations

These are the official egui integrations:

* [`eframe`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe) for compiling the same app to web/wasm and desktop/native. Uses `egui-winit` and `egui_glow` or `egui-wgpu`
* [`egui_glow`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/egui_glow) for rendering egui with [glow](https://github.com/grovesNL/glow) on native and web, and for making native apps
* [`egui-wgpu`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/egui-wgpu) for [wgpu](https://crates.io/crates/wgpu) (WebGPU API)
* [`egui-winit`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/egui-winit) for integrating with [winit](https://github.com/rust-windowing/winit)

### 3rd party integrations

Check the wiki to find [3rd party integrations](https://github.com/emilk/egui/wiki/3rd-party-integrations)
and [egui crates](https://github.com/emilk/egui/wiki/3rd-party-egui-crates).

### Writing your own egui integration
Missing an integration for the thing you&#039;re working on? Create one, it&#039;s easy!
See &lt;https://docs.rs/egui/latest/egui/#integrating-with-egui&gt;.


## Why immediate mode

`egui` is an [immediate mode GUI library](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immediate_mode_GUI), as opposed to a *retained mode* GUI library. The difference between retained mode and immediate mode is best illustrated with the example of a button: In a retained GUI you create a button, add it to some UI and install some on-click handler (callback). The button is retained in the UI, and to change the text on it you need to store some sort of reference to it. By contrast, in immediate mode you show the button and interact with it immediately, and you do so every frame (e.g. 60 times per second). This means there is no need for any on-click handler, nor to store any reference to it. In `egui` this looks like this: `if ui.button(&quot;Save file&quot;).clicked() { save(file); }`.

A more detailed description of immediate mode can be found [in the `egui` docs](https://docs.rs/egui/latest/egui/#understanding-immediate-mode).

There are advantages and disadvantages to both systems.

The short of it is this: immediate mode GUI libraries are easier to use, but less powerful.

### Advantages of immediate mode
#### Usability
The main advantage of immediate mode is that the application code becomes vastly simpler:

* You never need to have any on-click handlers and callbacks that disrupts your code flow.
* You don&#039;t have to worry about a lingering callback calling something that is gone.
* Your GUI code can easily live in a simple function (no need for an object just for the UI).
* You don&#039;t have to worry about app state and GUI state being out-of-sync (i.e. the GUI showing something outdated), because the GUI isn&#039;t storing any state - it is showing the latest state *immediately*.

In other words, a whole lot of code, complexity and bugs are gone, and you can focus your time on something more interesting than writing GUI code.

### Disadvantages of immediate mode

#### Layout
The main disadvantage of immediate mode is it makes layout more difficult. Say you want to show a small dialog window in the center of the screen. To position the window correctly the GUI library must first know the size of it. To know the size of the window the GUI library must first layout the contents of the window. In retained mode this is easy: the GUI library does the window layout, positions the window, then checks for interaction (&quot;was the OK button clicked?&quot;).

In immediate mode you run into a paradox: to know the size of the window, we must do the layout, but the layout code also checks for interaction (&quot;was the OK button clicked?&quot;) and so it needs to know the window position *before* showing the window contents. This means we must decide where to show the window *before* we know its size!

This is a fundamental shortcoming of immediate mode GUIs, and any attempt to resolve it comes with its own downsides.

One workaround is to store the size and use it the next frame. This produces a frame-delay for the correct layout, producing occasional flickering the first frame something shows up. `egui` does this for some things such as windows and grid layouts.

The &quot;first-frame jitter&quot; can be covered up with an extra _pass_, which egui supports via `Context::request_discard`.
The downside of this is the added CPU cost of a second pass, so egui only does this in very rare circumstances (the majority of frames are single-pass).

For &quot;atomic&quot; widgets (e.g. a button) `egui` knows the size before showing it, so centering buttons, labels etc is possible in `egui` without any special workarounds.

See [this issue](https://github.com/emilk/egui/issues/4378) for more.

#### CPU usage
Since an immediate mode GUI does a full layout each frame, the layout code needs to be quick. If you have a very complex GUI this can tax the CPU. In particular, having a very large UI in a scroll area (with very long scrollback) can be slow, as the content needs to be laid out each frame.

If you design the GUI with this in mind and refrain from huge scroll areas (or only lay out the part that is in view) then the performance hit is generally pretty small. For most cases you can expect `egui` to take up 1-2 ms per frame, but `egui` still has a lot of room for optimization (it&#039;s not something I&#039;ve focused on yet). `egui` only repaints when there is interaction (e.g. mouse movement) or an animation, so if your app is idle, no CPU is wasted.

If your GUI is highly interactive, then immediate mode may actually be more performant compared to retained mode. Go to any web page and resize the browser window, and you&#039;ll notice that the browser is very slow to do the layout and eats a lot of CPU doing it. Resize a window in `egui` by contrast, and you&#039;ll get smooth 60 FPS at no extra CPU cost.


#### IDs
There are some GUI state that you want the GUI library to retain, even in an immediate mode library such as `egui`. This includes position and sizes of windows and how far the user has scrolled in some UI. In these cases you need to provide `egui` with a seed of a unique identifier (unique within the parent UI). For instance: by default `egui` uses the window titles as unique IDs to store window positions. If you want two windows with the same name (or one window with a dynamic name) you must provide some other ID source to `egui` (some unique integer or string).

`egui` also needs to track which widget is being interacted with (e.g. which slider is being dragged). `egui` uses unique IDs for this as well, but in this case the IDs are automatically generated, so there is no need for the user to worry about it. In particular, having two buttons with the same name is no problem (this is in contrast with [`Dear ImGui`](https://github.com/ocornut/imgui)).

Overall, ID handling is a rare inconvenience, and not a big disadvantage.


## FAQ

Also see [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/emilk/egui/discussions/categories/q-a).

### Can I use `egui` with non-latin characters?
Yes! But you need to install your own font (`.ttf` or `.otf`) using [`Context::set_fonts`](https://docs.rs/egui/latest/egui/struct.Context.html#method.set_fonts).

### Can I customize the look of egui?
Yes! You can customize the colors, spacing, fonts and sizes of everything using `Context::set_style`.

This is not yet as powerful as say CSS, [but this is going to improve](https://github.com/emilk/egui/issues/3284).

Here is an example (from https://github.com/a-liashenko/TinyPomodoro):

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/e6107237-2547-41d6-996b-9a20ae0345ab&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;

### How do I use egui with `async`?
If you call `.await` in your GUI code, the UI will freeze, which is very bad UX. Instead, keep the GUI thread non-blocking and communicate with any concurrent tasks (`async` tasks or other threads) with something like:
* Channels (e.g. [`std::sync::mpsc::channel`](https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/mpsc/fn.channel.html)). Make sure to use [`try_recv`](https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/mpsc/struct.Receiver.html#method.try_recv) so you don&#039;t block the gui thread!
* `Arc&lt;Mutex&lt;Value&gt;&gt;` (background thread sets a value; GUI thread reads it)
* [`poll_promise::Promise`](https://docs.rs/poll-promise)
* [`eventuals::Eventual`](https://docs.rs/eventuals/latest/eventuals/struct.Eventual.html)
* [`tokio::sync::watch::channel`](https://docs.rs/tokio/latest/tokio/sync/watch/fn.channel.html)

### How do I create a file dialog?

The async version of [rfd](https://docs.rs/rfd/latest/rfd/) supports both native and Wasm. See example app here https://github.com/woelper/egui_pick_file which also has a demo available via [gitub pages](https://woelper.github.io/egui_pick_file/).

### What about accessibility, such as screen readers?
egui includes optional support for [AccessKit](https://accesskit.dev/), which currently implements the native accessibility APIs on Windows and macOS. This feature is enabled by default in eframe. For platforms that AccessKit doesn&#039;t yet support, including web, there is an experimental built-in screen reader; in [the web demo](https://www.egui.rs/#demo) you can enable it in the &quot;Backend&quot; tab.

The original discussion of accessibility in egui is at &lt;https://github.com/emilk/egui/issues/167&gt;. Now that AccessKit support is merged, providing a strong foundation for future accessibility work, please open new issues on specific accessibility problems.

### What is the difference between [egui](https://docs.rs/egui) and [eframe](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe)?

`egui` is a 2D user interface library for laying out and interacting with buttons, sliders, etc.
`egui` has no idea if it is running on the web or natively, and does not know how to collect input or show things on screen.
That is the job of *the integration* or *backend*.

It is common to use `egui` from a game engine (using e.g. [`bevy_egui`](https://docs.rs/bevy_egui)),
but you can also use `egui` stand-alone using `eframe`. `eframe` has integration for web and native, and handles input and rendering.
The _frame_ in `eframe` stands both for the frame in which your egui app resides and also for &quot;framework&quot; (`eframe` is a framework, `egui` is a library).

### How do I render 3D stuff in an egui area?
There are multiple ways to combine egui with 3D. The simplest way is to use a 3D library and have egui sit on top of the 3D view. See for instance [`bevy_egui`](https://github.com/mvlabat/bevy_egui) or [`three-d`](https://github.com/asny/three-d).

If you want to embed 3D into an egui view there are two options:

#### `Shape::Callback`
Example:
* &lt;https://github.com/emilk/egui/blob/master/examples/custom_3d_glow/src/main.rs&gt;

`Shape::Callback` will call your code when egui gets painted, to show anything using whatever the background rendering context is. When using [`eframe`](https://github.com/emilk/egui/tree/master/crates/eframe) this will be [`glow`](https://github.com/grovesNL/glow). Other integrations will give you other rendering contexts, if they suppor

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LGFae/swww]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/LGFae/swww</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/LGFae/swww</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Solution to your Wayland Wallpaper Woes]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/LGFae/swww">LGFae/swww</a></h1>
            <p>A Solution to your Wayland Wallpaper Woes</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,795</p>
            <p>Forks: 76</p>
            <p>Stars today: 4 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># A Solution to your Wayland Wallpaper Woes
### Efficient animated wallpaper daemon for wayland, controlled at runtime

![animated gif demonstration](https://i.imgur.com/Leuh6wm.gif)
![image transition demonstration](../demos/assets/grow.gif)

## Dependencies

 - a compositor that implements:
   * wlr-layer-shell (typically wlroots based compositors)
   * xdg-output
 - [lz4](https://github.com/lz4/lz4) (for compressing frames when animating)

**Note that this means `swww` will not run on Gnome, because it does not implement the `wlr-layer-shell` protocol**.

## Build

&lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/project/swww/versions&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/swww.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Packaging status&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### Dependencies:

  - Up to date stable rustc compiler and cargo (specifically, MSRV is 1.82.0)

To build, clone this repository and run:
```
cargo build --release
```
Then, put **both binaries** `target/release/swww` and
`target/release/swww-daemon` in your  path. Optionally, autocompletion scripts
for bash, zsh, fish and elvish are offered in the `completions` directory.

#### Man pages:

In order to generate the man pages, **you must have `scdoc` installed**. Run

```
./doc/gen.sh
```

The man pages will be in `doc/generated`. To install them, you must move them to
to the appropriate location in your system. You should be able to figure out
where that is by running `manpath`.

### Nix

NixOS users can directly use this repository to get the latest swww for their system.

Add in your `flake.nix`:

```nix
  inputs.swww.url = &quot;github:LGFae/swww&quot;;
```

Pass inputs to your modules using `specialArgs` and
Then in `configuration.nix`:

```nix
  environment.systemPackages = [
    inputs.swww.packages.${pkgs.system}.swww
  ];
```

## Features

 - Display animated gifs on your desktop
 - Display any image in the formats:
   * jpeg
   * png
   * gif
   * pnm
   * tga
   * tiff
   * webp
   * bmp
   * farbfeld
 - Clear the screen with an arbitrary rrggbb color
 - Smooth transition effect when you switch images
 - Do all of that without having to shutdown and reinitialize the daemon

## Why

There are two main reasons that compelled me to make this: the first is that
[`oguri`](https://github.com/vilhalmer/oguri) is unmaintained and archived,
despite there being serious problems with excess of memory use while displaying
certain gifs (see [this](https://github.com/vilhalmer/oguri/issues/38), for
example). The best alternative I&#039;ve found for `oguri` was
[`mpvpaper`](https://github.com/GhostNaN/mpvpaper), but if felt overkill for my
purposes.

Comparing to `oguri`, `swww` uses less cpu power to animate once it has cached
all the frames in the animation. It should also be **significantly** more
memory efficient.

The second is that, to my knowledge, there is no wallpaper daemon for wayland
that allows you to change the wallpaper at runtime. That is, in order to, for
example, cycle through the images of a directory, you&#039;d have to kill the daemon
and restart it. Not only does it make simple shell scripts a pain to write, it
makes switching from one image to the next to happen very abruptly.

## Usage

Start by initializing the daemon:
```
swww-daemon
```
Then, in a different terminal, simply pass the image you want to display:
```
swww img &lt;path/to/img&gt;

# You can also specify outputs:
swww img -o &lt;outputs&gt; &lt;path/to/img&gt;

# Control how smoothly the transition will happen, as well as its frame rate.
# --transition-step: smaller values = smoother. Default is 2 if --transition-type is `simple`, and 90 if it is not.
# --transition-fps: Default = 30.
swww img &lt;path/to/img&gt; --transition-step &lt;1 to 255&gt; --transition-fps &lt;1 to 255&gt;

# There are also many different transition effects:
swww img &lt;path/to/img&gt; --transition-type center

# Note you may also control the above by setting up the SWWW_TRANSITION_FPS,
# SWWW_TRANSITION_STEP, and SWWW_TRANSITION environment variables.

# To see all options, run
swww img --help
```
If you would like to know the valid values for *\&lt;outputs\&gt;*, you can query the
daemon. This will also tell you what the current image being displayed is, as
well as the dimensions detected for the outputs. If you need more detailed
information, I would recommend using
[`wlr-randr`](https://sr.ht/~emersion/wlr-randr/).
```
swww query
```
Finally, to stop the daemon, kill it:
```
swww kill
```
For a more complete description, run `swww --help` or `swww &lt;subcommand&gt;
--help`.

Finally, to get a feel for what you can do with some shell scripting, check out
the [example_scripts](/example_scripts/) folder. It can help you get started.

## Transitions

#### Example wipe transition:

&gt; wipe transition with angle set to 30 deg

![top transition demonstration](../demos/assets/wipe.gif)

The `left`, `right`, `top` and `bottom` transitions all work similarly.

#### Example outer transition

![outer transition demonstration](../demos/assets/outer.gif)

The `center` transition is the opposite: it starts from the center and goes
towards the edges.

There is also `simple`, which simply fades into the new image, `any`, which
starts at a random point with either `center` of `outer` transitions, and `random`,
which selects a transition effect at random.

## Troubleshooting

### The image looks tilted and in grayscale on my laptop

See #233. Current workaround is to use `swww-daemon --format xrgb` when starting
the daemon.

### High cpu usage during caching of a gif&#039;s frames

`swww` will use a non-insignificant amount of cpu power while caching the
images. This will be specially noticeable if the images need to be resized
before being displayed. So, if you have a very large gif, I would recommend
resizing it **before** sending it to `swww`. That would make the caching phase
much faster, and thus ultimately reduce power consumption. I can personally
recommend [`gifsicle`](https://github.com/kohler/gifsicle) for this purpose.

### Wallpaper disappears when reconnecting monitor

`swww` used to cache its images so that it could reload the current the last
displayed image automatically. This lead to many problems and also proved to be
very annoying to keep working with when we updated to
[`sctk 0.17`](https://github.com/Smithay/client-toolkit). So I decided to nuke
it.

If you want a wallpaper to be set automatically when you reconnect to a monitor,
you should use a combination of scripts and a program that lets you run commands
when a new output is connected, like [`kanshi`](https://sr.ht/~emersion/kanshi/).

## About new features

Broadly speaking, **NEW FEATURES WILL NOT BE ADDED, UNLESS THEY ARE EGREGIOUSLY
SIMPLE**. I made `swww` with the specific usecase of making shell scripts in
mind. So, for example, stuff like timed wallpapers, or a setup that loads a
different image at different times of the day, and so on, should all be done by
combining `swww` with other programs (see the [example_scripts](/example_scripts/) for some
examples).

If you really want some new feature within `swww` itself, I would recommend
forking the repository.

## Alternatives

`swww` isn&#039;t really the simplest, mostest minimalest software you could find
for managing wallpapers. If you are looking for something simpler, have a look
at the [awesome-wayland repository list of wallpaper programs
](https://github.com/natpen/awesome-wayland#wallpaper). I can personally
recommend:

 - [`wbg`](https://codeberg.org/dnkl/wbg) - probably the simplest of them all.
 Strongly recommend if you just care about setting a single png as your
 permanent wallpaper on something like a laptop.
 - [`swaybg`](https://github.com/swaywm/swaybg) - made by the wlroots gods
 themselves.
 - [`mpvpaper`](https://github.com/GhostNaN/mpvpaper) - if you want to display
 videos as your wallpapers. This is also what I used for gifs before making
 `swww`.
 - [`kitty`](https://sw.kovidgoyal.net/kitty/) - you can use the kitty terminal emulator with its [panel](https://sw.kovidgoyal.net/kitty/kittens/panel/) kitten to have the output of an arbitrary TUI program such as htop or btop or similar as your desktop wallpaper.

## Acknowledgments

A huge thanks to everyone involved in the [smithay](https://github.com/Smithay)
project. Making this program would not have been possible without it. In fact,
the first versions of swww were quite literally copy pasted from the
[layer shell example in the client-toolkit
](https://github.com/Smithay/client-toolkit/blob/master/examples/layer_shell.rs).

A big thank-you also to [HakierGrzonzo](https://github.com/HakierGrzonzo), for
setting up the AUR package.

### Wallpapers used in this README

Pixel Art, by Waneella - https://www.patreon.com/waneella

Gradient - https://www.behance.net/gallery/86128681/Free-Unicorn-Vector-Gradients

Silhouette of Skyway - https://unsplash.com/photos/silhouette-of-skyway-UUJzCuHUfYI
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[librespot-org/librespot]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Open Source Spotify client library]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot">librespot-org/librespot</a></h1>
            <p>Open Source Spotify client library</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,199</p>
            <p>Forks: 668</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Build Status](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/workflows/test/badge.svg)](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/actions)
[![Gitter chat](https://badges.gitter.im/librespot-org/librespot.png)](https://gitter.im/librespot-org/spotify-connect-resources)
[![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/librespot.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/librespot)

Current maintainers are [listed on GitHub](https://github.com/orgs/librespot-org/people).

# librespot
*librespot* is an open source client library for Spotify. It enables applications to use Spotify&#039;s service to control and play music via various backends, and to act as a Spotify Connect receiver. It is an alternative to the official and [now deprecated](https://pyspotify.mopidy.com/en/latest/#libspotify-s-deprecation) closed-source `libspotify`. Additionally, it will provide extra features which are not available in the official library.

_Note: librespot only works with Spotify Premium. This will remain the case. We will not support any features to make librespot compatible with free accounts, such as limited skips and adverts._

## Quick start
We&#039;re available on [crates.io](https://crates.io/crates/librespot) as the _librespot_ package. Simply run `cargo install librespot` to install librespot on your system. Check the wiki for more info and possible [usage options](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/wiki/Options).

After installation, you can run librespot from the CLI using a command such as `librespot -n &quot;Librespot Speaker&quot; -b 160` to create a speaker called _Librespot Speaker_ serving 160 kbps audio.

## This fork
As the origin by [plietar](https://github.com/plietar/) is no longer actively maintained, this organisation and repository have been set up so that the project may be maintained and upgraded in the future.

# Documentation
Documentation is currently a work in progress, contributions are welcome!

There is some brief documentation on how the protocol works in the [docs](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/tree/master/docs) folder.

[COMPILING.md](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/blob/master/COMPILING.md) contains detailed instructions on setting up a development environment, and compiling librespot. More general usage and compilation information is available on the [wiki](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/wiki).
[CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md) also contains our contributing guidelines.

If you wish to learn more about how librespot works overall, the best way is to simply read the code, and ask any questions you have in our [Gitter Room](https://gitter.im/librespot-org/spotify-connect-resources).

# Issues &amp; Discussions
**We have recently started using Github discussions for general questions and feature requests, as they are a more natural medium for such cases, and allow for upvoting to prioritize feature development. Check them out [here](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/discussions). Bugs and issues with the underlying library should still be reported as issues.**

If you run into a bug when using librespot, please search the existing issues before opening a new one. Chances are, we&#039;ve encountered it before, and have provided a resolution. If not, please open a new one, and where possible, include the backtrace librespot generates on crashing, along with anything we can use to reproduce the issue, e.g. the Spotify URI of the song that caused the crash.

# Building
A quick walkthrough of the build process is outlined below, while a detailed compilation guide can be found [here](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/blob/master/COMPILING.md).

## Additional Dependencies
We recently switched to using [Rodio](https://github.com/tomaka/rodio) for audio playback by default, hence for macOS and Windows, you should just be able to clone and build librespot (with the command below).
For Linux, you will need to run the additional commands below, depending on your distro.

On Debian/Ubuntu, the following command will install these dependencies:
```shell
sudo apt-get install build-essential libasound2-dev
```

On Fedora systems, the following command will install these dependencies:
```shell
sudo dnf install alsa-lib-devel make gcc
```

librespot currently offers the following selection of [audio backends](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/wiki/Audio-Backends):
```
Rodio (default)
ALSA
GStreamer
PortAudio
PulseAudio
JACK
JACK over Rodio
SDL
Pipe
Subprocess
```
Please check the corresponding [Compiling](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/wiki/Compiling#general-dependencies) entry on the wiki for backend specific dependencies.

Once you&#039;ve installed the dependencies and cloned this repository you can build *librespot* with the default backend using Cargo.
```shell
cargo build --release
```

# Packages

librespot is also available via official package system on various operating systems such as Linux, FreeBSD, NetBSD. [Repology](https://repology.org/project/librespot/versions) offers a good overview.

[![Packaging status](https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/librespot.svg)](https://repology.org/project/librespot/versions)

## Usage
A sample program implementing a headless Spotify Connect receiver is provided.
Once you&#039;ve built *librespot*, run it using :
```shell
target/release/librespot --name DEVICENAME
```

The above is a minimal example. Here is a more fully fledged one:
```shell
target/release/librespot -n &quot;Librespot&quot; -b 320 -c ./cache --enable-volume-normalisation --initial-volume 75 --device-type avr
```
The above command will create a receiver named ```Librespot```, with bitrate set to 320 kbps, initial volume at 75%, with volume normalisation enabled, and the device displayed in the app as an Audio/Video Receiver. A folder named ```cache``` will be created/used in the current directory, and be used to cache audio data and credentials.

A full list of runtime options is available [here](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot/wiki/Options).

_Please Note: When using the cache feature, an authentication blob is stored for your account in the cache directory. For security purposes, we recommend that you set directory permissions on the cache directory to `700`._

## Contact
Come and hang out on gitter if you need help or want to offer some:
https://gitter.im/librespot-org/spotify-connect-resources

## Disclaimer
Using this code to connect to Spotify&#039;s API is probably forbidden by them.
Use at your own risk.

## License
Everything in this repository is licensed under the MIT license.

## Related Projects
This is a non exhaustive list of projects that either use or have modified librespot. If you&#039;d like to include yours, submit a PR.

- [librespot-golang](https://github.com/librespot-org/librespot-golang) - A golang port of librespot.
- [plugin.audio.spotify](https://github.com/marcelveldt/plugin.audio.spotify) - A Kodi plugin for Spotify.
- [raspotify](https://github.com/dtcooper/raspotify) - A Spotify Connect client that mostly Just Works™
- [Spotifyd](https://github.com/Spotifyd/spotifyd) - A stripped down librespot UNIX daemon.
- [rpi-audio-receiver](https://github.com/nicokaiser/rpi-audio-receiver) - easy Raspbian install scripts for Spotifyd, Bluetooth, Shairport and other audio receivers
- [Spotcontrol](https://github.com/badfortrains/spotcontrol) - A golang implementation of a Spotify Connect controller. No Playback functionality.
- [librespot-java](https://github.com/devgianlu/librespot-java) - A Java port of librespot.
- [ncspot](https://github.com/hrkfdn/ncspot) - Cross-platform ncurses Spotify client.
- [ansible-role-librespot](https://github.com/xMordax/ansible-role-librespot/tree/master) - Ansible role that will build, install and configure Librespot.
- [Spot](https://github.com/xou816/spot) - Gtk/Rust native Spotify client for the GNOME desktop. 
- [Snapcast](https://github.com/badaix/snapcast) - synchronised multi-room audio player that uses librespot as its source for Spotify content
- [MuPiBox](https://mupibox.de/) - Portable music box for Spotify and local media based on Raspberry Pi. Operated via touchscreen. Suitable for children and older people.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[linera-io/linera-protocol]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Main repository for the Linera protocol]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol">linera-io/linera-protocol</a></h1>
            <p>Main repository for the Linera protocol</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 21,152</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,284</p>
            <p>Stars today: 61 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/assets/1105398/fe08c941-93af-4114-bb83-bcc0eaec95f9&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; /&gt;

[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache-green.svg)](LICENSE)
[![Build Status for Docker](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/docker-compose.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/docker-compose.yml)
[![Build Status for Rust](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/rust.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/rust.yml)
[![Build Status for Documentation](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/documentation.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/documentation.yml)
[![Twitter](https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/linera_io)](https://x.com/linera_io)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/984941796272521226)](https://discord.com/invite/linera)

&lt;!-- [![Build Status for Kubernetes](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/kubernetes.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-protocol/actions/workflows/kubernetes.yml) --&gt;

[Linera](https://linera.io) is a decentralized blockchain infrastructure designed for highly scalable,
low-latency Web3 applications.

Visit our [developer page](https://linera.dev) and read our
[whitepaper](https://linera.io/whitepaper) to learn more about the Linera protocol.

## Repository Structure

The main crates and directories of this repository can be summarized as follows: (listed
from low to high levels in the dependency graph)

* [`linera-base`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_base/index.html) Base
  definitions, including cryptography.

* [`linera-version`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_version/index.html)
  A library to manage version info in binaries and services.

* [`linera-views`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_views/index.html) A
  library mapping complex data structures onto a key-value store. The corresponding
  procedural macros are implemented in `linera-views-derive`.

* [`linera-execution`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_execution/index.html)
  Persistent data and the corresponding logic for runtime and execution of Linera
  applications.

* [`linera-chain`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_chain/index.html)
  Persistent data and the corresponding logic for chains of blocks, certificates, and
  cross-chain messaging.

* [`linera-storage`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_storage/index.html)
  Defines the storage abstractions for the protocol on top of `linera-chain`.

* [`linera-core`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_core/index.html) The
  core Linera protocol, including client and server logic, node synchronization, etc.

* [`linera-rpc`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_rpc/index.html)
  Defines the data-type for RPC messages (currently all client &amp;#x2194; proxy &amp;#x2194;
  chain &amp;#x2194; chain interactions), and track the corresponding data schemas.

* [`linera-client`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_client/index.html)
  Library for writing Linera clients.  Used for the command-line
  client and the node service in `linera-service`, as well as the Web
  client in [`linera-web`](https://github.com/linera-io/linera-web/).

* [`linera-service`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_service/index.html)
  Executable for clients (aka CLI wallets), proxy (aka validator frontend) and servers.

* [`linera-sdk`](https://linera-io.github.io/linera-protocol/linera_sdk/index.html) The
  library to develop Linera applications written in Rust for the Wasm virtual machine. The
  corresponding procedural macros are implemented in `linera-sdk-derive`.

* [`examples`](./examples) Examples of Linera applications written in Rust.


## Quickstart with the Linera CLI tool

The following commands set up a local test network and run some transfers between the
microchains owned by a single wallet.

```bash
# Make sure to compile the Linera binaries and add them in the $PATH.
# cargo build -p linera-storage-service -p linera-service --bins
export PATH=&quot;$PWD/target/debug:$PATH&quot;

# Import the optional helper function `linera_spawn`.
source /dev/stdin &lt;&lt;&lt;&quot;$(linera net helper 2&gt;/dev/null)&quot;

# Run a local test network with the default parameters and a number of microchains
# owned by the default wallet. This also defines `LINERA_TMP_DIR`.
linera_spawn \
linera net up --with-faucet --faucet-port 8080

# Remember the URL of the faucet.
FAUCET_URL=http://localhost:8080

# If you&#039;re using a testnet, start here and run this instead:
#   LINERA_TMP_DIR=$(mktemp -d)
#   FAUCET_URL=https://faucet.testnet-XXX.linera.net  # for some value XXX

# Set the path of the future wallet.
export LINERA_WALLET=&quot;$LINERA_TMP_DIR/wallet.json&quot;
export LINERA_STORAGE=&quot;rocksdb:$LINERA_TMP_DIR/client.db&quot;

# Initialize a new user wallet.
linera wallet init --faucet $FAUCET_URL

# Request chains.
INFO1=($(linera wallet request-chain --faucet $FAUCET_URL))
INFO2=($(linera wallet request-chain --faucet $FAUCET_URL))
CHAIN1=&quot;${INFO1[0]}&quot;
ACCOUNT1=&quot;${INFO1[3]}&quot;
CHAIN2=&quot;${INFO2[0]}&quot;
ACCOUNT2=&quot;${INFO2[3]}&quot;

# Show the different chains tracked by the wallet.
linera wallet show

# Query the chain balance of some of the chains.
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN1&quot;
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN2&quot;

# Transfer 10 units then 5 back.
linera transfer 10 --from &quot;$CHAIN1&quot; --to &quot;$CHAIN2&quot;
linera transfer 5 --from &quot;$CHAIN2&quot; --to &quot;$CHAIN1&quot;

# Query balances again.
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN1&quot;
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN2&quot;

# Now let&#039;s fund the user balances.
linera transfer 5 --from &quot;$CHAIN1&quot; --to &quot;$CHAIN1:$ACCOUNT1&quot;
linera transfer 2 --from &quot;$CHAIN1:$ACCOUNT1&quot; --to &quot;$CHAIN2:$ACCOUNT2&quot;

# Query user balances again.
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN1:$ACCOUNT1&quot;
linera query-balance &quot;$CHAIN2:$ACCOUNT2&quot;
```

More complex examples may be found in our [developer manual](https://linera.dev) as well
as the [example applications](./examples) in this repository.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GyulyVGC/sniffnet]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Comfortably monitor your Internet traffic 🕵️‍♂️]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet">GyulyVGC/sniffnet</a></h1>
            <p>Comfortably monitor your Internet traffic 🕵️‍♂️</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 23,325</p>
            <p>Forks: 712</p>
            <p>Stars today: 47 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sniffnet&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/header_repository.png&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;#download&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Download&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/download.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/blob/main/ROADMAP.md&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Roadmap&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/roadmap.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sniffnet.net&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Website&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/website.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/wiki&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Wiki&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/wiki.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Application to comfortably monitor your Internet traffic.&lt;br&gt;
Cross-platform. Intuitive. Reliable.

Translated in:&lt;br&gt;
🇨🇳 🇩🇪 🇫🇷 🇷🇺 🇵🇹 🇪🇦 🇮🇹 🇵🇱 [+&amp;nbsp;12&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;languages](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/issues/60)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/hr.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Overview page&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/pages/overview.png&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Inspect page&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/pages/inspect.png&quot; width=&quot;47%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Notifications page&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/pages/notifications.png&quot; width=&quot;47%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Custom theme&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/pages/catppuccin.png&quot; width=&quot;47%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Thumbnail mode&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/pages/thumbnail.png&quot; width=&quot;47%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/hr.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


## _Support Sniffnet&#039;s development_ 💖

&lt;i&gt;Sniffnet is completely free, open-source software which needs lots of effort and time to develop and maintain.&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;i&gt;If you appreciate Sniffnet, [consider sponsoring](https://github.com/sponsors/GyulyVGC):
your support will enable a constant growth with [new features and functionalities](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/blob/main/ROADMAP.md).&lt;br&gt;
Do you want to help the project in an alternative way? You can also head to the [official store](https://grindhouse.dev/collections/sniffnet) and put your hands on some cool merchandise!&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;i&gt;A special mention goes to these awesome organizations and folks who are sponsoring Sniffnet:&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/github&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/github?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl&quot; title=&quot;NLnet&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/logo/logo.svg&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;NLnet&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ipinfo.io&quot; title=&quot;IPinfo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/ipinfo?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;IPinfo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Cthulu201&quot; title=&quot;Cthulu201&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/Cthulu201?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;Cthulu201&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/0x0177b11f&quot; title=&quot;Tiansheng Li&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/0x0177b11f?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;Tiansheng Li&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ZEROF&quot; title=&quot;ZEROF&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/ZEROF?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;ZEROF&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.janwalter.org/&quot; title=&quot;Jan Walter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/wahn?v=4&quot; width=&quot;60px&quot; alt=&quot;Jan Walter&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


## Download

|                                                                        &lt;a href=&quot;#download&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Windows&quot; title=&quot;Windows&quot; height=&quot;35px&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/windows.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;                                                                         |                           &lt;a href=&quot;#download&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;macOS&quot; title=&quot;macOS&quot; height=&quot;35px&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/macos.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;                            |                                                                                                                          &lt;a href=&quot;#download&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Linux (.deb)&quot; title=&quot;Linux (.deb)&quot; height=&quot;35px&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/linux_deb.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;                                                                                                                           |                                                              &lt;a href=&quot;#download&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Linux (.rpm)&quot; title=&quot;Linux (.rpm)&quot; height=&quot;35px&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/linux_rpm.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;                                                               |
|:--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------:|:--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------:|:------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------:|:------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------:|
| &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[64&amp;#8209;bit](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_Windows_64-bit.msi)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[32&amp;#8209;bit](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_Windows_32-bit.msi)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; | [Intel](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_macOS_Intel.dmg)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[Apple&amp;nbsp;silicon](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_macOS_AppleSilicon.dmg) | [amd64](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxDEB_amd64.deb)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[arm64](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxDEB_arm64.deb)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[i386](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxDEB_i386.deb)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[armhf](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxDEB_armhf.deb) | &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;[x86_64](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxRPM_x86_64.rpm)&amp;nbsp;\|&amp;nbsp;[aarch64](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases/latest/download/Sniffnet_LinuxRPM_aarch64.rpm)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; |

Links in the table above will download the latest version of Sniffnet directly from [GitHub releases](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/releases). &lt;br&gt;

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt;
&gt; Remember to also install the [required dependencies](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/wiki/Required-dependencies) for your operating system.

**Alternative installation methods** are reported in the following:

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;from Crates.io&lt;/summary&gt;

Follow this method only if you have [Rust installed](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install) on your machine. &lt;br&gt;
In this case, the application binary can be built and installed with:

```sh
cargo install sniffnet --locked
```

&lt;/details&gt;


&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;from Homebrew&lt;/summary&gt;

  You can install [Sniffnet Homebrew package](https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/pkgs/container/core%2Fsniffnet) with:

  ```sh
brew install sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;from Nixpkgs&lt;/summary&gt;

  You can install [Sniffnet Nix package](https://search.nixos.org/packages?channel=23.05&amp;show=sniffnet&amp;from=0&amp;size=50&amp;sort=relevance&amp;type=packages&amp;query=sniffnet) adding the following Nix code to your NixOS Configuration, usually located in `/etc/nixos/configuration.nix`:

  ```nix
  environment.systemPackages = [
    pkgs.sniffnet
  ];
```

  Alternatively, you can install it in your home using [Home Manager](https://github.com/nix-community/home-manager) with:

  ```nix
  home.packages = [
    pkgs.sniffnet
  ];
```

  Alternatively, you can try it in a shell with:
  ```sh
nix-shell -p sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;on Arch Linux&lt;/summary&gt;

  You can install Sniffnet community package via [pacman](https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Pacman):

  ```sh
pacman -S sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;on FreeBSD&lt;/summary&gt;

You can install Sniffnet port with:

  ```sh
pkg install sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;on NetBSD&lt;/summary&gt;

You can install Sniffnet from the official repositories via [pkgin](https://pkgin.net):

  ```sh
pkgin install sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;on Tiny Core Linux&lt;/summary&gt;

You can install Sniffnet from the official repository with:

  ```
tce-load -wi sniffnet
```

&lt;/details&gt;

## Features

- 💻 choose a **network adapter** of your PC to inspect
- 🏷️ select a set of **filters** to apply to the observed traffic
- 📖 view overall **statistics** about your Internet traffic
- 📈 view **real-time charts** about traffic intensity
- 📌 keep an eye on your network even when the application is **minimized**
- 📁 **export** comprehensive capture reports as **PCAP files**
- 🔎 identify **6000+ upper layer services**, protocols, trojans, and worms
- 🌐 find out **domain name** and **ASN** of the hosts you are exchanging traffic with
- 🏠 identify connections in your **local network**
- 🌍 get information about the country of remote hosts (**IP geolocation**)
- ⭐ save your **favorite** network hosts
- 🕵️‍♂️ search and **inspect** each of your network connections in real time
- 🔉 set **custom notifications** to inform you when defined network events occur
- 🎨 choose the **style** that fits you the most, including custom themes support
- ...and more!

## User manual

Do you want to **learn more**? &lt;br&gt;
Check out the [**Sniffnet Wiki**](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/wiki), a comprehensive manual to help you
thoroughly master the application from a basic setup to the most advanced functionalities. &lt;br&gt;
The Wiki includes step-by-step guides, tips, examples of usage, and answers to frequent questions.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/wiki&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sniffnet Wiki&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/logos/wiki/wikilogo.svg&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Troubleshooting

&lt;details&gt;

  &lt;summary&gt;See details&lt;/summary&gt;

### Missing dependencies

Most of the errors that may arise are likely due to your system missing dependencies
required to correctly analyze a network adapter. &lt;br&gt;
Check the [required dependencies page](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/wiki/Required-dependencies) 
for instructions on how to proceed depending on your operating system.

### Rendering problems

In some circumstances, especially if you are running on an old architecture or your graphical drivers are not updated,
the `wgpu` default renderer used by [iced](https://github.com/iced-rs/iced)
may manifest bugs (the interface glitches, color gradients are unsupported, or some icons are completely black). &lt;br&gt;
In these cases you can set an environment variable to switch to the `tiny-skia` renderer,
a CPU-only software renderer that should work properly on every environment:

```sh
ICED_BACKEND=tiny-skia
```

### ***In any case, don&#039;t hesitate to [open an issue](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/issues/new/choose), and I will do my best to help you!***

&lt;/details&gt;


## Acknowledgements

- A big shout-out to [all the contributors](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/blob/main/CONTRIBUTORS.md) of Sniffnet!
- The graphical user interface has been realized with [iced](https://github.com/iced-rs/iced), a cross-platform GUI library for Rust focused on simplicity and type-safety
- IP geolocation and ASN data are provided by [MaxMind](https://www.maxmind.com)
- Last but not least, thanks to [every single stargazer](https://github.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/stargazers): all forms of support made it possible to keep improving Sniffnet!


## Stay in the loop

Wait... there&#039;s more!&lt;br&gt;Sniffnet is rapidly evolving, and new features are added on a regular basis.&lt;br&gt;
Follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sniffnet.net/news&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;news&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Sniffnet socials to never miss an update.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/sniffnet.net&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;Bluesky&quot; title=&quot;Bluesky&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/bluesky.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/sniffnet&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;LinkedIn&quot; title=&quot;LinkedIn&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/linkedin.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@sniffnet&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;Mastodon&quot; title=&quot;Mastodon&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/mastodon.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/sniffnet&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;Telegram&quot; title=&quot;Telegram&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/telegram.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/sniffnet_app&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;48&quot; height=&quot;48&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter / X&quot; title=&quot;Twitter / X&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GyulyVGC/sniffnet/main/resources/repository/badges/x.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[cordx56/rustowl]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/cordx56/rustowl</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/cordx56/rustowl</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Visualize Ownership and Lifetimes in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/cordx56/rustowl">cordx56/rustowl</a></h1>
            <p>Visualize Ownership and Lifetimes in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,316</p>
            <p>Forks: 86</p>
            <p>Stars today: 24 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;
      &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;docs/assets/rustowl-logo-dark.svg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;RustOwl&quot; src=&quot;docs/assets/rustowl-logo.svg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
    &lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Visualize ownership and lifetimes in Rust for debugging and optimization
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;docs/assets/readme-screenshot-3.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

RustOwl visualizes ownership movement and lifetimes of variables.
When you save Rust source code, it is analyzed, and the ownership and lifetimes of variables are visualized when you hover over a variable or function call.

RustOwl visualizes those by using underlines:

- 🟩 green: variable&#039;s actual lifetime
- 🟦 blue: immutable borrowing
- 🟪 purple: mutable borrowing
- 🟧 orange: value moved / function call
- 🟥 red: lifetime error
    - diff of lifetime between actual and expected, or
    - invalid overlapped lifetime of mutable and shared (immutable) references

Detailed usage is described [here](docs/usage.md).

Currently, we offer VSCode extension, Neovim plugin and Emacs package.
For these editors, move the text cursor over the variable or function call you want to inspect and wait for 2 seconds to visualize the information.
We implemented LSP server with an extended protocol.
So, RustOwl can be used easily from other editor.

## Support

If you&#039;re looking for support, please consider checking all issues, existing discussions, and [starting a discussion](https://github.com/cordx56/rustowl/discussions/new?category=q-a) first!

## Quick Start

Here we describe how to start using RustOwl with VS Code.

### Prerequisite

- `rustup` installed
    - You can install `rustup` from [this link](https://rustup.rs/).
- Visual Studio Code (VS Code) installed

We tested this guide on macOS Sequoia 15.3.2 on arm64 architecture with VS Code 1.99.1 and `rustup` 1.28.1.

We also tested this guide on Ubuntu 25.04.
On Ubuntu, you need to run `apt install build-essential` before installing.

After installation, the extension will automatically run RustOwl when you save any Rust program in cargo workspace.
The initial analysis may take some time, but from the second run onward, compile caching is used to reduce the analysis time.

We tested on Windows 11 Education 23H2 on amd64 architecture.

### Install RustOwl

Install from crates.io:

```bash
cargo install rustowl -F installer --locked
```

Or, install from GitHub release (using sh, Unix-like / WSL only):

```bash
curl -L &quot;https://github.com/cordx56/rustowl/releases/latest/download/install.sh&quot; | sh
```

### VS Code

You can install VS Code extension from [this link](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=cordx56.rustowl-vscode).

## Other editor support

We support Neovim and Emacs.
You can also create your own LSP client.
If you would like to implement a client, please refer to the [The RustOwl LSP specification](docs/lsp-spec.md).

### Neovim

Minimal setup with [lazy.nvim](https://github.com/folke/lazy.nvim):

```lua
{
  &#039;cordx56/rustowl&#039;,
  version = &#039;*&#039;, -- Latest stable version
  build = &#039;cd rustowl &amp;&amp; cargo install --path . -F installer --locked&#039;,
  lazy = false, -- This plugin is already lazy
  opts = {},
}
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Recommended configuration: &lt;b&gt;Click to expand&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```lua
{
  &#039;cordx56/rustowl&#039;,
  version = &#039;*&#039;, -- Latest stable version
  build = &#039;cd rustowl &amp;&amp; cargo install --path . --locked&#039;,
  lazy = false, -- This plugin is already lazy
  opts = {
    client = {
      on_attach = function(_, buffer)
        vim.keymap.set(&#039;n&#039;, &#039;&lt;leader&gt;o&#039;, function()
          require(&#039;rustowl&#039;).toggle(buffer)
        end, { buffer = buffer, desc = &#039;Toggle RustOwl&#039; })
      end
    },
  },
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

Default options:

```lua
{
  auto_attach = true, -- Auto attach the RustOwl LSP client when opening a Rust file
  auto_enable = false, -- Enable RustOwl immediately when attaching the LSP client
  idle_time = 500, -- Time in milliseconds to hover with the cursor before triggering RustOwl
  client = {}, -- LSP client configuration that gets passed to `vim.lsp.start`
}
```

When opening a Rust file, the Neovim plugin creates the `Rustowl` user command:

```vim
:Rustowl {subcommand}
```

where `{subcommand}` can be one of:

- `start_client`: Start the rustowl LSP client.
- `stop_client`: Stop the rustowl LSP client.
- `restart_client`: Restart the rustowl LSP client.
- `enable`: Enable rustowl highlights.
- `disable`: Disable rustowl highlights.
- `toggle`: Toggle rustowl highlights.


### Emacs

Elpaca example:

```elisp
(elpaca
  (rustowlsp
    :host github
    :repo &quot;cordx56/rustowl&quot;
    :files (:defaults &quot;emacs/*&quot;)))
```

### RustRover / IntelliJ IDEs

There is a [third-party repository](https://github.com/siketyan/intellij-rustowl) that supports IntelliJ IDEs.


## Build manually

Here, we describe manual install instructions from source code.

### RustOwl

#### Prerequisite

- `rustup` and `cargo` installed
    - You can install `rustup` from [this link](https://rustup.rs/).
    - You need to set up the `PATH` environment variable. To do this, follow the instructions provided by the `rustup` installer. For example, in bash, run `export PATH=$HOME/.cargo/bin:$PATH`.

RustOwl has been tested on macOS Sequoia 15.3.2 on arm64 architecture with `rustup` 1.28.1.
We have not tested the installation of dependencies from other package repositories, such as Homebrew.
You may need to uninstall any Rust-related packages installed through those repositories first.
Other dependencies are locked in the configuration files and will be installed automatically.

We have also tested this on Ubuntu 25.04 on arm64 architecture.
Additional dependencies may be required.
We have confirmed that running `apt install build-essential` is necessary on a freshly installed Ubuntu for linking.

#### Build &amp; Run

```bash
cd rustowl
cargo install --path . -F installer --locked
rustowl check
```


### VSCode extension

#### Prerequisite

- VSCode installed
    - You can install VSCode from [this link](https://code.visualstudio.com/).
- Node.js installed
- `yarn` installed
    - After installing Node.js, You can install `yarn` by running `npm install -g yarn`.

VSCode extension has been tested on macOS Sequoia 15.2 on arm64 architecture with Visual Studio Code 1.96.4, Node.js v20.16.0, and `yarn` 1.22.22.
Other dependencies are locked in the configuration files and will be installed automatically.

#### Build &amp; Run

First, install the dependencies.

```bash
cd vscode
yarn install --frozen-lockfile
```

Then open `vscode` directory in VSCode.

A notification to install the recommended VSCode extension will appear in the bottom right corner of VSCode.
Click the install button, wait for the installation to finish, and then restart VSCode.

Open `vscode` directory again, and press the `F5` key in the VSCode window.
A new VSCode window with the extension enabled will appear.

Open cargo workspace directory in the new VSCode window.

When you save Rust files, decoration indicating the movement of ownership and lifetimes will appear in the editor.


## Note

In this tool, due to the limitations of VSCode&#039;s decoration specifications, characters with descenders, such as g or parentheses, may occasionally not display underlines properly.
Additionally, we observed that the `println!` macro sometimes produces extra output, though this does not affect usability in any significant way.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[girlbossceo/conduwuit]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[a very cool, featureful fork of conduit (rust matrix homeserver)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit">girlbossceo/conduwuit</a></h1>
            <p>a very cool, featureful fork of conduit (rust matrix homeserver)</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 971</p>
            <p>Forks: 104</p>
            <p>Stars today: 8 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># conduwuit

[![conduwuit main room](https://img.shields.io/matrix/conduwuit%3Apuppygock.gay?server_fqdn=matrix.transfem.dev&amp;style=flat&amp;logo=matrix&amp;logoColor=%23f5b3ff&amp;label=%23conduwuit%3Apuppygock.gay&amp;color=%23f652ff)](https://matrix.to/#/#conduwuit:puppygock.gay) [![conduwuit space](https://img.shields.io/matrix/conduwuit-space%3Apuppygock.gay?server_fqdn=matrix.transfem.dev&amp;style=flat&amp;logo=matrix&amp;logoColor=%23f5b3ff&amp;label=%23conduwuit-space%3Apuppygock.gay&amp;color=%23f652ff)](https://matrix.to/#/#conduwuit-space:puppygock.gay)

[![CI and Artifacts](https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg?branch=main)](https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit/actions/workflows/ci.yml)

![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/girlbossceo/conduwuit?style=flat&amp;color=%23fcba03&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fgirlbossceo%2Fconduwuit) ![GitHub commit activity](https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/girlbossceo/conduwuit?style=flat&amp;color=%2303fcb1&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fgirlbossceo%2Fconduwuit%2Fpulse%2Fmonthly) ![GitHub Created At](https://img.shields.io/github/created-at/girlbossceo/conduwuit) ![GitHub Sponsors](https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/girlbossceo?color=%23fc03ba&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fsponsors%2Fgirlbossceo) ![GitHub License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/girlbossceo/conduwuit)



![Docker Image Size (tag)](https://img.shields.io/docker/image-size/girlbossceo/conduwuit/latest?label=image%20size%20(latest)&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fhub.docker.com%2Frepository%2Fdocker%2Fgirlbossceo%2Fconduwuit%2Ftags%3Fname%3Dlatest) ![Docker Image Size (tag)](https://img.shields.io/docker/image-size/girlbossceo/conduwuit/main?label=image%20size%20(main)&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fhub.docker.com%2Frepository%2Fdocker%2Fgirlbossceo%2Fconduwuit%2Ftags%3Fname%3Dmain)



&lt;!-- ANCHOR: catchphrase --&gt;

### a very cool [Matrix](https://matrix.org/) chat homeserver written in Rust

&lt;!-- ANCHOR_END: catchphrase --&gt;

Visit the [conduwuit documentation](https://conduwuit.puppyirl.gay/) for more
information and how to deploy/setup conduwuit.

&lt;!-- ANCHOR: body --&gt;

#### What is Matrix?

[Matrix](https://matrix.org) is an open, federated, and extensible network for
decentralised communication. Users from any Matrix homeserver can chat with users from all
other homeservers over federation. Matrix is designed to be extensible and built on top of.
You can even use bridges such as Matrix Appservices to communicate with users outside of Matrix, like a community on Discord.

#### What is the goal?

A high-performance, efficient, low-cost, and featureful Matrix homeserver that&#039;s
easy to set up and just works with minimal configuration needed.

#### Can I try it out?

An official conduwuit server ran by me is available at transfem.dev
([element.transfem.dev](https://element.transfem.dev) /
[cinny.transfem.dev](https://cinny.transfem.dev))

transfem.dev is a public homeserver that can be used, it is not a &quot;test only
homeserver&quot;. This means there are rules, so please read the rules:
[https://transfem.dev/homeserver_rules.txt](https://transfem.dev/homeserver_rules.txt)

transfem.dev is also listed at
[servers.joinmatrix.org](https://servers.joinmatrix.org/), which is a list of
popular public Matrix homeservers, including some others that run conduwuit.

#### What is the current status?

conduwuit is technically a hard fork of [Conduit](https://conduit.rs/), which is in beta.
The beta status initially was inherited from Conduit, however the huge amount of
codebase divergance, changes, fixes, and improvements have effectively made this
beta status not entirely applicable to us anymore.

conduwuit is very stable based on our rapidly growing userbase, has lots of features that users
expect, and very usable as a daily driver for small, medium, and upper-end medium sized homeservers.

A lot of critical stability and performance issues have been fixed, and a lot of
necessary groundwork has finished; making this project way better than it was
back in the start at ~early 2024.

#### Where is the differences page?

conduwuit historically had a &quot;differences&quot; page that listed each and every single
different thing about conduwuit from Conduit, as a way to promote and advertise
conduwuit by showing significant amounts of work done. While this was feasible to
maintain back when the project was new in early-2024, this became impossible
very quickly and has unfortunately became heavily outdated, missing tons of things, etc.

It&#039;s difficult to list out what we do differently, what are our notable features, etc
when there&#039;s so many things and features and bug fixes and performance optimisations, 
the list goes on. We simply recommend folks to just try out conduwuit, or ask us
what features you are looking for and if they&#039;re implemented in conduwuit.

#### How is conduwuit funded? Is conduwuit sustainable?

conduwuit has no external funding. This is made possible purely in my freetime with
contributors, also in their free time, and only by user-curated donations.

conduwuit has existed since around November 2023, but [only became more publicly known
in March/April 2024](https://matrix.org/blog/2024/04/26/this-week-in-matrix-2024-04-26/#conduwuit-website)
and we have no plans in stopping or slowing down any time soon!

#### Can I migrate or switch from Conduit?

conduwuit had drop-in migration/replacement support for Conduit for about 12 months before
bugs somewhere along the line broke it. Maintaining this has been difficult and
the majority of Conduit users have already migrated, additionally debugging Conduit
is not one of our interests, and so Conduit migration no longer works. We also
feel that 12 months has been plenty of time for people to seamlessly migrate.

If you are a Conduit user looking to migrate, you will have to wipe and reset
your database. We may fix seamless migration support at some point, but it&#039;s not an interest
from us.

#### Can I migrate from Synapse or Dendrite?

Currently there is no known way to seamlessly migrate all user data from the old
homeserver to conduwuit. However it is perfectly acceptable to replace the old
homeserver software with conduwuit using the same server name and there will not
be any issues with federation.

There is an interest in developing a built-in seamless user data migration
method into conduwuit, however there is no concrete ETA or timeline for this.


&lt;!-- ANCHOR_END: body --&gt;

&lt;!-- ANCHOR: footer --&gt;

#### Contact

[`#conduwuit:puppygock.gay`](https://matrix.to/#/#conduwuit:puppygock.gay)
is the official project Matrix room. You can get support here, ask questions or
concerns, get assistance setting up conduwuit, etc.

This room should stay relevant and focused on conduwuit. An offtopic general
chatter room can be found in the room topic there as well.

Please keep the issue trackers focused on *actual* bug reports and enhancement requests.

General support is extremely difficult to be offered over an issue tracker, and
simple questions should be asked directly in an interactive platform like our
Matrix room above as they can turn into a relevant discussion and/or may not be
simple to answer. If you&#039;re not sure, just ask in the Matrix room.

If you have a bug or feature to request: [Open an issue on GitHub](https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit/issues/new)

If you need to contact the primary maintainer, my contact methods are on my website: https://girlboss.ceo

#### Donate

conduwuit development is purely made possible by myself and contributors. I do
not get paid to work on this, and I work on it in my free time. Donations are
heavily appreciated! 💜🥺

- Liberapay: &lt;https://liberapay.com/girlbossceo&gt;
- GitHub Sponsors: &lt;https://github.com/sponsors/girlbossceo&gt;
- Ko-fi: &lt;https://ko-fi.com/puppygock&gt;

I do not and will not accept cryptocurrency donations, including things related.

Note that donations will NOT guarantee you or give you any kind of tangible product,
feature prioritisation, etc. By donating, you are agreeing that conduwuit is NOT
going to provide you any goods or services as part of your donation, and this
donation is purely a generous donation. We will not provide things like paid
personal/direct support, feature request priority, merchandise, etc.

#### Logo

Original repo and Matrix room picture was from bran (&lt;3). Current banner image
and logo is directly from [this cohost
post](https://web.archive.org/web/20241126004041/https://cohost.org/RatBaby/post/1028290-finally-a-flag-for).

An SVG logo made by [@nktnet1](https://github.com/nktnet1) is available here: &lt;https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit/blob/main/docs/assets/&gt;

#### Is it conduwuit or Conduwuit?

Both, but I prefer conduwuit.

#### Mirrors of conduwuit

If GitHub is unavailable in your country, or has poor connectivity, conduwuit&#039;s
source code is mirrored onto the following additional platforms I maintain:

- GitHub: &lt;https://github.com/girlbossceo/conduwuit&gt;
- GitLab: &lt;https://gitlab.com/conduwuit/conduwuit&gt;
- git.girlcock.ceo: &lt;https://git.girlcock.ceo/strawberry/conduwuit&gt;
- git.gay: &lt;https://git.gay/june/conduwuit&gt;
- mau.dev: &lt;https://mau.dev/june/conduwuit&gt;
- Codeberg: &lt;https://codeberg.org/arf/conduwuit&gt;
- sourcehut: &lt;https://git.sr.ht/~girlbossceo/conduwuit&gt;

&lt;!-- ANCHOR_END: footer --&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[tikv/tikv]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/tikv/tikv</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/tikv/tikv</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Distributed transactional key-value database, originally created to complement TiDB]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/tikv/tikv">tikv/tikv</a></h1>
            <p>Distributed transactional key-value database, originally created to complement TiDB</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,719</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,176</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;img src=&quot;images/tikv-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;tikv_logo&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;/&gt;

## [Website](https://tikv.org) | [Documentation](https://tikv.org/docs/latest/concepts/overview/) | [Community Chat](https://slack.tidb.io/invite?team=tikv-wg&amp;channel=general)

[![Build Status](https://ci.pingcap.net/buildStatus/icon?job=tikv_ghpr_build_master)](https://ci.pingcap.net/blue/organizations/jenkins/tikv_ghpr_build_master/activity)
[![Coverage Status](https://codecov.io/gh/tikv/tikv/branch/master/graph/badge.svg)](https://codecov.io/gh/tikv/tikv)
[![CII Best Practices](https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/2574/badge)](https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/2574)

TiKV is an open-source, distributed, and transactional key-value database. Unlike other traditional NoSQL systems, TiKV not only provides classical key-value APIs, but also transactional APIs with ACID compliance. Built in Rust and powered by Raft, TiKV was originally created by [PingCAP](https://en.pingcap.com) to complement [TiDB](https://github.com/pingcap/tidb), a distributed HTAP database compatible with the MySQL protocol.

The design of TiKV (&#039;Ti&#039; stands for titanium) is inspired by some great distributed systems from Google, such as BigTable, Spanner, and Percolator, and some of the latest achievements in academia in recent years, such as the Raft consensus algorithm.

If you&#039;re interested in contributing to TiKV, or want to build it from source, see [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md).

![cncf_logo](images/cncf.png#gh-light-mode-only)
![cncf_logo](images/cncf-white.png#gh-dark-mode-only)

TiKV is a graduated project of the [Cloud Native Computing Foundation](https://cncf.io/) (CNCF). If you are an organization that wants to help shape the evolution of technologies that are container-packaged, dynamically-scheduled and microservices-oriented, consider joining the CNCF. For details about who&#039;s involved and how TiKV plays a role, read the CNCF [announcement](https://www.cncf.io/announcements/2020/09/02/cloud-native-computing-foundation-announces-tikv-graduation/).

---

With the implementation of the Raft consensus algorithm in Rust and consensus state stored in RocksDB, TiKV guarantees data consistency. [Placement Driver (PD)](https://github.com/pingcap/pd/), which is introduced to implement auto-sharding, enables automatic data migration. The transaction model is similar to Google&#039;s Percolator with some performance improvements. TiKV also provides snapshot isolation (SI), snapshot isolation with lock (SQL: `SELECT ... FOR UPDATE`), and externally consistent reads and writes in distributed transactions.

TiKV has the following key features:

- **Geo-Replication**

    TiKV uses [Raft](http://raft.github.io/) and the Placement Driver to support Geo-Replication.

- **Horizontal scalability**

    With PD and carefully designed Raft groups, TiKV excels in horizontal scalability and can easily scale to 100+ TBs of data.

- **Consistent distributed transactions**

    Similar to Google&#039;s Spanner, TiKV supports externally-consistent distributed transactions.

- **Coprocessor support**

    Similar to HBase, TiKV implements a coprocessor framework to support distributed computing.

- **Cooperates with [TiDB](https://github.com/pingcap/tidb)**

    Thanks to the internal optimization, TiKV and TiDB can work together to be a compelling database solution with high horizontal scalability, externally-consistent transactions, support for RDBMS, and NoSQL design patterns.

## Governance

See [Governance](https://github.com/tikv/community/blob/master/GOVERNANCE.md).

## Documentation

For instructions on deployment, configuration, and maintenance of TiKV,see TiKV documentation on our [website](https://tikv.org/docs/4.0/tasks/introduction/). For more details on concepts and designs behind TiKV, see [Deep Dive TiKV](https://tikv.org/deep-dive/introduction/).

&gt; **Note:**
&gt;
&gt; We have migrated our documentation from the [TiKV&#039;s wiki page](https://github.com/tikv/tikv/wiki/) to the [official website](https://tikv.org/docs). The original Wiki page is discontinued. If you have any suggestions or issues regarding documentation, offer your feedback [here](https://github.com/tikv/website).

## TiKV adopters

You can view the list of [TiKV Adopters](https://tikv.org/adopters/).

## TiKV software stack

![The TiKV software stack](images/tikv_stack.png)

- **Placement Driver:** PD is the cluster manager of TiKV, which periodically checks replication constraints to balance load and data automatically.
- **Store:** There is a RocksDB within each Store and it stores data into the local disk.
- **Region:** Region is the basic unit of Key-Value data movement. Each Region is replicated to multiple Nodes. These multiple replicas form a Raft group.
- **Node:** A physical node in the cluster. Within each node, there are one or more Stores. Within each Store, there are many Regions.

When a node starts, the metadata of the Node, Store and Region are recorded into PD. The status of each Region and Store is reported to PD regularly.

## Quick start

### Deploy a playground with TiUP

The most quickest to try out TiKV with TiDB is using TiUP, a component manager for TiDB.

You can see [this page](https://docs.pingcap.com/tidb/stable/quick-start-with-tidb#deploy-a-local-test-environment-using-tiup-playground) for a step by step tutorial.

### Deploy a playground with binary

TiKV is able to run separately with PD, which is the minimal deployment required.

1. Download and extract binaries.

```bash
$ export TIKV_VERSION=v7.5.0
$ export GOOS=darwin  # only {darwin, linux} are supported
$ export GOARCH=amd64 # only {amd64, arm64} are supported
$ curl -O  https://tiup-mirrors.pingcap.com/tikv-$TIKV_VERSION-$GOOS-$GOARCH.tar.gz
$ curl -O  https://tiup-mirrors.pingcap.com/pd-$TIKV_VERSION-$GOOS-$GOARCH.tar.gz
$ tar -xzf tikv-$TIKV_VERSION-$GOOS-$GOARCH.tar.gz
$ tar -xzf pd-$TIKV_VERSION-$GOOS-$GOARCH.tar.gz
```

2. Start PD instance.

```bash
$ ./pd-server --name=pd --data-dir=/tmp/pd/data --client-urls=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:2379&quot; --peer-urls=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:2380&quot; --initial-cluster=&quot;pd=http://127.0.0.1:2380&quot; --log-file=/tmp/pd/log/pd.log
```

3. Start TiKV instance.

```bash
$ ./tikv-server --pd-endpoints=&quot;127.0.0.1:2379&quot; --addr=&quot;127.0.0.1:20160&quot; --data-dir=/tmp/tikv/data --log-file=/tmp/tikv/log/tikv.log
```

4. Install TiKV Client(Python) and verify the deployment, required Python 3.5+.

```bash
$ pip3 install -i https://test.pypi.org/simple/ tikv-client
```

```python
from tikv_client import RawClient

client = RawClient.connect(&quot;127.0.0.1:2379&quot;)

client.put(b&#039;foo&#039;, b&#039;bar&#039;)
print(client.get(b&#039;foo&#039;)) # b&#039;bar&#039;

client.put(b&#039;foo&#039;, b&#039;baz&#039;)
print(client.get(b&#039;foo&#039;)) # b&#039;baz&#039;
```

### Deploy a cluster with TiUP

You can see [this manual](./doc/deploy.md) of production-like cluster deployment presented by @c4pt0r.

### Build from source

See [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Client drivers

- [Go](https://github.com/tikv/client-go) (The most stable and widely used)
- [Java](https://github.com/tikv/client-java)
- [Rust](https://github.com/tikv/client-rust)
- [C](https://github.com/tikv/client-c)

If you want to try the Go client, see [Go Client](https://tikv.org/docs/4.0/reference/clients/go/).

## Security

### Security audit

A third-party security auditing was performed by Cure53. See the full report [here](./security/Security-Audit.pdf).

### Reporting Security Vulnerabilities

To report a security vulnerability, please send an email to [TiKV-security](mailto:tikv-security@lists.cncf.io) group.

See [Security](SECURITY.md) for the process and policy followed by the TiKV project.

## Communication

Communication within the TiKV community abides by [TiKV Code of Conduct](./CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md). Here is an excerpt:

&gt; In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as
contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and
our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body
size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression,
level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal
appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.

### Social Media

- [Twitter](https://twitter.com/tikvproject)
- [Blog](https://tikv.org/blog/)
- [Reddit](https://www.reddit.com/r/TiKV)
- Post questions or help answer them on [Stack Overflow](https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tikv)

### Slack

Join the TiKV community on [Slack](https://slack.tidb.io/invite?team=tikv-wg&amp;channel=general) - Sign up and join channels on TiKV topics that interest you.

## License

TiKV is under the Apache 2.0 license. See the [LICENSE](./LICENSE) file for details.

## Acknowledgments

- Thanks [etcd](https://github.com/coreos/etcd) for providing some great open source tools.
- Thanks [RocksDB](https://github.com/facebook/rocksdb) for their powerful storage engines.
- Thanks [rust-clippy](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy). We do love the great project.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[qarmin/czkawka]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/qarmin/czkawka</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/qarmin/czkawka</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Multi functional app to find duplicates, empty folders, similar images etc.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/qarmin/czkawka">qarmin/czkawka</a></h1>
            <p>Multi functional app to find duplicates, empty folders, similar images etc.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 23,072</p>
            <p>Forks: 730</p>
            <p>Stars today: 36 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![com github qarmin czkawka](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/41945903/102616149-66490400-4137-11eb-9cd6-813b2b070834.png)

**Czkawka** (_tch•kav•ka_ (IPA: [ˈʧ̑kafka]), &quot;hiccup&quot; in Polish) is a simple, fast and free app to remove unnecessary
files from your computer.

**Krokiet** ((IPA: [ˈkrɔcɛt]), &quot;croquet&quot; in Polish) same as above, but uses Slint frontend.

## Features

- Written in memory-safe Rust - almost 100% unsafe code free
- Amazingly fast - due to using more or less advanced algorithms and multithreading
- Free, Open Source without ads
- Multiplatform - works on Linux, Windows, macOS, FreeBSD and many more
- Cache support - second and further scans should be much faster than the first one
- CLI frontend - for easy automation
- GUI frontend - uses GTK 4 or Slint frameworks
- No spying - Czkawka does not have access to the Internet, nor does it collect any user information or statistics
- Multilingual - support multiple languages like Polish, English or Italian
- Multiple tools to use:
    - Duplicates - Finds duplicates based on file name, size or hash
    - Empty Folders - Finds empty folders with the help of an advanced algorithm
    - Big Files - Finds the provided number of the biggest files in given location
    - Empty Files - Looks for empty files across the drive
    - Temporary Files - Finds temporary files
    - Similar Images - Finds images which are not exactly the same (different resolution, watermarks)
    - Similar Videos - Looks for visually similar videos
    - Same Music - Searches for similar music by tags or by reading content and comparing it
    - Invalid Symbolic Links - Shows symbolic links which point to non-existent files/directories
    - Broken Files - Finds files that are invalid or corrupted
    - Bad Extensions - Lists files whose content not match with their extension

![Czkawka](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/b0409515-1bec-4e13-8fac-7bdfa15f5848)

![Krokiet](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/906cbbc3-f011-4306-81da-9e4e53b49a9f)

Changelog about each version can be found in [CHANGELOG.md](CHANGELOG.md).

New releases can be found in [Github releases](https://github.com/qarmin/czkawka/releases) and nightly builds also in [Nightly releases](https://github.com/qarmin/czkawka/releases/tag/Nightly)

## Usage, installation, compilation, requirements, license

Each tool uses different technologies, so you can find instructions for each of them in the appropriate file:

- [Czkawka GUI (GTK frontend)](czkawka_gui/README.md)&lt;/br&gt;
- [Czkawka CLI](czkawka_cli/README.md)&lt;/br&gt;
- [Czkawka Core](czkawka_core/README.md)&lt;/br&gt;
- [Krokiet GUI (Slint frontend)](krokiet/README.md)&lt;/br&gt;

## Comparison to other tools

Bleachbit is a master at finding and removing temporary files, while Czkawka only finds the most basic ones. So these
two apps shouldn&#039;t be compared directly or be considered as an alternative to one another.

In this comparison remember, that even if app have same features they may work different(e.g. one app may have more
options to choose than other).

|                          |   Czkawka   |   Krokiet   | FSlint |     DupeGuru      |  Bleachbit  |
|:------------------------:|:-----------:|:-----------:|:------:|:-----------------:|:-----------:|
|         Language         |    Rust     |    Rust     | Python |   Python/Obj-C    |   Python    |
| Framework base language  |      C      |    Rust     |   C    | C/C++/Obj-C/Swift |      C      |
|        Framework         |    GTK 4    |    Slint    | PyGTK2 | Qt 5 (PyQt)/Cocoa |   PyGTK3    |
|            OS            | Lin,Mac,Win | Lin,Mac,Win |  Lin   |    Lin,Mac,Win    | Lin,Mac,Win |
|     Duplicate finder     |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |         ✔         |             |
|       Empty files        |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |             |
|      Empty folders       |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |             |
|     Temporary files      |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |      ✔      |
|        Big files         |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |                   |             |
|      Similar images      |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |         ✔         |             |
|      Similar videos      |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |                   |             |
|  Music duplicates(tags)  |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |         ✔         |             |
|     Invalid symlinks     |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |             |
|       Broken files       |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |                   |             |
|      Names conflict      |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |             |
| Invalid names/extensions |      ✔      |      ✔      |   ✔    |                   |             |
|    Installed packages    |             |             |   ✔    |                   |             |
|          Bad ID          |             |             |   ✔    |                   |             |
|  Non stripped binaries   |             |             |   ✔    |                   |             |
|   Redundant whitespace   |             |             |   ✔    |                   |             |
|    Overwriting files     |             |             |   ✔    |                   |      ✔      |
|    Multiple languages    |      ✔      |             |   ✔    |         ✔         |      ✔      |
|      Cache support       |      ✔      |      ✔      |        |         ✔         |             |
|  In active development   |     Yes     |     Yes     |   No   |        Yes        |     Yes     |

## Other apps

There are many similar applications to Czkawka on the Internet, which do some things better and some things worse:

### GUI

- [DupeGuru](https://github.com/arsenetar/dupeguru) - Many options to customize; great photo compare tool
- [FSlint](https://github.com/pixelb/fslint) - A little outdated, but still have some tools not available in Czkawka
- [AntiDupl.NET](https://github.com/ermig1979/AntiDupl) - Shows a lot of metadata of compared images
- [Video Duplicate Finder](https://github.com/0x90d/videoduplicatefinder) - Finds similar videos(surprising, isn&#039;t it), supports video thumbnails

### CLI

Due to limited time, the biggest emphasis is on the GUI version so if you are looking for really good and feature-packed
console apps, then take a look at these:

- [Fclones](https://github.com/pkolaczk/fclones) - One of the fastest tools to find duplicates; it is written also in
  Rust
- [Rmlint](https://github.com/sahib/rmlint) - Nice console interface and also is feature packed
- [RdFind](https://github.com/pauldreik/rdfind) - Fast, but written in C++ ¯\\\_(ツ)\_/¯

## Contributions

Contributions to this repository are welcome.

You can help by creating:

- Bug reports - memory leaks, unexpected behavior, crashes
- Feature proposals - proposal to change/add/delete some features
- Pull Requests - implementing a new feature yourself or fixing bugs.
  If the change is bigger, then it&#039;s a good idea to open a new issue to discuss changes, but issues with
  label `PR welcome` are already checked and accepted.
- Documentation - There is an [instruction](instructions/Instruction.md) which you can improve.
- Translations - Instruction how to translate files is available [here](instructions/Translations.md)
- External contributions - App use big number of external libraries
  like [lofty](https://github.com/Serial-ATA/lofty-rs), [image-rs](https://github.com/image-rs/image)
  or [symphonia](https://github.com/pdeljanov/Symphonia) so improving this libraries will automatically improve Czkawka

You can also help by doing other things:

- Creating text
  articles - [LinuxUprising](https://www.linuxuprising.com/2021/03/find-and-remove-duplicate-files-similar.html)
  or [Ubunlog](https://ubunlog.com/en/czkawka-finds-and-removes-empty-and-broken-duplicate-files/)
- Adding Czkawka to repositories - [Alpine Linux](https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/packages?name=czkawka&amp;branch=edge)
  or [NixOS](https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/pull/116441)
  or [OpenMandriva](https://github.com/OpenMandrivaAssociation/czkawka)
- Creating videos - [First Video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CWlRiTD4vDc)
  or [Spanish Tutorial](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9x-pHJRmKY)
- Recommending it to others

## Thanks

Big thanks to Pádraig Brady, creator of fantastic FSlint, because without his work I wouldn&#039;t create this tool.

Thanks also to all the people who create patches for this program, make it available on other systems, create videos,
articles about it etc.

Also, I really appreciate work of people that create crates on which Czkawka is based and for that I try to report bugs
to make it even better.

## Donations

If you are using the app, I would appreciate a donation for its further development, which can be
done [here](https://github.com/sponsors/qarmin).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mufeedvh/code2prompt]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A CLI tool to convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt with source tree, prompt templating, and token counting.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt">mufeedvh/code2prompt</a></h1>
            <p>A CLI tool to convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt with source tree, prompt templating, and token counting.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,390</p>
            <p>Forks: 312</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://code2prompt.dev&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;550px&quot; src=&quot;.assets/logo_dark_v0.0.2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Code2prompt&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt !&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://code2prompt.dev&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.assets/CLI.png&quot; alt=&quot;code2prompt&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

[![crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/code2prompt.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/code2prompt)
[![LICENSE](https://img.shields.io/github/license/mufeedvh/code2prompt.svg#cache1)](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/blob/master/LICENSE)
[![PRs Welcome](https://img.shields.io/badge/PRs-welcome-brightgreen.svg)](https://github.com/user/repo/pulls)
[![Lines of Code](https://tokei.rs/b1/github/mufeedvh/code2prompt)](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/1342336677905039451?logo=discord)](https://discord.com/invite/ZZyBbsHTwH)

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Want to engage with us ? Join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/invite/ZZyBbsHTwH&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; channel!&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Stay updated on new features&lt;/i&gt; 📢&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Give your insight and suggestion&lt;/i&gt; 💬&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Get help with configuration and usage&lt;/i&gt; 🛠️&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Report Bug&lt;/i&gt; 🐛&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Quick Install ⚡

```bash
# Cargo
$ cargo install code2prompt

# Homebrew
$ brew install code2prompt
```

SDK with pip 🐍

```bash
pip install code2prompt-rs
```

## How is it useful?

**Core**

`code2prompt` is a code ingestion tool that streamline the process of creating LLM prompts for code analysis, generation, and other tasks. It works by traversing directories, building a tree structure, and gathering informations about each file. The core library can easily be integrated into other applications.

**CLI**

`code2prompt` command line interface (CLI) was designed for humans to generate prompts directly from your codebase. The generated prompt is automatically copied to your clipboard and can also be saved to an output file. Furthermore, you can customize the prompt generation using Handlebars templates. Check out the provided prompts in the doc !

**SDK**

`code2prompt` software development kit (SDK) offers python binding to the core library. This is perfect for AI agents or automation scripts that want to interact with codebase seamlessly. The SDK is hosted on Pypi and can be installed via pip.

**MCP**

`code2prompt` is also available as a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, which allows you to run it as a local service. This enables LLMs on steroids by providing them a tool to automatically gather a well-structured context of your codebase.

## Documentation 📚

Check our online [documentation](https://code2prompt.dev/docs/welcome/) for detailed instructions

## Features

Code2Prompt transforms your entire codebase into a well-structured prompt for large language models. Key features include:

- **Automatic Code Processing**: Convert codebases of any size into readable, formatted prompts
- **Smart Filtering**: Include/exclude files using glob patterns and respect `.gitignore` rules
- **Flexible Templating**: Customize prompts with Handlebars templates for different use cases
- **Token Tracking**: Track token usage to stay within LLM context limits
- **Git Integration**: Include diffs, logs, and branch comparisons in your prompts
- **Developer Experience**: Automatic clipboard copy, line numbers, and file organization options

Stop manually copying files and formatting code for LLMs. Code2Prompt handles the tedious work so you can focus on getting insights and solutions from AI models.

## Alternative Installation

Refer to the [documentation](https://code2prompt.dev/docs/how_to/install/) for detailed installation instructions.

### Binary releases

Download the latest binary for your OS from [Releases](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/releases).

### Source build

Requires:

- [Git](https://git-scm.org/downloads), [Rust](https://rust-lang.org/tools/install) and `Cargo`.

```sh
git clone https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt.git
cd code2prompt/
cargo install --path crates/code2prompt
```

## Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=mufeedvh/code2prompt&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#mufeedvh/code2prompt&amp;Date)

## License

Licensed under the MIT License, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for more information.

## Liked the project?

If you liked the project and found it useful, please give it a :star: !

## Contribution

Ways to contribute:

- Suggest a feature
- Report a bug
- Fix something and open a pull request
- Help me document the code
- Spread the word
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ruffle-rs/ruffle]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Flash Player emulator written in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle">ruffle-rs/ruffle</a></h1>
            <p>A Flash Player emulator written in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,475</p>
            <p>Forks: 861</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle&quot; src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/logo.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/actions&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rust Build Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/ruffle-rs/ruffle/test_rust.yml?label=Rust%20Build&amp;logo=github&amp;branch=master&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/actions/workflows/test_web.yml&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Web Build Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/ruffle-rs/ruffle/test_web.yml?label=Web%20Build&amp;logo=github&amp;branch=master&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://flathub.org/apps/rs.ruffle.Ruffle&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle Flathub&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/flathub/v/rs.ruffle.Ruffle?color=007acc&amp;logo=flathub&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@ruffle-rs/ruffle&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle npm&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@ruffle-rs/ruffle?color=007acc&amp;logo=npm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/ruffle-nightly-bin&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle AUR&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/aur/version/ruffle-nightly-bin?logo=archlinux&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/ruffle&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/610531541889581066?label=&amp;color=7389d8&amp;labelColor=6a7ec2&amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;logo=discord&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crowdin.com/project/ruffle&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruffle translations&quot; src=&quot;https://badges.crowdin.net/ruffle/localized.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/demo&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/releases&quot;&gt;nightly builds&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/wiki&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

# Ruffle

Ruffle is an Adobe Flash Player emulator written in the Rust programming language. Ruffle targets both the desktop and the web using WebAssembly.

## Table of Contents
* [Project status](#project-status)
* [Using Ruffle](#using-ruffle)
* [Building from source](#building-from-source)
  * [Prerequisites](#prerequisites)
  * [Linux prerequisites](#linux-prerequisites)
  * [Desktop](#desktop)
    * [Build](#build)
    * [macOS](#macos)
  * [Web or Extension](#web-or-extension)
  * [Android](#android)
  * [Scanner](#scanner)
  * [Exporter](#exporter)
* [Structure](#structure)
* [Sponsors](#sponsors)
* [License](#license)
* [Contributing](#contributing)


## Project status

Ruffle supports ActionScript 1, 2 and 3 pretty well, but it&#039;s still not finished by any means. Please report any issues in the [Issue Tracker](https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/issues).

## Using Ruffle

The easiest way to try out Ruffle is to visit the [web demo page](https://ruffle.rs/demo/), then click the &quot;Select File&quot; button to load a SWF file of your choice.

[Nightly builds](https://ruffle.rs/downloads#nightly-releases) of Ruffle are available for desktop and web platforms.

For more detailed instructions, see our [wiki page](https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle/wiki/Using-Ruffle).

## Building from source

### Prerequisites

* Latest stable channel of [Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install)
* Java, available on your PATH as `java` (required for building the library containing the builtin Flash classes for ActionScript 3)

### Linux prerequisites

The following are typical dependencies for Linux:

* libasound2-dev
* libxcb-shape0-dev
* libxcb-xfixes0-dev
* libgtk-3-dev
* libudev-dev
* libxcb-xinput-dev
* libxcb-xkb-dev
* libxcb-cursor-dev
* default-jre-headless
* cmake
* g++

### Desktop

#### Build

Use the following command to build and run the desktop app:

`cargo run --release --package=ruffle_desktop`

To run a specific SWF file, pass the SWF path as an argument:

`cargo run --release --package=ruffle_desktop -- test.swf`

To build in debug mode, simply omit `--release` from the command.

#### macOS

Ruffle desktop can be built from our [Homebrew Tap](https://github.com/ruffle-rs/homebrew-ruffle/):

`brew install --HEAD ruffle-rs/ruffle/ruffle`

_Note: because it is HEAD-only, you&#039;ll need to run `brew upgrade --fetch-HEAD ruffle` each time you want to update._

### Web or Extension

Follow [the instructions in the web directory](web/README.md#building-from-source) for building
either the web or browser extension version of Ruffle.

This project is tested with BrowserStack.

### Android

Follow the [instructions](https://github.com/ruffle-rs/ruffle-android/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md#building-from-source) in the `ruffle-android` project for building the Android application of Ruffle.

### Scanner

If you have a collection of &quot;real world&quot; SWFs to test against, the scanner may be used to benchmark
ruffle&#039;s parsing capabilities. Provided with a folder and an output filename, it will attempt to read
all of the Flash files and report on the success of such a task.

`cargo run --release --package=ruffle_scanner -- scan folder/with/swfs/ results.csv`

### Exporter

If you have a SWF file and would like to capture an image of it, you may use the exporter tool.
This currently requires hardware acceleration, but can be run headless (with no window).

- `cargo run --release --package=exporter -- path/to/file.swf`
- `cargo run --release --package=exporter -- path/to/file.swf path/to/screenshots --frames 5`

## Structure

- `core` - core emulator and common code
- `swf` - SWF and ActionScript parser
- `desktop` - desktop client (uses `wgpu-rs`)
- `web` - web client and browser extension (uses `wasm-bindgen`)
- `render` - various rendering backends for both desktop and web
- `video` - video decoding backends
- `flv` - Flash Video decoder
- `wstr` - a Flash-compatible implementation of strings
- `scanner` - a utility to bulk parse SWF files
- `exporter` - a utility to generate PNG screenshots of a SWF file

## Sponsors

You can support the development of Ruffle via [GitHub Sponsors](https://github.com/sponsors/ruffle-rs). Your sponsorship will help to ensure the accessibility of Flash content for the future. Thank you!

Sincere thanks to the diamond level sponsors of Ruffle:

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newgrounds.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/newgrounds.png&quot; alt=&quot;Newgrounds.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cpmstar.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/cpmstar.png&quot; alt=&quot;CPMStar&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepnight.net&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/deepnight.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sébastien Bénard&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crazygames.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/crazygames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crazy Games&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coolmathgames.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/coolmathgames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cool Math Games&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/nyt.png&quot; alt=&quot;The New York Times&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armorgames.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/armorgames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Armor Games&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ondaeduca.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/ondaeduca.png&quot; alt=&quot;Onda Educa&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twoplayergames.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/twoplayergames.png&quot; alt=&quot;TwoPlayerGames.org&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wowgame.jp/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/wowgame.png&quot; alt=&quot;wowgame.jp&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://kupogames.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/mattroszak.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matt Roszak&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dolldivine.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/dolldivine.png&quot; alt=&quot;Doll Divine&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://movavi.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/movavi.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Movavi&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kongregate.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/kongregate.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Kongregate&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bubbleshooter.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/bubble-shooter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bubble Shooter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neopets.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ruffle.rs/sponsors/neopets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Neopets&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## License

Ruffle is licensed under either of

- Apache License, Version 2.0 (http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0)
- MIT License (http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT)

at your option.

Ruffle depends on third-party libraries under compatible licenses. See [LICENSE.md](LICENSE.md) for full information.

### Contributing

Ruffle welcomes contribution from everyone. See [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md) for help getting started.

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted
for inclusion in the work by you shall be dual licensed as above, without any
additional terms or conditions.

The entire Ruffle community, including the chat room and GitHub project, is expected to abide by the [Code of Conduct](https://www.rust-lang.org/policies/code-of-conduct) that the Rust project itself follows.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[pola-rs/polars]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/pola-rs/polars</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/pola-rs/polars</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:05:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Dataframes powered by a multithreaded, vectorized query engine, written in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/pola-rs/polars">pola-rs/polars</a></h1>
            <p>Dataframes powered by a multithreaded, vectorized query engine, written in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 33,071</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,171</p>
            <p>Stars today: 25 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pola.rs&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pola-rs/polars-static/master/banner/polars_github_banner.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Polars logo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/polars&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/polars.svg&quot; alt=&quot;crates.io Latest Release&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/polars/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/polars.svg&quot; alt=&quot;PyPi Latest Release&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/nodejs-polars&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/nodejs-polars.svg&quot; alt=&quot;NPM Latest Release&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://rpolars.r-universe.dev&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://rpolars.r-universe.dev/badges/polars&quot; alt=&quot;R-universe Latest Release&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7697217&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.7697217.svg&quot; alt=&quot;DOI Latest Release&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Documentation&lt;/b&gt;:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pola.rs/api/python/stable/reference/index.html&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/polars/latest/polars/&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pola-rs.github.io/nodejs-polars/index.html&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pola-rs.github.io/r-polars/index.html&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;
  |
  &lt;b&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/b&gt;:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/python-polars&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/rust-polars&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/nodejs-polars&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;
  -
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/r-polars&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;
  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pola.rs/&quot;&gt;User guide&lt;/a&gt;
  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/4UfP5cfBE7&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Polars: Blazingly fast DataFrames in Rust, Python, Node.js, R, and SQL

Polars is a DataFrame interface on top of an OLAP Query Engine implemented in Rust using
[Apache Arrow Columnar Format](https://arrow.apache.org/docs/format/Columnar.html) as the memory
model.

- Lazy | eager execution
- Multi-threaded
- SIMD
- Query optimization
- Powerful expression API
- Hybrid Streaming (larger-than-RAM datasets)
- Rust | Python | NodeJS | R | ...

To learn more, read the [user guide](https://docs.pola.rs/).

## Python

```python
&gt;&gt;&gt; import polars as pl
&gt;&gt;&gt; df = pl.DataFrame(
...     {
...         &quot;A&quot;: [1, 2, 3, 4, 5],
...         &quot;fruits&quot;: [&quot;banana&quot;, &quot;banana&quot;, &quot;apple&quot;, &quot;apple&quot;, &quot;banana&quot;],
...         &quot;B&quot;: [5, 4, 3, 2, 1],
...         &quot;cars&quot;: [&quot;beetle&quot;, &quot;audi&quot;, &quot;beetle&quot;, &quot;beetle&quot;, &quot;beetle&quot;],
...     }
... )

# embarrassingly parallel execution &amp; very expressive query language
&gt;&gt;&gt; df.sort(&quot;fruits&quot;).select(
...     &quot;fruits&quot;,
...     &quot;cars&quot;,
...     pl.lit(&quot;fruits&quot;).alias(&quot;literal_string_fruits&quot;),
...     pl.col(&quot;B&quot;).filter(pl.col(&quot;cars&quot;) == &quot;beetle&quot;).sum(),
...     pl.col(&quot;A&quot;).filter(pl.col(&quot;B&quot;) &gt; 2).sum().over(&quot;cars&quot;).alias(&quot;sum_A_by_cars&quot;),
...     pl.col(&quot;A&quot;).sum().over(&quot;fruits&quot;).alias(&quot;sum_A_by_fruits&quot;),
...     pl.col(&quot;A&quot;).reverse().over(&quot;fruits&quot;).alias(&quot;rev_A_by_fruits&quot;),
...     pl.col(&quot;A&quot;).sort_by(&quot;B&quot;).over(&quot;fruits&quot;).alias(&quot;sort_A_by_B_by_fruits&quot;),
... )
shape: (5, 8)
┌──────────┬──────────┬──────────────┬─────┬─────────────┬─────────────┬─────────────┬─────────────┐
│ fruits   ┆ cars     ┆ literal_stri ┆ B   ┆ sum_A_by_ca ┆ sum_A_by_fr ┆ rev_A_by_fr ┆ sort_A_by_B │
│ ---      ┆ ---      ┆ ng_fruits    ┆ --- ┆ rs          ┆ uits        ┆ uits        ┆ _by_fruits  │
│ str      ┆ str      ┆ ---          ┆ i64 ┆ ---         ┆ ---         ┆ ---         ┆ ---         │
│          ┆          ┆ str          ┆     ┆ i64         ┆ i64         ┆ i64         ┆ i64         │
╞══════════╪══════════╪══════════════╪═════╪═════════════╪═════════════╪═════════════╪═════════════╡
│ &quot;apple&quot;  ┆ &quot;beetle&quot; ┆ &quot;fruits&quot;     ┆ 11  ┆ 4           ┆ 7           ┆ 4           ┆ 4           │
│ &quot;apple&quot;  ┆ &quot;beetle&quot; ┆ &quot;fruits&quot;     ┆ 11  ┆ 4           ┆ 7           ┆ 3           ┆ 3           │
│ &quot;banana&quot; ┆ &quot;beetle&quot; ┆ &quot;fruits&quot;     ┆ 11  ┆ 4           ┆ 8           ┆ 5           ┆ 5           │
│ &quot;banana&quot; ┆ &quot;audi&quot;   ┆ &quot;fruits&quot;     ┆ 11  ┆ 2           ┆ 8           ┆ 2           ┆ 2           │
│ &quot;banana&quot; ┆ &quot;beetle&quot; ┆ &quot;fruits&quot;     ┆ 11  ┆ 4           ┆ 8           ┆ 1           ┆ 1           │
└──────────┴──────────┴──────────────┴─────┴─────────────┴─────────────┴─────────────┴─────────────┘
```

## SQL

```python
&gt;&gt;&gt; df = pl.scan_csv(&quot;docs/assets/data/iris.csv&quot;)
&gt;&gt;&gt; ## OPTION 1
&gt;&gt;&gt; # run SQL queries on frame-level
&gt;&gt;&gt; df.sql(&quot;&quot;&quot;
...	SELECT species,
...	  AVG(sepal_length) AS avg_sepal_length
...	FROM self
...	GROUP BY species
...	&quot;&quot;&quot;).collect()
shape: (3, 2)
┌────────────┬──────────────────┐
│ species    ┆ avg_sepal_length │
│ ---        ┆ ---              │
│ str        ┆ f64              │
╞════════════╪══════════════════╡
│ Virginica  ┆ 6.588            │
│ Versicolor ┆ 5.936            │
│ Setosa     ┆ 5.006            │
└────────────┴──────────────────┘
&gt;&gt;&gt; ## OPTION 2
&gt;&gt;&gt; # use pl.sql() to operate on the global context
&gt;&gt;&gt; df2 = pl.LazyFrame({
...    &quot;species&quot;: [&quot;Setosa&quot;, &quot;Versicolor&quot;, &quot;Virginica&quot;],
...    &quot;blooming_season&quot;: [&quot;Spring&quot;, &quot;Summer&quot;, &quot;Fall&quot;]
...})
&gt;&gt;&gt; pl.sql(&quot;&quot;&quot;
... SELECT df.species,
...     AVG(df.sepal_length) AS avg_sepal_length,
...     df2.blooming_season
... FROM df
... LEFT JOIN df2 ON df.species = df2.species
... GROUP BY df.species, df2.blooming_season
... &quot;&quot;&quot;).collect()
```

SQL commands can also be run directly from your terminal using the Polars CLI:

```bash
# run an inline SQL query
&gt; polars -c &quot;SELECT species, AVG(sepal_length) AS avg_sepal_length, AVG(sepal_width) AS avg_sepal_width FROM read_csv(&#039;docs/assets/data/iris.csv&#039;) GROUP BY species;&quot;

# run interactively
&gt; polars
Polars CLI v0.3.0
Type .help for help.

&gt; SELECT species, AVG(sepal_length) AS avg_sepal_length, AVG(sepal_width) AS avg_sepal_width FROM read_csv(&#039;docs/assets/data/iris.csv&#039;) GROUP BY species;
```

Refer to the [Polars CLI repository](https://github.com/pola-rs/polars-cli) for more information.

## Performance 🚀🚀

### Blazingly fast

Polars is very fast. In fact, it is one of the best performing solutions available. See the
[PDS-H benchmarks](https://www.pola.rs/benchmarks.html) results.

### Lightweight

Polars is also very lightweight. It comes with zero required dependencies, and this shows in the
import times:

- polars: 70ms
- numpy: 104ms
- pandas: 520ms

### Handles larger-than-RAM data

If you have data that does not fit into memory, Polars&#039; query engine is able to process your query
(or parts of your query) in a streaming fashion. This drastically reduces memory requirements, so
you might be able to process your 250GB dataset on your laptop. Collect with
`collect(engine=&#039;streaming&#039;)` to run the query streaming. (This might be a little slower, but it is
still very fast!)

## Setup

### Python

Install the latest Polars version with:

```sh
pip install polars
```

We also have a conda package (`conda install -c conda-forge polars`), however pip is the preferred
way to install Polars.

Install Polars with all optional dependencies.

```sh
pip install &#039;polars[all]&#039;
```

You can also install a subset of all optional dependencies.

```sh
pip install &#039;polars[numpy,pandas,pyarrow]&#039;
```

See the [User Guide](https://docs.pola.rs/user-guide/installation/#feature-flags) for more details
on optional dependencies

To see the current Polars version and a full list of its optional dependencies, run:

```python
pl.show_versions()
```

Releases happen quite often (weekly / every few days) at the moment, so updating Polars regularly to
get the latest bugfixes / features might not be a bad idea.

### Rust

You can take latest release from `crates.io`, or if you want to use the latest features /
performance improvements point to the `main` branch of this repo.

```toml
polars = { git = &quot;https://github.com/pola-rs/polars&quot;, rev = &quot;&lt;optional git tag&gt;&quot; }
```

Requires Rust version `&gt;=1.80`.

## Contributing

Want to contribute? Read our [contributing guide](https://docs.pola.rs/development/contributing/).

## Python: compile Polars from source

If you want a bleeding edge release or maximal performance you should compile Polars from source.

This can be done by going through the following steps in sequence:

1. Install the latest [Rust compiler](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install)
2. Install [maturin](https://maturin.rs/): `pip install maturin`
3. `cd py-polars` and choose one of the following:
   - `make build`, slow binary with debug assertions and symbols, fast compile times
   - `make build-release`, fast binary without debug assertions, minimal debug symbols, long compile
     times
   - `make build-nodebug-release`, same as build-release but without any debug symbols, slightly
     faster to compile
   - `make build-debug-release`, same as build-release but with full debug symbols, slightly slower
     to compile
   - `make build-dist-release`, fastest binary, extreme compile times

By default the binary is compiled with optimizations turned on for a modern CPU. Specify `LTS_CPU=1`
with the command if your CPU is older and does not support e.g. AVX2.

Note that the Rust crate implementing the Python bindings is called `py-polars` to distinguish from
the wrapped Rust crate `polars` itself. However, both the Python package and the Python module are
named `polars`, so you can `pip install polars` and `import polars`.

## Using custom Rust functions in Python

Extending Polars with UDFs compiled in Rust is easy. We expose PyO3 extensions for `DataFrame` and
`Series` data structures. See more in https://github.com/pola-rs/pyo3-polars.

## Going big...

Do you expect more than 2^32 (~4.2 billion) rows? Compile Polars with the `bigidx` feature flag or,
for Python users, install `pip install polars-u64-idx`.

Don&#039;t use this unless you hit the row boundary as the default build of Polars is faster and consumes
less memory.

## Legacy

Do you want Polars to run on an old CPU (e.g. dating from before 2011), or on an `x86-64` build of
Python on Apple Silicon under Rosetta? Install `pip install polars-lts-cpu`. This version of Polars
is compiled without [AVX](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Vector_Extensions) target features.

## Sponsors

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/company/brand/img/jetbrains_logo.png&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; alt=&quot;JetBrains logo&quot; /&gt;](https://www.jetbrains.com)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>