<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for rust - Rust Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for rust.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EFForg/rayhunter]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Rust tool to detect cell site simulators on an orbic mobile hotspot]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter">EFForg/rayhunter</a></h1>
            <p>Rust tool to detect cell site simulators on an orbic mobile hotspot</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,591</p>
            <p>Forks: 115</p>
            <p>Stars today: 56 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![Rayhunter Logo - An Orca taking a bite out of a cellular signal bar](https://www.eff.org/files/styles/media_browser_preview/public/banner_library/rayhunter-banner.png)
# Rayhunter

![Tests](https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/actions/workflows/check-and-test.yml/badge.svg)

Rayhunter is an IMSI Catcher Catcher for the Orbic mobile hotspot.

**THIS CODE IS A PROOF OF CONCEPT AND SHOULD NOT BE RELIED UPON IN HIGH RISK SITUATIONS!**


## The Hardware

Rayhunter has been built and tested for the Orbic RC400L mobile hotspot. It may work on other orbics and other
linux/qualcom devices, but this is the only one we have tested on.
Buy the orbic [using bezos bucks](https://www.amazon.com/Orbic-Verizon-Hotspot-Connect-Enabled/dp/B08N3CHC4Y),
or on [Ebay](https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=orbic+rc400l).

## Setup


1. Download the latest [Rayhunter release bundle](https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/releases) and extract it.
**If you are installing from the cloned github repository please see the development instructions below, running `install.sh` from the git tree will not work.**
2. Turn on the Orbic device and plug it into your computer using a USB-C Cable.
3. On MacOS or Linux run the install script `install.sh`. 
4. Once finished, Rayhunter should be running! You can verify this by visiting the web UI as described below.

### Notes 
  * The install script has only been tested for Linux on the latest version of Ubuntu. If it fails you will need to follow the install steps outlined in **Development** below.
  * The install script also won&#039;t work on older macs with intel chips, for those macs you will need to follow the instructions at https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/wiki/Install-Rayhunter-on-Mac-Intel-devices
  * We don&#039;t currently support automated installs on windows, you will have to follow the manual install instructions below*

## Updating
Great news: if you&#039;ve successfully installed rayhunter, you already know how to update it! Our update process is identical to the setup process: simply download the latest release and follow the steps in the [setup section](#Setup).


## Usage

Once installed, Rayhunter will run automatically whenever your Orbic device is running. It serves a web UI that provides some basic controls, such as being able to start/stop recordings, download captures, and view heuristic analyses of captures. You can access this UI in one of two ways:

1. Over wifi: Connect your phone/laptop to the Orbic&#039;s wifi network and visit `http://192.168.1.1:8080` (click past your browser warning you about the connection not being secure, Rayhunter doesn&#039;t have HTTPS yet!).
    * Note that you&#039;ll need the Orbic&#039;s wifi password for this, which can be retrieved by pressing the &quot;MENU&quot; button on the device and opening the 2.4 GHz menu.
2. Over usb: Connect the Orbic device to your laptop via usb. Run `adb forward tcp:8080 tcp:8080`, then visit `http://localhost:8080`. For this you will need to install the Android Debug Bridge (ADB) on your computer, you can copy the version that was downloaded inside the releases/platform-tools/` folder to somewhere else in your path or you can install it manually.  You can find instructions for doing so on your platform [here](https://www.xda-developers.com/install-adb-windows-macos-linux/#how-to-set-up-adb-on-your-computer), (don&#039;t worry about instructions for installing it on a phone/device yet).

## Frequently Asked Questions

### Do I need an active SIM card to use Rayhunter?
**It Depends**. Operation of Rayhunter does require the insertion of a SIM card into the device, but whether that SIM card has to be currently active for our tests to work is still under investigation. If you want to use the device as a hotspot in addition to a research device an active plan would of course be necessary, however we have not done enough testing yet to know whether an active subscription is required for detection. If you want to test the device with an inactive SIM card, we would certainly be interested in seeing any data you collect, and especially any runs that trigger an alert!
### Help, Rayhunter&#039;s line is red! What should I do?
Unfortunately, the circumstances that might lead to a positive CSS signal are quite varied, so we don&#039;t have a universal recommendation for how to deal with the a positive signal. Depending on your circumstances and threat model, you may want to turn off your phone until you are out of the area (or put it on airplane mode) and tell your friends to do the same!

If you&#039;ve received a Rayhunter warning and would like to help us with our research, please send your Rayhunter data captures (QMDL and PCAP logs) to us at our [Signal](https://signal.org/) username [**ElectronicFrontierFoundation.90**](https://signal.me/#eu/HZbPPED5LyMkbTxJsG2PtWc2TXxPUR1OxBMcJGLOPeeCDGPuaTpOi5cfGRY6RrGf) with the following information: capture date, capture location, device, device model, and Rayhunter version. If you&#039;re unfamiliar with Signal, feel free to check out our [Security Self Defense guide on it](https://ssd.eff.org/module/how-to-use-signal).
 
Please note that this file may contain sensitive information such as your IMSI and the unique IDs of cell towers you were near which could be used to ascertain your location at the time.

### Does Rayhunter work outside of the US?
**Probably**. Some Rayhunter users have reported successfully using it in other countries with unlocked devices and SIM cards from local telcos. We can&#039;t guarantee whether or not it will work for you though.
### Should I get a locked or unlocked orbic device? What is the difference?
If you want to use a non verizon SIM card you will probably need an unlocked device. But it&#039;s not clear how locked the locked devices are nor how to unlock them, we welcome any experimentation and information regarding the use of unlocked devices.
### Does Rayhunter work on any other devices besides the Orbic RC400L?
**Maybe**. We have not tested Rayhunter on any other hardware but we would love to expand the supported platforms. We will consider giving official support to any hardware platform that can be bought for around $20-30USD. The Rayhunter daemon should theoretically work on any linux/android device that has a qualcomm chip with a /dev/diag interface and root access, though our installer script has only been tested with an Orbic. If you get it working on another device, please let us know!
### How do I delete capture files from the Rayhunter device?
You can get a shell on the device by inputting `adb shell` to a terminal with the device connected, you can check if it is detected with `adb devices`.
The capture files are located at */data/rayhunter/qmdl* but you will need root access to modify or delete them. From the adb shell run `/bin/rootshell` and you can now use commands like &#039;rm&#039; as root to modify and delete entries in the */data/rayhunter/qmdl* directory. **Be careful not to delete important files in other directories as you may seriously damage the device**.

## Development
* Install ADB on your computer using the instructions above, and make sure it&#039;s in your terminal&#039;s PATH
  * You can verify if ADB is in your PATH by running `which adb` in a terminal. If it prints the filepath to where ADB is installed, you&#039;re set! Otherwise, try following one of these guides:
    * [linux](https://askubuntu.com/questions/652936/adding-android-sdk-platform-tools-to-path-downloaded-from-umake)
    * [macOS](https://www.repeato.app/setting-up-adb-on-macos-a-step-by-step-guide/)
    * [Windows](https://medium.com/@yadav-ajay/a-step-by-step-guide-to-setting-up-adb-path-on-windows-0b833faebf18)

### If you&#039;re on x86 linux
Install rust the usual way and then install cross compiling dependences:
```
sudo apt install curl build-essential libc6-armhf-cross libc6-dev-armhf-cross gcc-arm-linux-gnueabihf
rustup target add x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu
rustup target add armv7-unknown-linux-gnueabihf
```

Now you can root your device and install Rayhunter by running `./tools/install-dev.sh`

### If you&#039;re on windows or can&#039;t run the install scripts
* Root your device on windows using the instructions here: https://xdaforums.com/t/resetting-verizon-orbic-speed-rc400l-firmware-flash-kajeet.4334899/#post-87855183

* Build for arm using `cargo build`

* Run tests using `cargo test_pc`

* Push the scripts in `scripts/` to `/etc/init.d` on device and make a directory called `/data/rayhunter` using `adb shell` (and sshell for your root shell if you followed the steps above)

* you also need to copy `config.toml.example` to `/data/rayhunter/config.toml`

* Then run `./make.sh` this will build the binary and push it over adb. Restart your device or run `/etc/init.d/rayhunter_daemon start` on the device and you are good to go.

* Write your code and write tests

* Build for arm using `cargo build`

* Run tests using `cargo test_pc`

* push to the device with `./make.sh`

## Support and Discussion

If you&#039;re having issues installing or using Rayhunter, please open an issue in this repo. Join us in the `#rayhunter` channel of [EFF&#039;s Mattermost](https://opensource.eff.org/signup_user_complete/?id=6iqur37ucfrctfswrs14iscobw&amp;md=link&amp;sbr=su) instance to chat!

## Documentation
* Build docs locally using `RUSTDOCFLAGS=&quot;--cfg docsrs&quot; cargo doc --no-deps --all-features  --open`

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER:** Use this program at your own risk. We believe running this program does not currently violate any laws or regulations in the United States. However, we are not responsible for civil or criminal liability resulting from the use of this software. If you are located outside of the US please consult with an attorney in your country to help you assess the legal risks of running this program.

*Good Hunting!*
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[juspay/hyperswitch]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch">juspay/hyperswitch</a></h1>
            <p>An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,216</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,544</p>
            <p>Stars today: 639 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-dark.svg#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-light.svg#gh-light-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Open-Source Payments Orchestration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; &gt;
Single API to access the payments ecosystem and its features
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/actions?query=workflow%3ACI+branch%3Amain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/workflows/CI-push/badge.svg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Made_in-Rust-orange&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- Uncomment when we reach &gt;50% coverage --&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch/graph/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/hyperswitch/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-hyperswitch-blue?logo=linkedin&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/hyperswitchio&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-%40hyperswitchio-white?logo=x&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on_slack-blue?logo=slack&amp;labelColor=grey&amp;color=%233f0e40&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

## Table of Contents

1. [Introduction](#introduction)
2. [Architectural Overview](#architectural-overview) 
3. [Try Hyperswitch](#try-hyperswitch)  
4. [Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs](#support-feature-requests)  
5. [Our Vision](#our-vision)  
6. [Versioning](#versioning)  
7. [Copyright and License](#copyright-and-license)

&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
Juspay, founded in 2012, is a global leader in payment orchestration and checkout solutions, trusted by 400+ leading enterprises and brands worldwide. Hyperswitch is Juspay&#039;s new generation of composable, commercial open-source payments platform for merchant and brands. It is an enterprise-grade, transparent and modular payments platform designed to provide digital businesses access to the best payments infrastructure.

Here are the key components of Hyperswitch that deliver the whole solution:

* [Hyperswitch Backend](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch): Hyperswitch backend enables seamless payment processing with comprehensive support for various payment flows - authorization, authentication, void and capture workflows along with robust management of post-payment processes like refunds and chargeback handling. Additionally, Hyperswitch supports non-payment use cases by enabling connections with external FRM or authentication providers as part of the payment flow. The backend optimizes payment routing with customizable workflows, including success rate-based routing, rule-based routing, volume distribution, fallback handling, and intelligent retry mechanisms for failed payments based on specific error codes.

* [SDK (Frontend)](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-web): The SDK, available for web, [Android, and iOS](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-client-core), unifies the payment experience across various methods such as cards, wallets, BNPL, bank transfers, and more, while supporting the diverse payment flows of underlying PSPs. When paired with the locker, it surfaces the user&#039;s saved payment methods.    

* [Control Center](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-control-center): The Control Center enables users to manage the entire payments stack without any coding. It allows the creation of workflows for routing, payment retries, and defining conditions to invoke 3DS, fraud risk management (FRM), and surcharge modules. The Control Center provides access to transaction, refund, and chargeback operations across all integrated PSPs, transaction-level logs for initial debugging, and detailed analytics and insights into payment performance.

Read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/).

&lt;a href=&quot;#architectural-overview&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;architectural-overview&quot;&gt;Architectural Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/features.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/non-functional-features.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-architecture-v1.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;#try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Try Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### 1. Local Setup

You can run Hyperswitch on your system using Docker compose after cloning this repository. 

```shell
git clone --depth 1 --branch latest https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch
cd hyperswitch
docker compose up -d
```

Check out the [local setup guide][local-setup-guide] for a more details on setting up the entire stack or component wise. This takes 15-mins and gives the following output 
```shell
[+] Running 2/2
✔ hyperswitch-control-center Pulled 2.9s
✔ hyperswitch-server Pulled 3.0s
[+] Running 6/0

✔ Container hyperswitch-pg-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-redis-standalone-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-migration_runner-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-server-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-web-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-control-center-1 Created 0.0s

Attaching to hyperswitch-control-center-1, hyperswitch-server-1, hyperswitch-web-1, migration_runner-1, pg-1, redis-standalone-1
```

### 2. Deployment on cloud

The fastest and easiest way to try Hyperswitch on AWS is via our CDK scripts

1. Click on the following button for a quick standalone deployment on AWS, suitable for prototyping.
   No code or setup is required in your system and the deployment is covered within the AWS free-tier setup.

   &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home?region=us-east-1#/stacks/new?stackName=HyperswitchBootstarp&amp;templateURL=https://hyperswitch-synth.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/hs-starter-config.yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/docs/imgs/aws_button.png?raw=true&quot; height=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

2. Sign-in to your AWS console.

3. Follow the instructions provided on the console to successfully deploy Hyperswitch. This takes 30-45mins and gives the following output 

| Service| Host|
|----------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------|
| App server running on                        | `http://hyperswitch-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| HyperloaderJS Hosted at                      | `http://&lt;cloudfront.host-id&gt;/0.103.1/v0/HyperLoader.js` |
| Control center server running on             | `http://hyperswitch-control-center-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with Email: `test@gmail.com` |
| Hyperswitch Demo Store running on            | `http://hyperswitch-sdk-demo-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| Logs server running on                       | `http://hyperswitch-logs-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with username: `admin`, password: `admin` |

We support deployment on GCP and Azure via Helm charts which takes 30-45mins. You can read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/deploy-on-kubernetes-using-helm). 

### 3. Hosted Sandbox

You can experience the product by signing up for our [hosted sandbox](https://app.hyperswitch.io/). The signup process accepts any email ID and provides access to the entire Control Center. You can set up connectors, define workflows for routing and retries, and even try payments from the dashboard.

[docs-link-for-enterprise]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-cloud/quickstart
[docs-link-for-developers]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/overview
[contributing-guidelines]: docs/CONTRIBUTING.md
[dashboard-link]: https://app.hyperswitch.io/
[website-link]: https://hyperswitch.io/
[learning-resources]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/learn-more/payment-flows
[local-setup-guide]: /docs/try_local_system.md
[docker-compose-scheduler-monitoring]: /docs/try_local_system.md#running-additional-services


&lt;a href=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

For any support, join the conversation in [Slack](https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw)

For new product features, enhancements, roadmap discussions, or to share queries and ideas, visit our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/discussions)

For reporting a bug, please read the issue guidelines and search for [existing and closed issues]. If your problem or idea is not addressed yet, please [open a new issue].

[existing and closed issues]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues
[open a new issue]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues/new/choose

&lt;a href=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;Our Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&gt; Linux for Payments

Payments are evolving rapidly worldwide, with hundreds of processors, fraud detection systems, authentication modules, and new payment methods and flows emerging. Businesses building or managing their own payment stacks often face similar challenges, struggle with comparable issues, and find it hard to innovate at the desired pace.

Hyperswitch serves as a well-architected designed reference platform, built on best-in-class design principles, empowering businesses to own and customize their payment stack. It provides a reusable core payments stack that can be tailored to specific requirements while relying on the Hyperswitch team for enhancements, support, and continuous innovation.

### Our Values

1. Embrace Payments Diversity: It will drive innovation in the ecosystem in
   multiple ways.
2. Make it Open Source: Increases trust; Improves the quality and reusability of
   software.
3. Be community driven: It enables participatory design and development.
4. Build it like Systems Software: This sets a high bar for Reliability,
   Security and Performance SLAs.
5. Maximise Value Creation: For developers, customers &amp; partners.

This project is being created and maintained by [Juspay](https://juspay.io)

&lt;a href=&quot;#versioning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;versioning&quot;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Check the [CHANGELOG.md](./CHANGELOG.md) file for details.

&lt;a href=&quot;#copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;Copyright and License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

This product is licensed under the [Apache 2.0 License](LICENSE).


&lt;a href=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Team behind Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

The core team of 150+ engineers building Hyperswitch. Keep up the great work! 🥂

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=juspay/hyperswitch&quot; alt=&quot;Contributors&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[unionlabs/union]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/unionlabs/union</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/unionlabs/union</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The trust-minimized, zero-knowledge bridging protocol, designed for censorship resistance, extremely high security, and usage in decentralized finance.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/unionlabs/union">unionlabs/union</a></h1>
            <p>The trust-minimized, zero-knowledge bridging protocol, designed for censorship resistance, extremely high security, and usage in decentralized finance.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 50,151</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,527</p>
            <p>Stars today: 321 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;./.github/images/union-logo-white.svg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;./.github/images/union-logo-black.svg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Union&quot;
         src=&quot;./.github/images/union-logo-black.svg&quot;
         width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![built with garnix](https://img.shields.io/endpoint.svg?url=https%3A%2F%2Fgarnix.io%2Fapi%2Fbadges%2Funionlabs%2Funion%3Fbranch%3Dmain)](https://garnix.io)
[![Docs](https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-main-blue)][docs]
[![Discord badge]](https://discord.union.build)
[![Twitter handle]][twitter badge]

&lt;/div&gt;

Union is the hyper-efficient zero-knowledge infrastructure layer for general message passing, asset transfers, NFTs, and DeFi. It’s based on [Consensus Verification] and has no dependencies on trusted third parties, oracles, multi-signatures, or MPC. It implements [IBC] for compatibility with [Cosmos] chains and connects to EVM chains like [Ethereum], [Berachain (beacon-kit)](https://github.com/berachain/beacon-kit), [Arbitrum], and more.

The upgradability of contracts on other chains, connections, token configurations, and evolution of the protocol will all be controlled by decentralized governance, aligning the priorities of Union with its users, validators, and operators.

## Components

| Component                                             | Description                                          | Language(s)           |
| ----------------------------------------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------- | --------------------- |
| [`uniond`](./uniond/README.md)                        | The Union node implementation, using [`CometBLS`]    | [Go]                  |
| [`galoisd`](./galoisd)                                | The zero-knowledge prover implementation             | [Go] [Gnark]          |
| [`voyager`](./voyager)                                | Modular hyper-performant cross-ecosystem relayer     | [Rust]                |
| [`hubble`](./hubble)                                  | Multi-ecosystem, GMP-enabled chain indexer           | [Rust]                |
| [`cosmwasm`](./cosmwasm)                              | [CosmWasm] smart contract stack                      | [Rust]                |
| [`light-clients`](./cosmwasm/ibc-union/lightclient)   | [Light Clients] for various ecosystems               | [Rust]                |
| [`unionvisor`](./unionvisor/README.md)                | Node supervisor intended for production usage        | [Rust]                |
| [`drip`](./drip)                                      | Faucet for [Cosmos] chains: [app.union.build/faucet] | [Rust]                |
| [`evm`](./evm)                                        | [EVM] smart contract stack                           | [Solidity]            |
| [`app`](./app)                                        | [app.union.build]                                    | [TypeScript] [Svelte] |
| [`site`](./site)                                      | [union.build]                                        | [TypeScript] [Astro]  |
| [`TypeScript SDK`](./typescript-sdk)                  | TypeScript SDK for interacting with Union            | [TypeScript]          |

## Quickstart

Install [Nix] to _[reproducibly build](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reproducible_builds) any component_, and to enter a dev shell with _all dependencies_:

```sh
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf -L https://install.determinate.systems/nix | sh -s -- install
```

_(Note that some components can only be built on Linux. If you are using macOS, we recommend using [OrbStack] to easily set up a [NixOS] VM within two minutes. Most Union developers use macOS with [OrbStack], and there is no need to install Nix inside of the [NixOS] VM.)_

You can now _reproducibly_ build any of Union&#039;s components from source:

```sh
nix build .#uniond -L
nix build .#voyager -L
nix build .#app -L

# to see all packages, run:
nix flake show
```

The result of whatever you build will be in `result/`

You can now also enter our dev shell, which has all of the dependencies (`cargo`, `rustc`, `node`, `go`, etc.) you need to work on any component:
_(Don&#039;t worry, this will not affect your system outside of this repo)_

```sh
nix develop
```

Run the following to format the entire repo and check your spelling before each PR:

```sh
nix run .#pre-commit -L
```

Check the `#developers` channel on [Union&#039;s discord](https://discord.union.build) if you need any help with this.

## Docs

The official docs are hosted [here][docs]. Each individual component also has accompanying developer documentation for contributors, which you can find in each `README.md`.

[app.union.build]: https://app.union.build
[app.union.build/faucet]: https://app.union.build/faucet
[arbitrum]: https://github.com/OffchainLabs/arbitrum
[astro]: https://astro.build
[consensus verification]: https://union.build/docs/concepts/consensus-verification/
[cosmos]: https://cosmos.network
[cosmwasm]: https://cosmwasm.com/
[discord badge]: https://img.shields.io/discord/1158939416870522930?logo=discord
[docs]: https://docs.union.build &quot;Official Union Docs&quot;
[ethereum]: https://ethereum.org
[evm]: https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/evm/
[gnark]: https://github.com/ConsenSys/gnark
[go]: https://go.dev/
[ibc]: https://github.com/cosmos/ibc &quot;cosmos/ibc&quot;
[light clients]: https://a16zcrypto.com/posts/article/an-introduction-to-light-clients/
[nix]: https://zero-to-nix.com/
[nixos]: https://nixos.org
[orbstack]: https://orbstack.dev/
[rust]: https://www.rust-lang.org/
[solidity]: https://soliditylang.org/
[svelte]: https://svelte.dev
[twitter badge]: https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=union_build
[twitter handle]: https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/union_build.svg?style=social&amp;label=Follow
[typescript]: https://www.typescriptlang.org/
[union.build]: https://union.build
[`cometbls`]: https://github.com/unionlabs/cometbls
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[aws/amazon-q-developer-cli]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[✨ Add autocomplete and AI to your existing terminal on macOS & Linux]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli">aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</a></h1>
            <p>✨ Add autocomplete and AI to your existing terminal on macOS & Linux</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 223</p>
            <p>Forks: 43</p>
            <p>Stars today: 16 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./.github/media/amazon-q-logo.avif&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Q&quot;
        width=&quot;200px&quot;
      &gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Amazon Q CLI brings IDE-style autocomplete and agentic capabilities to your terminal.
&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/graphs/commit-activity&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub commit activity&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/issues&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub open issues&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Rust Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/rust.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/rust.yml)
[![Typos Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typos.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typos.yml)
[![Typescript Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typescript.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typescript.yml)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./.github/media/amazon-q-cli-features.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Q CLI Features&quot;
      &gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 😍 Features
-   🔮 [**Auto Completion**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete.html): IDE-style completions to hundreds of popular CLIs like `git`, `npm`, `docker`, and `aws`.
-   💬 [**Natural Language Chat**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-chat.html): Interact with your terminal using natural language to ask questions, debug issues, or explore the codebase.
-   🧠 [**Contextual Awareness**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-chat.html#command-line-chat-context-integration): Integrates context from your local development environment, so answers are tailored to your specific code and setup.
-   🤖 [**Agentic Execution**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete.html): Let Amazon Q take action: generate code, edit files, automate Git workflows, resolve merge conflicts, and more — with your permission.

## ⚡️ Installation

- **macOS**:
  - **DMG**: Download from AWS:
    [aws.amazon.com](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-getting-started-installing.html)
  - **Homebrew**: `brew install amazon-q`
- **Linux**:
  - [Ubuntu/Debian](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-ubuntu)
  - [AppImage](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-appimage)
  - [Alternative Linux builds](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-alternative-linux)
- **Windows**:
  - Follow the discussions for
    [Windows](https://github.com/aws/q-command-line-discussions/discussions/15)
  - Or [use it on Window with WSL](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-windows)
- **Remote machines**
  - [Autocomplete in SSH](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete-ssh.html)


## 🚀 Start Contributing

### Prerequisites

- MacOS
  - Xcode 13 or later
  - Brew

### 1. Clone repo

```shell
git clone https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-for-command-line.git
```

### 2. Setup
Hassle-free setup:
```shell
npm run setup
```

Or if you&#039;d like to DIY:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Manual Setup&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

### 1. Install platform dependencies

For Debian/Ubuntu:

```shell
sudo apt update
sudo apt install build-essential pkg-config jq dpkg curl wget cmake clang libssl-dev libgtk-3-dev libayatana-appindicator3-dev librsvg2-dev libdbus-1-dev libwebkit2gtk-4.1-dev libjavascriptcoregtk-4.1-dev valac libibus-1.0-dev libglib2.0-dev sqlite3 libxdo-dev protobuf-compiler
```
### 2. Install Rust toolchain using [Rustup](https://rustup.rs):

```shell
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh
rustup default stable
```

For pre-commit hooks, the following commands are required:

```shell
rustup toolchain install nightly
cargo install typos-cli
```

For MacOS development make sure the right targets are installed:

```shell
rustup target add x86_64-apple-darwin
rustup target add aarch64-apple-darwin
```

### 3. Setup Python and Node using [`mise`](https://mise.jdx.dev)

Add mise integrations to your shell:

For zsh:
```shell
echo &#039;eval &quot;$(mise activate zsh)&quot;&#039; &gt;&gt; &quot;${ZDOTDIR-$HOME}/.zshrc&quot;
```

For bash:
```shell
echo &#039;eval &quot;$(mise activate bash)&quot;&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc
```

For fish:
```shell
echo &#039;mise activate fish | source&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.config/fish/config.fish
```

Install the Python and Node toolchains using:

```shell
mise trust
mise install
```

### 4. Setup precommit hooks

Run `pnpm` in root directory to add pre-commit hooks:

```shell
pnpm install --ignore-scripts
```

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;


### 3. Start Local Development
To compile and view changes made to `q chat`:
```shell
alias run_q_chat=&#039;cargo run --bin q_cli -- chat&#039;
run_q_chat
```

&gt; If you are working on other q commands, just replace `chat` with the command name 



### 💡 Quick Tip for Onboarding

Use Q CLI to help you onboard Q CLI! 

Start a `q chat` session:

```shell
q chat
```

Once inside `q chat`, you can supply project context by adding the [`codebase-summary.md`](codebase-summary.md) file:

```shell
/context add codebase-summary.md
```

This enables Q to answer onboarding questions like:

- “What does this crate do?”

- “Where is X implemented?”

- “How do these components interact?”

Great for speeding up your ramp-up and navigating the repo more effectively.




## 🏗️ Project Layout

Several projects live here:

- [`autocomplete`](packages/autocomplete/) - The autocomplete react app
- [`dashboard`](packages/dashboard/) - The dashboard react app
- [`figterm`](crates/figterm/) - figterm, our headless terminal/pseudoterminal that
  intercepts the user’s terminal edit buffer.
- [`q_cli`](crates/q_cli/) - the `q` CLI, allows users to interface with Amazon Q Developer from
  the command line
- [`fig_desktop`](crates/fig_desktop/) - the Rust desktop app, uses
  [`tao`](https://docs.rs/tao/latest/tao/)/[`wry`](https://docs.rs/wry/latest/wry/)
  for windowing/webviews
- [`fig_input_method`](crates/fig_input_method/) - The input method used to get cursor
  position on macOS
- [`vscode`](extensions/vscode/) - Contains the VSCode plugin needed
  for the Amazon Q Developer for command line to work in VSCode
- [`jetbrains`](extensions/jetbrains/) - Contains the VSCode plugin
  needed for the Amazon Q Developer for command line to work in Jetbrains IDEs

Other folder to be aware of

- [`build-scripts/`](build-scripts/) - Contains all python scripts to build,
  sign, and test the project on macOS and Linux
- [`crates/`](crates/) - Contains all internal rust crates
- [`packages/`](packages/) - Contains all internal npm packages
- [`proto/`](proto/) -
  [protocol buffer](https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/) message
  specification for inter-process communication
- [`tests/`](tests/) - Contain integration tests for the projects

Below is a high level architecture of how the different components of the app and
their IPC:

![architecture](docs/assets/architecture.svg)




## 🛡️ Security

See [CONTRIBUTING](CONTRIBUTING.md#security-issue-notifications) for more information.

## 📜 Licensing

This repo is dual licensed under MIT and Apache 2.0 licenses.

“Amazon Web Services” and all related marks, including logos, graphic designs, and service names, are trademarks or trade dress of AWS in the U.S. and other countries. AWS’s trademarks and trade dress may not be used in connection with any product or service that is not AWS’s, in any manner that is likely to cause confusion among customers, or in any manner that disparages or discredits AWS.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[medialab/xan]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/medialab/xan</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/medialab/xan</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The CSV magician]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/medialab/xan">medialab/xan</a></h1>
            <p>The CSV magician</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 827</p>
            <p>Forks: 21</p>
            <p>Stars today: 124 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Build Status](https://github.com/medialab/xan/workflows/Tests/badge.svg)](https://github.com/medialab/xan/actions)

# `xan`, the CSV magician

`xan` is a command line tool that can be used to process CSV files directly from the shell.

It has been written in Rust to be as fast as possible, use as little memory as possible, and can easily handle very large CSV files (Gigabytes). It is also able to leverage parallelism (through multithreading) to make some tasks complete as fast as your computer can allow.

It can easily preview, filter, slice, aggregate, sort, join CSV files, and exposes a large collection of composable commands that can be chained together to perform a wide variety of typical tasks.

`xan` also leverages its own expression language so you can perform complex tasks that cannot be done by relying on the simplest commands. This minimalistic language has been tailored for CSV data and is faster than evaluating typical dynamically-typed languages such as Python, Lua, JavaScript etc.

Note that this tool is originally a fork of [BurntSushi](https://github.com/BurntSushi)&#039;s [`xsv`](https://github.com/BurntSushi/xsv), but has been nearly entirely rewritten at that point, to fit [SciencesPo&#039;s médialab](https://github.com/medialab) use-cases, rooted in web data collection and analysis geared towards social sciences (you might think CSV is outdated by now, but read our [love letter](./docs/LOVE_LETTER.md) to the format before judging too quickly). `xan` therefore goes beyond typical data manipulation and expose utilities related to lexicometry, graph theory and even scraping.

Finally, `xan` can be used to display CSV files in the terminal, for easy exploration, and can even be used to draw basic data visualisations:

|*view command*|*flatten command*|
|:---:|:---:|
|![view](./docs/img/grid/view.png)|![flatten](./docs/img/grid/flatten.png)|
|__*categorical histogram*__|__*scatterplot*__|
|![categ-hist](./docs/img/grid/categ-hist.png)|![correlation](./docs/img/grid/correlation.png)|
|__*categorical scatterplot*__|__*histograms*__|
|![scatter](./docs/img/grid/scatter.png)|![hist](./docs/img/grid/hist.png)|
|__*parallel processing*__|__*time series*__|
|![parallel](./docs/img/grid/parallel.png)|![series](./docs/img/grid/series.png)|
|__*small multiples (facet grid)*__|__*grouped view*__|
|![small-multiples](./docs/img/grid/small-multiples.png)|![view-grid](./docs/img/grid/view-grid.png)|
|__*correlation matrix heatmap*__|__*heatmap*__|
|![small-multiples](./docs/img/grid/corr-heatmap.png)|![view-grid](./docs/img/grid/heatmap.png)|

## Summary

* [How to install](#how-to-install)
  * [Cargo](#cargo)
  * [Homebrew (macOS)](#homebrew-macos)
  * [Arch Linux](#arch-linux)
  * [Nix](#nix)
  * [Pre-built binaries](#pre-built-binaries)
  * [Installing completions](#installing-completions)
* [Quick tour](#quick-tour)
* [Available commands](#available-commands)
* [General flags and IO model](#general-flags-and-io-model)
* [Expression language reference](#expression-language-reference)
* [Cookbook](#cookbook)
* [News](#news)
* [Frequently Asked Questions](#frequently-asked-questions)

## How to install

### Cargo

`xan` can be installed using cargo (it usually comes with [Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install)):

```bash
cargo install xan
```

You can also tweak the build flags to make sure the Rust compiler is able to leverage all your CPU&#039;s features:

```bash
CARGO_BUILD_RUSTFLAGS=&#039;-C target-cpu=native&#039; cargo install xan
```

You can also install the latest dev version thusly:

```bash
cargo install --git https://github.com/medialab/xan
```

### Homebrew (macOS)

`xan` can be installed with [Homebrew](https://brew.sh/) on macOS thusly:

```bash
brew install xan
```

### Arch Linux

You can install `xan` from the [extra repository](https://archlinux.org/packages/extra/x86_64/xan/) using `pacman`:

```bash
sudo pacman -S xan
```

### Nix

`xan` is packaged for Nix, and is available in Nixpkgs as of 25.05 release. To
install it, you may add it to your `environment.systemPackages` as `pkgs.xan` or
use `nix-shell` to enter an ephemeral shell.

```bash
nix-shell -p xan
```

### Pre-built binaries

Pre-built binaries can be found attached to every GitHub [releases](https://github.com/medialab/xan/releases/latest).

Currently supported targets include:

- `x86_64-unknown-linux-musl`
- `x86_64-pc-windows-gnu`

Feel free to open a PR to improve the CI by adding relevant targets.

### Installing completions

Note that `xan` also exposes handy automatic completions for command and header/column names that you can install through the `xan completions` command.

Run the following command to understand how to install those completions:

```bash
xan completions -h
```

## Quick tour

Let&#039;s learn about the most commonly used `xan` commands by exploring a corpus of French medias:

### Downloading the corpus

```bash
curl -LO https://github.com/medialab/corpora/raw/master/polarisation/medias.csv
```

### Displaying the file&#039;s headers

```bash
xan headers medias.csv
```

```
0   webentity_id
1   name
2   prefixes
3   home_page
4   start_pages
5   indegree
6   hyphe_creation_timestamp
7   hyphe_last_modification_timestamp
8   outreach
9   foundation_year
10  batch
11  edito
12  parody
13  origin
14  digital_native
15  mediacloud_ids
16  wheel_category
17  wheel_subcategory
18  has_paywall
19  inactive
```

### Counting the number of rows

```bash
xan count medias.csv
```

```
478
```

### Previewing the file in the terminal

```bash
xan view medias.csv
```

```
Displaying 5/20 cols from 10 first rows of medias.csv
┌───┬───────────────┬───────────────┬────────────┬───┬─────────────┬──────────┐
│ - │ name          │ prefixes      │ home_page  │ … │ has_paywall │ inactive │
├───┼───────────────┼───────────────┼────────────┼───┼─────────────┼──────────┤
│ 0 │ Acrimed.org   │ http://acrim… │ http://ww… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 1 │ 24matins.fr   │ http://24mat… │ https://w… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 2 │ Actumag.info  │ http://actum… │ https://a… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 3 │ 2012un-Nouve… │ http://2012u… │ http://ww… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 4 │ 24heuresactu… │ http://24heu… │ http://24… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 5 │ AgoraVox      │ http://agora… │ http://ww… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 6 │ Al-Kanz.org   │ http://al-ka… │ https://w… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 7 │ Alalumieredu… │ http://alalu… │ http://al… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 8 │ Allodocteurs… │ http://allod… │ https://w… │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 9 │ Alterinfo.net │ http://alter… │ http://ww… │ … │ &lt;empty&gt;     │ true     │
│ … │ …             │ …             │ …          │ … │ …           │ …        │
└───┴───────────────┴───────────────┴────────────┴───┴─────────────┴──────────┘
```

On unix, don&#039;t hesitate to use the `-p` flag to automagically forward the full output to an appropriate pager and skim through all the columns.

### Reading a flattened representation of the first row

```bash
# NOTE: drop -c to avoid truncating the values
xan flatten -c medias.csv
```

```
Row n°0
───────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────
webentity_id                      1
name                              Acrimed.org
prefixes                          http://acrimed.org|http://acrimed69.blogspot…
home_page                         http://www.acrimed.org
start_pages                       http://acrimed.org|http://acrimed69.blogspot…
indegree                          61
hyphe_creation_timestamp          1560347020330
hyphe_last_modification_timestamp 1560526005389
outreach                          nationale
foundation_year                   2002
batch                             1
edito                             media
parody                            false
origin                            france
digital_native                    true
mediacloud_ids                    258269
wheel_category                    Opinion Journalism
wheel_subcategory                 Left Wing
has_paywall                       false
inactive                          &lt;empty&gt;

Row n°1
───────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────
webentity_id                      2
...
```

### Searching for rows

```bash
xan search -s outreach internationale medias.csv | xan view
```

```
Displaying 4/20 cols from 10 first rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌───┬──────────────┬────────────────────┬───┬─────────────┬──────────┐
│ - │ webentity_id │ name               │ … │ has_paywall │ inactive │
├───┼──────────────┼────────────────────┼───┼─────────────┼──────────┤
│ 0 │ 25           │ Businessinsider.fr │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 1 │ 59           │ Europe-Israel.org  │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 2 │ 66           │ France 24          │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 3 │ 220          │ RFI                │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 4 │ 231          │ fr.Sott.net        │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 5 │ 246          │ Voltairenet.org    │ … │ true        │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 6 │ 254          │ Afp.com /fr        │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 7 │ 265          │ Euronews FR        │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 8 │ 333          │ Arte.tv            │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ 9 │ 341          │ I24News.tv         │ … │ false       │ &lt;empty&gt;  │
│ … │ …            │ …                  │ … │ …           │ …        │
└───┴──────────────┴────────────────────┴───┴─────────────┴──────────┘
```

### Selecting some columns

```bash
xan select foundation_year,name medias.csv | xan view
```

```
Displaying 2 cols from 10 first rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌───┬─────────────────┬───────────────────────────────────────┐
│ - │ foundation_year │ name                                  │
├───┼─────────────────┼───────────────────────────────────────┤
│ 0 │ 2002            │ Acrimed.org                           │
│ 1 │ 2006            │ 24matins.fr                           │
│ 2 │ 2013            │ Actumag.info                          │
│ 3 │ 2012            │ 2012un-Nouveau-Paradigme.com          │
│ 4 │ 2010            │ 24heuresactu.com                      │
│ 5 │ 2005            │ AgoraVox                              │
│ 6 │ 2008            │ Al-Kanz.org                           │
│ 7 │ 2012            │ Alalumieredunouveaumonde.blogspot.com │
│ 8 │ 2005            │ Allodocteurs.fr                       │
│ 9 │ 2005            │ Alterinfo.net                         │
│ … │ …               │ …                                     │
└───┴─────────────────┴───────────────────────────────────────┘
```

### Sorting the file

```bash
xan sort -s foundation_year medias.csv | xan view -s name,foundation_year
```

```
Displaying 2 cols from 10 first rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌───┬────────────────────────────────────┬─────────────────┐
│ - │ name                               │ foundation_year │
├───┼────────────────────────────────────┼─────────────────┤
│ 0 │ Le Monde Numérique (Ouest France)  │ &lt;empty&gt;         │
│ 1 │ Le Figaro                          │ 1826            │
│ 2 │ Le journal de Saône-et-Loire       │ 1826            │
│ 3 │ L&#039;Indépendant                      │ 1846            │
│ 4 │ Le Progrès                         │ 1859            │
│ 5 │ La Dépêche du Midi                 │ 1870            │
│ 6 │ Le Pélerin                         │ 1873            │
│ 7 │ Dernières Nouvelles d&#039;Alsace (DNA) │ 1877            │
│ 8 │ La Croix                           │ 1883            │
│ 9 │ Le Chasseur Francais               │ 1885            │
│ … │ …                                  │ …               │
└───┴────────────────────────────────────┴─────────────────┘
```

### Deduplicating the file on some column

```bash
# Some medias of our corpus have the same ids on mediacloud.org
xan dedup -s mediacloud_ids medias.csv | xan count &amp;&amp; xan count medias.csv
```

```
457
478
```

Deduplicating can also be done while sorting:

```bash
xan sort -s mediacloud_ids -u medias.csv
```

### Computing frequency tables

```bash
xan frequency -s edito medias.csv | xan view
```

```
Displaying 3 cols from 5 rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌───┬───────┬────────────┬───────┐
│ - │ field │ value      │ count │
├───┼───────┼────────────┼───────┤
│ 0 │ edito │ media      │ 423   │
│ 1 │ edito │ individu   │ 30    │
│ 2 │ edito │ plateforme │ 14    │
│ 3 │ edito │ agrégateur │ 10    │
│ 4 │ edito │ agence     │ 1     │
└───┴───────┴────────────┴───────┘
```

### Printing a histogram

```bash
xan frequency -s edito medias.csv | xan hist
```

```
Histogram for edito (bars: 5, sum: 478, max: 423):

media      |423  88.49%|━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━━|
individu   | 30   6.28%|━━━╸                                                  |
plateforme | 14   2.93%|━╸                                                    |
agrégateur | 10   2.09%|━╸                                                    |
agence     |  1   0.21%|╸                                                     |
```

### Computing descriptive statistics

```bash
xan stats -s indegree,edito medias.csv | xan transpose | xan view -I
```

```
Displaying 2 cols from 14 rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌─────────────┬───────────────────┬────────────┐
│ field       │ indegree          │ edito      │
├─────────────┼───────────────────┼────────────┤
│ count       │ 463               │ 478        │
│ count_empty │ 15                │ 0          │
│ type        │ int               │ string     │
│ types       │ int|empty         │ string     │
│ sum         │ 25987             │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ mean        │ 56.12742980561554 │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ variance    │ 4234.530197929737 │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ stddev      │ 65.07326792108829 │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ min         │ 0                 │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ max         │ 424               │ &lt;empty&gt;    │
│ lex_first   │ 0                 │ agence     │
│ lex_last    │ 99                │ plateforme │
│ min_length  │ 0                 │ 5          │
│ max_length  │ 3                 │ 11         │
└─────────────┴───────────────────┴────────────┘
```

### Evaluating an expression to filter a file

```bash
xan filter &#039;batch &gt; 1&#039; medias.csv | xan count
```

```
130
```

To access the expression language&#039;s [cheatsheet](./docs/moonblade/cheatsheet.md), run `xan help cheatsheet`. To display the full list of available [functions](./docs/moonblade/functions.md), run `xan help functions`.

### Evaluating an expression to create a new column based on other ones

```bash
xan map &#039;fmt(&quot;{} ({})&quot;, name, foundation_year)&#039; key medias.csv | xan select key | xan slice -l 10
```

```
key
Acrimed.org (2002)
24matins.fr (2006)
Actumag.info (2013)
2012un-Nouveau-Paradigme.com (2012)
24heuresactu.com (2010)
AgoraVox (2005)
Al-Kanz.org (2008)
Alalumieredunouveaumonde.blogspot.com (2012)
Allodocteurs.fr (2005)
Alterinfo.net (2005)
```

To access the expression language&#039;s [cheatsheet](./docs/moonblade/cheatsheet.md), run `xan help cheatsheet`. To display the full list of available [functions](./docs/moonblade/functions.md), run `xan help functions`.

### Transform a column by evaluating an expression

```bash
xan transform name &#039;split(name, &quot;.&quot;) | first | upper&#039; medias.csv | xan select name | xan slice -l 10
```

```
name
ACRIMED
24MATINS
ACTUMAG
2012UN-NOUVEAU-PARADIGME
24HEURESACTU
AGORAVOX
AL-KANZ
ALALUMIEREDUNOUVEAUMONDE
ALLODOCTEURS
ALTERINFO
```

To access the expression language&#039;s [cheatsheet](./docs/moonblade/cheatsheet.md), run `xan help cheatsheet`. To display the full list of available [functions](./docs/moonblade/functions.md), run `xan help functions`.

### Performing custom aggregation

```bash
xan agg &#039;sum(indegree) as total_indegree, mean(indegree) as mean_indegree&#039; medias.csv | xan view -I
```

```
Displaying 1 col from 1 rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌────────────────┬───────────────────┐
│ total_indegree │ mean_indegree     │
├────────────────┼───────────────────┤
│ 25987          │ 56.12742980561554 │
└────────────────┴───────────────────┘
```

To access the expression language&#039;s [cheatsheet](./docs/moonblade/cheatsheet.md), run `xan help cheatsheet`. To display the full list of available [functions](./docs/moonblade/functions.md), run `xan help functions`. Finally, to display the list of available [aggregation functions](./docs/moonblade/aggs.md), run `xan help aggs`.

### Grouping rows and performing per-group aggregation

```bash
xan groupby edito &#039;sum(indegree) as indegree&#039; medias.csv | xan view -I
```

```
Displaying 1 col from 5 rows of &lt;stdin&gt;
┌────────────┬──────────┐
│ edito      │ indegree │
├────────────┼──────────┤
│ agence     │ 50       │
│ agrégateur │ 459      │
│ plateforme │ 658      │
│ media      │ 24161    │
│ individu   │ 659      │
└────────────┴──────────┘
```

To access the expression language&#039;s [cheatsheet](./docs/moonblade/cheatsheet.md), run `xan help cheatsheet`. To display the full list of available [functions](./docs/moonblade/functions.md), run `xan help functions`. Finally, to display the list of available [aggregation functions](./docs/moonblade/aggs.md), run `xan help aggs`.

## Available commands

- [**help**](./docs/cmd/help.md): Get help regarding the expression language

*Explore &amp; visualize*

- [**count (c)**](./docs/cmd/count.md): Count rows in file
- [**headers (h)**](./docs/cmd/headers.md): Show header names
- [**view (v)**](./docs/cmd/view.md): Preview a CSV file in a human-friendly way
- [**flatten**](./docs/cmd/flatten.md): Display a flattened version of each row of a file
- [**hist**](./docs/cmd/hist.md): Print a histogram with rows of CSV file as bars
- [**plot**](./docs/cmd/plot.md): Draw a scatter plot or line chart
- [**heatmap**](./docs/cmd/heatmap.md): Draw a heatmap of a CSV matrix
- [**progress**](./docs/cmd/progress.md): Display a progress bar while reading CSV data

*Search &amp; filter*

- [**search**](./docs/cmd/search.md): Search for patterns in CSV data
- [**filter**](./docs/cmd/filter.md): Only keep some CSV rows based on an evaluated expression
- [**slice**](./docs/cmd/slice.md): Slice rows of CSV file
- [**top**](./docs/cmd/top.md): Find top rows of a CSV file according to some column
- [**sample**](./docs/cmd/sample.md): Randomly sample CSV data

*Sort &amp; deduplicate*

- [**sort**](./docs/cmd/sort.md): Sort CSV data
- [**dedup**](./docs/cmd/dedup.md): Deduplicate a CSV file
- [**shuffle**](./docs/cmd/shuffle.md): Shuffle CSV data

*Aggregate*

- [**frequency (freq)**](./docs/cmd/frequency.md): Show frequency tables
- [**groupby**](./docs/cmd/groupby.md): Aggregate data by groups of a CSV file
- [**stats**](./docs/cmd/stats.md): Compute basic statistics
- [**agg**](./docs/cmd/agg.md): Aggregate data from CSV file
- [**bins**](./docs/cmd/bins.md): Dispatch numeric columns into bins

*Combine multiple CSV files*

- [**cat**](./docs/cmd/cat.md): Concatenate by row or column
- [**join**](./docs/cmd/join.md): Join CSV files
- [**regex-join**](./docs/cmd/regex-join.md): Fuzzy join CSV files using regex patterns
- [**url-join**](./docs/cmd/url-join.md): Join CSV files on url prefixes
- [**merge**](./docs/cmd/merge.md): Merge multiple similar already sorted CSV files

*Add, transform, drop and move columns*

- [**select**](./docs/cmd/select.md): Select columns from a CSV file
- [**drop**](./docs/cmd/drop.md): Drop columns from a CSV file
- [**map**](./docs/cmd/map.md): Create a new column by evaluating an expression on each CSV row
- [**transform**](./docs/cmd/transform.md): Transform a column by evaluating an expression on each CSV row
- [**enum**](./docs/cmd/enum.md): Enumerate CSV file by preprending an index column
- [**flatmap**](./docs/cmd/flatmap.md): Emit one row per value yielded by an expression evaluated for each CSV row
- [**fill**](./docs/cmd/fill.md): Fill empty cells
- [**blank**](./docs/cmd/blank.md): Blank down contiguous identical cell values

*Format, convert &amp; recombobulate*

- [**behead**](./docs/cmd/behead.md): Drop header from CSV file
- [**rename**](./docs/cmd/rename.md): Rename columns of a CSV file
- [**input**](./docs/cmd/input.md): Read unus

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[signalapp/libsignal]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Home to the Signal Protocol as well as other cryptographic primitives which make Signal possible.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal">signalapp/libsignal</a></h1>
            <p>Home to the Signal Protocol as well as other cryptographic primitives which make Signal possible.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,145</p>
            <p>Forks: 489</p>
            <p>Stars today: 107 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Overview

libsignal contains platform-agnostic APIs used by the official Signal clients and servers, exposed
as a Java, Swift, or TypeScript library. The underlying implementations are written in Rust:

- libsignal-protocol: Implements the Signal protocol, including the [Double Ratchet algorithm][]. A
  replacement for [libsignal-protocol-java][] and [libsignal-metadata-java][].
- signal-crypto: Cryptographic primitives such as AES-GCM. We use [RustCrypto][]&#039;s where we can
  but sometimes have differing needs.
- device-transfer: Support logic for Signal&#039;s device-to-device transfer feature.
- attest: Functionality for remote attestation of [SGX enclaves][] and server-side [HSMs][].
- zkgroup: Functionality for [zero-knowledge groups][] and related features available in Signal.
- zkcredential: An abstraction for the sort of zero-knowledge credentials used by zkgroup, based on the paper &quot;[The Signal Private Group System][]&quot; by Chase, Perrin, and Zaverucha.
- poksho: Utilities for implementing zero-knowledge proofs (such as those used by zkgroup); stands for &quot;proof-of-knowledge, stateful-hash-object&quot;.
- account-keys: Functionality for consistently using [PINs][] as passwords in Signal&#039;s Secure Value Recovery system, as well as other account-wide key operations.
- usernames: Functionality for username generation, hashing, and proofs.
- media: Utilities for manipulating media.

This repository is used by the Signal client apps ([Android][], [iOS][], and [Desktop][]) as well as
server-side. Use outside of Signal is unsupported. In particular, the products of this repository
are the Java, Swift, and TypeScript libraries that wrap the underlying Rust implementations. All
APIs and implementations are subject to change without notice, as are the JNI, C, and Node add-on
&quot;bridge&quot; layers. However, backwards-incompatible changes to the Java, Swift, TypeScript, and
non-bridge Rust APIs will be reflected in the version number on a best-effort basis, including
increases to the minimum supported tools versions.

[Double Ratchet algorithm]: https://signal.org/docs/
[libsignal-protocol-java]: https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal-protocol-java
[libsignal-metadata-java]: https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal-metadata-java
[RustCrypto]: https://github.com/RustCrypto
[Noise protocol]: http://noiseprotocol.org/
[SGX enclaves]: https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/software-guard-extensions.html
[HSMs]: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardware_security_module
[zero-knowledge groups]: https://signal.org/blog/signal-private-group-system/
[The Signal Private Group System]: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1416.pdf
[PINs]: https://signal.org/blog/signal-pins/
[Android]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-Android
[iOS]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-iOS
[Desktop]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-Desktop


# Building

### Toolchain Installation

To build anything in this repository you must have [Rust](https://rust-lang.org) installed,
as well as Clang, libclang, [CMake](https://cmake.org), Make, protoc, and git.

#### Linux/Debian

On a Debian-like system, you can get these extra dependencies through `apt`:

```shell
$ apt-get install clang libclang-dev cmake make protobuf-compiler git
```

#### macOS

On macOS, we have a best-effort maintained script to set up the Rust toolchain you can run by:

```shell
$ bin/mac_setup.sh
```

## Rust

### First Build and Test

The build currently uses a specific version of the Rust nightly compiler, which
will be downloaded automatically by cargo. To build and test the basic protocol
libraries:

```shell
$ cargo build
...
$ cargo test
...
```

### Additional Rust Tools

The basic tools above should get you set up for most libsignal Rust development. 

Eventually, you may find that you need some additional Rust tools like `cbindgen` to modify the bridges to the 
client libraries or `taplo` for code formatting. 

You should always install any Rust tools you need that may affect the build from cargo rather than from your system
package manager (e.g. `apt` or `brew`). Package managers sometimes contain outdated versions of these tools that can break
the build with incompatibility issues (especially cbindgen).

To install the main Rust extra dependencies matching the versions we use, you can run the following commands: 

```shell
$ cargo +stable install cbindgen cargo-fuzz
$ cargo +stable install --version &quot;$(cat ../acknowledgments/cargo-about-version)&quot; --locked cargo-about
$ cargo +stable install --version &quot;$(cat ../.taplo-cli-version)&quot; --locked taplo-cli
```

## Java/Android

To build for Android you must install several additional packages including a JDK,
the Android NDK/SDK, and add the Android targets to the Rust compiler, using

```rustup target add armv7-linux-androideabi aarch64-linux-android i686-linux-android x86_64-linux-android```

To build the Java/Android ``jar`` and ``aar``, and run the tests:

```shell
$ cd java
$ ./gradlew test
$ ./gradlew build # if you need AAR outputs
```

You can pass `-P debugLevelLogs` to Gradle to build without filtering out debug- and verbose-level
logs from Rust.

Alternately, a build system using Docker is available:

```shell
$ cd java
$ make
```

When exposing new APIs to Java, you will need to run `rust/bridge/jni/bin/gen_java_decl.py` in
addition to rebuilding. This requires installing the `cbindgen` Rust tool, as detailed above. 

### Maven Central

Signal publishes Java packages on [Maven Central](https://central.sonatype.org) for its own use,
under the names org.signal:libsignal-server, org.signal:libsignal-client, and
org.signal:libsignal-android. libsignal-client and libsignal-server contain native libraries for
Debian-flavored x86_64 Linux as well as Windows (x86_64) and macOS (x86_64 and arm64).
libsignal-android contains native libraries for armeabi-v7a, arm64-v8a, x86, and x86_64 Android.

When building for Android you need *both* libsignal-android and libsignal-client, but the Windows
and macOS libraries in libsignal-client won&#039;t automatically be excluded from your final app. You can
explicitly exclude them using `packagingOptions`:

```
android {
  // ...
  packagingOptions {
    resources {
      excludes += setOf(&quot;libsignal_jni*.dylib&quot;, &quot;signal_jni*.dll&quot;)
    }
  }
  // ...
}
```

You can additionally exclude `libsignal_jni_testing.so` if you do not plan to use any of the APIs
intended for client testing.


## Swift

To learn about the Swift build process see [``swift/README.md``](swift/)


## Node

You&#039;ll need Node installed to build. If you have [nvm][], you can run `nvm use` to select an
appropriate version automatically.

We use `npm` as our package manager, and `node-gyp` to control building the Rust library.

```shell
$ cd node
$ nvm use
$ npm install
$ npx node-gyp rebuild  # clean-&gt;configure-&gt;build
$ npm run tsc
$ npm run test
```

When testing changes locally, you can use `npm run build` to do an incremental rebuild of the Rust library. Alternately, `npm run build-with-debug-level-logs` will rebuild without filtering out debug- and verbose-level logs.

When exposing new APIs to Node, you will need to run `rust/bridge/node/bin/gen_ts_decl.py` in
addition to rebuilding.

[nvm]: https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm

### NPM

Signal publishes the NPM package `@signalapp/libsignal-client` for its own use, including native
libraries for Windows, macOS, and Debian-flavored Linux. Both x64 and arm64 builds are included for
all three platforms, but the arm64 builds for Windows and Linux are considered experimental, since
there are no official builds of Signal for those architectures.


# Contributions

Signal does accept external contributions to this project. However unless the change is
simple and easily understood, for example fixing a bug or portability issue, adding a new
test, or improving performance, first open an issue to discuss your intended change as not
all changes can be accepted.

Contributions that will not be used directly by one of Signal&#039;s official client apps may still be
considered, but only if they do not pose an undue maintenance burden or conflict with the goals of
the project.

Signing a [CLA (Contributor License Agreement)](https://signal.org/cla/) is required for all contributions.

## Code Formatting and Acknowledgments

You can run the styler on the entire project by running:

```shell
just format-all
```

You can run more extensive tests as well as linters and clippy by running:

```shell
just check-pre-commit
```

When making a PR that adjusts dependencies, you&#039;ll need to regenerate our acknowledgments files. See [``acknowledgments/README.md``](acknowledgments/).

# Legal things
## Cryptography Notice

This distribution includes cryptographic software. The country in which you currently reside may have restrictions on
the import, possession, use, and/or re-export to another country, of encryption software.  BEFORE using any encryption
software, please check your country&#039;s laws, regulations and policies concerning the import, possession, or use, and
re-export of encryption software, to see if this is permitted.  See &lt;http://www.wassenaar.org/&gt; for more information.

The U.S. Government Department of Commerce, Bureau of Industry and Security (BIS), has classified this software as
Export Commodity Control Number (ECCN) 5D002.C.1, which includes information security software using or performing
cryptographic functions with asymmetric algorithms.  The form and manner of this distribution makes it eligible for
export under the License Exception ENC Technology Software Unrestricted (TSU) exception (see the BIS Export
Administration Regulations, Section 740.13) for both object code and source code.

## License

Copyright 2020-2024 Signal Messenger, LLC

Licensed under the GNU AGPLv3: https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[hyperlight-dev/hyperlight]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within micro virtual machines with very low latency and minimal overhead.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight">hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</a></h1>
            <p>Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within micro virtual machines with very low latency and minimal overhead.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,086</p>
            <p>Forks: 108</p>
            <p>Stars today: 87 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Hyperlight&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight/refs/heads/main/docs/assets/hyperlight-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot; alt=&quot;hyperlight logo&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within &lt;i&gt;micro virtual machines&lt;/i&gt; with very low latency and minimal overhead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;    
&lt;/div&gt;

&gt; Note: Hyperlight is a nascent project with an evolving API and no guaranteed support. Assistance is provided on a
&gt; best-effort basis by the developers.

---

## Overview

Hyperlight is a library for creating _micro virtual machines_  — or _sandboxes_ — specifically optimized for securely
running untrusted code with minimal impact. It supports both Windows and Linux,
utilizing [Windows Hypervisor Platform](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/api/#windows-hypervisor-platform)
on Windows, and either Microsoft Hypervisor (mshv) or [KVM](https://linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page) on Linux.

These micro VMs operate without a kernel or operating system, keeping overhead low. Instead, guests are built
specifically for Hyperlight using the Hyperlight Guest library, which provides a controlled set of APIs that facilitate
interaction between host and guest:

- The host can call functions implemented and exposed by the guest (known as _guest functions_).
- Once running, the guest can call functions implemented and exposed by the host (known as _host functions_).

By default, Hyperlight restricts guest access to a minimal API. The only _host function_ available by default allows the
guest to print messages, which are displayed on the host console or redirected to stdout, as configured. Hosts can
choose to expose additional host functions, expanding the guest’s capabilities as needed.

Below is an example demonstrating the use of the Hyperlight host library in Rust to execute a simple guest application
and an example of a simple guest application using the Hyperlight guest library in also written in Rust.

### Host

```rust
use std::{thread, sync::{Arc, Mutex}};

use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_types::{ParameterValue, ReturnType};
use hyperlight_host::{UninitializedSandbox, MultiUseSandbox, func::HostFunction0, sandbox_state::transition::Noop, sandbox_state::sandbox::EvolvableSandbox};

fn main() -&gt; hyperlight_host::Result&lt;()&gt; {
    // Create an uninitialized sandbox with a guest binary
    let mut uninitialized_sandbox = UninitializedSandbox::new(
        hyperlight_host::GuestBinary::FilePath(hyperlight_testing::simple_guest_as_string().unwrap()),
        None, // default configuration
        None, // default run options
        None, // default host print function
    )?;

    // Register a host function
    fn sleep_5_secs() -&gt; hyperlight_host::Result&lt;()&gt; {
        thread::sleep(std::time::Duration::from_secs(5));
        Ok(())
    }

    let host_function = Arc::new(Mutex::new(sleep_5_secs));

    // Registering a host function makes it available to be called by the guest
    host_function.register(&amp;mut uninitialized_sandbox, &quot;Sleep5Secs&quot;)?;
    // Note: This function is unused by the guest code below, it&#039;s just here for demonstration purposes

    // Initialize sandbox to be able to call host functions
    let mut multi_use_sandbox: MultiUseSandbox = uninitialized_sandbox.evolve(Noop::default())?;

    // Call a function in the guest
    let message = &quot;Hello, World! I am executing inside of a VM :)\n&quot;.to_string();
    // in order to call a function it first must be defined in the guest and exposed so that 
    // the host can call it
    let result = multi_use_sandbox.call_guest_function_by_name(
        &quot;PrintOutput&quot;,
        ReturnType::Int,
        Some(vec![ParameterValue::String(message.clone())]),
    );

    assert!(result.is_ok());

    Ok(())
}
```

### Guest

```rust
#![no_std]
#![no_main]
extern crate alloc;

use alloc::string::ToString;
use alloc::vec::Vec;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_call::FunctionCall;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_types::{
    ParameterType, ParameterValue, ReturnType,
};
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::guest_error::ErrorCode;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::util::get_flatbuffer_result_from_int;

use hyperlight_guest::error::{HyperlightGuestError, Result};
use hyperlight_guest::guest_function_definition::GuestFunctionDefinition;
use hyperlight_guest::guest_function_register::register_function;
use hyperlight_guest::host_function_call::{
    call_host_function, get_host_value_return_as_int,
};

fn print_output(function_call: &amp;FunctionCall) -&gt; Result&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt; {
    if let ParameterValue::String(message) = function_call.parameters.clone().unwrap()[0].clone() {
        call_host_function(
            &quot;HostPrint&quot;,
            Some(Vec::from(&amp;[ParameterValue::String(message.to_string())])),
            ReturnType::Int,
        )?;
        let result = get_host_value_return_as_int()?;
        Ok(get_flatbuffer_result_from_int(result))
    } else {
        Err(HyperlightGuestError::new(
            ErrorCode::GuestFunctionParameterTypeMismatch,
            &quot;Invalid parameters passed to simple_print_output&quot;.to_string(),
        ))
    }
}

#[no_mangle]
pub extern &quot;C&quot; fn hyperlight_main() {
    let print_output_def = GuestFunctionDefinition::new(
        &quot;PrintOutput&quot;.to_string(),
        Vec::from(&amp;[ParameterType::String]),
        ReturnType::Int,
        print_output as i64,
    );
    register_function(print_output_def);
}

#[no_mangle]
pub fn guest_dispatch_function(function_call: FunctionCall) -&gt; Result&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt; {
    let function_name = function_call.function_name.clone();
    return Err(HyperlightGuestError::new(
        ErrorCode::GuestFunctionNotFound,
        function_name,
    ));
}
```

For additional examples of using the Hyperlight host Rust library, see
the [./src/hyperlight_host/examples](./src/hyperlight_host/examples) directory.

For examples of guest applications, see the [./src/tests/c_guests](./src/tests/c_guests) directory for C guests and
the [./src/tests/rust_guests](./src/tests/rust_guests) directory for Rust guests.

&gt; Note: Hyperlight guests can be written using the Hyperlight Rust or C Guest libraries.

## Repository Structure

- Hyperlight Host Libraries (i.e., the ones that create and manage the VMs)
    - [src/hyperlight_host](./src/hyperlight_host) - This is the Rust Hyperlight host library.

- Hyperlight Guest Libraries (i.e., the ones to make it easier to create guests that run inside the VMs)
    - [src/hyperlight_guest](./src/hyperlight_guest) - This is the Rust Hyperlight guest library.
    - [src/hyperlight_guest_capi](./src/hyperlight_guest_capi) - This is the C compatible wrapper for the Hyperlight
      guest library.

- Hyperlight Common (functionality used by both the host and the guest)
    - [src/hyperlight_common](./src/hyperlight_common)

- Test Guest Applications:
    - [src/tests/rust_guests](./src/tests/rust_guests) - This directory contains three Hyperlight Guest programs written
      in Rust, which are intended to be launched within partitions as &quot;guests&quot;.
    - [src/tests/c_guests](./src/tests/c_guests) - This directory contains two Hyperlight Guest programs written in C,
      which are intended to be launched within partitions as &quot;guests&quot;.

- Tests:
    - [src/hyperlight-testing](./src/hyperlight_testing) - Shared testing code for Hyperlight projects built in Rust.

## Try it yourself!

You can run Hyperlight on:

- [Linux with KVM][kvm].
- [Windows with Windows Hypervisor Platform (WHP).][whp] -  Note that you need Windows 11 / Windows Server 2022 or later to use hyperlight, if you are running on earlier versions of Windows then you should consider using our devcontainer on [GitHub codespaces]((https://codespaces.new/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight)) or WSL2.
- Windows Subsystem for Linux 2 (see instructions [here](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install) for Windows client and [here](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-on-server) for Windows Server) with KVM.
- Azure Linux with mshv (note that you need mshv to be installed to use Hyperlight)

After having an environment with a hypervisor setup, running the example has the following pre-requisites:

1. On Linux or WSL, you&#039;ll most likely need build essential. For Ubuntu, run `sudo apt install build-essential`. For
   Azure Linux, run `sudo dnf install build-essential`.
2. [Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install). Install toolchain v1.81 or later.

   Also, install the `x86_64-pc-windows-msvc` and `x86_64-unknown-none` targets, these are needed to build the test
   guest binaries. (Note: install both targets on either Linux or Windows: Hyperlight can load ELF or PE files on either
   OS, and the tests/examples are built for both):

    ```sh
    rustup target add x86_64-unknown-none
    rustup target add x86_64-pc-windows-msvc
    ```

3. [just](https://github.com/casey/just). `cargo install just` On Windows you also need [pwsh](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell-on-windows?view=powershell-7.4).
4. [clang and LLVM](https://clang.llvm.org/get_started.html).
    - On Ubuntu, run:

        ```sh
        wget https://apt.llvm.org/llvm.sh
        chmod +x ./llvm.sh
        sudo ./llvm.sh 17 all
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/clang-cl /usr/bin/clang-cl
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/llvm-lib /usr/bin/llvm-lib
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/lld-link /usr/bin/lld-link
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/llvm-ml /usr/bin/llvm-ml
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/ld.lld /usr/bin/ld.lld
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/clang /usr/bin/clang
        ```

    - On Windows, see [this](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/cpp/build/clang-support-msbuild?view=msvc-170).

    - On Azure Linux, run:

        ```sh
        sudo dnf remove clang -y || true
        sudo dnf install clang17 -y
        sudo dnf install clang17-tools-extra -y
        ```

Then, we are ready to build and run the example:

```sh
just build  # build the Hyperlight library
just rg     # build the rust test guest binaries
cargo run --example hello-world
```

If all worked as expected, you should see the following message in your console:

```text
Hello, World! I am executing inside of a VM :)
```

If you get the error `Error: NoHypervisorFound` and KVM or mshv is set up then this may be a permissions issue. In bash,
you can use `ls -l /dev/kvm` or  `ls -l /dev/mshv` to check which group owns that device and then `groups` to make sure
your user is a member of that group.

For more details on how to verify that KVM is correctly installed and permissions are correct, follow the
guide [here](https://help.ubuntu.com/community/KVM/Installation).

### Or you can use a codespace

[![Open in GitHub Codespaces](https://github.com/codespaces/badge.svg)](https://codespaces.new/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight)

## Contributing to Hyperlight

If you are interested in contributing to Hyperlight, running the entire test-suite is a good way to get started. To do
so, on your console, run the following commands:

```sh
just guests  # build the c and rust test guests
just build  # build the Hyperlight library
just test # runs the tests
```

Also , please review the [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) file for more information on how to contribute to
Hyperlight.

&gt; Note: For general Hyperlight development, you may also need flatc (Flatbuffer compiler): for instructions,
&gt; see [here](https://github.com/google/flatbuffers).

## Join our Community Meetings

This project holds fortnightly community meetings to discuss the project&#039;s progress, roadmap, and any other topics of interest. The meetings are open to everyone, and we encourage you to join us.

- **When**: Every other Wednesday 09:00 (PST/PDT) [Convert to your local time](https://dateful.com/convert/pst-pdt-pacific-time?t=09)
- **Where**: Zoom! - Agenda and information on how to join can be found in the [Hyperlight Community Meeting Notes](https://hackmd.io/blCrncfOSEuqSbRVT9KYkg#Agenda). Please log into hackmd to edit!

## Chat with us on the CNCF Slack

The Hyperlight project Slack is hosted in the CNCF Slack #hyperlight. To join the Slack, [join the CNCF Slack](https://www.cncf.io/membership-faq/#how-do-i-join-cncfs-slack), and join the #hyperlight channel.

## More Information

For more information, please refer to our compilation of documents in the [`docs/` directory](./docs/README.md).

## Code of Conduct

See the [CNCF Code of Conduct](https://github.com/cncf/foundation/blob/main/code-of-conduct.md).

[wsl2]: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install

[kvm]: https://help.ubuntu.com/community/KVM/Installation

[whp]: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/hyper-v-android-emulator-support/#1-enable-hyper-v-and-the-windows-hypervisor-platform
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rustdesk/rustdesk]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An open-source remote desktop application designed for self-hosting, as an alternative to TeamViewer.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk">rustdesk/rustdesk</a></h1>
            <p>An open-source remote desktop application designed for self-hosting, as an alternative to TeamViewer.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 84,947</p>
            <p>Forks: 12,025</p>
            <p>Stars today: 58 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;res/logo-header.svg&quot; alt=&quot;RustDesk - Your remote desktop&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#raw-steps-to-build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-build-with-docker&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#file-structure&quot;&gt;Structure&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#snapshot&quot;&gt;Snapshot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-UA.md&quot;&gt;Українська&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-CS.md&quot;&gt;česky&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-ZH.md&quot;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-HU.md&quot;&gt;Magyar&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-ES.md&quot;&gt;Español&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-FA.md&quot;&gt;فارسی&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-FR.md&quot;&gt;Français&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-DE.md&quot;&gt;Deutsch&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-PL.md&quot;&gt;Polski&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-ID.md&quot;&gt;Indonesian&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-FI.md&quot;&gt;Suomi&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-ML.md&quot;&gt;മലയാളം&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-JP.md&quot;&gt;日本語&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-NL.md&quot;&gt;Nederlands&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-IT.md&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-RU.md&quot;&gt;Русский&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-PTBR.md&quot;&gt;Português (Brasil)&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-EO.md&quot;&gt;Esperanto&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-KR.md&quot;&gt;한국어&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-AR.md&quot;&gt;العربي&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-VN.md&quot;&gt;Tiếng Việt&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-DA.md&quot;&gt;Dansk&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-GR.md&quot;&gt;Ελληνικά&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-TR.md&quot;&gt;Türkçe&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;docs/README-NO.md&quot;&gt;Norsk&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;We need your help to translate this README, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/lang&quot;&gt;RustDesk UI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rustdesk/doc.rustdesk.com&quot;&gt;RustDesk Doc&lt;/a&gt; to your native language&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&gt; [!Caution]
&gt; **Misuse Disclaimer:** &lt;br&gt;
&gt; The developers of RustDesk do not condone or support any unethical or illegal use of this software. Misuse, such as unauthorized access, control or invasion of privacy, is strictly against our guidelines. The authors are not responsible for any misuse of the application.


Chat with us: [Discord](https://discord.gg/nDceKgxnkV) | [Twitter](https://twitter.com/rustdesk) | [Reddit](https://www.reddit.com/r/rustdesk)

[![ko-fi](https://ko-fi.com/img/githubbutton_sm.svg)](https://ko-fi.com/I2I04VU09)

Yet another remote desktop software, written in Rust. Works out of the box, no configuration required. You have full control of your data, with no concerns about security. You can use our rendezvous/relay server, [set up your own](https://rustdesk.com/server), or [write your own rendezvous/relay server](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server-demo).

![image](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/71636191/171661982-430285f0-2e12-4b1d-9957-4a58e375304d.png)

RustDesk welcomes contribution from everyone. See [CONTRIBUTING.md](docs/CONTRIBUTING.md) for help getting started.

[**FAQ**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/wiki/FAQ)

[**BINARY DOWNLOAD**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/releases)

[**NIGHTLY BUILD**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/releases/tag/nightly)

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://f-droid.org/badge/get-it-on.png&quot;
    alt=&quot;Get it on F-Droid&quot;
    height=&quot;80&quot;&gt;](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.carriez.flutter_hbb)
[&lt;img src=&quot;https://flathub.org/api/badge?svg&amp;locale=en&quot;
    alt=&quot;Get it on Flathub&quot;
    height=&quot;80&quot;&gt;](https://flathub.org/apps/com.rustdesk.RustDesk)

## Dependencies

Desktop versions use Flutter or Sciter (deprecated) for GUI, this tutorial is for Sciter only, since it is easier and more friendly to start. Check out our [CI](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/blob/master/.github/workflows/flutter-build.yml) for building Flutter version.

Please download Sciter dynamic library yourself.

[Windows](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/c-smile/sciter-sdk/master/bin.win/x64/sciter.dll) |
[Linux](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/c-smile/sciter-sdk/master/bin.lnx/x64/libsciter-gtk.so) |
[macOS](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/c-smile/sciter-sdk/master/bin.osx/libsciter.dylib)

## Raw steps to build

- Prepare your Rust development env and C++ build env

- Install [vcpkg](https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg), and set `VCPKG_ROOT` env variable correctly

  - Windows: vcpkg install libvpx:x64-windows-static libyuv:x64-windows-static opus:x64-windows-static aom:x64-windows-static
  - Linux/macOS: vcpkg install libvpx libyuv opus aom

- run `cargo run`

## [Build](https://rustdesk.com/docs/en/dev/build/)

## How to build on Linux

### Ubuntu 18 (Debian 10)

```sh
sudo apt install -y zip g++ gcc git curl wget nasm yasm libgtk-3-dev clang libxcb-randr0-dev libxdo-dev \
        libxfixes-dev libxcb-shape0-dev libxcb-xfixes0-dev libasound2-dev libpulse-dev cmake make \
        libclang-dev ninja-build libgstreamer1.0-dev libgstreamer-plugins-base1.0-dev libpam0g-dev
```

### openSUSE Tumbleweed

```sh
sudo zypper install gcc-c++ git curl wget nasm yasm gcc gtk3-devel clang libxcb-devel libXfixes-devel cmake alsa-lib-devel gstreamer-devel gstreamer-plugins-base-devel xdotool-devel pam-devel
```

### Fedora 28 (CentOS 8)

```sh
sudo yum -y install gcc-c++ git curl wget nasm yasm gcc gtk3-devel clang libxcb-devel libxdo-devel libXfixes-devel pulseaudio-libs-devel cmake alsa-lib-devel gstreamer1-devel gstreamer1-plugins-base-devel pam-devel
```

### Arch (Manjaro)

```sh
sudo pacman -Syu --needed unzip git cmake gcc curl wget yasm nasm zip make pkg-config clang gtk3 xdotool libxcb libxfixes alsa-lib pipewire
```

### Install vcpkg

```sh
git clone https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg
cd vcpkg
git checkout 2023.04.15
cd ..
vcpkg/bootstrap-vcpkg.sh
export VCPKG_ROOT=$HOME/vcpkg
vcpkg/vcpkg install libvpx libyuv opus aom
```

### Fix libvpx (For Fedora)

```sh
cd vcpkg/buildtrees/libvpx/src
cd *
./configure
sed -i &#039;s/CFLAGS+=-I/CFLAGS+=-fPIC -I/g&#039; Makefile
sed -i &#039;s/CXXFLAGS+=-I/CXXFLAGS+=-fPIC -I/g&#039; Makefile
make
cp libvpx.a $HOME/vcpkg/installed/x64-linux/lib/
cd
```

### Build

```sh
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh
source $HOME/.cargo/env
git clone https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk
cd rustdesk
mkdir -p target/debug
wget https://raw.githubusercontent.com/c-smile/sciter-sdk/master/bin.lnx/x64/libsciter-gtk.so
mv libsciter-gtk.so target/debug
VCPKG_ROOT=$HOME/vcpkg cargo run
```

## How to build with Docker

Begin by cloning the repository and building the Docker container:

```sh
git clone https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk
cd rustdesk
git submodule update --init --recursive
docker build -t &quot;rustdesk-builder&quot; .
```

Then, each time you need to build the application, run the following command:

```sh
docker run --rm -it -v $PWD:/home/user/rustdesk -v rustdesk-git-cache:/home/user/.cargo/git -v rustdesk-registry-cache:/home/user/.cargo/registry -e PUID=&quot;$(id -u)&quot; -e PGID=&quot;$(id -g)&quot; rustdesk-builder
```

Note that the first build may take longer before dependencies are cached, subsequent builds will be faster. Additionally, if you need to specify different arguments to the build command, you may do so at the end of the command in the `&lt;OPTIONAL-ARGS&gt;` position. For instance, if you wanted to build an optimized release version, you would run the command above followed by `--release`. The resulting executable will be available in the target folder on your system, and can be run with:

```sh
target/debug/rustdesk
```

Or, if you&#039;re running a release executable:

```sh
target/release/rustdesk
```

Please ensure that you are running these commands from the root of the RustDesk repository, otherwise the application might not be able to find the required resources. Also note that other cargo subcommands such as `install` or `run` are not currently supported via this method as they would install or run the program inside the container instead of the host.

## File Structure

- **[libs/hbb_common](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/libs/hbb_common)**: video codec, config, tcp/udp wrapper, protobuf, fs functions for file transfer, and some other utility functions
- **[libs/scrap](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/libs/scrap)**: screen capture
- **[libs/enigo](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/libs/enigo)**: platform specific keyboard/mouse control
- **[libs/clipboard](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/libs/clipboard)**: file copy and paste implementation for Windows, Linux, macOS.
- **[src/ui](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/ui)**: obsolete Sciter UI (deprecated)
- **[src/server](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/server)**: audio/clipboard/input/video services, and network connections
- **[src/client.rs](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/client.rs)**: start a peer connection
- **[src/rendezvous_mediator.rs](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/rendezvous_mediator.rs)**: Communicate with [rustdesk-server](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server), wait for remote direct (TCP hole punching) or relayed connection
- **[src/platform](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/src/platform)**: platform specific code
- **[flutter](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/flutter)**: Flutter code for desktop and mobile
- **[flutter/web/js](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/tree/master/flutter/web/v1/js)**: JavaScript for Flutter web client

## Screenshots

![Connection Manager](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/assets/28412477/db82d4e7-c4bc-4823-8e6f-6af7eadf7651)

![Connected to a Windows PC](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/assets/28412477/9baa91e9-3362-4d06-aa1a-7518edcbd7ea)

![File Transfer](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/assets/28412477/39511ad3-aa9a-4f8c-8947-1cce286a46ad)

![TCP Tunneling](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/assets/28412477/78e8708f-e87e-4570-8373-1360033ea6c5)

</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BoundaryML/baml]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/BoundaryML/baml</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/BoundaryML/baml</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The AI framework that adds the engineering to prompt engineering (Python/TS/Ruby/Java/C#/Rust/Go compatible)]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/BoundaryML/baml">BoundaryML/baml</a></h1>
            <p>The AI framework that adds the engineering to prompt engineering (Python/TS/Ruby/Java/C#/Rust/Go compatible)</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,772</p>
            <p>Forks: 110</p>
            <p>Stars today: 16 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://boundaryml.com?utm_source=github&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;fern/assets/baml-lamb-white.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;fern/assets/baml-lamb-white.png&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; id=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

## BAML: Basically a Made-up Language

*or &quot;Bad-Ass Machine Learning&quot; if your boss isn&#039;t around*


&lt;h3&gt;

[Homepage](https://www.boundaryml.com/) | [Docs](https://docs.boundaryml.com) | [BAML Chat](https://www.boundaryml.com/chat) | [Discord](https://discord.gg/BTNBeXGuaS)

&lt;/h3&gt;

[![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/boundaryml/baml)](https://github.com/boundaryml/baml)
[![License: Apache-2](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache-green.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2)
[![BAML Version](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/baml-py?color=006dad&amp;label=BAML%20Version)](https://pypi.org/project/baml-py/)


**Try BAML**: [Prompt Fiddle](https://www.promptfiddle.com) • [Examples](https://baml-examples.vercel.app/) • [Example Source Code](https://github.com/BoundaryML/baml-examples)

**5 minute quickstarts**
[Python](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/installation-language/python) • [Typescript](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/installation-language/typescript) • [NextJS](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/framework-integration/react-next-js/quick-start) • [Ruby](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/installation-language/ruby) • [Others](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/installation-language/rest-api-other-languages) (Go, Java, C++, Rust, PHP, etc)

&lt;/div&gt;

|   |     |
| - | - |
| What is BAML? | BAML is a new programming language for building AI applications. |
| Do I need to write my whole app in BAML? | Nope, only the AI parts, you can then use BAML with any existing language of your choice! [python](/python), [typescript](/ts), and [more](/more). |
| Is BAML stable? | Yes, many companies use it in production! We ship updates weekly and rarely have breaking changes |
| Why a new language? | [Jump to section](#why-a-new-programming-language) |
| Why a lamb? | Baaaaa-ml. LAMB == BAML |


## The core BAML principle: LLM Prompts are functions

The fundamental building block in BAML is a function. Every prompt is a function that takes in parameters and returns a type.

```rust
function ChatAgent(message: Message[], tone: &quot;happy&quot; | &quot;sad&quot;) -&gt; string
```

Every function additionally defines which models it uses and what its prompt is.

```rust
function ChatAgent(message: Message[], tone: &quot;happy&quot; | &quot;sad&quot;) -&gt; StopTool | ReplyTool {
    client &quot;openai/gpt-4o-mini&quot;

    prompt #&quot;
        Be a {{ tone }} bot.

        {{ ctx.output_format }}

        {% for m in message %}
        {{ _.role(m.role) }}
        {{ m.content }}
        {% endfor %}
    &quot;#
}

class Message {
    role string
    content string
}

class ReplyTool {
  response string
}

class StopTool {
  action &quot;stop&quot; @description(#&quot;
    when it might be a good time to end the conversation
  &quot;#)
}
```

Then in any language of your choice you can do the following:

```python
from baml_client import b
from baml_client.types import Message, StopTool

messages = [Message(role=&quot;assistant&quot;, content=&quot;How can I help?&quot;)]

while True:
  print(messages[-1].content)
  user_reply = input()
  messages.append(Message(role=&quot;user&quot;, content=user_reply))
  tool = b.ChatAgent(messages, &quot;happy&quot;)
  if isinstance(tool, StopTool):
    print(&quot;Goodbye!&quot;)
    break
  else:
    messages.append(Message(role=&quot;assistant&quot;, content=tool.response))
```

### Making prompts easy to find and read

Since every prompt is a function, we can build tools to find every prompt you&#039;ve written. But we&#039;ve taken BAML one step further and built native tooling for VSCode (jetbrains + neovim coming soon).

1. You can see the full prompt (including any multi-modal assets)
![Multi Modal](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/02-multi-modal.gif)
2. You can see the exact network request we are making
![Token Preview](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/03-curl-token-preview.gif)
3. You can see every function you&#039;ve ever written

![Functions](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/04-functions-preview.png)

### Swapping models: 1-line change

It&#039;s just 1 line (ok, maybe 2). [Docs](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/baml-basics/switching-llms)
![Sorry Sam](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/05-sorry-sam.png)

[Retry policies](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-strategies/retry-policy) • [fallbacks](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-strategies/fallback) • [model rotations](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-strategies/round-robin). All statically defined.
![Fallback Retry](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/06-fallback-retry.gif)

&gt; Want to do pick models at runtime? Check out [Client Registry](https://docs.boundaryml.com/guide/baml-advanced/llm-client-registry).

We currently support: [OpenAI](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/open-ai) • [Anthropic](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/anthropic) • [Gemini](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/google-ai-gemini) • [Vertex](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/google-vertex) • [Bedrock](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/aws-bedrock) • [Azure OpenAI](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/open-ai-from-azure) • [Anything OpenAI Compatible](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic) ([Ollama](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic-ollama), [OpenRouter](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic-open-router), [VLLM](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic-v-llm), [LMStudio](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic-lm-studio), [TogetherAI](https://docs.boundaryml.com/ref/llm-client-providers/openai-generic-together-ai), and more)

### Hot-reloading for prompts

Using AI is all about iteration speed.

If testing your pipeline takes 2 minutes, in 20 minutes, you can only test 10 ideas.

If testing your pipeline took 5 seconds, in 20 minutes, you can test 240 ideas.

Introducing testing, for prompts.

![Hot Reload](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/07-hotreload.gif)

### Structured outputs with any LLM

JSON is amazing for REST APIs, but way too strict and verbose for LLMs. LLMs need something flexible. We created the SAP (schema-aligned parsing) algorithm to support the flexible outputs LLMs can provide, like markdown within a JSON blob or chain-of-thought prior to answering.

![Chain of Thought](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/09-cot.gif)

SAP works with any model on day-1, without depending on tool-use or function-calling APIs.

To learn more about SAP you can read this post: [Schema-Aligned Parsing](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/schema-aligned-parsing).

See it in action with: [Deepseek-R1](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/deepseek-r1-function-calling) and [OpenAI O1](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/openai-o1).

### Streaming (when it&#039;s a first class citizen)

Streaming is way harder than it should be. With our [Python/Typescript/Ruby] generated code, streaming becomes natural and type-safe.

![Streaming](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/2025-01-24-ai-agents-need-a-new-syntax/10-streaming-client.gif#still)

### No strings attached

- 100% open-source (Apache 2)
- 100% private. AGI will not require an internet connection, neither will BAML
    - No network requests beyond model calls you explicitly set
    - Not stored or used for any training data
- BAML files can be saved locally on your machine and checked into Github for easy diffs.
- Built in Rust. So fast, you can&#039;t even tell it&#039;s there.

## BAML&#039;s Design Philosophy

Everything is fair game when making new syntax. If you can code it, it can be yours. This is our design philosophy to help restrict ideas:

- **1:** Avoid invention when possible
    - Yes, prompts need versioning — we have a great versioning tool: git
    - Yes, you need to save prompts — we have a great storage tool: filesystems
- **2:** Any file editor and any terminal should be enough to use it
- **3:** Be fast
- **4:** A first year university student should be able to understand it

## Why a new programming language

We used to write websites like this:

```python
def home():
    return &quot;&lt;button onclick=\&quot;() =&gt; alert(\\\&quot;hello!\\\&quot;)\&quot;&gt;Click&lt;/button&gt;&quot;
```

And now we do this:

```jsx
function Home() {
  return &lt;button onClick={() =&gt; setCount(prev =&gt; prev + 1)}&gt;
          {count} clicks!
         &lt;/button&gt;
}
```

New syntax can be incredible at expressing new ideas. Plus the idea of maintaining hundreds of f-strings for prompts kind of disgusts us 🤮. Strings are bad for maintainable codebases. We prefer structured strings.

The goal of BAML is to give you the expressiveness of English, but the structure of code.

Full [blog post](https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/ai-agents-need-new-syntax) by us.


## Conclusion

As models get better, we&#039;ll continue expecting even more out of them. But what will never change is that we&#039;ll want a way to write maintainable code that uses those models. The current way we all just assemble strings is very reminiscent of the early days PHP/HTML soup in web development. We hope some of the ideas we shared today can make a tiny dent in helping us all shape the way we all code tomorrow.


## Contributing
Checkout our [guide on getting started](/CONTRIBUTING.md)

---

Made with ❤️ by Boundary

HQ in Seattle, WA

P.S. We&#039;re hiring for software engineers that love rust. [Email us](founders@boundaryml.com) or reach out on [discord](https://discord.gg/ENtBB6kkXH)!

&lt;div align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;align-items: left;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Back%20to%20Top-000000?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github&amp;logoColor=white&quot; alt=&quot;Back to Top&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/standards.png&quot; alt_text=&quot;hi&quot; /&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[huggingface/text-embeddings-inference]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A blazing fast inference solution for text embeddings models]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference">huggingface/text-embeddings-inference</a></h1>
            <p>A blazing fast inference solution for text embeddings models</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,368</p>
            <p>Forks: 232</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# Text Embeddings Inference

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Repo stars&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference?style=social&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.github.io/text-embeddings-inference&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Swagger API documentation&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/API-Swagger-informational&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

A blazing fast inference solution for text embeddings models.

Benchmark for [BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5](https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5) on an Nvidia A10 with a sequence
length of 512 tokens:

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/bs1-lat.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/bs1-tp.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/bs32-lat.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;assets/bs32-tp.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

## Table of contents

- [Get Started](#get-started)
    - [Supported Models](#supported-models)
    - [Docker](#docker)
    - [Docker Images](#docker-images)
    - [API Documentation](#api-documentation)
    - [Using a private or gated model](#using-a-private-or-gated-model)
    - [Air gapped deployment](#air-gapped-deployment)
    - [Using Re-rankers models](#using-re-rankers-models)
    - [Using Sequence Classification models](#using-sequence-classification-models)
    - [Using SPLADE pooling](#using-splade-pooling)
    - [Distributed Tracing](#distributed-tracing)
    - [gRPC](#grpc)
- [Local Install](#local-install)
- [Docker Build](#docker-build)
    - [Apple M1/M2 Arm](#apple-m1m2-arm64-architectures)
- [Examples](#examples)

Text Embeddings Inference (TEI) is a toolkit for deploying and serving open source text embeddings and sequence
classification models. TEI enables high-performance extraction for the most popular models, including FlagEmbedding,
Ember, GTE and E5. TEI implements many features such as:

* No model graph compilation step
* Metal support for local execution on Macs
* Small docker images and fast boot times. Get ready for true serverless!
* Token based dynamic batching
* Optimized transformers code for inference using [Flash Attention](https://github.com/HazyResearch/flash-attention),
  [Candle](https://github.com/huggingface/candle)
  and [cuBLASLt](https://docs.nvidia.com/cuda/cublas/#using-the-cublaslt-api)
* [Safetensors](https://github.com/huggingface/safetensors) weight loading
* [ONNX](https://github.com/onnx/onnx) weight loading
* Production ready (distributed tracing with Open Telemetry, Prometheus metrics)

## Get Started

### Supported Models

#### Text Embeddings

Text Embeddings Inference currently supports Nomic, BERT, CamemBERT, XLM-RoBERTa models with absolute positions, JinaBERT
model with Alibi positions and Mistral, Alibaba GTE, Qwen2 models with Rope positions, and MPNet.

Below are some examples of the currently supported models:

| MTEB Rank | Model Size          | Model Type  | Model ID                                                                                         |
|-----------|---------------------|-------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| 3         | 7B (Very Expensive) | Qwen2       | [Alibaba-NLP/gte-Qwen2-7B-instruct](https://hf.co/Alibaba-NLP/gte-Qwen2-7B-instruct)             |
| 11        | 1.5B (Expensive)    | Qwen2       | [Alibaba-NLP/gte-Qwen2-1.5B-instruct](https://hf.co/Alibaba-NLP/gte-Qwen2-1.5B-instruct)         |
| 14        | 7B (Very Expensive) | Mistral     | [Salesforce/SFR-Embedding-2_R](https://hf.co/Salesforce/SFR-Embedding-2_R)                       |
| 20        | 0.3B                | Bert        | [WhereIsAI/UAE-Large-V1](https://hf.co/WhereIsAI/UAE-Large-V1)                                   |
| 31        | 0.5B                | XLM-RoBERTa | [Snowflake/snowflake-arctic-embed-l-v2.0](https://hf.co/Snowflake/snowflake-arctic-embed-l-v2.0) |
| 37        | 0.3B                | Alibaba GTE | [Snowflake/snowflake-arctic-embed-m-v2.0](https://hf.co/Snowflake/snowflake-arctic-embed-m-v2.0) |
| 49        | 0.5B                | XLM-RoBERTa | [intfloat/multilingual-e5-large-instruct](https://hf.co/intfloat/multilingual-e5-large-instruct) |
| N/A       | 0.4B                | Alibaba GTE | [Alibaba-NLP/gte-large-en-v1.5](https://hf.co/Alibaba-NLP/gte-large-en-v1.5)                     |
| N/A       | 0.1B                | NomicBert   | [nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1](https://hf.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1)                       |
| N/A       | 0.1B                | NomicBert   | [nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5](https://hf.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5)                   |
| N/A       | 0.1B                | JinaBERT    | [jinaai/jina-embeddings-v2-base-en](https://hf.co/jinaai/jina-embeddings-v2-base-en)             |
| N/A       | 0.1B                | JinaBERT    | [jinaai/jina-embeddings-v2-base-code](https://hf.co/jinaai/jina-embeddings-v2-base-code)         |
| N/A       | 0.1B                | MPNet       | [sentence-transformers/all-mpnet-base-v2](https://hf.co/sentence-transformers/all-mpnet-base-v2) |

To explore the list of best performing text embeddings models, visit the
[Massive Text Embedding Benchmark (MTEB) Leaderboard](https://huggingface.co/spaces/mteb/leaderboard).

#### Sequence Classification and Re-Ranking

Text Embeddings Inference currently supports CamemBERT, and XLM-RoBERTa Sequence Classification models with absolute positions.

Below are some examples of the currently supported models:

| Task               | Model Type  | Model ID                                                                                                        |
|--------------------|-------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| Re-Ranking         | XLM-RoBERTa | [BAAI/bge-reranker-large](https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-reranker-large)                                       |
| Re-Ranking         | XLM-RoBERTa | [BAAI/bge-reranker-base](https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-reranker-base)                                         |
| Re-Ranking         | GTE         | [Alibaba-NLP/gte-multilingual-reranker-base](https://huggingface.co/Alibaba-NLP/gte-multilingual-reranker-base) |
| Sentiment Analysis | RoBERTa     | [SamLowe/roberta-base-go_emotions](https://huggingface.co/SamLowe/roberta-base-go_emotions)                     |

### Docker

```shell
model=BAAI/bge-large-en-v1.5
volume=$PWD/data # share a volume with the Docker container to avoid downloading weights every run

docker run --gpus all -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id $model
```

And then you can make requests like

```bash
curl 127.0.0.1:8080/embed \
    -X POST \
    -d &#039;{&quot;inputs&quot;:&quot;What is Deep Learning?&quot;}&#039; \
    -H &#039;Content-Type: application/json&#039;
```

**Note:** To use GPUs, you need to install
the [NVIDIA Container Toolkit](https://docs.nvidia.com/datacenter/cloud-native/container-toolkit/install-guide.html).
NVIDIA drivers on your machine need to be compatible with CUDA version 12.2 or higher.

To see all options to serve your models:

```shell
text-embeddings-router --help
```

```
Usage: text-embeddings-router [OPTIONS]

Options:
      --model-id &lt;MODEL_ID&gt;
          The name of the model to load. Can be a MODEL_ID as listed on &lt;https://hf.co/models&gt; like `thenlper/gte-base`.
          Or it can be a local directory containing the necessary files as saved by `save_pretrained(...)` methods of
          transformers

          [env: MODEL_ID=]
          [default: thenlper/gte-base]

      --revision &lt;REVISION&gt;
          The actual revision of the model if you&#039;re referring to a model on the hub. You can use a specific commit id
          or a branch like `refs/pr/2`

          [env: REVISION=]

      --tokenization-workers &lt;TOKENIZATION_WORKERS&gt;
          Optionally control the number of tokenizer workers used for payload tokenization, validation and truncation.
          Default to the number of CPU cores on the machine

          [env: TOKENIZATION_WORKERS=]

      --dtype &lt;DTYPE&gt;
          The dtype to be forced upon the model

          [env: DTYPE=]
          [possible values: float16, float32]

      --pooling &lt;POOLING&gt;
          Optionally control the pooling method for embedding models.

          If `pooling` is not set, the pooling configuration will be parsed from the model `1_Pooling/config.json` configuration.

          If `pooling` is set, it will override the model pooling configuration

          [env: POOLING=]

          Possible values:
          - cls:        Select the CLS token as embedding
          - mean:       Apply Mean pooling to the model embeddings
          - splade:     Apply SPLADE (Sparse Lexical and Expansion) to the model embeddings. This option is only
          available if the loaded model is a `ForMaskedLM` Transformer model
          - last-token: Select the last token as embedding

      --max-concurrent-requests &lt;MAX_CONCURRENT_REQUESTS&gt;
          The maximum amount of concurrent requests for this particular deployment.
          Having a low limit will refuse clients requests instead of having them wait for too long and is usually good
          to handle backpressure correctly

          [env: MAX_CONCURRENT_REQUESTS=]
          [default: 512]

      --max-batch-tokens &lt;MAX_BATCH_TOKENS&gt;
          **IMPORTANT** This is one critical control to allow maximum usage of the available hardware.

          This represents the total amount of potential tokens within a batch.

          For `max_batch_tokens=1000`, you could fit `10` queries of `total_tokens=100` or a single query of `1000` tokens.

          Overall this number should be the largest possible until the model is compute bound. Since the actual memory
          overhead depends on the model implementation, text-embeddings-inference cannot infer this number automatically.

          [env: MAX_BATCH_TOKENS=]
          [default: 16384]

      --max-batch-requests &lt;MAX_BATCH_REQUESTS&gt;
          Optionally control the maximum number of individual requests in a batch

          [env: MAX_BATCH_REQUESTS=]

      --max-client-batch-size &lt;MAX_CLIENT_BATCH_SIZE&gt;
          Control the maximum number of inputs that a client can send in a single request

          [env: MAX_CLIENT_BATCH_SIZE=]
          [default: 32]

      --auto-truncate
          Automatically truncate inputs that are longer than the maximum supported size

          Unused for gRPC servers

          [env: AUTO_TRUNCATE=]

      --default-prompt-name &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT_NAME&gt;
          The name of the prompt that should be used by default for encoding. If not set, no prompt will be applied.

          Must be a key in the `sentence-transformers` configuration `prompts` dictionary.

          For example if ``default_prompt_name`` is &quot;query&quot; and the ``prompts`` is {&quot;query&quot;: &quot;query: &quot;, ...}, then the
          sentence &quot;What is the capital of France?&quot; will be encoded as &quot;query: What is the capital of France?&quot; because
          the prompt text will be prepended before any text to encode.

          The argument &#039;--default-prompt-name &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT_NAME&gt;&#039; cannot be used with &#039;--default-prompt &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT&gt;`

          [env: DEFAULT_PROMPT_NAME=]

      --default-prompt &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT&gt;
          The prompt that should be used by default for encoding. If not set, no prompt will be applied.

          For example if ``default_prompt`` is &quot;query: &quot; then the sentence &quot;What is the capital of France?&quot; will be
          encoded as &quot;query: What is the capital of France?&quot; because the prompt text will be prepended before any text
          to encode.

          The argument &#039;--default-prompt &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT&gt;&#039; cannot be used with &#039;--default-prompt-name &lt;DEFAULT_PROMPT_NAME&gt;`

          [env: DEFAULT_PROMPT=]

      --hf-token &lt;HF_TOKEN&gt;
          Your Hugging Face Hub token

          [env: HF_TOKEN=]

      --hostname &lt;HOSTNAME&gt;
          The IP address to listen on

          [env: HOSTNAME=]
          [default: 0.0.0.0]

  -p, --port &lt;PORT&gt;
          The port to listen on

          [env: PORT=]
          [default: 3000]

      --uds-path &lt;UDS_PATH&gt;
          The name of the unix socket some text-embeddings-inference backends will use as they communicate internally
          with gRPC

          [env: UDS_PATH=]
          [default: /tmp/text-embeddings-inference-server]

      --huggingface-hub-cache &lt;HUGGINGFACE_HUB_CACHE&gt;
          The location of the huggingface hub cache. Used to override the location if you want to provide a mounted disk
          for instance

          [env: HUGGINGFACE_HUB_CACHE=]

      --payload-limit &lt;PAYLOAD_LIMIT&gt;
          Payload size limit in bytes

          Default is 2MB

          [env: PAYLOAD_LIMIT=]
          [default: 2000000]

      --api-key &lt;API_KEY&gt;
          Set an api key for request authorization.

          By default the server responds to every request. With an api key set, the requests must have the Authorization
          header set with the api key as Bearer token.

          [env: API_KEY=]

      --json-output
          Outputs the logs in JSON format (useful for telemetry)

          [env: JSON_OUTPUT=]

      --disable-spans
          Disables the span logging trace

          [env: DISABLE_SPANS=]

      --otlp-endpoint &lt;OTLP_ENDPOINT&gt;
          The grpc endpoint for opentelemetry. Telemetry is sent to this endpoint as OTLP over gRPC. e.g. `http://localhost:4317`

          [env: OTLP_ENDPOINT=]

      --otlp-service-name &lt;OTLP_SERVICE_NAME&gt;
          The service name for opentelemetry. e.g. `text-embeddings-inference.server`

          [env: OTLP_SERVICE_NAME=]
          [default: text-embeddings-inference.server]

      --cors-allow-origin &lt;CORS_ALLOW_ORIGIN&gt;
          Unused for gRPC servers

          [env: CORS_ALLOW_ORIGIN=]
```

### Docker Images

Text Embeddings Inference ships with multiple Docker images that you can use to target a specific backend:

| Architecture                        | Image                                                                   |
|-------------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| CPU                                 | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:cpu-1.6                   |
| Volta                               | NOT SUPPORTED                                                           |
| Turing (T4, RTX 2000 series, ...)   | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:turing-1.6 (experimental) |
| Ampere 80 (A100, A30)               | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6                       |
| Ampere 86 (A10, A40, ...)           | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:86-1.6                    |
| Ada Lovelace (RTX 4000 series, ...) | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:89-1.6                    |
| Hopper (H100)                       | ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:hopper-1.6 (experimental) |

**Warning**: Flash Attention is turned off by default for the Turing image as it suffers from precision issues.
You can turn Flash Attention v1 ON by using the `USE_FLASH_ATTENTION=True` environment variable.

### API documentation

You can consult the OpenAPI documentation of the `text-embeddings-inference` REST API using the `/docs` route.
The Swagger UI is also available
at: [https://huggingface.github.io/text-embeddings-inference](https://huggingface.github.io/text-embeddings-inference).

### Using a private or gated model

You have the option to utilize the `HF_TOKEN` environment variable for configuring the token employed by
`text-embeddings-inference`. This allows you to gain access to protected resources.

For example:

1. Go to https://huggingface.co/settings/tokens
2. Copy your cli READ token
3. Export `HF_TOKEN=&lt;your cli READ token&gt;`

or with Docker:

```shell
model=&lt;your private model&gt;
volume=$PWD/data # share a volume with the Docker container to avoid downloading weights every run
token=&lt;your cli READ token&gt;

docker run --gpus all -e HF_TOKEN=$token -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id $model
```

### Air gapped deployment

To deploy Text Embeddings Inference in an air-gapped environment, first download the weights and then mount them inside
the container using a volume.

For example:

```shell
# (Optional) create a `models` directory
mkdir models
cd models

# Make sure you have git-lfs installed (https://git-lfs.com)
git lfs install
git clone https://huggingface.co/Alibaba-NLP/gte-base-en-v1.5

# Set the models directory as the volume path
volume=$PWD

# Mount the models directory inside the container with a volume and set the model ID
docker run --gpus all -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id /data/gte-base-en-v1.5
```

### Using Re-rankers models

`text-embeddings-inference` v0.4.0 added support for CamemBERT, RoBERTa, XLM-RoBERTa, and GTE Sequence Classification models.
Re-rankers models are Sequence Classification cross-encoders models with a single class that scores the similarity
between a query and a text.

See [this blogpost](https://blog.llamaindex.ai/boosting-rag-picking-the-best-embedding-reranker-models-42d079022e83) by
the LlamaIndex team to understand how you can use re-rankers models in your RAG pipeline to improve
downstream performance.

```shell
model=BAAI/bge-reranker-large
volume=$PWD/data # share a volume with the Docker container to avoid downloading weights every run

docker run --gpus all -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id $model
```

And then you can rank the similarity between a query and a list of texts with:

```bash
curl 127.0.0.1:8080/rerank \
    -X POST \
    -d &#039;{&quot;query&quot;: &quot;What is Deep Learning?&quot;, &quot;texts&quot;: [&quot;Deep Learning is not...&quot;, &quot;Deep learning is...&quot;]}&#039; \
    -H &#039;Content-Type: application/json&#039;
```

### Using Sequence Classification models

You can also use classic Sequence Classification models like `SamLowe/roberta-base-go_emotions`:

```shell
model=SamLowe/roberta-base-go_emotions
volume=$PWD/data # share a volume with the Docker container to avoid downloading weights every run

docker run --gpus all -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id $model
```

Once you have deployed the model you can use the `predict` endpoint to get the emotions most associated with an input:

```bash
curl 127.0.0.1:8080/predict \
    -X POST \
    -d &#039;{&quot;inputs&quot;:&quot;I like you.&quot;}&#039; \
    -H &#039;Content-Type: application/json&#039;
```

### Using SPLADE pooling

You can choose to activate SPLADE pooling for Bert and Distilbert MaskedLM architectures:

```shell
model=naver/efficient-splade-VI-BT-large-query
volume=$PWD/data # share a volume with the Docker container to avoid downloading weights every run

docker run --gpus all -p 8080:80 -v $volume:/data --pull always ghcr.io/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference:1.6 --model-id $model --pooling splade
```

Once you have deployed the model you can use the `/embed_sparse` endpoint to get the sparse embedding:

```bash
curl 127.0.0.1:8080/embed_sparse \
    -X POST \
    -d &#039;{&quot;inputs&quot;:&quot;I like you.&quot;}&#039; \
    -H &#039;Content-Type: application/json&#039;
```

### Distributed Tracing

`text-embeddings-inference` is instrumented with distributed tracing using OpenTelemetry. You can use this feature
by setting the address to an OTLP collector with the `--otlp-endpoint` argument.

### gRPC

`text-embeddings-inference` offers a gRPC API as an alternative to the default HTTP API for high performance
deployments. The API protobuf definition can be
found [here](https://github.com/huggingface/text-embeddings-inference/blob/main/proto/tei.proto).

You can use the gRPC API by adding the `-grpc` tag to any TEI Docker image. For example:

```shell
model=BAAI/

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[block/goose]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/block/goose</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/block/goose</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[an open source, extensible AI agent that goes beyond code suggestions - install, execute, edit, and test with any LLM]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/block/goose">block/goose</a></h1>
            <p>an open source, extensible AI agent that goes beyond code suggestions - install, execute, edit, and test with any LLM</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,985</p>
            <p>Forks: 792</p>
            <p>Stars today: 51 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# codename goose

_a local, extensible, open source AI agent that automates engineering tasks_

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2.0&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache_2.0-blue.svg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/7GaTvbDwga&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/1287729918100246654?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;label=Join+Us&amp;color=blueviolet&quot; alt=&quot;Discord&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/block/goose/actions/workflows/ci.yml&quot;&gt;
     &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/block/goose/ci.yml?branch=main&quot; alt=&quot;CI&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

goose is your on-machine AI agent, capable of automating complex development tasks from start to finish. More than just code suggestions, goose can build entire projects from scratch, write and execute code, debug failures, orchestrate workflows, and interact with external APIs - _autonomously_.

Whether you&#039;re prototyping an idea, refining existing code, or managing intricate engineering pipelines, goose adapts to your workflow and executes tasks with precision.

Designed for maximum flexibility, goose works with any LLM and seamlessly integrates with MCP-enabled APIs, making it the ultimate AI-powered assistant for developers who want to move faster and focus on innovation. 


# Quick Links
- [Quickstart](https://block.github.io/goose/docs/quickstart)
- [Installation](https://block.github.io/goose/docs/getting-started/installation)
- [Tutorials](https://block.github.io/goose/docs/category/tutorials)
- [Documentation](https://block.github.io/goose/docs/category/getting-started)


# Goose Around with Us
- [Discord](https://discord.gg/block-opensource)
- [YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/@blockopensource)
- [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/company/block-opensource)
- [Twitter/X](https://x.com/blockopensource)
- [Bluesky](https://bsky.app/profile/opensource.block.xyz)
- [Nostr](https://njump.me/opensource@block.xyz)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[paritytech/polkadot-sdk]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Parity Polkadot Blockchain SDK]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk">paritytech/polkadot-sdk</a></h1>
            <p>The Parity Polkadot Blockchain SDK</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,177</p>
            <p>Forks: 871</p>
            <p>Stars today: 1 star today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

![SDK Logo](./docs/images/Polkadot_Logo_Horizontal_Pink_White.png#gh-dark-mode-only)
![SDK Logo](./docs/images/Polkadot_Logo_Horizontal_Pink_Black.png#gh-light-mode-only)

# Polkadot SDK

![GitHub stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/paritytech/polkadot-sdk)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;![GitHub
forks](https://img.shields.io/github/forks/paritytech/polkadot-sdk)

&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable-next-line MD013 --&gt;
[![StackExchange](https://img.shields.io/badge/StackExchange-Community%20&amp;%20Support-222222?logo=stackexchange)](https://substrate.stackexchange.com/)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;![GitHub contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/paritytech/polkadot-sdk)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;![GitHub commit activity](https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/paritytech/polkadot-sdk)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;![GitHub last commit](https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/paritytech/polkadot-sdk)

&gt; The Polkadot SDK repository provides all the components needed to start building on the
&gt; [Polkadot](https://polkadot.com/) network, a multi-chain blockchain platform that enables
&gt; different blockchains to interoperate and share information in a secure and scalable way.

&lt;/div&gt;

## ⚡ Quickstart
If you want to get an example node running quickly you can execute the following getting started script:

```
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://raw.githubusercontent.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk/master/scripts/getting-started.sh | bash
```

## 📚 Documentation

* [Polkadot Documentation Portal](https://docs.polkadot.com)
* [🦀 rust-docs](https://paritytech.github.io/polkadot-sdk/master/polkadot_sdk_docs/index.html): Where we keep track of
the API docs of our Rust crates. Includes:
  * [Introduction](https://paritytech.github.io/polkadot-sdk/master/polkadot_sdk_docs/polkadot_sdk/index.html)
	to each component of the Polkadot SDK: Substrate, FRAME, Cumulus, and XCM
  * [Guides](https://paritytech.github.io/polkadot-sdk/master/polkadot_sdk_docs/guides/index.html),
	namely how to build your first FRAME pallet
  * [Templates](https://paritytech.github.io/polkadot-sdk/master/polkadot_sdk_docs/polkadot_sdk/templates/index.html)
    for starting a new project.
  * [External Resources](https://paritytech.github.io/polkadot-sdk/master/polkadot_sdk_docs/external_resources/index.html)

## 🚀 Releases

&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable-next-line MD013 --&gt;
![Current Stable Release](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/paritytech/release-registry/main/badges/polkadot-sdk-latest.svg)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;![Next Stable Release](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/paritytech/release-registry/main/badges/polkadot-sdk-next.svg)

The Polkadot SDK is released every three months as a `Polkadot stableYYMM` release. Each stable release is supported for
one year with patches. See the next upcoming versions in the [Release
Registry](https://github.com/paritytech/release-registry/) and more docs in [RELEASE.md](./docs/RELEASE.md).

You can use [`psvm`](https://github.com/paritytech/psvm) to update all dependencies to a specific
version without needing to manually select the correct version for each crate.

## 🛠️ Tooling

[Polkadot SDK Version Manager](https://github.com/paritytech/psvm):
A simple tool to manage and update the Polkadot SDK dependencies in any Cargo.toml file.
It will automatically update the Polkadot SDK dependencies to their correct crates.io version.

## 🔐 Security

The security policy and procedures can be found in
[docs/contributor/SECURITY.md](./docs/contributor/SECURITY.md).

## 🤍 Contributing &amp; Code of Conduct

Ensure you follow our [contribution guidelines](./docs/contributor/CONTRIBUTING.md). In every
interaction and contribution, this project adheres to the [Contributor Covenant Code of
Conduct](./docs/contributor/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md).

### 👾 Ready to Contribute?

Take a look at the issues labeled with [`mentor`](https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk/labels/C1-mentor)
(or alternatively [this](https://mentor.tasty.limo/) page, created by one of the maintainers) label to get started!
We always recognize valuable contributions by proposing an on-chain tip to the Polkadot network as a token of our
appreciation.

## Polkadot Fellowship

Development in this repo usually goes hand in hand with the `fellowship` organization. In short,
this repository provides all the SDK pieces needed to build both Polkadot and its parachains. But,
the actual Polkadot runtime lives in the `fellowship/runtimes` repository. Read more about the
fellowship, this separation, the RFC process
[here](https://polkadot-fellows.github.io/dashboard/).

## History

This repository is the amalgamation of 3 separate repositories that used to make up Polkadot SDK,
namely Substrate, Polkadot and Cumulus. Read more about the merge and its history
[here](https://polkadot-public.notion.site/Polkadot-SDK-FAQ-fbc4cecc2c46443fb37b9eeec2f0d85f).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[firecracker-microvm/firecracker]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Secure and fast microVMs for serverless computing.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker">firecracker-microvm/firecracker</a></h1>
            <p>Secure and fast microVMs for serverless computing.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 27,382</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,898</p>
            <p>Stars today: 13 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;picture&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;docs/images/fc_logo_full_transparent-bg_white-fg.png&quot;&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;docs/images/fc_logo_full_transparent-bg.png&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Firecracker Logo Title&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; src=&quot;docs/images/fc_logo_full_transparent-bg.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

Our mission is to enable secure, multi-tenant, minimal-overhead execution of
container and function workloads.

Read more about the Firecracker Charter [here](CHARTER.md).

## What is Firecracker?

Firecracker is an open source virtualization technology that is purpose-built
for creating and managing secure, multi-tenant container and function-based
services that provide serverless operational models. Firecracker runs workloads
in lightweight virtual machines, called microVMs, which combine the security and
isolation properties provided by hardware virtualization technology with the
speed and flexibility of containers.

## Overview

The main component of Firecracker is a virtual machine monitor (VMM) that uses
the Linux Kernel Virtual Machine (KVM) to create and run microVMs. Firecracker
has a minimalist design. It excludes unnecessary devices and guest-facing
functionality to reduce the memory footprint and attack surface area of each
microVM. This improves security, decreases the startup time, and increases
hardware utilization. Firecracker has also been integrated in container
runtimes, for example
[Kata Containers](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers) and
[Flintlock](https://github.com/liquidmetal-dev/flintlock).

Firecracker was developed at Amazon Web Services to accelerate the speed and
efficiency of services like [AWS Lambda](https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/) and
[AWS Fargate](https://aws.amazon.com/fargate/). Firecracker is open sourced
under [Apache version 2.0](LICENSE).

To read more about Firecracker, check out
[firecracker-microvm.io](https://firecracker-microvm.github.io).

## Getting Started

To get started with Firecracker, download the latest
[release](https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/releases) binaries
or build it from source.

You can build Firecracker on any Unix/Linux system that has Docker running (we
use a development container) and `bash` installed, as follows:

```bash
git clone https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker
cd firecracker
tools/devtool build
toolchain=&quot;$(uname -m)-unknown-linux-musl&quot;
```

The Firecracker binary will be placed at
`build/cargo_target/${toolchain}/debug/firecracker`. For more information on
building, testing, and running Firecracker, go to the
[quickstart guide](docs/getting-started.md).

The overall security of Firecracker microVMs, including the ability to meet the
criteria for safe multi-tenant computing, depends on a well configured Linux
host operating system. A configuration that we believe meets this bar is
included in [the production host setup document](docs/prod-host-setup.md).

## Contributing

Firecracker is already running production workloads within AWS, but it&#039;s still
Day 1 on the journey guided by our [mission](CHARTER.md). There&#039;s a lot more to
build and we welcome all contributions.

To contribute to Firecracker, check out the development setup section in the
[getting started guide](docs/getting-started.md) and then the Firecracker
[contribution guidelines](CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Releases

New Firecracker versions are released via the GitHub repository
[releases](https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/releases) page,
typically every two or three months. A history of changes is recorded in our
[changelog](CHANGELOG.md).

The Firecracker release policy is detailed [here](docs/RELEASE_POLICY.md).

## Design

Firecracker&#039;s overall architecture is described in
[the design document](docs/design.md).

## Features &amp; Capabilities

Firecracker consists of a single micro Virtual Machine Manager process that
exposes an API endpoint to the host once started. The API is
[specified in OpenAPI format](src/firecracker/swagger/firecracker.yaml). Read
more about it in the [API docs](docs/api_requests).

The **API endpoint** can be used to:

- Configure the microvm by:
  - Setting the number of vCPUs (the default is 1).
  - Setting the memory size (the default is 128 MiB).
  - Configuring a [CPU template](docs/cpu_templates/cpu-templates.md).
- Add one or more network interfaces to the microVM.
- Add one or more read-write or read-only disks to the microVM, each represented
  by a file-backed block device.
- Trigger a block device re-scan while the guest is running. This enables the
  guest OS to pick up size changes to the block device&#039;s backing file.
- Change the backing file for a block device, before or after the guest boots.
- Configure rate limiters for virtio devices which can limit the bandwidth,
  operations per second, or both.
- Configure the logging and metric system.
- `[BETA]` Configure the data tree of the guest-facing metadata service. The
  service is only available to the guest if this resource is configured.
- Add a [vsock socket](docs/vsock.md) to the microVM.
- Add a [entropy device](docs/entropy.md) to the microVM.
- Start the microVM using a given kernel image, root file system, and boot
  arguments.
- [x86_64 only] Stop the microVM.

**Built-in Capabilities**:

- Demand fault paging and CPU oversubscription enabled by default.
- Advanced, thread-specific seccomp filters for enhanced security.
- [Jailer](docs/jailer.md) process for starting Firecracker in production
  scenarios; applies a cgroup/namespace isolation barrier and then drops
  privileges.

## Tested platforms

We test all combinations of:

| Instance       | Host OS &amp; Kernel | Guest Rootfs | Guest Kernel |
| :------------- | :--------------- | :----------- | :----------- |
| c5n.metal      | al2 linux_5.10   | ubuntu 24.04 | linux_5.10   |
| m5n.metal      | al2023 linux_6.1 |              | linux_6.1    |
| m6i.metal      |                  |              |              |
| m6a.metal      |                  |              |              |
| m7a.metal-48xl |                  |              |              |
| m6g.metal      |                  |              |              |
| m7g.metal      |                  |              |              |

## Known issues and Limitations

- The `pl031` RTC device on aarch64 does not support interrupts, so guest
  programs which use an RTC alarm (e.g. `hwclock`) will not work.

## Performance

Firecracker&#039;s performance characteristics are listed as part of the
[specification documentation](SPECIFICATION.md). All specifications are a part
of our commitment to supporting container and function workloads in serverless
operational models, and are therefore enforced via continuous integration
testing.

## Policy for Security Disclosures

The security of Firecracker is our top priority. If you suspect you have
uncovered a vulnerability, contact us privately, as outlined in our
[security policy document](SECURITY.md); we will immediately prioritize your
disclosure.

## FAQ &amp; Contact

Frequently asked questions are collected in our [FAQ doc](FAQ.md).

You can get in touch with the Firecracker community in the following ways:

- Security-related issues, see our [security policy document](SECURITY.md).
- Chat with us on our
  [Slack workspace](https://join.slack.com/t/firecracker-microvm/shared_invite/zt-2tc0mfxpc-tU~HYAYSzLDl5XGGJU3YIg)
  _Note: most of the maintainers are on a European time zone._
- Open a GitHub issue in this repository.
- Email the maintainers at
  [firecracker-maintainers@amazon.com](mailto:firecracker-maintainers@amazon.com).

When communicating within the Firecracker community, please mind our
[code of conduct](CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[web-infra-dev/rspack]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The fast Rust-based web bundler with webpack-compatible API 🦀️]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack">web-infra-dev/rspack</a></h1>
            <p>The fast Rust-based web bundler with webpack-compatible API 🦀️</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,188</p>
            <p>Forks: 632</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;picture&gt;
  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://assets.rspack.dev/rspack/rspack-banner-plain-dark.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Rspack Banner&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.rspack.dev/rspack/rspack-banner-plain-light.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

# Rspack

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/79ZZ66GH9E&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-discord-blue?style=flat-square&amp;logo=discord&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;discord channel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rspack/core?activeTab=readme&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@rspack/core?style=flat-square&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;npm version&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://npmcharts.com/compare/@rspack/core?minimal=true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/@rspack/core.svg?style=flat-square&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;downloads&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/en/about/previous-releases&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/node/v/@rspack/core.svg?style=flat-square&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;node version&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-blue.svg?style=flat-square&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;license&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://codspeed.io/web-infra-dev/rspack&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcodspeed.io%2Fbadge.json&amp;style=flat-square&amp;colorA=564341&amp;colorB=EDED91&quot; alt=&quot;codspeed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

English | [简体中文](./README.zh-CN.md)

Rspack is a high performance JavaScript bundler written in Rust. It offers strong compatibility with the webpack ecosystem, allowing for seamless replacement of webpack, and provides lightning fast build speeds.

## ✨ Features

- 🚀 **Fast Startup**: Based on Rust, the build speed is extremely fast, bringing you the ultimate development experience.
- ⚡ **Lightning HMR**: With a built-in incremental compilation mechanism, HMR is extremely fast and fully capable of developing large-scale projects.
- 📦 **Webpack Compatible**: Compatible with plugins and loaders in the webpack ecosystem, seamlessly integrating excellent libraries built by the community.
- 🎨 **Module Federation**: Provide first-class support for Module Federation to facilitate the development of large-scale web applications.
- 🛠️ **Production Optimization**: Various optimization strategies are built in by default, such as tree shaking, minification, etc.
- 🎯 **Framework Agnostic**: Not bound to any frontend framework, ensuring enough flexibility.

Read [Introduction](https://rspack.dev/guide/start/introduction) for details.

## Getting started

See [Quick start](https://rspack.dev/guide/start/quick-start).

## Contribution

Please read the [contributing guide](./CONTRIBUTING.md) and let&#039;s build Rspack together.

### Code of conduct

This repo has adopted the ByteDance Open Source Code of Conduct. Please check [Code of conduct](./CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md) for more details.

## Community

Come chat with us on [Discord](https://discord.gg/79ZZ66GH9E)! Rspack team and Rspack users are active there, and we&#039;re always looking for contributions.

## Links

| Name                                                                                 | Description                                                                     |
| ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| [awesome-rspack](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/awesome-rspack)                    | A curated list of awesome things related to Rspack                              |
| [Rspack 1.x documentation](https://rspack.dev/)                                      | Documentation for Rspack 1.x (latest)                                           |
| [Rspack 0.x documentation](https://v0.rspack.dev/)                                   | Documentation for Rspack 0.x version                                            |
| [Rsbuild](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rsbuild)                                  | An out-of-the-box build tool based on Rspack                                    |
| [Rspress](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspress)                                  | A fast static site generator based on Rsbuild                                   |
| [Rsdoctor](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rsdoctor)                                | A one-stop build analyzer for Rspack                                            |
| [Rslib](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rslib)                                      | A library development tool powered by Rsbuild                                   |
| [rspack-dev-server](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack-dev-server)              | Dev server for Rspack                                                           |
| [rstack-examples](https://github.com/rspack-contrib/rstack-examples)                 | Examples showcasing Rstack ecosystem tools (Rspack, Rsbuild, Rspress, Rsdoctor) |
| [rspack-sources](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack-sources)                    | Rust port of [webpack-sources](https://www.npmjs.com/package/webpack-sources)   |
| [rstack-design-resources](https://github.com/rspack-contrib/rstack-design-resources) | Design resources for Rspack Stack                                               |

## Contributors

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://opencollective.com/rspack/contributors.svg?width=890&amp;button=false&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Benchmark

See [Benchmark](https://web-infra-dev.github.io/rspack-ecosystem-benchmark/).

## Credits

Thanks to:

- [The webpack team and community](https://webpack.js.org/) for creating a great bundler and ecosystem from which we draw a lot of inspiration.
- [@sokra](https://github.com/sokra) for the great work on the [webpack](https://github.com/webpack/webpack) project.
- [@ScriptedAlchemy](https://github.com/ScriptedAlchemy) for creating Module Federation and helping Rspack connect with the community.
- The [SWC](https://github.com/swc-project/swc) project created by [@kdy1](https://github.com/kdy1), which powers Rspack&#039;s code parsing, transformation and minification.
- The [esbuild](https://github.com/evanw/esbuild) project created by [@evanw](https://github.com/evanw), which inspired the concurrent architecture of Rspack.
- The [NAPI-RS](https://github.com/napi-rs/napi-rs) project created by [@Brooooooklyn](https://github.com/Brooooooklyn), which powers Rspack&#039;s node-binding implementation.
- The [Parcel](https://github.com/parcel-bundler/parcel) project created by [@devongovett](https://github.com/devongovett) which is the pioneer of rust bundler and inspired Rspack&#039;s incremental rebuild design.
- The [Vite](https://github.com/vitejs/vite) project created by [Evan You](https://github.com/yyx990803) which inspired Rspack&#039;s compatibility design of webpack&#039;s ecosystem.
- The `rolldown-legacy` project created by old Rolldown team, It&#039;s the predecessor of the [rolldown](https://github.com/rolldown) project, which explores the possibility of making a performant bundler in Rust with Rollup-compatible API. It inspires the design principles of Rspack.
- The [html-webpack-plugin](https://github.com/jantimon/html-webpack-plugin) project created by [@jantimon](https://github.com/jantimon), `@rspack/html-plugin` is a fork of [html-webpack-plugin](https://github.com/jantimon/html-webpack-plugin) to avoid some webpack API usage not supported in Rspack.
- The [Turbopack](https://github.com/vercel/turbo) project which inspired the AST path logic of Rspack.
- The [react-refresh-webpack-plugin](https://github.com/pmmmwh/react-refresh-webpack-plugin) created by [@pmmmwh](https://github.com/pmmmwh), which inspires implement [react refresh rspack plugin](https://github.com/rspack-contrib/rspack-plugin-react-refresh).
- The [prefresh](https://github.com/preactjs/prefresh) created by [@Jovi De Croock](https://github.com/JoviDeCroock), which inspires implement [preact refresh rspack plugin](https://github.com/rspack-contrib/rspack-plugin-preact-refresh).
- The [mini-css-extract-plugin](https://github.com/webpack-contrib/mini-css-extract-plugin) project created by [@sokra](https://github.com/sokra) which inspired implement css extract plugin.
- The [copy-webpack-plugin](https://github.com/webpack-contrib/copy-webpack-plugin) project created by [@kevlened](https://github.com/kevlened) which inspired implement copy rspack plugin.
- The [webpack-subresource-integrity](https://github.com/waysact/webpack-subresource-integrity) project created by [@jscheid](https://github.com/jscheid), which inspires implement subresource integrity rspack plugin.
- The [circular-dependency-plugin](https://github.com/aackerman/circular-dependency-plugin) project created by [@aackerman](https://github.com/aackerman), which inspres implement circular dependency rspack plugin.

## License

Rspack is [MIT licensed](https://github.com/web-infra-dev/rspack/blob/main/LICENSE).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mullvad/mullvadvpn-app]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Mullvad VPN client app for desktop and mobile]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app">mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</a></h1>
            <p>The Mullvad VPN client app for desktop and mobile</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,613</p>
            <p>Forks: 384</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Mullvad VPN desktop and mobile app

Welcome to the Mullvad VPN client app source code repository.
This is the VPN client software for the Mullvad VPN service.
For more information about the service, please visit our website,
[mullvad.net](https://mullvad.net) (Also accessible via Tor on our
[onion service](http://o54hon2e2vj6c7m3aqqu6uyece65by3vgoxxhlqlsvkmacw6a7m7kiad.onion/)).

This repository contains all the source code for the
desktop and mobile versions of the app. For desktop this includes the system service/daemon
([`mullvad-daemon`](mullvad-daemon/)), a graphical user interface ([GUI](desktop/)) and a command
line interface ([CLI](mullvad-cli/)). The Android app uses the same backing system service for the
tunnel and security but has a dedicated frontend in [android/](android/). iOS consists of a
completely standalone implementation that resides in [ios/](ios/).

## Releases

There are built and signed releases for macOS, Windows, Linux and Android available on
[our website](https://mullvad.net/download/) and on
[GitHub](https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app/releases/). The Android app is also available
on [Google Play] and [F-Droid] and the iOS version on [App Store].

[Google Play]: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.mullvad.mullvadvpn
[F-Droid]: https://f-droid.org/packages/net.mullvad.mullvadvpn/
[App Store]: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mullvad-vpn/id1488466513

You can find our code signing keys as well as instructions for how to cryptographically verify
your download on [Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page].

### Platform/OS support

These are the operating systems and their versions that the app officially supports. It might
work on many more versions, but we don&#039;t test for those and can&#039;t guarantee the quality or
security.

| OS/Platform | Supported versions |
|-------------|--------------------|
| Windows     | 10 and 11          |
| macOS       | The three latest major releases |
| Linux (Ubuntu)| The two latest LTS releases and the latest non-LTS releases |
| Linux (Fedora) | The versions that are not yet [EOL](https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/End_of_life) |
| Linux (Debian) | 12 and newer    |
| Android     | 8 and newer        |
| iOS         | 15.0 and newer     |

On Linux we test using the Gnome desktop environment. The app should, and probably does work
in other DEs, but we don&#039;t regularly test those.

## Features

Here is a table containing the features of the app across platforms. This is intended to reflect
the current state of the latest code in git, not necessarily any existing release.

|                               | Windows | Linux | macOS | Android | iOS |
|-------------------------------|:-------:|:-----:|:-----:|:-------:|:---:|
| OpenVPN                       |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |         |     |
| WireGuard                     |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Quantum-resistant tunnels     |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| [DAITA]                       |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard multihop            |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard over TCP            |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard over Shadowsocks    |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| OpenVPN over Shadowsocks      |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |         |     |
| Split tunneling               |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |     |
| Custom DNS server             |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Content blockers (Ads etc)    |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Optional local network access |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓\* |
| [Externally audited](./audits)|    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓ |

\* The local network is always accessible on iOS with the current implementation

[DAITA]: https://mullvad.net/en/blog/introducing-defense-against-ai-guided-traffic-analysis-daita

## Security and anonymity

This app is a privacy preserving VPN client. As such it goes to great lengths to stop traffic
leaks. And basically all settings default to the more secure/private option. The user has to
explicitly allow more loose rules if desired. See the [dedicated security document] for details
on what the app blocks and allows, as well as how it does it.

[dedicated security document]: docs/security.md

## Checking out the code

This repository contains submodules needed for building the app. However, some of those submodules
also have further submodules that are quite large and not needed to build the app. So unless
you want the source code for OpenSSL, OpenVPN and a few other projects you should avoid a recursive
clone of the repository. Instead clone the repository normally and then get one level of submodules:
```bash
git clone https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app.git
cd mullvadvpn-app
git submodule update --init
```

On Android, Windows, Linux and macOS you also want to checkout the wireguard-go submodule:
```bash
git submodule update --init wireguard-go-rs/libwg/wireguard-go
```
Further details on why this is necessary can be found in the [wireguard-go-rs crate](./wireguard-go-rs/README.md).

We sign every commit on the `main` branch as well as our release tags. If you would like to verify
your checkout, you can find our developer keys on [Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page].

### Binaries submodule

This repository has a git submodule at `dist-assets/binaries`. This submodule contains binaries and
build scripts for third party code we need to bundle with the app. Such as OpenVPN, Wintun
etc.

This submodule conforms to the same integrity/security standards as this repository. Every merge
commit should be signed. And this main repository should only ever point to a signed merge commit
of the binaries submodule.

See the [binaries submodule&#039;s](https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app-binaries) README for more
details about that repository.

## Building the app

See the [build instructions](BuildInstructions.md) for help building the app on desktop platforms.

For building the Android app, see the [instructions](./android/BuildInstructions.md) for Android.

For building the iOS app, see the [instructions](./ios/BuildInstructions.md) for iOS.

## Releasing the app

See [this](Release.md) for instructions on how to make a new release.

## Environment variables used by the service

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DEBUG` - Helps debugging the firewall. Does different things depending on
  platform:
  * Linux: Set to `&quot;1&quot;` to add packet counters to all firewall rules.
  * macOS: Makes rules log the packets they match to the `pflog0` interface.
    * Set to `&quot;all&quot;` to add logging to all rules.
    * Set to `&quot;pass&quot;` to add logging to rules allowing packets.
    * Set to `&quot;drop&quot;` to add logging to rules blocking packets.

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DONT_SET_SRC_VALID_MARK` - Set this variable to `1` to stop the daemon from
    setting the `net.ipv4.conf.all.src_valid_mark` kernel parameter to `1` on Linux when a tunnel
    is established.
    The kernel config parameter is set by default, because otherwise strict reverse path filtering
    may prevent relay traffic from reaching the daemon. If `rp_filter` is set to `1` on the interface
    that will be receiving relay traffic, and `src_valid_mark` is not set to `1`, the daemon will
    not be able to receive relay traffic.

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DONT_SET_ARP_IGNORE` - Set this variable to `1` to stop the daemon from
    setting the `net.ipv4.conf.all.arp_ignore` kernel parameter to `2` on Linux when a tunnel
    is established.
    The kernel config parameter is set by default, because otherwise an attacker who can send ARP
    requests to the device running Mullvad can figure out the in-tunnel IP.

* `TALPID_DNS_MODULE` - Allows changing the method that will be used for DNS configuration.
  By default this is automatically detected, but you can set it to one of the options below to
  choose a specific method.

  * Linux
    * `&quot;static-file&quot;`: change the `/etc/resolv.conf` file directly
    * `&quot;resolvconf&quot;`: use the `resolvconf` program
    * `&quot;systemd&quot;`: use systemd&#039;s `resolved` service through DBus
    * `&quot;network-manager&quot;`: use `NetworkManager` service through DBus

  * Windows
    * `iphlpapi`: use the IP helper API
    * `netsh`: use the `netsh` program
    * `tcpip`: set TCP/IP parameters in the registry

* `TALPID_FORCE_USERSPACE_WIREGUARD` - Forces the daemon to use the userspace implementation of
   WireGuard on Linux.

* `TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR` - Forces the daemon to always assume the host is online.

* `TALPID_NET_CLS_MOUNT_DIR` - On Linux, forces the daemon to mount the `net_cls` controller in the
  specified directory if it isn&#039;t mounted already.

* `MULLVAD_MANAGEMENT_SOCKET_GROUP` - On Linux and macOS, this restricts access to the management
  interface UDS socket to users in the specified group. This means that only users in that group can
  use the CLI and GUI. By default, everyone has access to the socket.

* `MULLVAD_BACKTRACE_ON_FAULT` - When enabled, if the daemon encounters a fault (e.g. `SIGSEGV`),
  it will log a backtrace to stdout, and to `daemon.log`. By default, this is disabled in
  release-builds and enabled in debug-builds. Set variable to `1` or `0` to explicitly enable or
  disable this feature. Logging the backtrace cause heap allocation. Allocation is not signal safe,
  but here it runs in the signal handler. This in technically undefined behavior and therefore
  disabled by default. This usually works, but enable at your own risk.

### Development builds only

* `MULLVAD_API_HOST` - Set the hostname to use in API requests. E.g. `api.mullvad.net`.

* `MULLVAD_API_ADDR` - Set the IP address and port to use in API requests. E.g. `10.10.1.2:443`.

* `MULLVAD_API_DISABLE_TLS` - Use plain HTTP for API requests.

* `MULLVAD_CONNCHECK_HOST` - Set the hostname to use in connection check requests. E.g. `am.i.mullvad.net`.

### Setting environment variables

#### Windows

Use `setx` from an elevated shell:

```bat
setx TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE 1 /m
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bat
sc.exe stop mullvadvpn
sc.exe start mullvadvpn
```

#### Linux

Edit the systemd unit file via `systemctl edit mullvad-daemon.service`:

```ini
[Service]
Environment=&quot;TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR=1&quot;
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bash
sudo systemctl restart mullvad-daemon
```

#### macOS

Use `plutil`:

```bash
sudo plutil -replace EnvironmentVariables -json &#039;{&quot;TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR&quot;: &quot;1&quot;}&#039; /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bash
launchctl unload -w /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
launchctl load -w /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
```

## Environment variables used by the desktop frontend

* `MULLVAD_PATH` - Allows changing the path to the folder with the `mullvad-problem-report` tool
   when running in development mode. Defaults to: `&lt;repo&gt;/target/debug/`.
* `MULLVAD_DISABLE_UPDATE_NOTIFICATION` - If set to `1`, notification will be disabled when
   an update is available.


## Command line tools for Electron app development

- `$ npm run develop` - develop app with live-reload enabled
- `$ npm run lint` - lint code
- `$ npm run pack:&lt;OS&gt;` - prepare app for distribution for your platform. Where `&lt;OS&gt;` can be
  `linux`, `mac` or `win`
- `$ npm test` - run tests


## Tray icon on Linux

The requirements for displaying a tray icon varies between different desktop environments. If the
tray icon doesn&#039;t appear, try installing one of these packages:
- `libappindicator3-1`
- `libappindicator1`
- `libappindicator`

If you&#039;re using GNOME, try installing one of these GNOME Shell extensions:
- `TopIconsFix`
- `TopIcons Plus`


## Repository structure

### Electron app and electron-builder packaging assets
- **desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/**
  - **assets/** - Graphical assets and stylesheets
  - **src/**
    - **main/**
      - **index.ts** - Entry file for the main process
    - **renderer/**
      - **app.tsx** - Entry file for the renderer process
      - **routes.tsx** - Routes configurator
      - **transitions.ts** - Transition rules between views
  - **tasks/** - Gulp tasks used to build app and watch for changes during development
    - **distribution.js** - Configuration for `electron-builder`
  - **test/** - Electron GUI tests
- **dist-assets/** - Icons, binaries and other files used when creating the distributables
  - **binaries/** - Git submodule containing binaries bundled with the app. For example the
    statically linked OpenVPN binary. See the README in the submodule for details
  - **linux/** - Scripts and configuration files for the deb and rpm artifacts
  - **pkg-scripts/** - Scripts bundled with and executed by the macOS pkg installer
  - **windows/** - Windows NSIS installer configuration and assets
  - **ca.crt** - The Mullvad relay server root CA. Bundled with the app and only OpenVPN relays
    signed by this CA are trusted


### Building, testing and misc
- **build-windows-modules.sh** - Compiles the C++ libraries needed on Windows
- **build.sh** - Sanity checks the working directory state and then builds installers for the app

### Mullvad Daemon

The daemon is implemented in Rust and is implemented in several crates. The main, or top level,
crate that builds the final daemon binary is `mullvad-daemon` which then depend on the others.

In general one can look at the daemon as split into two parts, the crates starting with `talpid`
and the crates starting with `mullvad`. The `talpid` crates are supposed to be completely unrelated
to Mullvad specific things. A `talpid` crate is not allowed to know anything about the API through
which the daemon fetch Mullvad account details or download VPN server lists for example. The
`talpid` components should be viewed as a generic VPN client with extra privacy and anonymity
preserving features. The crates having `mullvad` in their name on the other hand make use of the
`talpid` components to build a secure and Mullvad specific VPN client.


- **Cargo.toml** - Main Rust workspace definition. See this file for which folders here are daemon
  Rust crates.
- **mullvad-daemon/** - Main Rust crate building the daemon binary.
- **talpid-core/** - Main crate of the VPN client implementation itself. Completely Mullvad agnostic
  privacy preserving VPN client library.


## Vocabulary

Explanations for some common words used in the documentation and code in this repository.

- **App** - This entire product (everything in this repository) is the &quot;Mullvad VPN App&quot;, or App for
  short.
  - **Daemon** - Refers to the `mullvad-daemon` Rust program. This headless program exposes a
    management interface that can be used to control the daemon
  - **Frontend** - Term used for any program or component that connects to the daemon management
    interface and allows a user to control the daemon.
    - **GUI** - The Electron + React program that is a graphical frontend for the Mullvad VPN App.
    - **CLI** - The Rust program named `mullvad` that is a terminal based frontend for the Mullvad
      VPN app.


## File paths used by Mullvad VPN app

A list of file paths written to and read from by the various components of the Mullvad VPN app

### Daemon

On Windows, when a process runs as a system service the variable `%LOCALAPPDATA%` expands to
`C:\Windows\system32\config\systemprofile\AppData\Local`.

All directory paths are defined in, and fetched from, the `mullvad-paths` crate.

#### Settings

The settings directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_SETTINGS_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/etc/mullvad-vpn/` |
| macOS | `/etc/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `%LOCALAPPDATA%\Mullvad VPN\` |
| Android | [`getFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getFilesDir()) |

#### Logs

The log directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_LOG_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/log/mullvad-vpn/` + systemd |
| macOS | `/var/log/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `C:\ProgramData\Mullvad VPN\` |
| Android | [`getFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getFilesDir()) |

#### Cache

The cache directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_CACHE_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/cache/mullvad-vpn/` |
| macOS | `/Library/Caches/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `C:\ProgramData\Mullvad VPN\cache` |
| Android | [`getCacheDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getCacheDir())  |

#### RPC address file

The full path to the RPC address file can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_RPC_SOCKET_PATH`
environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/run/mullvad-vpn` |
| macOS | `/var/run/mullvad-vpn` |
| Windows | `//./pipe/Mullvad VPN` |
| Android | [`getNoBackupFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/ContextWrapper#getNoBackupFilesDir()) |

### Desktop Electron app

The desktop Electron app has a specific settings file that is configured for each user. The path is
set in the `desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/src/main/gui-settings.ts` file.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/Mullvad VPN/gui_settings.json` |
| macOS | `~/Library/Application Support/Mullvad VPN/gui_settings.json` |
| Windows | `%LOCALAPPDATA%\Mullvad VPN\gui_settings.json` |
| Android | Present in Android&#039;s `logcat` |

## Icons

See [graphics README](graphics/README.md) for information about icons.

## Locales and translations

Instructions for how to handle locales and translations are found
[here](./desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/locales/README.md).

For instructions specific to the Android app, see [here](./android/README.md).

## Audits, pentests and external security reviews

Mullvad has used external pentesting companies to carry out security audits of this VPN app. Read
more about them in the [audits readme](./audits/README.md).

# License

Copyright (C) 2025  Mullvad VPN AB

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the
GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of
the License, or (at your option) any later version.

For the full license agreement, see the LICENSE.md file

The source code for the iOS app is GPL-3 licensed like everything else in this repository.
But the distributed app on the Apple App Store is not GPL licensed,
it falls under the [Apple App Store EULA].

[Apple App Store EULA]: https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/dev/stdeula/
[Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page]: https://mullvad.net/en/guides/open-source/
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[juhaku/utoipa]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Simple, Fast, Code first and Compile time generated OpenAPI documentation for Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa">juhaku/utoipa</a></h1>
            <p>Simple, Fast, Code first and Compile time generated OpenAPI documentation for Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,937</p>
            <p>Forks: 248</p>
            <p>Stars today: 8 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># utoipa - Auto-generated OpenAPI documentation

[![Utoipa build](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/actions/workflows/build.yaml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/actions/workflows/build.yaml)
[![crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/utoipa.svg?label=crates.io&amp;color=orange&amp;logo=rust)](https://crates.io/crates/utoipa)
[![docs.rs](https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=docs.rs&amp;message=utoipa&amp;color=blue&amp;logo=data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2ZyByb2xlPSJpbWciIHhtbG5zPSJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnczLm9yZy8yMDAwL3N2ZyIgdmlld0JveD0iMCAwIDUxMiA1MTIiPjxwYXRoIGZpbGw9IiNmNWY1ZjUiIGQ9Ik00ODguNiAyNTAuMkwzOTIgMjE0VjEwNS41YzAtMTUtOS4zLTI4LjQtMjMuNC0zMy43bC0xMDAtMzcuNWMtOC4xLTMuMS0xNy4xLTMuMS0yNS4zIDBsLTEwMCAzNy41Yy0xNC4xIDUuMy0yMy40IDE4LjctMjMuNCAzMy43VjIxNGwtOTYuNiAzNi4yQzkuMyAyNTUuNSAwIDI2OC45IDAgMjgzLjlWMzk0YzAgMTMuNiA3LjcgMjYuMSAxOS45IDMyLjJsMTAwIDUwYzEwLjEgNS4xIDIyLjEgNS4xIDMyLjIgMGwxMDMuOS01MiAxMDMuOSA1MmMxMC4xIDUuMSAyMi4xIDUuMSAzMi4yIDBsMTAwLTUwYzEyLjItNi4xIDE5LjktMTguNiAxOS45LTMyLjJWMjgzLjljMC0xNS05LjMtMjguNC0yMy40LTMzLjd6TTM1OCAyMTQuOGwtODUgMzEuOXYtNjguMmw4NS0zN3Y3My4zek0xNTQgMTA0LjFsMTAyLTM4LjIgMTAyIDM4LjJ2LjZsLTEwMiA0MS40LTEwMi00MS40di0uNnptODQgMjkxLjFsLTg1IDQyLjV2LTc5LjFsODUtMzguOHY3NS40em0wLTExMmwtMTAyIDQxLjQtMTAyLTQxLjR2LS42bDEwMi0zOC4yIDEwMiAzOC4ydi42em0yNDAgMTEybC04NSA0Mi41di03OS4xbDg1LTM4Ljh2NzUuNHptMC0xMTJsLTEwMiA0MS40LTEwMi00MS40di0uNmwxMDItMzguMiAxMDIgMzguMnYuNnoiPjwvcGF0aD48L3N2Zz4K)](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/)
![MSRV](https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=MSRV&amp;message=1.75&amp;color=orange&amp;logo=rust)

Pronounced **_/u:ˈtoʊ:i.pɑ/_** or **_/u:ˈtoʊˌaɪ.piˈeɪ/_** whatever works better for you.

Want to have your API documented with OpenAPI? But don&#039;t want to be bothered
with manual YAML or JSON tweaking? Would like it to be so easy that it would almost
be utopic? Don&#039;t worry: utoipa is here to fill this gap. It aims to do, if not all, then
most of the heavy lifting for you, enabling you to focus on writing the actual API logic instead of
documentation. It aims to be _minimal_, _simple_ and _fast_. It uses simple `proc` macros which
you can use to annotate your code to have items documented.

The `utoipa` crate provides auto-generated OpenAPI documentation for Rust REST APIs. It treats
code-first approach as a first class citizen and simplifies API documentation by providing
simple macros for generating the documentation from your code.

It also contains Rust types of the OpenAPI spec, allowing you to write the OpenAPI spec only using
Rust if auto generation is not your flavor or does not fit your purpose.

Long term goal of the library is to be the place to go when OpenAPI documentation is needed in any Rust
codebase.

Utoipa is framework-agnostic, and could be used together with any web framework, or even without one. While
being portable and standalone, one of its key aspects is simple integration with web frameworks.

## Choose your flavor and document your API with ice-cold IPA

|Flavor|Support|
|--|--|
|[actix-web](https://github.com/actix/actix-web)|Parse path, path parameters and query parameters, recognize request body and response body, [`utoipa-actix-web` bindings](./utoipa-actix-web/README.md). See more at [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#actix_extras-feature-support-for-actix-web)|
|[axum](https://github.com/tokio-rs/axum)|Parse path and query parameters, recognize request body and response body, [`utoipa-axum` bindings](./utoipa-axum/README.md). See more at [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#axum_extras-feature-support-for-axum)|
|[rocket](https://github.com/SergioBenitez/Rocket)| Parse path, path parameters and query parameters, recognize request body and response body. See more at [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#rocket_extras-feature-support-for-rocket)|
|Others*| Plain `utoipa` without extra flavor. This gives you all the basic benefits listed below in **[Features](#features)** section but with little less automation.|

&gt; Others* = For example [warp](https://github.com/seanmonstar/warp) but could be anything.

Refer to the existing [examples](./examples) to find out more.

## Features

* OpenAPI 3.1
* Pluggable, easy setup and integration with frameworks. 
* No bloat, enable what you need.
* Support for generic types
  * **Note!**&lt;br&gt;
    Tuples, arrays and slices cannot be used as generic arguments on types. Types implementing `ToSchema` manually should not have generic arguments, as
    they are not composeable and will result compile error.
* Automatic schema collection from usages recursively. 
  * Request body from either handler function arguments (if supported by framework) or from `request_body` attribute.
  * Response body from response `body` attribute or response `content` attribute.
* Various OpenAPI visualization tools supported out of the box.
* Rust type aliases via [`utoipa-config`](./utoipa-config/README.md).

## What&#039;s up with the word play?

The name comes from the words `utopic` and `api` where `uto` are the first three letters of _utopic_
and the `ipa` is _api_ reversed. Aaand... `ipa` is also an awesome type of beer :beer:.

## Crate Features

- **`macros`** Enable `utoipa-gen` macros. **This is enabled by default.**
- **`yaml`**: Enables **serde_norway** serialization of OpenAPI objects.
- **`actix_extras`**: Enhances [actix-web](https://github.com/actix/actix-web/) integration with being able to
  parse `path`, `path` and `query` parameters from actix web path attribute macros. See
  [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#actix_extras-feature-support-for-actix-web) or [examples](./examples) for more details.
- **`rocket_extras`**: Enhances [rocket](https://github.com/SergioBenitez/Rocket) framework integration with being
  able to parse `path`, `path` and `query` parameters from rocket path attribute macros. See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#rocket_extras-feature-support-for-rocket)
  or [examples](./examples) for more details.
- **`axum_extras`**: Enhances [axum](https://github.com/tokio-rs/axum) framework integration allowing users to use `IntoParams` without
  defining the `parameter_in` attribute. See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/attr.path.html#axum_extras-feature-support-for-axum)
  or [examples](./examples) for more details.
- **`debug`**: Add extra traits such as debug traits to openapi definitions and elsewhere.
- **`chrono`**: Add support for [chrono](https://crates.io/crates/chrono) `DateTime`, `Date`, `NaiveDate`, `NaiveDateTime`, `NaiveTime` and `Duration`
  types. By default these types are parsed to `string` types with additional `format` information.
  `format: date-time` for `DateTime` and `NaiveDateTime` and `format: date` for `Date` and `NaiveDate` according
  [RFC3339](https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc3339#section-5.6) as `ISO-8601`. To
  override default `string` representation users have to use `value_type` attribute to override the type.
  See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToSchema.html) for more details.
- **`time`**: Add support for [time](https://crates.io/crates/time) `OffsetDateTime`, `PrimitiveDateTime`, `Date`, and `Duration` types.
  By default these types are parsed as `string`. `OffsetDateTime` and `PrimitiveDateTime` will use `date-time` format. `Date` will use
  `date` format and `Duration` will not have any format. To override default `string` representation users have to use `value_type` attribute
  to override the type. See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToSchema.html) for more details.
- **`decimal`**: Add support for [rust_decimal](https://crates.io/crates/rust_decimal) `Decimal` type. **By default**
  it is interpreted as `String`. If you wish to change the format you need to override the type.
  See the `value_type` in [component derive docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToSchema.html).
- **`decimal_float`**: Add support for [rust_decimal](https://crates.io/crates/rust_decimal) `Decimal` type. **By default**
  it is interpreted as `Number`. This feature is mutually exclusive with **decimal** and allow to change the default type used in your
  documentation for `Decimal` much like `serde_with_float` feature exposed by rust_decimal.
- **`uuid`**: Add support for [uuid](https://github.com/uuid-rs/uuid). `Uuid` type will be presented as `String` with
  format `uuid` in OpenAPI spec.
- **`ulid`**: Add support for [ulid](https://github.com/dylanhart/ulid-rs). `Ulid` type will be presented as `String` with
  format `ulid` in OpenAPI spec.
- **`url`**: Add support for [url](https://github.com/servo/rust-url). `Url` type will be presented as `String` with
  format `uri` in OpenAPI spec.
- **`smallvec`**: Add support for [smallvec](https://crates.io/crates/smallvec). `SmallVec` will be treated as `Vec`.
- **`openapi_extensions`**: Adds traits and functions that provide extra convenience functions.
  See the [`request_body` docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/openapi/request_body) for an example.
- **`repr`**: Add support for [repr_serde](https://github.com/dtolnay/serde-repr)&#039;s `repr(u*)` and `repr(i*)` attributes to unit type enums for
  C-like enum representation. See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToSchema.html) for more details.
- **`preserve_order`**: Preserve order of properties when serializing the schema for a component.
  When enabled, the properties are listed in order of fields in the corresponding struct definition.
  When disabled, the properties are listed in alphabetical order.
- **`preserve_path_order`**: Preserve order of OpenAPI Paths according to order they have been
  introduced to the `#[openapi(paths(...))]` macro attribute. If disabled the paths will be
  ordered in alphabetical order. **However** the operations order under the path **will** be always constant according to [specification](https://spec.openapis.org/oas/latest.html#fixed-fields-6)
- **`indexmap`**: Add support for [indexmap](https://crates.io/crates/indexmap). When enabled `IndexMap` will be rendered as a map similar to
  `BTreeMap` and `HashMap`.
- **`non_strict_integers`**: Add support for non-standard integer formats `int8`, `int16`, `uint8`, `uint16`, `uint32`, and `uint64`.
- **`rc_schema`**: Add `ToSchema` support for `Arc&lt;T&gt;` and `Rc&lt;T&gt;` types. **Note!** serde `rc` feature flag must be enabled separately to allow
  serialization and deserialization of `Arc&lt;T&gt;` and `Rc&lt;T&gt;` types. See more about [serde feature flags](https://serde.rs/feature-flags.html).
- **`config`** Enables [`utoipa-config`](./utoipa-config/README.md) for the project which allows defining global configuration options for `utoipa`.

### Default Library Support

* Implicit partial support for `serde` attributes. See [docs](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToSchema.html#partial-serde-attributes-support) for more details.
* Support for [http](https://crates.io/crates/http) `StatusCode` in responses.

## Install

Add dependency declaration to `Cargo.toml`.

```toml
[dependencies]
utoipa = &quot;5&quot;
```

## Examples

_Create type with `ToSchema` and use it in `#[utoipa::path(...)]` that is registered to the `OpenApi`._

```rust
use utoipa::{OpenApi, ToSchema};

#[derive(ToSchema)]
struct Pet {
   id: u64,
   name: String,
   age: Option&lt;i32&gt;,
}

mod pet_api {
    /// Get pet by id
    ///
    /// Get pet from database by pet id
    #[utoipa::path(
        get,
        path = &quot;/pets/{id}&quot;,
        responses(
            (status = 200, description = &quot;Pet found successfully&quot;, body = Pet),
            (status = NOT_FOUND, description = &quot;Pet was not found&quot;)
        ),
        params(
            (&quot;id&quot; = u64, Path, description = &quot;Pet database id to get Pet for&quot;),
        )
    )]
    async fn get_pet_by_id(pet_id: u64) -&gt; Result&lt;Pet, NotFound&gt; {
        Ok(Pet {
            id: pet_id,
            age: None,
            name: &quot;lightning&quot;.to_string(),
        })
    }
}

#[derive(OpenApi)]
#[openapi(paths(pet_api::get_pet_by_id))]
struct ApiDoc;

println!(&quot;{}&quot;, ApiDoc::openapi().to_pretty_json().unwrap());
```

&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Above example will produce an OpenAPI doc like this:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```json
{
  &quot;openapi&quot;: &quot;3.1.0&quot;,
  &quot;info&quot;: {
    &quot;title&quot;: &quot;application name from Cargo.toml&quot;,
    &quot;description&quot;: &quot;description from Cargo.toml&quot;,
    &quot;contact&quot;: {
      &quot;name&quot;: &quot;author name from Cargo.toml&quot;,
      &quot;email&quot;: &quot;author email from Cargo.toml&quot;
    },
    &quot;license&quot;: {
      &quot;name&quot;: &quot;license from Cargo.toml&quot;
    },
    &quot;version&quot;: &quot;version from Cargo.toml&quot;
  },
  &quot;paths&quot;: {
    &quot;/pets/{id}&quot;: {
      &quot;get&quot;: {
        &quot;tags&quot;: [
          &quot;pet_api&quot;
        ],
        &quot;summary&quot;: &quot;Get pet by id&quot;,
        &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Get pet from database by pet id&quot;,
        &quot;operationId&quot;: &quot;get_pet_by_id&quot;,
        &quot;parameters&quot;: [
          {
            &quot;name&quot;: &quot;id&quot;,
            &quot;in&quot;: &quot;path&quot;,
            &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Pet database id to get Pet for&quot;,
            &quot;required&quot;: true,
            &quot;schema&quot;: {
              &quot;type&quot;: &quot;integer&quot;,
              &quot;format&quot;: &quot;int64&quot;,
              &quot;minimum&quot;: 0
            }
          }
        ],
        &quot;responses&quot;: {
          &quot;200&quot;: {
            &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Pet found successfully&quot;,
            &quot;content&quot;: {
              &quot;application/json&quot;: {
                &quot;schema&quot;: {
                  &quot;$ref&quot;: &quot;#/components/schemas/Pet&quot;
                }
              }
            }
          },
          &quot;404&quot;: {
            &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Pet was not found&quot;
          }
        }
      }
    }
  },
  &quot;components&quot;: {
    &quot;schemas&quot;: {
      &quot;Pet&quot;: {
        &quot;type&quot;: &quot;object&quot;,
        &quot;required&quot;: [
          &quot;id&quot;,
          &quot;name&quot;
        ],
        &quot;properties&quot;: {
          &quot;age&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: [
              &quot;integer&quot;,
              &quot;null&quot;
            ],
            &quot;format&quot;: &quot;int32&quot;
          },
          &quot;id&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;integer&quot;,
            &quot;format&quot;: &quot;int64&quot;,
            &quot;minimum&quot;: 0
          },
          &quot;name&quot;: {
            &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot;
          }
        }
      }
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;/details&gt;

## Modify OpenAPI at runtime

You can modify generated OpenAPI at runtime either via generated types directly or using
[Modify](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/trait.Modify.html) trait.

_Modify generated OpenAPI via types directly._

```rust
#[derive(OpenApi)]
#[openapi(
    info(description = &quot;My Api description&quot;),
)]
struct ApiDoc;

let mut doc = ApiDoc::openapi();
doc.info.title = String::from(&quot;My Api&quot;);
```

_You can even convert the generated [OpenApi](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/openapi/struct.OpenApi.html) to [OpenApiBuilder](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/openapi/struct.OpenApiBuilder.html)._

```rust
let builder: OpenApiBuilder = ApiDoc::openapi().into();
```

See [Modify](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/trait.Modify.html) trait for examples on how to modify generated OpenAPI via it.

## Go beyond the surface

- See how to serve OpenAPI doc via Swagger UI check [utoipa-swagger-ui](https://docs.rs/utoipa-swagger-ui/) crate for more details.
- Browse to [examples](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/tree/master/examples) for more comprehensive examples.
- Check [IntoResponses](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.IntoResponses.html) and [ToResponse](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/derive.ToResponse.html) for examples on deriving responses.
- More about OpenAPI security in [security documentation](https://docs.rs/utoipa/latest/utoipa/openapi/security/index.html).
- Dump generated API doc to file at build time. See [issue 214 comment](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/issues/214#issuecomment-1179589373).

## FAQ

### Swagger UI returns 404 NotFound from built binary

This is highly probably due to `RustEmbed` not embedding the Swagger UI to the executable. This is natural since the `RustEmbed`
library **does not** by default embed files on debug builds. To get around this you can do one of the following.

1. Build your executable in `--release` mode
2. or add `debug-embed` feature flag to your `Cargo.toml` for `utoipa-swagger-ui`. This will enable the `debug-emebed` feature flag for
   `RustEmbed` as well. Read more about this [here](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/issues/527#issuecomment-1474219098) and [here](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/issues/268).

Find `utoipa-swagger-ui` [feature flags here](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/tree/master/utoipa-swagger-ui#crate-features).

### How to implement `ToSchema` for external type?

There are few ways around this that are elaborated [here in detail](https://github.com/juhaku/utoipa/issues/790#issuecomment-1787754185).

### Auto discover for OpenAPI schemas and paths?

Currently there is no build in solution to automatically discover the OpenAPI types but for your luck there is a pretty neat crate that 
just does this for you called [utoipauto](https://github.com/ProbablyClem/utoipauto).

## License

Licensed under either of [Apache 2.0](LICENSE-APACHE) or [MIT](LICENSE-MIT) license at your option.

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted for inclusion in this crate
by you, shall be dual licensed, without any additional terms or conditions.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rust-lang/rustlings]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🦀 Small exercises to get you used to reading and writing Rust code!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings">rust-lang/rustlings</a></h1>
            <p>🦀 Small exercises to get you used to reading and writing Rust code!</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 57,237</p>
            <p>Forks: 10,502</p>
            <p>Stars today: 33 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div class=&quot;oranda-hide&quot;&gt;

# Rustlings 🦀❤️

&lt;/div&gt;

Greetings and welcome to Rustlings.
This project contains small exercises to get you used to reading and writing Rust code.
This includes reading and responding to compiler messages!

It is recommended to do the Rustlings exercises in parallel to reading [the official Rust book](https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/), the most comprehensive resource for learning Rust 📚️

[Rust By Example](https://doc.rust-lang.org/rust-by-example/) is another recommended resource that you might find helpful.
It contains code examples and exercises similar to Rustlings, but online.

## Getting Started

### Installing Rust

Before installing Rustlings, you need to have the **latest version of Rust** installed.
Visit [www.rust-lang.org/tools/install](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install) for further instructions on installing Rust.
This will also install _Cargo_, Rust&#039;s package/project manager.

&gt; 🐧 If you are on Linux, make sure you have installed `gcc` (for a linker).
&gt;
&gt; Deb: `sudo apt install gcc`
&gt;
&gt; Dnf: `sudo dnf install gcc`

&gt; 🍎 If you are on MacOS, make sure you have installed Xcode and its developer tools by running `xcode-select --install`.

### Installing Rustlings

The following command will download and compile Rustlings:

```bash
cargo install rustlings
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the installation fails…&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;click to expand&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/summary&gt;

- Make sure you have the latest Rust version by running `rustup update`
- Try adding the `--locked` flag: `cargo install rustlings --locked`
- Otherwise, please [report the issue](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/issues/new)

&lt;/details&gt;

### Initialization

After installing Rustlings, run the following command to initialize the `rustlings/` directory:

```bash
rustlings init
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the command &lt;code&gt;rustlings&lt;/code&gt; can&#039;t be found…&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;click to expand&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/summary&gt;

You are probably using Linux and installed Rust using your package manager.

Cargo installs binaries to the directory `~/.cargo/bin`.
Sadly, package managers often don&#039;t add `~/.cargo/bin` to your `PATH` environment variable.

The solution is to …

- either add `~/.cargo/bin` manually to `PATH`
- or to uninstall Rust from the package manager and install it using the official way with `rustup`: https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install

&lt;/details&gt;

Now, go into the newly initialized directory and launch Rustlings for further instructions on getting started with the exercises:

```bash
cd rustlings/
rustlings
```

## Working environment

### Editor

Our general recommendation is [VS Code](https://code.visualstudio.com/) with the [rust-analyzer plugin](https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=rust-lang.rust-analyzer).
But any editor that supports [rust-analyzer](https://rust-analyzer.github.io/) should be enough for working on the exercises.

### Terminal

While working with Rustlings, please use a modern terminal for the best user experience.
The default terminal on Linux and Mac should be sufficient.
On Windows, we recommend the [Windows Terminal](https://aka.ms/terminal).

## Doing exercises

The exercises are sorted by topic and can be found in the subdirectory `exercises/&lt;topic&gt;`.
For every topic, there is an additional `README.md` file with some resources to get you started on the topic.
We highly recommend that you have a look at them before you start 📚️

Most exercises contain an error that keeps them from compiling, and it&#039;s up to you to fix it!
Some exercises contain tests that need to pass for the exercise to be done ✅

Search for `TODO` and `todo!()` to find out what you need to change.
Ask for hints by entering `h` in the _watch mode_ 💡

### Watch Mode

After the [initialization](#initialization), Rustlings can be launched by simply running the command `rustlings`.

This will start the _watch mode_ which walks you through the exercises in a predefined order (what we think is best for newcomers).
It will rerun the current exercise automatically every time you change the exercise&#039;s file in the `exercises/` directory.

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If detecting file changes in the &lt;code&gt;exercises/&lt;/code&gt; directory fails…&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;click to expand&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/summary&gt;

&gt; You can add the **`--manual-run`** flag (`rustlings --manual-run`) to manually rerun the current exercise by entering `r` in the watch mode.
&gt;
&gt; Please [report the issue](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/issues/new) with some information about your operating system and whether you run Rustlings in a container or virtual machine (e.g. WSL).

&lt;/details&gt;

### Exercise List

In the [watch mode](#watch-mode) (after launching `rustlings`), you can enter `l` to open the interactive exercise list.

The list allows you to…

- See the status of all exercises (done or pending)
- `c`: Continue at another exercise (temporarily skip some exercises or go back to a previous one)
- `r`: Reset status and file of the selected exercise (you need to _reload/reopen_ its file in your editor afterwards)

See the footer of the list for all possible keys.

## Questions?

If you need any help while doing the exercises and the builtin-hints aren&#039;t helpful, feel free to ask in the [_Q&amp;A_ category of the discussions](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/discussions/categories/q-a?discussions_q=) if your question wasn&#039;t asked yet 💡

## Third-Party Exercises

Third-party exercises are a set of exercises maintained by the community.
You can use the same `rustlings` program that you installed with `cargo install rustlings` to run them:

- 🇯🇵 [Japanese Rustlings](https://github.com/sotanengel/rustlings-jp)：A Japanese translation of the Rustlings exercises.
- 🇨🇳 [Simplified Chinese Rustlings](https://github.com/SandmeyerX/rustlings-zh-cn): A simplified Chinese translation of the Rustlings exercises.

Do you want to create your own set of Rustlings exercises to focus on some specific topic?
Or do you want to translate the original Rustlings exercises?
Then follow the the guide about [third-party exercises](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/blob/main/THIRD_PARTY_EXERCISES.md)!

## Continuing On

Once you&#039;ve completed Rustlings, put your new knowledge to good use!
Continue practicing your Rust skills by building your own projects, contributing to Rustlings, or finding other open-source projects to contribute to.

## Uninstalling Rustlings

If you want to remove Rustlings from your system, run the following command:

```bash
cargo uninstall rustlings
```

## Contributing

See [CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md) 🔗

Thanks to [all the wonderful contributors](https://github.com/rust-lang/rustlings/graphs/contributors) ✨
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[astral-sh/uv]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/astral-sh/uv</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/astral-sh/uv</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An extremely fast Python package and project manager, written in Rust.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/uv">astral-sh/uv</a></h1>
            <p>An extremely fast Python package and project manager, written in Rust.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 46,844</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,318</p>
            <p>Stars today: 185 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># uv

[![uv](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://raw.githubusercontent.com/astral-sh/uv/main/assets/badge/v0.json)](https://github.com/astral-sh/uv)
[![image](https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/uv.svg)](https://pypi.python.org/pypi/uv)
[![image](https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/uv.svg)](https://pypi.python.org/pypi/uv)
[![image](https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/uv.svg)](https://pypi.python.org/pypi/uv)
[![Actions status](https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/actions)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-%235865F2.svg?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white)](https://discord.gg/astral-sh)

An extremely fast Python package and project manager, written in Rust.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/assets/1309177/03aa9163-1c79-4a87-a31d-7a9311ed9310&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/assets/1309177/629e59c0-9c6e-4013-9ad4-adb2bcf5080d&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Shows a bar chart with benchmark results.&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/assets/1309177/629e59c0-9c6e-4013-9ad4-adb2bcf5080d&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Installing &lt;a href=&quot;https://trio.readthedocs.io/&quot;&gt;Trio&lt;/a&gt;&#039;s dependencies with a warm cache.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Highlights

- 🚀 A single tool to replace `pip`, `pip-tools`, `pipx`, `poetry`, `pyenv`, `twine`, `virtualenv`,
  and more.
- ⚡️ [10-100x faster](https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/blob/main/BENCHMARKS.md) than `pip`.
- 🗂️ Provides [comprehensive project management](#projects), with a
  [universal lockfile](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/concepts/projects/layout#the-lockfile).
- ❇️ [Runs scripts](#scripts), with support for
  [inline dependency metadata](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts#declaring-script-dependencies).
- 🐍 [Installs and manages](#python-versions) Python versions.
- 🛠️ [Runs and installs](#tools) tools published as Python packages.
- 🔩 Includes a [pip-compatible interface](#the-pip-interface) for a performance boost with a
  familiar CLI.
- 🏢 Supports Cargo-style [workspaces](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/concepts/projects/workspaces) for
  scalable projects.
- 💾 Disk-space efficient, with a [global cache](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/concepts/cache) for
  dependency deduplication.
- ⏬ Installable without Rust or Python via `curl` or `pip`.
- 🖥️ Supports macOS, Linux, and Windows.

uv is backed by [Astral](https://astral.sh), the creators of
[Ruff](https://github.com/astral-sh/ruff).

## Installation

Install uv with our standalone installers:

```bash
# On macOS and Linux.
curl -LsSf https://astral.sh/uv/install.sh | sh
```

```bash
# On Windows.
powershell -ExecutionPolicy ByPass -c &quot;irm https://astral.sh/uv/install.ps1 | iex&quot;
```

Or, from [PyPI](https://pypi.org/project/uv/):

```bash
# With pip.
pip install uv
```

```bash
# Or pipx.
pipx install uv
```

If installed via the standalone installer, uv can update itself to the latest version:

```bash
uv self update
```

See the [installation documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/getting-started/installation/) for
details and alternative installation methods.

## Documentation

uv&#039;s documentation is available at [docs.astral.sh/uv](https://docs.astral.sh/uv).

Additionally, the command line reference documentation can be viewed with `uv help`.

## Features

### Projects

uv manages project dependencies and environments, with support for lockfiles, workspaces, and more,
similar to `rye` or `poetry`:

```console
$ uv init example
Initialized project `example` at `/home/user/example`

$ cd example

$ uv add ruff
Creating virtual environment at: .venv
Resolved 2 packages in 170ms
   Built example @ file:///home/user/example
Prepared 2 packages in 627ms
Installed 2 packages in 1ms
 + example==0.1.0 (from file:///home/user/example)
 + ruff==0.5.0

$ uv run ruff check
All checks passed!

$ uv lock
Resolved 2 packages in 0.33ms

$ uv sync
Resolved 2 packages in 0.70ms
Audited 1 package in 0.02ms
```

See the [project documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/projects/) to get started.

uv also supports building and publishing projects, even if they&#039;re not managed with uv. See the
[publish guide](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/publish/) to learn more.

### Scripts

uv manages dependencies and environments for single-file scripts.

Create a new script and add inline metadata declaring its dependencies:

```console
$ echo &#039;import requests; print(requests.get(&quot;https://astral.sh&quot;))&#039; &gt; example.py

$ uv add --script example.py requests
Updated `example.py`
```

Then, run the script in an isolated virtual environment:

```console
$ uv run example.py
Reading inline script metadata from: example.py
Installed 5 packages in 12ms
&lt;Response [200]&gt;
```

See the [scripts documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/) to get started.

### Tools

uv executes and installs command-line tools provided by Python packages, similar to `pipx`.

Run a tool in an ephemeral environment using `uvx` (an alias for `uv tool run`):

```console
$ uvx pycowsay &#039;hello world!&#039;
Resolved 1 package in 167ms
Installed 1 package in 9ms
 + pycowsay==0.0.0.2
  &quot;&quot;&quot;

  ------------
&lt; hello world! &gt;
  ------------
   \   ^__^
    \  (oo)\_______
       (__)\       )\/\
           ||----w |
           ||     ||
```

Install a tool with `uv tool install`:

```console
$ uv tool install ruff
Resolved 1 package in 6ms
Installed 1 package in 2ms
 + ruff==0.5.0
Installed 1 executable: ruff

$ ruff --version
ruff 0.5.0
```

See the [tools documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/tools/) to get started.

### Python versions

uv installs Python and allows quickly switching between versions.

Install multiple Python versions:

```console
$ uv python install 3.10 3.11 3.12
Searching for Python versions matching: Python 3.10
Searching for Python versions matching: Python 3.11
Searching for Python versions matching: Python 3.12
Installed 3 versions in 3.42s
 + cpython-3.10.14-macos-aarch64-none
 + cpython-3.11.9-macos-aarch64-none
 + cpython-3.12.4-macos-aarch64-none
```

Download Python versions as needed:

```console
$ uv venv --python 3.12.0
Using Python 3.12.0
Creating virtual environment at: .venv
Activate with: source .venv/bin/activate

$ uv run --python pypy@3.8 -- python --version
Python 3.8.16 (a9dbdca6fc3286b0addd2240f11d97d8e8de187a, Dec 29 2022, 11:45:30)
[PyPy 7.3.11 with GCC Apple LLVM 13.1.6 (clang-1316.0.21.2.5)] on darwin
Type &quot;help&quot;, &quot;copyright&quot;, &quot;credits&quot; or &quot;license&quot; for more information.
&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;
```

Use a specific Python version in the current directory:

```console
$ uv python pin 3.11
Pinned `.python-version` to `3.11`
```

See the [Python installation documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/install-python/) to get
started.

### The pip interface

uv provides a drop-in replacement for common `pip`, `pip-tools`, and `virtualenv` commands.

uv extends their interfaces with advanced features, such as dependency version overrides,
platform-independent resolutions, reproducible resolutions, alternative resolution strategies, and
more.

Migrate to uv without changing your existing workflows — and experience a 10-100x speedup — with the
`uv pip` interface.

Compile requirements into a platform-independent requirements file:

```console
$ uv pip compile docs/requirements.in \
   --universal \
   --output-file docs/requirements.txt
Resolved 43 packages in 12ms
```

Create a virtual environment:

```console
$ uv venv
Using Python 3.12.3
Creating virtual environment at: .venv
Activate with: source .venv/bin/activate
```

Install the locked requirements:

```console
$ uv pip sync docs/requirements.txt
Resolved 43 packages in 11ms
Installed 43 packages in 208ms
 + babel==2.15.0
 + black==24.4.2
 + certifi==2024.7.4
 ...
```

See the [pip interface documentation](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/pip/index/) to get started.

## Platform support

See uv&#039;s [platform support](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/reference/platforms/) document.

## Versioning policy

See uv&#039;s [versioning policy](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/reference/versioning/) document.

## Contributing

We are passionate about supporting contributors of all levels of experience and would love to see
you get involved in the project. See the
[contributing guide](https://github.com/astral-sh/uv/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md) to get started.

## Acknowledgements

uv&#039;s dependency resolver uses [PubGrub](https://github.com/pubgrub-rs/pubgrub) under the hood. We&#039;re
grateful to the PubGrub maintainers, especially [Jacob Finkelman](https://github.com/Eh2406), for
their support.

uv&#039;s Git implementation is based on [Cargo](https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo).

Some of uv&#039;s optimizations are inspired by the great work we&#039;ve seen in [pnpm](https://pnpm.io/),
[Orogene](https://github.com/orogene/orogene), and [Bun](https://github.com/oven-sh/bun). We&#039;ve also
learned a lot from Nathaniel J. Smith&#039;s [Posy](https://github.com/njsmith/posy) and adapted its
[trampoline](https://github.com/njsmith/posy/tree/main/src/trampolines/windows-trampolines/posy-trampoline)
for Windows support.

## License

uv is licensed under either of

- Apache License, Version 2.0, ([LICENSE-APACHE](LICENSE-APACHE) or
  &lt;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&gt;)
- MIT license ([LICENSE-MIT](LICENSE-MIT) or &lt;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&gt;)

at your option.

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted for inclusion in uv
by you, as defined in the Apache-2.0 license, shall be dually licensed as above, without any
additional terms or conditions.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://astral.sh&quot; style=&quot;background:none&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/astral-sh/uv/main/assets/svg/Astral.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Made by Astral&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[tauri-apps/tauri]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Build smaller, faster, and more secure desktop and mobile applications with a web frontend.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri">tauri-apps/tauri</a></h1>
            <p>Build smaller, faster, and more secure desktop and mobile applications with a web frontend.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 90,971</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,786</p>
            <p>Stars today: 42 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;img src=&quot;.github/splash.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tauri&quot; /&gt;

[![status](https://img.shields.io/badge/status-stable-blue.svg)](https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri/tree/dev)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT%20or%20Apache%202-green.svg)](https://opencollective.com/tauri)
[![test core](https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/tauri-apps/tauri/test-core.yml?label=test%20core&amp;logo=github)](https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri/actions/workflows/test-core.yml)
[![FOSSA Status](https://app.fossa.com/api/projects/git%2Bgithub.com%2Ftauri-apps%2Ftauri.svg?type=shield)](https://app.fossa.com/projects/git%2Bgithub.com%2Ftauri-apps%2Ftauri?ref=badge_shield)
[![Chat Server](https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-discord-7289da.svg)](https://discord.gg/SpmNs4S)
[![website](https://img.shields.io/badge/website-tauri.app-purple.svg)](https://tauri.app)
[![https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation/assets/images/badge.svg)](https://good-labs.github.io/greater-good-affirmation)
[![support](https://img.shields.io/badge/sponsor-Open%20Collective-blue.svg)](https://opencollective.com/tauri)

## Introduction

Tauri is a framework for building tiny, blazingly fast binaries for all major desktop platforms. Developers can integrate any front-end framework that compiles to HTML, JS and CSS for building their user interface. The backend of the application is a rust-sourced binary with an API that the front-end can interact with.

The user interface in Tauri apps currently leverages [`tao`](https://docs.rs/tao) as a window handling library on macOS, Windows, Linux, Android and iOS. To render your application, Tauri uses [WRY](https://github.com/tauri-apps/wry), a library which provides a unified interface to the system webview, leveraging WKWebView on macOS &amp; iOS, WebView2 on Windows, WebKitGTK on Linux and Android System WebView on Android.

To learn more about the details of how all of these pieces fit together, please consult this [ARCHITECTURE.md](https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri/blob/dev/ARCHITECTURE.md) document.

## Getting Started

If you are interested in making a tauri app, please visit the [documentation website](https://tauri.app).

The quickest way to get started is to install the [prerequisites](https://v2.tauri.app/start/prerequisites/) for your system and create a new project with [`create-tauri-app`](https://github.com/tauri-apps/create-tauri-app/#usage). For example with `npm`:

```sh
npm create tauri-app@latest
```

## Features

The list of Tauri&#039;s features includes, but is not limited to:

- Built-in app bundler to create app bundles in formats like `.app`, `.dmg`, `.deb`, `.rpm`, `.AppImage` and Windows installers like `.exe` (via NSIS) and `.msi` (via WiX).
- Built-in self updater (desktop only)
- System tray icons
- Native notifications
- Native WebView Protocol (tauri doesn&#039;t create a localhost http(s) server to serve the WebView contents)
- GitHub action for streamlined CI
- VS Code extension

### Platforms

Tauri currently supports development and distribution on the following platforms:

| Platform   | Versions                                                                                                        |
| :--------- | :-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Windows    | 7 and above                                                                                                     |
| macOS      | 10.15 and above                                                                                                 |
| Linux      | webkit2gtk 4.0 for Tauri v1 (for example Ubuntu 18.04). webkit2gtk 4.1 for Tauri v2 (for example Ubuntu 22.04). |
| iOS/iPadOS | 9 and above                                                                                                     |
| Android    | 7 and above (currently 8 and above)                                                                             |

## Contributing

Before you start working on something, it&#039;s best to check if there is an existing issue first. It&#039;s also a good idea to stop by the Discord server and confirm with the team if it makes sense or if someone else is already working on it.

Please make sure to read the [Contributing Guide](./.github/CONTRIBUTING.md) before making a pull request.

Thank you to everyone contributing to Tauri!

### Documentation

Documentation in a polyglot system is a tricky proposition. To this end, we prefer to use inline documentation in the Rust &amp; JS source code as much as possible. Check out the hosting repository for the documentation site for further information: &lt;https://github.com/tauri-apps/tauri-docs&gt;

## Partners

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://crabnebula.dev&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;.github/sponsors/crabnebula.svg&quot; alt=&quot;CrabNebula&quot; width=&quot;283&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

For the complete list of sponsors please visit our [website](https://tauri.app#sponsors) and [Open Collective](https://opencollective.com/tauri).

## Organization

Tauri aims to be a sustainable collective based on principles that guide [sustainable free and open software communities](https://sfosc.org). To this end it has become a Programme within the [Commons Conservancy](https://commonsconservancy.org/), and you can contribute financially via [Open Collective](https://opencollective.com/tauri).

## Licenses

Code: (c) 2015 - Present - The Tauri Programme within The Commons Conservancy.

MIT or MIT/Apache 2.0 where applicable.

Logo: CC-BY-NC-ND

- Original Tauri Logo Designs by [Alve Larsson](https://alve.io/), [Daniel Thompson-Yvetot](https://github.com/nothingismagick) and [Guillaume Chau](https://github.com/akryum)

[![FOSSA Status](https://app.fossa.com/api/projects/git%2Bgithub.com%2Ftauri-apps%2Ftauri.svg?type=large)](https://app.fossa.com/projects/git%2Bgithub.com%2Ftauri-apps%2Ftauri?ref=badge_large)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[kata-containers/kata-containers]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Kata Containers is an open source project and community working to build a standard implementation of lightweight Virtual Machines (VMs) that feel and perform like containers, but provide the workload isolation and security advantages of VMs. https://katacontainers.io/]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers">kata-containers/kata-containers</a></h1>
            <p>Kata Containers is an open source project and community working to build a standard implementation of lightweight Virtual Machines (VMs) that feel and perform like containers, but provide the workload isolation and security advantages of VMs. https://katacontainers.io/</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,977</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,082</p>
            <p>Stars today: 8 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;img src=&quot;https://object-storage-ca-ymq-1.vexxhost.net/swift/v1/6e4619c416ff4bd19e1c087f27a43eea/www-images-prod/openstack-logo/kata/SVG/kata-1.svg&quot; width=&quot;900&quot;&gt;

[![CI | Publish Kata Containers payload](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/actions/workflows/payload-after-push.yaml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/actions/workflows/payload-after-push.yaml) [![Kata Containers Nightly CI](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/actions/workflows/ci-nightly.yaml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/actions/workflows/ci-nightly.yaml)

# Kata Containers

Welcome to Kata Containers!

This repository is the home of the Kata Containers code for the 2.0 and newer
releases.

If you want to learn about Kata Containers, visit the main
[Kata Containers website](https://katacontainers.io).

## Introduction

Kata Containers is an open source project and community working to build a
standard implementation of lightweight Virtual Machines (VMs) that feel and
perform like containers, but provide the workload isolation and security
advantages of VMs.

## License

The code is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license.
See [the license file](LICENSE) for further details.

## Platform support

Kata Containers currently runs on 64-bit systems supporting the following
technologies:

| Architecture | Virtualization technology |
|-|-|
| `x86_64`, `amd64` | [Intel](https://www.intel.com) VT-x, AMD SVM |
| `aarch64` (&quot;`arm64`&quot;)| [ARM](https://www.arm.com) Hyp |
| `ppc64le` | [IBM](https://www.ibm.com) Power |
| `s390x` | [IBM](https://www.ibm.com) Z &amp; LinuxONE SIE |

### Hardware requirements

The [Kata Containers runtime](src/runtime) provides a command to
determine if your host system is capable of running and creating a
Kata Container:

```bash
$ kata-runtime check
```

&gt; **Notes:**
&gt;
&gt; - This command runs a number of checks including connecting to the
&gt;   network to determine if a newer release of Kata Containers is
&gt;   available on GitHub. If you do not wish this to check to run, add
&gt;   the `--no-network-checks` option.
&gt;
&gt; - By default, only a brief success / failure message is printed.
&gt;   If more details are needed, the `--verbose` flag can be used to display the
&gt;   list of all the checks performed.
&gt;
&gt; - If the command is run as the `root` user additional checks are
&gt;   run (including checking if another incompatible hypervisor is running).
&gt;   When running as `root`, network checks are automatically disabled.

## Getting started

See the [installation documentation](docs/install).

## Documentation

See the [official documentation](docs) including:

- [Installation guides](docs/install)
- [Developer guide](docs/Developer-Guide.md)
- [Design documents](docs/design)
  - [Architecture overview](docs/design/architecture)
  - [Architecture 3.0 overview](docs/design/architecture_3.0/)

## Configuration

Kata Containers uses a single
[configuration file](src/runtime/README.md#configuration)
which contains a number of sections for various parts of the Kata
Containers system including the [runtime](src/runtime), the
[agent](src/agent) and the [hypervisor](#hypervisors).

## Hypervisors

See the [hypervisors document](docs/hypervisors.md) and the
[Hypervisor specific configuration details](src/runtime/README.md#hypervisor-specific-configuration).

## Community

To learn more about the project, its community and governance, see the
[community repository](https://github.com/kata-containers/community). This is
the first place to go if you wish to contribute to the project.

## Getting help

See the [community](#community) section for ways to contact us.

### Raising issues

Please raise an issue
[in this repository](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/issues).

&gt; **Note:**
&gt; If you are reporting a security issue, please follow the [vulnerability reporting process](https://github.com/kata-containers/community#vulnerability-handling)

## Developers

See the [developer guide](docs/Developer-Guide.md).

### Components

### Main components

The table below lists the core parts of the project:

| Component | Type | Description |
|-|-|-|
| [runtime](src/runtime) | core | Main component run by a container manager and providing a containerd shimv2 runtime implementation. |
| [runtime-rs](src/runtime-rs) | core | The Rust version runtime. |
| [agent](src/agent) | core | Management process running inside the virtual machine / POD that sets up the container environment. |
| [`dragonball`](src/dragonball) | core | An optional built-in VMM brings out-of-the-box Kata Containers experience with optimizations on container workloads |
| [documentation](docs) | documentation | Documentation common to all components (such as design and install documentation). |
| [tests](tests) | tests | Excludes unit tests which live with the main code. |

### Additional components

The table below lists the remaining parts of the project:

| Component | Type | Description |
|-|-|-|
| [packaging](tools/packaging) | infrastructure | Scripts and metadata for producing packaged binaries&lt;br/&gt;(components, hypervisors, kernel and rootfs). |
| [kernel](https://www.kernel.org) | kernel | Linux kernel used by the hypervisor to boot the guest image. Patches are stored [here](tools/packaging/kernel). |
| [osbuilder](tools/osbuilder) | infrastructure | Tool to create &quot;mini O/S&quot; rootfs and initrd images and kernel for the hypervisor. |
| [kata-debug](tools/packaging/kata-debug/README.md) | infrastructure | Utility tool to gather Kata Containers debug information from Kubernetes clusters. |
| [`agent-ctl`](src/tools/agent-ctl) | utility | Tool that provides low-level access for testing the agent. |
| [`kata-ctl`](src/tools/kata-ctl) | utility | Tool that provides advanced commands and debug facilities. |
| [`trace-forwarder`](src/tools/trace-forwarder) | utility | Agent tracing helper. |
| [`runk`](src/tools/runk) | utility | Standard OCI container runtime based on the agent. |
| [`ci`](.github/workflows) | CI | Continuous Integration configuration files and scripts. |
| [`ocp-ci`](ci/openshift-ci/README.md) | CI | Continuous Integration configuration for the OpenShift pipelines. |
| [`katacontainers.io`](https://github.com/kata-containers/www.katacontainers.io) | Source for the [`katacontainers.io`](https://www.katacontainers.io) site. |
| [`Webhook`](tools/testing/kata-webhook/README.md) | utility | Example of a simple admission controller webhook to annotate pods with the Kata runtime class |

### Packaging and releases

Kata Containers is now
[available natively for most distributions](docs/install/README.md#packaged-installation-methods).

## General tests

See the [tests documentation](tests/README.md).

## Metrics tests

See the [metrics documentation](tests/metrics/README.md).

## Glossary of Terms

See the [glossary of terms](https://github.com/kata-containers/kata-containers/wiki/Glossary) related to Kata Containers.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MaterializeInc/materialize]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Real-time Data Integration and Transformation: use SQL to transform, deliver, and act on fast-changing data.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize">MaterializeInc/materialize</a></h1>
            <p>Real-time Data Integration and Transformation: use SQL to transform, deliver, and act on fast-changing data.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,925</p>
            <p>Forks: 468</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Build status](https://badge.buildkite.com/97d6604e015bf633d1c2a12d166bb46f3b43a927d3952c999a.svg?branch=main)](https://buildkite.com/materialize/test)
[![Doc reference](https://img.shields.io/badge/doc-reference-orange)](https://materialize.com/docs)
[![Chat on Slack](https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on%20slack-purple)](https://materialize.com/s/chat)

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/assets/23521087/39270ecb-7ac4-4829-b98b-c5b5699a16b8&quot; width=35%&gt;](https://materialize.com)

Materialize is a real-time data integration platform that creates and continually updates consistent views of transactional data from across your organization. Its SQL interface democratizes the ability to serve and access live data. Materialize can be deployed anywhere your infrastructure runs.

Use Materialize to do things like deliver fresh context for AI/RAG pipelines, power operational dashboards, and create more dynamic customer experiences without building time-consuming custom data pipelines.


The three most common patterns for adopting Materialize are the following:

- Query Offload (CQRS) - Scale complex read queries more efficiently than a read replica, and without the headaches of cache invalidation.
- Integration Hub (ODS) - Extract, load, and incrementally transform data from multiple sources. Create live views of your data that can be queried directly or pushed downstream.
- Operational Data Mesh (ODM) - Use SQL to create and deliver real-time, strongly consistent data products to streamline coordination across services and domains.


## Get started

Ready to try out Materialize? You can [sign up](https://materialize.com/register/) for a free cloud trial or [download](https://materialize.com/download/) our community edition, which is free forever for deployments using less than 24 GiB of memory and 48 GiB of disk!

Have questions? We&#039;d love to hear from you:
  * [Join our Slack](https://materialize.com/s/chat)
  * [Send us mail](https://materialize.com/contact/)

## About

Materialize focuses on providing correct and [consistent](https://materialize.com/docs/overview/isolation-level/) answers with minimal latency, and does not ask you to accept either approximate answers or eventual consistency. This guarantee holds even when joining data from [multiple upstream systems](https://materialize.com/blog/strong-consistency-in-materialize/). Whenever Materialize answers a query, that answer is the correct result on some specific (and recent) version of your data. Materialize does all of this by recasting your SQL queries as *dataflows*, which can react efficiently to changes in your data as they happen.

Our fully managed service is cloud-native, featuring **high availability** through multi-active replication, **horizontal scalability** by seamlessly scaling dataflows across multiple machines, and **near-infinite storage** by leveraging cloud object storage (e.g., Amazon S3). You can self-manage Materialize using our Enterprise or Community editions.

We support a large fraction of PostgreSQL features and are actively expanding support for more built-in PostgreSQL functions. Please file an issue if you have an idea for an improvement!

## Get data in

Materialize can read data directly from a [PostgreSQL](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/postgres/) or [MySQL](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/mysql/) replication stream, from [Kafka](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/kafka/) (and other Kafka API-compatible systems like [Redpanda](https://materialize.com/docs/integrations/redpanda/)), or from SaaS applications [via webhooks](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/webhook/).

## Transform, manipulate, and read your data

Once you&#039;ve got the data in, define views and perform reads via the PostgreSQL protocol. Use your favorite SQL client, including the `psql` you probably already have on your system. Customers using Materialize in production tend to use [dbt Core](https://www.getdbt.com/).

Materialize supports a comprehensive variety of SQL features, all using the PostgreSQL dialect and protocol:

-   Joins, joins, joins! Materialize supports multi-column join conditions, multi-way joins, self-joins, cross-joins, inner joins, outer joins, etc.
-   Delta-joins avoid intermediate state blowup compared to systems that can only plan nested binary joins - tested on joins of up to 64 relations.
-   Support for subqueries. Materialize&#039;s SQL optimizer performs subquery decorrelation out-of-the-box, avoiding the need to manually rewrite subqueries into joins.
-   Materialize can incrementally maintain views in the presence of arbitrary inserts, updates, and deletes. No asterisks.
-   All the aggregations: `min`, `max`, `count`, `sum`, `stddev`, etc.
-   `HAVING`
-   `ORDER BY`
-   `LIMIT`
-   `DISTINCT`
-   JSON support in the PostgreSQL dialect including operators and functions like `-&gt;`, `-&gt;&gt;`, `@&gt;`, `?`, `jsonb_array_element`, `jsonb_each`. Materialize automatically plans lateral joins for efficient `jsonb_each` support.
-   Nest views on views on views!
-   Multiple views that have overlapping subplans can share underlying indices for space and compute efficiency, so just declaratively define _what you want_, and we&#039;ll worry about how to efficiently maintain them.

We’ve also extended our SQL support to enable [recursion](https://materialize.com/blog/recursion-in-materialize/) that supports incrementally updating tree and graph structures.

### Just show us what it can do!

Here&#039;s an example join query that works fine in Materialize, `TPC-H` query 15:

```sql
CREATE SOURCE tpch
  FROM LOAD GENERATOR TPCH (SCALE FACTOR 1)
  FOR ALL TABLES;

-- Views define commonly reused subqueries.
CREATE VIEW revenue (supplier_no, total_revenue) AS
    SELECT
        l_suppkey,
        SUM(l_extendedprice * (1 - l_discount))
    FROM
        lineitem
    WHERE
        l_shipdate &gt;= DATE &#039;1996-01-01&#039;
        AND l_shipdate &lt; DATE &#039;1996-01-01&#039; + INTERVAL &#039;3&#039; month
    GROUP BY
        l_suppkey;

-- The MATERIALIZED keyword is the trigger to begin
-- eagerly, consistently, and incrementally maintaining
-- results that are stored directly in durable storage.
CREATE MATERIALIZED VIEW tpch_q15 AS
  SELECT
    s_suppkey,
    s_name,
    s_address,
    s_phone,
    total_revenue
FROM
    supplier,
    revenue
WHERE
    s_suppkey = supplier_no
    AND total_revenue = (
        SELECT
            max(total_revenue)
        FROM
            revenue
    )
ORDER BY
    s_suppkey;

-- Creating an index keeps results always up to date and in memory.
-- In this example, the index will allow for fast point lookups of
-- individual supply keys.
CREATE INDEX tpch_q15_idx ON tpch_q15 (s_suppkey);
```

Stream inserts, updates, and deletes on the underlying tables (`lineitem` and `supplier`), and Materialize keeps the materialized view incrementally updated. You can type `SELECT * FROM tpch_q15` and expect to see the current results immediately!

## Get data out

**Pull based**: Use any PostgreSQL-compatible driver in any language/environment to make `SELECT` queries against your views. Tell them they&#039;re talking to a PostgreSQL database, they don&#039;t ever need to know otherwise. This is particularly helpful for pointing services and BI tools directly at Materialize.

**Push based**: Listen to changes directly using `SUBSCRIBE` or configure Materialize to stream results to a Kafka topic as soon as the views change. You can also copy updates to object storage.

## Documentation

Check out [our documentation](https://materialize.com/docs/).

## License

Materialize is provided as a self-managed product and a fully managed cloud service with
[credit-based pricing](https://materialize.com/pricing/). Included in the price
are proprietary cloud-native features like horizontal scalability, high
availability, and a web management console.

We&#039;re big believers in advancing the frontier of human knowledge. To
that end, the source code of the standalone database engine is publicly
available, in this repository, and [licensed](LICENSE) under the BSL 1.1,
converting to the open-source Apache 2.0 license after 4 years. As stated in the
BSL, use of the standalone database engine on a single node is free forever.

Materialize depends upon many open source Rust crates. We maintain a [list of
these crates and their licenses](https://dev.materialize.com/licenses.html),
including links to their source repositories.

## For developers

Materialize is primarily written in Rust.

Developers can find docs at [doc/developer](doc/developer), and Rust API documentation is hosted at &lt;https://dev.materialize.com/api/rust/&gt;.

Contributions are welcome. Prospective code contributors might find the [D-good
for external
contributors](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/discussions/categories/contribute-to-materialize?discussions_q=is%3Aopen+category%3A%22Contribute+to+Materialize%22+label%3A%22D-good+for+external+contributors%22)
discussion label useful. See
[CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md)
for additional guidance.

## Credits

Materialize is lovingly crafted by [a team of developers](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/graphs/contributors) and one bot. [Join us](https://materialize.com/careers/).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rustdesk/rustdesk-server]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[RustDesk Server Program]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server">rustdesk/rustdesk-server</a></h1>
            <p>RustDesk Server Program</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,516</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,669</p>
            <p>Stars today: 5 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-build-manually&quot;&gt;Manually&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#docker-images&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#s6-overlay-based-images&quot;&gt;S6-overlay&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-create-a-keypair&quot;&gt;Keypair&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#deb-packages&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#env-variables&quot;&gt;Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  [&lt;a href=&quot;README-DE.md&quot;&gt;Deutsch&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-NL.md&quot;&gt;Nederlands&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-TW.md&quot;&gt;繁體中文&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-ZH.md&quot;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

# RustDesk Server Program

[![build](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/actions/workflows/build.yaml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/actions/workflows/build.yaml)

[**Download**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases)

[**Manual**](https://rustdesk.com/docs/en/self-host/)

[**FAQ**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/wiki/FAQ)

Self-host your own RustDesk server, it is free and open source.

## How to build manually

```bash
cargo build --release
```

Three executables will be generated in target/release.

- hbbs - RustDesk ID/Rendezvous server
- hbbr - RustDesk relay server
- rustdesk-utils - RustDesk CLI utilities

You can find updated binaries on the [Releases](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases) page.

If you want extra features, [RustDesk Server Pro](https://rustdesk.com/pricing.html) might suit you better.

If you want to develop your own server, [rustdesk-server-demo](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server-demo) might be a better and simpler start for you than this repo.

## Docker images

Docker images are automatically generated and published to [Docker Hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk?tab=packages&amp;repo_name=rustdesk-server) on every GitHub release. We have 2 kind of images.

### Classic image

These images are built from scratch with two main binaries (`hbbs` and `hbbr`). They&#039;re available on [Docker Hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) with these architectures:

* amd64
* arm64v8
* armv7

You could use `latest` tag or major version tag `1` with supported architectures:

| Version       | image:tag                         |
| ------------- | --------------------------------- |
| latest        | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest` |
| Major version | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server:1`      |


You can start these images directly with `docker run` with these commands:

```bash
docker run --name hbbs --net=host -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbs -r &lt;relay-server-ip[:port]&gt; 
docker run --name hbbr --net=host -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbr 
```

or without `--net=host`, but P2P direct connection can not work.

For systems using SELinux, replacing `/root` by `/root:z` is required for the containers to run correctly. Alternatively, SELinux container separation can be disabled completely adding the option `--security-opt label=disable`.

```bash
docker run --name hbbs -p 21115:21115 -p 21116:21116 -p 21116:21116/udp -p 21118:21118 -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbs -r &lt;relay-server-ip[:port]&gt; 
docker run --name hbbr -p 21117:21117 -p 21119:21119 -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbr 
```

The `relay-server-ip` parameter is the IP address (or dns name) of the server running these containers. The **optional** `port` parameter has to be used if you use a port different than **21117** for `hbbr`.

You can also use docker-compose, using this configuration as a template:

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

networks:
  rustdesk-net:
    external: false

services:
  hbbs:
    container_name: hbbs
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21118:21118
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest
    command: hbbs -r rustdesk.example.com:21117
    volumes:
      - ./data:/root
    networks:
      - rustdesk-net
    depends_on:
      - hbbr
    restart: unless-stopped

  hbbr:
    container_name: hbbr
    ports:
      - 21117:21117
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest
    command: hbbr
    volumes:
      - ./data:/root
    networks:
      - rustdesk-net
    restart: unless-stopped
```

Edit line 16 to point to your relay server (the one listening on port 21117). You can also edit the volume lines (line 18 and line 33) if you need.

(docker-compose credit goes to @lukebarone and @QuiGonLeong)

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; The rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest in China may be replaced with the latest version number on Docker Hub, such as `rustdesk-server:1.1.10-3`. Otherwise, the old version may be pulled due to image acceleration.

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; If you are experiencing issues pulling from Docker Hub, try pulling from the [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) instead.

## S6-overlay based images

These images are build against `busybox:stable` with the addition of the binaries (both `hbbs` and `hbbr`) and [S6-overlay](https://github.com/just-containers/s6-overlay). They&#039;re available on [Docker hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6/) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) with these architectures:

* amd64
* i386
* arm64v8
* armv7

You could use `latest` tag or major version tag `1` with supported architectures:

| Version       | image:tag                            |
| ------------- | ------------------------------------ |
| latest        | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest` |
| Major version | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:1`      |

The S6-overlay acts as a supervisor and keeps both process running, so with this image, there&#039;s no need to have two separate running containers.

You can start these images directly with `docker run` with this command:

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \ 
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/data:/data&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

or without `--net=host`, but P2P direct connection cannot work.

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \
  -p 21115:21115 -p 21116:21116 -p 21116:21116/udp \
  -p 21117:21117 -p 21118:21118 -p 21119:21119 \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/data:/data&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

Or you can use a docker-compose file:

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./data:/data
    restart: unless-stopped
```

For this container image, you can use these environment variables, **in addition** to the ones specified in the following **ENV variables** section:

| variable | optional | description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| RELAY | no | the IP address/DNS name of the machine running this container |
| ENCRYPTED_ONLY | yes | if set to **&quot;1&quot;** unencrypted connection will not be accepted |
| KEY_PUB | yes | public part of the key pair |
| KEY_PRIV | yes | private part of the key pair |

### Secret management in S6-overlay based images

You can obviously keep the key pair in a docker volume, but the best practices tells you to not write the keys on the filesystem; so we provide a couple of options.

On container startup, the presence of the keypair is checked (`/data/id_ed25519.pub` and `/data/id_ed25519`) and if one of these keys doesn&#039;t exist, it&#039;s recreated from ENV variables or docker secrets.
Then the validity of the keypair is checked: if public and private keys doesn&#039;t match, the container will stop.
If you provide no keys, `hbbs` will generate one for you, and it&#039;ll place it in the default location.

#### Use ENV to store the key pair

You can use docker environment variables to store the keys. Just follow this examples:

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \ 
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -e &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot; \
  -e &quot;KEY_PRIV=FR2j78IxfwJNR+HjLluQ2Nh7eEryEeIZCwiQDPVe+PaITKyShphHAsPLn7So0OqRs92nGvSRdFJnE2MSyrKTIQ==&quot; \
  -e &quot;KEY_PUB=iEyskoaYRwLDy5+0qNDqkbPdpxr0kXRSZxNjEsqykyE=&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/db:/db&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
      - &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot;
      - &quot;KEY_PRIV=FR2j78IxfwJNR+HjLluQ2Nh7eEryEeIZCwiQDPVe+PaITKyShphHAsPLn7So0OqRs92nGvSRdFJnE2MSyrKTIQ==&quot;
      - &quot;KEY_PUB=iEyskoaYRwLDy5+0qNDqkbPdpxr0kXRSZxNjEsqykyE=&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./db:/db
    restart: unless-stopped
```

#### Use Docker secrets to store the key pair

You can alternatively use docker secrets to store the keys.
This is useful if you&#039;re using **docker-compose** or **Docker Swarm**.
Just follow this examples:

```bash
cat secrets/id_ed25519.pub | docker secret create key_pub -
cat secrets/id_ed25519 | docker secret create key_priv -
docker service create --name rustdesk-server \
  --secret key_priv --secret key_pub \
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -e &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot; \
  --mount &quot;type=bind,source=$PWD/db,destination=/db&quot; \
  rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
      - &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./db:/db
    restart: unless-stopped
    secrets:
      - key_pub
      - key_priv

secrets:
  key_pub:
    file: secrets/id_ed25519.pub
  key_priv:
    file: secrets/id_ed25519      
```

## How to create a keypair

A keypair is needed for encryption; you can provide it, as explained before, but you need a way to create one.

You can use this command to generate a keypair:

```bash
/usr/bin/rustdesk-utils genkeypair
```

If you don&#039;t have (or don&#039;t want) the `rustdesk-utils` package installed on your system, you can invoke the same command with docker:

```bash
docker run --rm --entrypoint /usr/bin/rustdesk-utils  rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest genkeypair
```

The output will be something like this:

```text
Public Key:  8BLLhtzUBU/XKAH4mep3p+IX4DSApe7qbAwNH9nv4yA=
Secret Key:  egAVd44u33ZEUIDTtksGcHeVeAwywarEdHmf99KM5ajwEsuG3NQFT9coAfiZ6nen4hfgNICl7upsDA0f2e/jIA==
```

## .deb packages

Separate .deb packages are available for each binary, you can find them in the [Releases](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases).
These packages are meant for the following distributions:

- Ubuntu 24.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 22.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 20.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 18.04 LTS
- Debian 12 bookworm
- Debian 11 bullseye
- Debian 10 buster

## ENV variables

`hbbs` and `hbbr` can be configured using these ENV variables.
You can specify the variables as usual or use an `.env` file.

| variable | binary | description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| ALWAYS_USE_RELAY | hbbs | if set to **&quot;Y&quot;** disallows direct peer connection |
| DB_URL | hbbs | path for database file |
| DOWNGRADE_START_CHECK | hbbr | delay (in seconds) before downgrade check |
| DOWNGRADE_THRESHOLD | hbbr | threshold of downgrade check (bit/ms) |
| KEY | hbbs/hbbr | if set force the use of a specific key, if set to **&quot;_&quot;** force the use of any key |
| LIMIT_SPEED | hbbr | speed limit (in Mb/s) |
| PORT | hbbs/hbbr | listening port (21116 for hbbs - 21117 for hbbr) |
| RELAY | hbbs | IP address/DNS name of the machines running hbbr (separated by comma) |
| RUST_LOG | all | set debug level (error\|warn\|info\|debug\|trace) |
| SINGLE_BANDWIDTH | hbbr | max bandwidth for a single connection (in Mb/s) |
| TOTAL_BANDWIDTH | hbbr | max total bandwidth (in Mb/s) |
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[jj-vcs/jj]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A Git-compatible VCS that is both simple and powerful]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj">jj-vcs/jj</a></h1>
            <p>A Git-compatible VCS that is both simple and powerful</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 12,027</p>
            <p>Forks: 433</p>
            <p>Stars today: 19 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div class=&quot;title-block&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# Jujutsu—a version control system

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;jj logo&quot; src=&quot;docs/images/jj-logo.svg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;320&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

[![Release](https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/martinvonz/jj)](https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/releases)
[![Release date](https://img.shields.io/github/release-date/martinvonz/jj)](https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/releases)
&lt;br/&gt;
[![License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/martinvonz/jj)](https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/blob/main/LICENSE)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/968932220549103686.svg?label=&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;color=7389D8&amp;labelColor=6A7EC2)](https://discord.gg/dkmfj3aGQN)
[![IRC](https://img.shields.io/badge/irc-%23jujutsu-blue.svg)](https://web.libera.chat/?channel=#jujutsu)

**[Homepage] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;bull;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;**
**[Installation] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;bull;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;**
**[Getting Started] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;bull;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;**
**[Development Roadmap] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;bull;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;**
**[Contributing](#contributing)**

[Homepage]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj
[Installation]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/install-and-setup
[Getting Started]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/tutorial
[Development Roadmap]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/roadmap

&lt;/div&gt;

## Introduction

Jujutsu is a powerful [version control system](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control)
for software projects. You use it to get a copy of your code, track changes
to the code, and finally publish those changes for others to see and use.
It is designed from the ground up to be easy to use—whether you&#039;re new or
experienced, working on brand new projects alone, or large scale software
projects with large histories and teams.

Jujutsu is unlike most other systems, because internally it abstracts the user
interface and version control algorithms from the *storage systems* used to
serve your content. This allows it to serve as a VCS with many possible physical
backends, that may have their own data or networking models—like [Mercurial] or
[Breezy], or hybrid systems like Google&#039;s cloud-based design, [Piper/CitC].

[Mercurial]: https://www.mercurial-scm.org/
[Breezy]: https://www.breezy-vcs.org/
[Piper/CitC]: https://youtu.be/W71BTkUbdqE?t=645

Today, we use Git repositories as a storage layer to serve and track content,
making it **compatible with many of your favorite Git-based tools, right now!**
All core developers use Jujutsu to develop Jujutsu, right here on GitHub. But it
should hopefully work with your favorite Git forges, too.

We combine many distinct design choices and concepts from other version control
systems into a single tool. Some of those sources of inspiration include:

- **Git**: We make an effort to [be fast][perf]—with a snappy UX, efficient
  algorithms, correct data structures, and good-old-fashioned attention to
  detail. The default storage backend uses Git repositories for &quot;physical
  storage&quot;, for wide interoperability and ease of onboarding.

- **Mercurial &amp; Sapling**: There are many Mercurial-inspired features, such as
  the [revset] language to select commits. There is [no explicit index][no-index]
  or staging area. Branches are &quot;anonymous&quot; like Mercurial, so you don&#039;t need
  to make up a name for each small change. Primitives for rewriting history are
  powerful and simple. Formatting output is done with a robust template language
  that can be configured by the user.

- **Darcs**: Jujutsu keeps track of conflicts as [first-class
  objects][conflicts] in its model; they are first-class in the same way commits
  are, while alternatives like Git simply think of conflicts as textual diffs.
  While not as rigorous as systems like Darcs (which is based on a formalized
  theory of patches, as opposed to snapshots), the effect is that many forms of
  conflict resolution can be performed and propagated automatically.

[perf]: https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/discussions/49
[revset]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/revsets/
[no-index]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-comparison/#the-index
[conflicts]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/conflicts/

And it adds several innovative, useful features of its own:

- **Working-copy-as-a-commit**: Changes to files are [recorded automatically][wcc]
  as normal commits, and amended on every subsequent change. This &quot;snapshot&quot;
  design simplifies the user-facing data model (commits are the only visible
  object), simplifies internal algorithms, and completely subsumes features like
  Git&#039;s stashes or the index/staging-area.

- **Operation log &amp; undo**: Jujutsu records every operation that is performed on the
  repository, from commits, to pulls, to pushes. This makes debugging problems like
  &quot;what just happened?&quot; or &quot;how did I end up here?&quot; easier, *especially* when
  you&#039;re helping your coworker answer those questions about their repository!
  And because everything is recorded, you can undo that mistake you just made
  with ease. Version control has finally entered [the 1960s][undo-history]!

- **Automatic rebase and conflict resolution**: When you modify a commit, every
  descendent is automatically rebased on top of the freshly-modified one. This
  makes &quot;patch-based&quot; workflows a breeze. If you resolve a conflict in a commit,
  the _resolution_ of that conflict is also propagated through descendants as
  well. In effect, this is a completely transparent version of `git rebase
  --update-refs` combined with `git rerere`, supported by design.

&gt; [!WARNING]
&gt; The following features are available for use, but experimental; they may have
&gt; bugs, backwards incompatible storage changes, and user-interface changes!

- **Safe, concurrent replication**: Have you ever wanted to store your version
  controlled repositories inside a Dropbox folder? Or continuously backup
  repositories to S3? No? Well, now you can!

  The fundamental problem with using filesystems like Dropbox and backup tools
  like `rsync` on your typical Git/Mercurial repositories is that they rely
  on *local filesystem operations* being atomic, serialized, and non-concurrent
  with respect to other reads and writes—which is _not_ true when operating on
  distributed file systems, or when operations like concurrent file copies (for
  backup) happen while lock files are being held.

  Jujutsu is instead designed to be [safe under concurrent scenarios][conc-safety];
  simply using rsync or Dropbox and then using that resulting repository
  should never result in a repository in a *corrupt state*. The worst that
  _should_ happen is that it will expose conflicts between the local and remote
  state, leaving you to resolve them.

[wcc]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/working-copy/
[undo-history]: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Undo#History
[conc-safety]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/technical/concurrency/

The command-line tool is called `jj` for now because it&#039;s easy to type and easy
to replace (rare in English). The project is called &quot;Jujutsu&quot; because it matches
&quot;jj&quot;.

Jujutsu is relatively young, with lots of work to still be done. If you have any
questions, or want to talk about future plans, please join us on Discord
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/968932220549103686.svg?label=&amp;logo=discord&amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;color=7389D8&amp;labelColor=6A7EC2)](https://discord.gg/dkmfj3aGQN),
start a [GitHub Discussion](https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/discussions), or
send an IRC message to [`#jujutsu` on Libera
Chat](https://web.libera.chat/?channel=#jujutsu). The developers monitor all of
these channels[^bridge].

[^bridge]: To be more precise, the `#jujutsu` Libera IRC channel is bridged to
one of the channels on jj&#039;s Discord. Some of the developers stay on Discord and
use the bridge to follow IRC.

### News and Updates 📣

- **December 2024**: The `jj` Repository has moved to the `jj-vcs` GitHub
  organisation.
- **November 2024**: Version 0.24 is released which adds `jj file annotate`,
  which is equivalent to `git blame` or `hg annotate`.
- **September 2024**: Martin gave a [presentation about Jujutsu][merge-vid-2024] at
  Git Merge 2024.
- **Feb 2024**: Version 0.14 is released, which deprecates [&quot;jj checkout&quot; and &quot;jj merge&quot;](CHANGELOG.md#0140---2024-02-07),
  as well as `jj init --git`, which is now just called `jj git init`.
- **Oct 2023**: Version 0.10.0 is released! Now includes a bundled merge and
  diff editor for all platforms, &quot;immutable revsets&quot; to avoid accidentally
  `edit`-ing the wrong revisions, and lots of polish.
- **Jan 2023**: Martin gave a presentation about Google&#039;s plans for Jujutsu at
  Git Merge 2022!
  See the [slides][merge-slides] or the [recording][merge-talk].

### Related Media

- **Mar 2024**: Chris Krycho started [a YouTube series about Jujutsu][krycho-yt].
- **Feb 2024**: Chris Krycho published an article about Jujutsu called [jj init][krycho]
  and Steve Klabnik followed up with the [Jujutsu Tutorial][klabnik].
- **Jan 2024**: Jujutsu was featured in an LWN.net article called
  [Jujutsu: a new, Git-compatible version control system][lwn].
- **Jan 2023**: Martin&#039;s Talk about Jujutsu at Git Merge 2022, [video][merge-talk]
  and the associated [slides][merge-slides].

The wiki also contains a more extensive list of [media references][wiki-media].

[krycho-yt]: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLelyiwKWHHAq01Pvmpf6x7J0y-yQpmtxp
[krycho]: https://v5.chriskrycho.com/essays/jj-init/
[klabnik]: https://steveklabnik.github.io/jujutsu-tutorial/
[lwn]: https://lwn.net/Articles/958468/
[merge-talk]: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bx_LGilOuE4
[merge-slides]: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1F8j9_UOOSGUN9MvHxPZX_L4bQ9NMcYOp1isn17kTC_M/view
[merge-vid-2024]: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LV0JzI8IcCY
[wiki-media]: https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/wiki/Media

## Getting started

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; Jujutsu is an **experimental version control system**. While Git compatibility
&gt; is stable, and most developers use it daily for all their needs, there may
&gt; still be work-in-progress features, suboptimal UX, and workflow gaps that make
&gt; it unusable for your particular use.

Follow the [installation
instructions](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/install-and-setup) to
obtain and configure `jj`.

The best way to get started is probably to go through [the
tutorial](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/tutorial). Also see the [Git
comparison](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-comparison), which
includes a table of `jj` vs. `git` commands.

As you become more familiar with Jujutsu, the following resources may be helpful:

- The [FAQ](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/FAQ).
- The [Glossary](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/glossary).
- The `jj help` command (e.g. `jj help rebase`).
- The `jj help -k &lt;keyword&gt;` command (e.g. `jj help -k config`). Use `jj help --help`
  to see what keywords are available.

If you are using a **prerelease** version of `jj`, you would want to consult
[the docs for the prerelease (main branch)
version](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/prerelease/). You can also get there
from the docs for the latest release by using the website&#039;s version switcher. The version switcher is visible in
the header of the website when you scroll to the top of any page.

## Features

### Compatible with Git

Jujutsu is designed so that the underlying data and storage model is abstract.
Today, only the Git backend is production-ready. The Git backend uses the
[libgit2](https://libgit2.org/) C library and the
[gitoxide](https://github.com/Byron/gitoxide) Rust library.

[backends]: https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/glossary#backend

The Git backend is fully featured and maintained, and allows you to use Jujutsu
with any Git remote. The commits you create will look like regular Git commits.
You can fetch branches from a regular Git remote and push branches to the
remote. You can always switch back to Git.

Here is how you can explore a GitHub repository with `jj`.

&lt;img src=&quot;demos/git_compat.png&quot; /&gt;

You can even have a [&quot;co-located&quot; local
repository](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-compatibility#co-located-jujutsugit-repos)
where you can use both `jj` and `git` commands interchangeably.

### The working copy is automatically committed

Jujutsu uses a real commit to represent the working copy. Checking out a commit
results a new working-copy commit on top of the target commit. Almost all
commands automatically amend the working-copy commit.

The working-copy being a commit means that commands never fail because the
working copy is dirty (no &quot;error: Your local changes to the following
files...&quot;), and there is no need for `git stash`. Also, because the working copy
is a commit, commands work the same way on the working-copy commit as on any
other commit, so you can set the commit message before you&#039;re done with the
changes.

&lt;img src=&quot;demos/working_copy.png&quot; /&gt;

### The repo is the source of truth

With Jujutsu, the working copy plays a smaller role than with Git. Commands
snapshot the working copy before they start, then they update the repo, and then
the working copy is updated (if the working-copy commit was modified). Almost
all commands (even checkout!) operate on the commits in the repo, leaving the
common functionality of snapshotting and updating of the working copy to
centralized code. For example, `jj restore` (similar to `git restore`) can
restore from any commit and into any commit, and `jj describe` can set the
commit message of any commit (defaults to the working-copy commit).

### Entire repo is under version control

All operations you perform in the repo are recorded, along with a snapshot of
the repo state after the operation. This means that you can easily revert to an
earlier repo state, or to simply undo a particular operation (which does not
necessarily have to be the most recent operation).

&lt;img src=&quot;demos/operation_log.png&quot; /&gt;

### Conflicts can be recorded in commits

If an operation results in
[conflicts](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/glossary#conflict),
information about those conflicts will be recorded in the commit(s). The
operation will succeed. You can then resolve the conflicts later. One
consequence of this design is that there&#039;s no need to continue interrupted
operations. Instead, you get a single workflow for resolving conflicts,
regardless of which command caused them. This design also lets Jujutsu rebase
merge commits correctly (unlike both Git and Mercurial).

Basic conflict resolution:

&lt;img src=&quot;demos/resolve_conflicts.png&quot; /&gt;

Juggling conflicts:

&lt;img src=&quot;demos/juggle_conflicts.png&quot; /&gt;

### Automatic rebase

Whenever you modify a commit, any descendants of the old commit will be rebased
onto the new commit. Thanks to the conflict design described above, that can be
done even if there are conflicts. Bookmarks pointing to rebased commits will be
updated. So will the working copy if it points to a rebased commit.

### Comprehensive support for rewriting history

Besides the usual rebase command, there&#039;s `jj describe` for editing the
description (commit message) of an arbitrary commit. There&#039;s also `jj diffedit`,
which lets you edit the changes in a commit without checking it out. To split
a commit into two, use `jj split`. You can even move part of the changes in a
commit to any other commit using `jj squash -i --from X --into Y`.

## Status

The tool is fairly feature-complete, but some important features like support
for Git submodules are not yet completed. There
are also several performance bugs. It&#039;s likely that workflows and setups
different from what the core developers use are not well supported, e.g. there
is no native support for email-based workflows.

Today, all core developers use `jj` to work on `jj`. I (Martin von Zweigbergk)
have almost exclusively used `jj` to develop the project itself since early
January 2021. I haven&#039;t had to re-clone from source (I don&#039;t think I&#039;ve even had
to restore from backup).

There *will* be changes to workflows and backward-incompatible changes to the
on-disk formats before version 1.0.0. Even the binary&#039;s name may change (i.e.
away from `jj`). For any format changes, we&#039;ll try to implement transparent
upgrades (as we&#039;ve done with recent changes), or provide upgrade commands or
scripts if requested.

## Related work

There are several tools trying to solve similar problems as Jujutsu. See
[related work](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/related-work) for details.

## Contributing

We welcome outside contributions, and there&#039;s plenty of things to do, so
don&#039;t be shy. Please ask if you want a pointer on something you can help with,
and hopefully we can all figure something out.

We do have [a few policies and
suggestions](https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/prerelease/contributing/)
for contributors. The broad TL;DR:

- Bug reports are very welcome!
- Every commit that lands in the `main` branch is code reviewed.
- Please behave yourself, and obey the Community Guidelines.
- There **is** a mandatory CLA you must agree to. Importantly, it **does not**
  transfer copyright ownership to Google or anyone else; it simply gives us the
  right to safely redistribute and use your changes.

### Mandatory Google Disclaimer

I (Martin von Zweigbergk, &lt;martinvonz@google.com&gt;) started Jujutsu as a hobby
project in late 2019, and it has evolved into my full-time project at Google,
with several other Googlers (now) assisting development in various capacities.
That said, **this is not a Google product**.

## License

Jujutsu is available as Open Source Software, under the Apache 2.0 license. See
[`LICENSE`](./LICENSE) for details about copyright and redistribution.

The `jj` logo was contributed by J. Jennings and is licensed under a Creative
Commons License, see [`docs/images/LICENSE`](docs/images/LICENSE).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>