<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for rust - Rust Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for rust.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[juspay/hyperswitch]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch">juspay/hyperswitch</a></h1>
            <p>An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,356</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,550</p>
            <p>Stars today: 240 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-dark.svg#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-light.svg#gh-light-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Open-Source Payments Orchestration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; &gt;
Single API to access the payments ecosystem and its features
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/actions?query=workflow%3ACI+branch%3Amain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/workflows/CI-push/badge.svg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Made_in-Rust-orange&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- Uncomment when we reach &gt;50% coverage --&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch/graph/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/hyperswitch/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-hyperswitch-blue?logo=linkedin&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/hyperswitchio&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-%40hyperswitchio-white?logo=x&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on_slack-blue?logo=slack&amp;labelColor=grey&amp;color=%233f0e40&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

## Table of Contents

1. [Introduction](#introduction)
2. [Architectural Overview](#architectural-overview) 
3. [Try Hyperswitch](#try-hyperswitch)  
4. [Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs](#support-feature-requests)  
5. [Our Vision](#our-vision)  
6. [Versioning](#versioning)  
7. [Copyright and License](#copyright-and-license)

&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
Juspay, founded in 2012, is a global leader in payment orchestration and checkout solutions, trusted by 400+ leading enterprises and brands worldwide. Hyperswitch is Juspay&#039;s new generation of composable, commercial open-source payments platform for merchant and brands. It is an enterprise-grade, transparent and modular payments platform designed to provide digital businesses access to the best payments infrastructure.

Here are the key components of Hyperswitch that deliver the whole solution:

* [Hyperswitch Backend](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch): Hyperswitch backend enables seamless payment processing with comprehensive support for various payment flows - authorization, authentication, void and capture workflows along with robust management of post-payment processes like refunds and chargeback handling. Additionally, Hyperswitch supports non-payment use cases by enabling connections with external FRM or authentication providers as part of the payment flow. The backend optimizes payment routing with customizable workflows, including success rate-based routing, rule-based routing, volume distribution, fallback handling, and intelligent retry mechanisms for failed payments based on specific error codes.

* [SDK (Frontend)](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-web): The SDK, available for web, [Android, and iOS](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-client-core), unifies the payment experience across various methods such as cards, wallets, BNPL, bank transfers, and more, while supporting the diverse payment flows of underlying PSPs. When paired with the locker, it surfaces the user&#039;s saved payment methods.    

* [Control Center](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-control-center): The Control Center enables users to manage the entire payments stack without any coding. It allows the creation of workflows for routing, payment retries, and defining conditions to invoke 3DS, fraud risk management (FRM), and surcharge modules. The Control Center provides access to transaction, refund, and chargeback operations across all integrated PSPs, transaction-level logs for initial debugging, and detailed analytics and insights into payment performance.

Read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/).

&lt;a href=&quot;#architectural-overview&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;architectural-overview&quot;&gt;Architectural Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/features.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/non-functional-features.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-architecture-v1.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;#try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Try Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### 1. Local Setup

You can run Hyperswitch on your system using Docker compose after cloning this repository. 

```shell
git clone --depth 1 --branch latest https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch
cd hyperswitch
docker compose up -d
```

Check out the [local setup guide][local-setup-guide] for a more details on setting up the entire stack or component wise. This takes 15-mins and gives the following output 
```shell
[+] Running 2/2
✔ hyperswitch-control-center Pulled 2.9s
✔ hyperswitch-server Pulled 3.0s
[+] Running 6/0

✔ Container hyperswitch-pg-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-redis-standalone-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-migration_runner-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-server-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-web-1 Created 0.0s
✔ Container hyperswitch-hyperswitch-control-center-1 Created 0.0s

Attaching to hyperswitch-control-center-1, hyperswitch-server-1, hyperswitch-web-1, migration_runner-1, pg-1, redis-standalone-1
```

### 2. Deployment on cloud

The fastest and easiest way to try Hyperswitch on AWS is via our CDK scripts

1. Click on the following button for a quick standalone deployment on AWS, suitable for prototyping.
   No code or setup is required in your system and the deployment is covered within the AWS free-tier setup.

   &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home?region=us-east-1#/stacks/new?stackName=HyperswitchBootstarp&amp;templateURL=https://hyperswitch-synth.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/hs-starter-config.yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/docs/imgs/aws_button.png?raw=true&quot; height=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

2. Sign-in to your AWS console.

3. Follow the instructions provided on the console to successfully deploy Hyperswitch. This takes 30-45mins and gives the following output 

| Service| Host|
|----------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------|
| App server running on                        | `http://hyperswitch-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| HyperloaderJS Hosted at                      | `http://&lt;cloudfront.host-id&gt;/0.103.1/v0/HyperLoader.js` |
| Control center server running on             | `http://hyperswitch-control-center-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with Email: `test@gmail.com` |
| Hyperswitch Demo Store running on            | `http://hyperswitch-sdk-demo-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| Logs server running on                       | `http://hyperswitch-logs-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with username: `admin`, password: `admin` |

We support deployment on GCP and Azure via Helm charts which takes 30-45mins. You can read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/deploy-on-kubernetes-using-helm). 

### 3. Hosted Sandbox

You can experience the product by signing up for our [hosted sandbox](https://app.hyperswitch.io/). The signup process accepts any email ID and provides access to the entire Control Center. You can set up connectors, define workflows for routing and retries, and even try payments from the dashboard.

[docs-link-for-enterprise]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-cloud/quickstart
[docs-link-for-developers]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/overview
[contributing-guidelines]: docs/CONTRIBUTING.md
[dashboard-link]: https://app.hyperswitch.io/
[website-link]: https://hyperswitch.io/
[learning-resources]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/learn-more/payment-flows
[local-setup-guide]: /docs/try_local_system.md
[docker-compose-scheduler-monitoring]: /docs/try_local_system.md#running-additional-services


&lt;a href=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

For any support, join the conversation in [Slack](https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw)

For new product features, enhancements, roadmap discussions, or to share queries and ideas, visit our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/discussions)

For reporting a bug, please read the issue guidelines and search for [existing and closed issues]. If your problem or idea is not addressed yet, please [open a new issue].

[existing and closed issues]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues
[open a new issue]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues/new/choose

&lt;a href=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;Our Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&gt; Linux for Payments

Payments are evolving rapidly worldwide, with hundreds of processors, fraud detection systems, authentication modules, and new payment methods and flows emerging. Businesses building or managing their own payment stacks often face similar challenges, struggle with comparable issues, and find it hard to innovate at the desired pace.

Hyperswitch serves as a well-architected designed reference platform, built on best-in-class design principles, empowering businesses to own and customize their payment stack. It provides a reusable core payments stack that can be tailored to specific requirements while relying on the Hyperswitch team for enhancements, support, and continuous innovation.

### Our Values

1. Embrace Payments Diversity: It will drive innovation in the ecosystem in
   multiple ways.
2. Make it Open Source: Increases trust; Improves the quality and reusability of
   software.
3. Be community driven: It enables participatory design and development.
4. Build it like Systems Software: This sets a high bar for Reliability,
   Security and Performance SLAs.
5. Maximise Value Creation: For developers, customers &amp; partners.

This project is being created and maintained by [Juspay](https://juspay.io)

&lt;a href=&quot;#versioning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;versioning&quot;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Check the [CHANGELOG.md](./CHANGELOG.md) file for details.

&lt;a href=&quot;#copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;Copyright and License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

This product is licensed under the [Apache 2.0 License](LICENSE).


&lt;a href=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Team behind Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

The core team of 150+ engineers building Hyperswitch. Keep up the great work! 🥂

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=juspay/hyperswitch&quot; alt=&quot;Contributors&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EFForg/rayhunter]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Rust tool to detect cell site simulators on an orbic mobile hotspot]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter">EFForg/rayhunter</a></h1>
            <p>Rust tool to detect cell site simulators on an orbic mobile hotspot</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,653</p>
            <p>Forks: 120</p>
            <p>Stars today: 98 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![Rayhunter Logo - An Orca taking a bite out of a cellular signal bar](https://www.eff.org/files/styles/media_browser_preview/public/banner_library/rayhunter-banner.png)
# Rayhunter

![Tests](https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/actions/workflows/check-and-test.yml/badge.svg)

Rayhunter is an IMSI Catcher Catcher for the Orbic mobile hotspot.

**THIS CODE IS A PROOF OF CONCEPT AND SHOULD NOT BE RELIED UPON IN HIGH RISK SITUATIONS!**


## The Hardware

Rayhunter has been built and tested for the Orbic RC400L mobile hotspot. It may work on other orbics and other
linux/qualcom devices, but this is the only one we have tested on.
Buy the orbic [using bezos bucks](https://www.amazon.com/Orbic-Verizon-Hotspot-Connect-Enabled/dp/B08N3CHC4Y),
or on [Ebay](https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=orbic+rc400l).

## Setup


1. Download the latest [Rayhunter release bundle](https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/releases) and extract it.
**If you are installing from the cloned github repository please see the development instructions below, running `install.sh` from the git tree will not work.**
2. Turn on the Orbic device and plug it into your computer using a USB-C Cable.
3. On MacOS or Linux run the install script `install.sh`. 
4. Once finished, Rayhunter should be running! You can verify this by visiting the web UI as described below.

### Notes 
  * The install script has only been tested for Linux on the latest version of Ubuntu. If it fails you will need to follow the install steps outlined in **Development** below.
  * The install script also won&#039;t work on older macs with intel chips, for those macs you will need to follow the instructions at https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/wiki/Install-Rayhunter-on-Mac-Intel-devices
  * We don&#039;t currently support automated installs on windows, you will have to follow the manual install instructions below*

## Updating
Great news: if you&#039;ve successfully installed rayhunter, you already know how to update it! Our update process is identical to the setup process: simply download the latest release and follow the steps in the [setup section](#Setup).


## Usage

Once installed, Rayhunter will run automatically whenever your Orbic device is running. It serves a web UI that provides some basic controls, such as being able to start/stop recordings, download captures, and view heuristic analyses of captures. You can access this UI in one of two ways:

1. Over wifi: Connect your phone/laptop to the Orbic&#039;s wifi network and visit `http://192.168.1.1:8080` (click past your browser warning you about the connection not being secure, Rayhunter doesn&#039;t have HTTPS yet!).
    * Note that you&#039;ll need the Orbic&#039;s wifi password for this, which can be retrieved by pressing the &quot;MENU&quot; button on the device and opening the 2.4 GHz menu.
2. Over usb: Connect the Orbic device to your laptop via usb. Run `adb forward tcp:8080 tcp:8080`, then visit `http://localhost:8080`. For this you will need to install the Android Debug Bridge (ADB) on your computer, you can copy the version that was downloaded inside the releases/platform-tools/` folder to somewhere else in your path or you can install it manually.  You can find instructions for doing so on your platform [here](https://www.xda-developers.com/install-adb-windows-macos-linux/#how-to-set-up-adb-on-your-computer), (don&#039;t worry about instructions for installing it on a phone/device yet).

## Frequently Asked Questions

### Do I need an active SIM card to use Rayhunter?
**It Depends**. Operation of Rayhunter does require the insertion of a SIM card into the device, but whether that SIM card has to be currently active for our tests to work is still under investigation. If you want to use the device as a hotspot in addition to a research device an active plan would of course be necessary, however we have not done enough testing yet to know whether an active subscription is required for detection. If you want to test the device with an inactive SIM card, we would certainly be interested in seeing any data you collect, and especially any runs that trigger an alert!
### Help, Rayhunter&#039;s line is red! What should I do?
Unfortunately, the circumstances that might lead to a positive CSS signal are quite varied, so we don&#039;t have a universal recommendation for how to deal with the a positive signal. Depending on your circumstances and threat model, you may want to turn off your phone until you are out of the area (or put it on airplane mode) and tell your friends to do the same!

If you&#039;ve received a Rayhunter warning and would like to help us with our research, please send your Rayhunter data captures (QMDL and PCAP logs) to us at our [Signal](https://signal.org/) username [**ElectronicFrontierFoundation.90**](https://signal.me/#eu/HZbPPED5LyMkbTxJsG2PtWc2TXxPUR1OxBMcJGLOPeeCDGPuaTpOi5cfGRY6RrGf) with the following information: capture date, capture location, device, device model, and Rayhunter version. If you&#039;re unfamiliar with Signal, feel free to check out our [Security Self Defense guide on it](https://ssd.eff.org/module/how-to-use-signal).
 
Please note that this file may contain sensitive information such as your IMSI and the unique IDs of cell towers you were near which could be used to ascertain your location at the time.

### Does Rayhunter work outside of the US?
**Probably**. Some Rayhunter users have reported successfully using it in other countries with unlocked devices and SIM cards from local telcos. We can&#039;t guarantee whether or not it will work for you though.
### Should I get a locked or unlocked orbic device? What is the difference?
If you want to use a non verizon SIM card you will probably need an unlocked device. But it&#039;s not clear how locked the locked devices are nor how to unlock them, we welcome any experimentation and information regarding the use of unlocked devices.
### Does Rayhunter work on any other devices besides the Orbic RC400L?
**Maybe**. We have not tested Rayhunter on any other hardware but we would love to expand the supported platforms. We will consider giving official support to any hardware platform that can be bought for around $20-30USD. The Rayhunter daemon should theoretically work on any linux/android device that has a qualcomm chip with a /dev/diag interface and root access, though our installer script has only been tested with an Orbic. If you get it working on another device, please let us know!
### How do I delete capture files from the Rayhunter device?
You can get a shell on the device by inputting `adb shell` to a terminal with the device connected, you can check if it is detected with `adb devices`.
The capture files are located at */data/rayhunter/qmdl* but you will need root access to modify or delete them. From the adb shell run `/bin/rootshell` and you can now use commands like &#039;rm&#039; as root to modify and delete entries in the */data/rayhunter/qmdl* directory. **Be careful not to delete important files in other directories as you may seriously damage the device**.

## Development
* Install ADB on your computer using the instructions above, and make sure it&#039;s in your terminal&#039;s PATH
  * You can verify if ADB is in your PATH by running `which adb` in a terminal. If it prints the filepath to where ADB is installed, you&#039;re set! Otherwise, try following one of these guides:
    * [linux](https://askubuntu.com/questions/652936/adding-android-sdk-platform-tools-to-path-downloaded-from-umake)
    * [macOS](https://www.repeato.app/setting-up-adb-on-macos-a-step-by-step-guide/)
    * [Windows](https://medium.com/@yadav-ajay/a-step-by-step-guide-to-setting-up-adb-path-on-windows-0b833faebf18)

### If you&#039;re on x86 linux
Install rust the usual way and then install cross compiling dependences:
```
sudo apt install curl build-essential libc6-armhf-cross libc6-dev-armhf-cross gcc-arm-linux-gnueabihf
rustup target add x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu
rustup target add armv7-unknown-linux-gnueabihf
```

Now you can root your device and install Rayhunter by running `./tools/install-dev.sh`

### If you&#039;re on windows or can&#039;t run the install scripts
* Root your device on windows using the instructions here: https://xdaforums.com/t/resetting-verizon-orbic-speed-rc400l-firmware-flash-kajeet.4334899/#post-87855183

* Build for arm using `cargo build`

* Run tests using `cargo test_pc`

* Push the scripts in `scripts/` to `/etc/init.d` on device and make a directory called `/data/rayhunter` using `adb shell` (and sshell for your root shell if you followed the steps above)

* you also need to copy `config.toml.example` to `/data/rayhunter/config.toml`

* Then run `./make.sh` this will build the binary and push it over adb. Restart your device or run `/etc/init.d/rayhunter_daemon start` on the device and you are good to go.

* Write your code and write tests

* Build for arm using `cargo build`

* Run tests using `cargo test_pc`

* push to the device with `./make.sh`

## Support and Discussion

If you&#039;re having issues installing or using Rayhunter, please open an issue in this repo. Join us in the `#rayhunter` channel of [EFF&#039;s Mattermost](https://opensource.eff.org/signup_user_complete/?id=6iqur37ucfrctfswrs14iscobw&amp;md=link&amp;sbr=su) instance to chat!

## Documentation
* Build docs locally using `RUSTDOCFLAGS=&quot;--cfg docsrs&quot; cargo doc --no-deps --all-features  --open`

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER:** Use this program at your own risk. We believe running this program does not currently violate any laws or regulations in the United States. However, we are not responsible for civil or criminal liability resulting from the use of this software. If you are located outside of the US please consult with an attorney in your country to help you assess the legal risks of running this program.

*Good Hunting!*
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[sharkdp/bat]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/sharkdp/bat</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/sharkdp/bat</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A cat(1) clone with wings.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/sharkdp/bat">sharkdp/bat</a></h1>
            <p>A cat(1) clone with wings.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 51,945</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,287</p>
            <p>Stars today: 28 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;doc/logo-header.svg&quot; alt=&quot;bat - a cat clone with wings&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/actions?query=workflow%3ACICD&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/workflows/CICD/badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/l/bat.svg&quot; alt=&quot;license&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/bat&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/bat.svg?colorB=319e8c&quot; alt=&quot;Version info&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  A &lt;i&gt;cat(1)&lt;/i&gt; clone with syntax highlighting and Git integration.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#syntax-highlighting&quot;&gt;Key Features&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-use&quot;&gt;How To Use&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#customization&quot;&gt;Customization&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#project-goals-and-alternatives&quot;&gt;Project goals, alternatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  [English]
  [&lt;a href=&quot;doc/README-zh.md&quot;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt;]
  [&lt;a href=&quot;doc/README-ja.md&quot;&gt;日本語&lt;/a&gt;]
  [&lt;a href=&quot;doc/README-ko.md&quot;&gt;한국어&lt;/a&gt;]
  [&lt;a href=&quot;doc/README-ru.md&quot;&gt;Русский&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;

### Sponsors

A special *thank you* goes to our biggest &lt;a href=&quot;doc/sponsors.md&quot;&gt;sponsor&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warp.dev/bat&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;doc/sponsors/warp-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; alt=&quot;Warp&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Warp, the intelligent terminal&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;sub&gt;Available on MacOS, Linux, Windows&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### Syntax highlighting

`bat` supports syntax highlighting for a large number of programming and markup
languages:

![Syntax highlighting example](https://imgur.com/rGsdnDe.png)

### Git integration

`bat` communicates with `git` to show modifications with respect to the index
(see left side bar):

![Git integration example](https://i.imgur.com/2lSW4RE.png)

### Show non-printable characters

You can use the `-A`/`--show-all` option to show and highlight non-printable
characters:

![Non-printable character example](https://i.imgur.com/WndGp9H.png)

### Automatic paging

By default, `bat` pipes its own output to a pager (e.g. `less`) if the output is too large for one screen.
If you would rather `bat` work like `cat` all the time (never page output), you can set `--paging=never` as an option, either on the command line or in your configuration file.
If you intend to alias `cat` to `bat` in your shell configuration, you can use `alias cat=&#039;bat --paging=never&#039;` to preserve the default behavior.

#### File concatenation

Even with a pager set, you can still use `bat` to concatenate files :wink:.
Whenever `bat` detects a non-interactive terminal (i.e. when you pipe into another process or into a file), `bat` will act as a drop-in replacement for `cat` and fall back to printing the plain file contents, regardless of the `--pager` option&#039;s value.

## How to use

Display a single file on the terminal

```bash
&gt; bat README.md
```

Display multiple files at once

```bash
&gt; bat src/*.rs
```

Read from stdin, determine the syntax automatically (note, highlighting will
only work if the syntax can be determined from the first line of the file,
usually through a shebang such as `#!/bin/sh`)

```bash
&gt; curl -s https://sh.rustup.rs | bat
```

Read from stdin, specify the language explicitly

```bash
&gt; yaml2json .travis.yml | json_pp | bat -l json
```

Show and highlight non-printable characters:
```bash
&gt; bat -A /etc/hosts
```

Use it as a `cat` replacement:

```bash
bat &gt; note.md  # quickly create a new file

bat header.md content.md footer.md &gt; document.md

bat -n main.rs  # show line numbers (only)

bat f - g  # output &#039;f&#039;, then stdin, then &#039;g&#039;.
```

### Integration with other tools

#### `fzf`

You can use `bat` as a previewer for [`fzf`](https://github.com/junegunn/fzf). To do this,
use `bat`s `--color=always` option to force colorized output. You can also use `--line-range`
option to restrict the load times for long files:

```bash
fzf --preview &quot;bat --color=always --style=numbers --line-range=:500 {}&quot;
```

For more information, see [`fzf`&#039;s `README`](https://github.com/junegunn/fzf#preview-window).

#### `find` or `fd`

You can use the `-exec` option of `find` to preview all search results with `bat`:

```bash
find … -exec bat {} +
```

If you happen to use [`fd`](https://github.com/sharkdp/fd), you can use the `-X`/`--exec-batch` option to do the same:

```bash
fd … -X bat
```

#### `ripgrep`

With [`batgrep`](https://github.com/eth-p/bat-extras/blob/master/doc/batgrep.md), `bat` can be used as the printer for [`ripgrep`](https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep) search results.

```bash
batgrep needle src/
```

#### `tail -f`

`bat` can be combined with `tail -f` to continuously monitor a given file with syntax highlighting.

```bash
tail -f /var/log/pacman.log | bat --paging=never -l log
```

Note that we have to switch off paging in order for this to work. We have also specified the syntax
explicitly (`-l log`), as it can not be auto-detected in this case.

#### `git`

You can combine `bat` with `git show` to view an older version of a given file with proper syntax
highlighting:

```bash
git show v0.6.0:src/main.rs | bat -l rs
```

#### `git diff`

You can combine `bat` with `git diff` to view lines around code changes with proper syntax
highlighting:
```bash
batdiff() {
    git diff --name-only --relative --diff-filter=d | xargs bat --diff
}
```
If you prefer to use this as a separate tool, check out `batdiff` in [`bat-extras`](https://github.com/eth-p/bat-extras).

If you are looking for more support for git and diff operations, check out [`delta`](https://github.com/dandavison/delta).

#### `xclip`

The line numbers and Git modification markers in the output of `bat` can make it hard to copy
the contents of a file. To prevent this, you can call `bat` with the `-p`/`--plain` option or
simply pipe the output into `xclip`:
```bash
bat main.cpp | xclip
```
`bat` will detect that the output is being redirected and print the plain file contents.

#### `man`

`bat` can be used as a colorizing pager for `man`, by setting the
`MANPAGER` environment variable:

```bash
export MANPAGER=&quot;sh -c &#039;sed -u -e \&quot;s/\\x1B\[[0-9;]*m//g; s/.\\x08//g\&quot; | bat -p -lman&#039;&quot;
man 2 select
```
(replace `bat` with `batcat` if you are on Debian or Ubuntu)

If you prefer to have this bundled in a new command, you can also use [`batman`](https://github.com/eth-p/bat-extras/blob/master/doc/batman.md).

&gt; [!WARNING]  
&gt; This will [not work](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/issues/1145) out of the box with Mandoc&#039;s `man` implementation.
&gt;
&gt; Please either use `batman`, or convert the shell script to a [shebang executable](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix)) and point `MANPAGER` to that.

Note that the [Manpage syntax](assets/syntaxes/02_Extra/Manpage.sublime-syntax) is developed in this repository and still needs some work.

#### `prettier` / `shfmt` / `rustfmt`

The [`prettybat`](https://github.com/eth-p/bat-extras/blob/master/doc/prettybat.md) script is a wrapper that will format code and print it with `bat`.

#### `Warp`

&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.warp.dev/drive/folder/-Bat-Warp-Pack-lxhe7HrEwgwpG17mvrFSz1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;doc/sponsors/warp-pack-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Warp&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

#### Highlighting `--help` messages

You can use `bat` to colorize help text: `$ cp --help | bat -plhelp`

You can also use a wrapper around this:

```bash
# in your .bashrc/.zshrc/*rc
alias bathelp=&#039;bat --plain --language=help&#039;
help() {
    &quot;$@&quot; --help 2&gt;&amp;1 | bathelp
}
```

Then you can do `$ help cp` or `$ help git commit`.

When you are using `zsh`, you can also use global aliases to override `-h` and `--help` entirely:

```bash
alias -g -- -h=&#039;-h 2&gt;&amp;1 | bat --language=help --style=plain&#039;
alias -g -- --help=&#039;--help 2&gt;&amp;1 | bat --language=help --style=plain&#039;
```

For `fish`, you can use abbreviations:

```fish
abbr -a --position anywhere -- --help &#039;--help | bat -plhelp&#039;
abbr -a --position anywhere -- -h &#039;-h | bat -plhelp&#039;
```

This way, you can keep on using `cp --help`, but get colorized help pages.

Be aware that in some cases, `-h` may not be a shorthand of `--help` (for example with `ls`).

Please report any issues with the help syntax in [this repository](https://github.com/victor-gp/cmd-help-sublime-syntax).


## Installation

[![Packaging status](https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/bat-cat.svg?columns=3&amp;exclude_unsupported=1)](https://repology.org/project/bat-cat/versions)

### On Ubuntu (using `apt`)
*... and other Debian-based Linux distributions.*

`bat` is available on [Ubuntu since 20.04 (&quot;Focal&quot;)](https://packages.ubuntu.com/search?keywords=bat&amp;exact=1) and [Debian since August 2021 (Debian 11 - &quot;Bullseye&quot;)](https://packages.debian.org/bullseye/bat).

If your Ubuntu/Debian installation is new enough you can simply run:

```bash
sudo apt install bat
```

**Important**: If you install `bat` this way, please note that the executable may be installed as `batcat` instead of `bat` (due to [a name
clash with another package](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/issues/982)). You can set up a `bat -&gt; batcat` symlink or alias to prevent any issues that may come up because of this and to be consistent with other distributions:
``` bash
mkdir -p ~/.local/bin
ln -s /usr/bin/batcat ~/.local/bin/bat
```

### On Ubuntu (using most recent `.deb` packages)
*... and other Debian-based Linux distributions.*

If the package has not yet been promoted to your Ubuntu/Debian installation, or you want
the most recent release of `bat`, download the latest `.deb` package from the
[release page](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/releases) and install it via:

```bash
sudo dpkg -i bat_0.18.3_amd64.deb  # adapt version number and architecture
```

### On Alpine Linux

You can install [the `bat` package](https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/packages?name=bat)
from the official sources, provided you have the appropriate repository enabled:

```bash
apk add bat
```

### On Arch Linux

You can install [the `bat` package](https://www.archlinux.org/packages/extra/x86_64/bat/)
from the official sources:

```bash
pacman -S bat
```

### On Fedora

You can install [the `bat` package](https://koji.fedoraproject.org/koji/packageinfo?packageID=27506) from the official [Fedora Modular](https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/modularity/using-modules/) repository.

```bash
dnf install bat
```

### On Funtoo Linux

You can install [the `bat` package](https://github.com/funtoo/dev-kit/tree/1.4-release/sys-apps/bat) from dev-kit.

```bash
emerge sys-apps/bat
```

### On Gentoo Linux

You can install [the `bat` package](https://packages.gentoo.org/packages/sys-apps/bat)
from the official sources:

```bash
emerge sys-apps/bat
```

### On Void Linux

You can install `bat` via xbps-install:
```bash
xbps-install -S bat
```

### On Termux

You can install `bat` via pkg:
```bash
pkg install bat
```

### On FreeBSD

You can install a precompiled [`bat` package](https://www.freshports.org/textproc/bat) with pkg:

```bash
pkg install bat
```

or build it on your own from the FreeBSD ports:

```bash
cd /usr/ports/textproc/bat
make install
```

### On OpenBSD

You can install `bat` package using [`pkg_add(1)`](https://man.openbsd.org/pkg_add.1):

```bash
pkg_add bat
```

### Via nix

You can install `bat` using the [nix package manager](https://nixos.org/nix):

```bash
nix-env -i bat
```

### Via flox

You can install `bat` using [Flox](https://flox.dev)

```bash
flox install bat
```

### On openSUSE

You can install `bat` with zypper:

```bash
zypper install bat
```

### Via snap package

There is currently no recommended snap package available.
Existing packages may be available, but are not officially supported and may contain [issues](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/issues/1519).

### On macOS (or Linux) via Homebrew

You can install `bat` with [Homebrew](https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/bat):

```bash
brew install bat
```

### On macOS via MacPorts

Or install `bat` with [MacPorts](https://ports.macports.org/port/bat/summary):

```bash
port install bat
```

### On Windows

There are a few options to install `bat` on Windows. Once you have installed `bat`,
take a look at the [&quot;Using `bat` on Windows&quot;](#using-bat-on-windows) section.

#### Prerequisites

You will need to install the [Visual C++ Redistributable](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2977003/the-latest-supported-visual-c-downloads) package.

#### With WinGet

You can install `bat` via [WinGet](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/package-manager/winget):

```bash
winget install sharkdp.bat
```

#### With Chocolatey

You can install `bat` via [Chocolatey](https://chocolatey.org/packages/Bat):
```bash
choco install bat
```

#### With Scoop

You can install `bat` via [scoop](https://scoop.sh/):
```bash
scoop install bat
```

#### From prebuilt binaries:

You can download prebuilt binaries from the [Release page](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/releases),

You will need to install the [Visual C++ Redistributable](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2977003/the-latest-supported-visual-c-downloads) package.

### From binaries

Check out the [Release page](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/releases) for
prebuilt versions of `bat` for many different architectures. Statically-linked
binaries are also available: look for archives with `musl` in the file name.

### From source

If you want to build `bat` from source, you need Rust 1.74.0 or
higher. You can then use `cargo` to build everything:

```bash
cargo install --locked bat
```

Note that additional files like the man page or shell completion
files can not be installed in this way. They will be generated by `cargo` and should be available in the cargo target folder (under `build`).

Shell completions are also available by running:
```bash
bat --completion &lt;shell&gt;
# see --help for supported shells
```

## Customization

### Highlighting theme

Use `bat --list-themes` to get a list of all available themes for syntax
highlighting. To select the `TwoDark` theme, call `bat` with the
`--theme=TwoDark` option or set the `BAT_THEME` environment variable to
`TwoDark`. Use `export BAT_THEME=&quot;TwoDark&quot;` in your shell&#039;s startup file to
make the change permanent. Alternatively, use `bat`s
[configuration file](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat#configuration-file).

If you want to preview the different themes on a custom file, you can use
the following command (you need [`fzf`](https://github.com/junegunn/fzf) for this):
```bash
bat --list-themes | fzf --preview=&quot;bat --theme={} --color=always /path/to/file&quot;
```

`bat` automatically picks a fitting theme depending on your terminal&#039;s background color.
You can use the `--theme-dark` / `--theme-light` options or the `BAT_THEME_DARK` / `BAT_THEME_LIGHT` environment variables
to customize the themes used. This is especially useful if you frequently switch between dark and light mode.

You can also use a custom theme by following the
[&#039;Adding new themes&#039; section below](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat#adding-new-themes).

### 8-bit themes

`bat` has three themes that always use [8-bit colors](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ANSI_escape_code#Colors),
even when truecolor support is available:

- `ansi` looks decent on any terminal. It uses 3-bit colors: black, red, green,
  yellow, blue, magenta, cyan, and white.
- `base16` is designed for [base16](https://github.com/chriskempson/base16) terminal themes. It uses
  4-bit colors (3-bit colors plus bright variants) in accordance with the
  [base16 styling guidelines](https://github.com/chriskempson/base16/blob/master/styling.md).
- `base16-256` is designed for [base16-shell](https://github.com/chriskempson/base16-shell).
  It replaces certain bright colors with 8-bit colors from 16 to 21. **Do not** use this simply
  because you have a 256-color terminal but are not using base16-shell.

Although these themes are more restricted, they have three advantages over truecolor themes. They:

- Enjoy maximum compatibility. Some terminal utilities do not support more than 3-bit colors.
- Adapt to terminal theme changes. Even for already printed output.
- Visually harmonize better with other terminal software.

### Output style

You can use the `--style` option to control the appearance of `bat`s output.
You can use `--style=numbers,changes`, for example, to show only Git changes
and line numbers but no grid and no file header. Set the `BAT_STYLE` environment
variable to make these changes permanent or use `bat`s
[configuration file](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat#configuration-file).

&gt;[!tip]
&gt; If you specify a default style in `bat`&#039;s config file, you can change which components
&gt; are displayed during a single run of `bat` using the `--style` command-line argument.
&gt; By prefixing a component with `+` or `-`, it can be added or removed from the current style.
&gt;
&gt; For example, if your config contains `--style=full,-snip`, you can run bat with
&gt; `--style=-grid,+snip` to remove the grid and add back the `snip` component.
&gt; Or, if you want to override the styles completely, you use `--style=numbers` to
&gt; only show the line numbers.

### Adding new syntaxes / language definitions

Should you find that a particular syntax is not available within `bat`, you can follow these
instructions to easily add new syntaxes to your current `bat` installation.

`bat` uses the excellent [`syntect`](https://github.com/trishume/syntect/)
library for syntax highlighting. `syntect` can read any
[Sublime Text `.sublime-syntax` file](https://www.sublimetext.com/docs/3/syntax.html)
and theme.

A good resource for finding Sublime Syntax packages is [Package Control](https://packagecontrol.io/). Once you found a
syntax:

1. Create a folder with syntax definition files:

   ```bash
   mkdir -p &quot;$(bat --config-dir)/syntaxes&quot;
   cd &quot;$(bat --config-dir)/syntaxes&quot;

   # Put new &#039;.sublime-syntax&#039; language definition files
   # in this folder (or its subdirectories), for example:
   git clone https://github.com/tellnobody1/sublime-purescript-syntax
   ```

2. Now use the following command to parse these files into a binary cache:

   ```bash
   bat cache --build
   ```

3. Finally, use `bat --list-languages` to check if the new languages are available.

   If you ever want to go back to the default settings, call:

   ```bash
   bat cache --clear
   ```

4. If you think that a specific syntax should be included in `bat` by default, please
   consider opening a &quot;syntax request&quot; ticket after reading the policies and
   instructions [here](doc/assets.md): [Open Syntax Request](https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/issues/new?labels=syntax-request&amp;template=syntax_request.md).

### Adding new themes

This works very similar to how we add new syntax definitions.

First, create a folder with the new syntax highlighting themes:
```bash
mkdir -p &quot;$(bat --config-dir)/themes&quot;
cd &quot;$(bat --config-dir)/themes&quot;

# Download a theme in &#039;.tmTheme&#039; format, for example:
git clone https://github.com/greggb/sublime-snazzy

# Update the binary cache
bat cache --build
```

Finally, use `bat --list-themes` to check if the new themes are available.

### Adding or changing file type associations

You can add new (or change existing) file name patterns using the `--map-syntax`
command line option. The option takes an argument of the form `pattern:syntax` where
`pattern` is a glob pattern that is matched against the file name and
the absolute file path. The `syntax` part is the full name of a supported language
(use `bat --list-languages` for an overview).

**Note:** You probably want to use this option as [an entry in `bat`&#039;s configuration file](#configuration-file)
for persistence instead of passing it on the command line as a one-off. Generally
you&#039;d just use `-l` if you want to manually specify a language for a file.

Example: To use &quot;INI&quot; syntax highlighting for all files with a `.conf` file extension, use
```bash
--map-syntax=&#039;*.conf:INI&#039;
```

Example: To open all files called `.ignore` (exact match) with the &quot;Git Ignore&quot; syntax, use:
```bash
--map-syntax=&#039;.ignore:Git Ignore&#039;
```

Example: To open all `.conf` files in subfolders of `/etc/apache2` with the &quot;Apache Conf&quot;
syntax, use (this mapping is already built in):
```bash
--map-syntax=&#039;/e

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[eythaann/Seelen-UI]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/eythaann/Seelen-UI</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/eythaann/Seelen-UI</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Fully Customizable Desktop Environment for Windows 10/11.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/eythaann/Seelen-UI">eythaann/Seelen-UI</a></h1>
            <p>The Fully Customizable Desktop Environment for Windows 10/11.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,311</p>
            <p>Forks: 200</p>
            <p>Stars today: 35 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[hyperlight-dev/hyperlight]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within micro virtual machines with very low latency and minimal overhead.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight">hyperlight-dev/hyperlight</a></h1>
            <p>Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within micro virtual machines with very low latency and minimal overhead.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,130</p>
            <p>Forks: 110</p>
            <p>Stars today: 54 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Hyperlight&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight/refs/heads/main/docs/assets/hyperlight-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;150px&quot; alt=&quot;hyperlight logo&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyperlight is a lightweight Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) designed to be embedded within applications. It enables safe execution of untrusted code within &lt;i&gt;micro virtual machines&lt;/i&gt; with very low latency and minimal overhead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;    
&lt;/div&gt;

&gt; Note: Hyperlight is a nascent project with an evolving API and no guaranteed support. Assistance is provided on a
&gt; best-effort basis by the developers.

---

## Overview

Hyperlight is a library for creating _micro virtual machines_  — or _sandboxes_ — specifically optimized for securely
running untrusted code with minimal impact. It supports both Windows and Linux,
utilizing [Windows Hypervisor Platform](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/api/#windows-hypervisor-platform)
on Windows, and either Microsoft Hypervisor (mshv) or [KVM](https://linux-kvm.org/page/Main_Page) on Linux.

These micro VMs operate without a kernel or operating system, keeping overhead low. Instead, guests are built
specifically for Hyperlight using the Hyperlight Guest library, which provides a controlled set of APIs that facilitate
interaction between host and guest:

- The host can call functions implemented and exposed by the guest (known as _guest functions_).
- Once running, the guest can call functions implemented and exposed by the host (known as _host functions_).

By default, Hyperlight restricts guest access to a minimal API. The only _host function_ available by default allows the
guest to print messages, which are displayed on the host console or redirected to stdout, as configured. Hosts can
choose to expose additional host functions, expanding the guest’s capabilities as needed.

Below is an example demonstrating the use of the Hyperlight host library in Rust to execute a simple guest application
and an example of a simple guest application using the Hyperlight guest library in also written in Rust.

### Host

```rust
use std::{thread, sync::{Arc, Mutex}};

use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_types::{ParameterValue, ReturnType};
use hyperlight_host::{UninitializedSandbox, MultiUseSandbox, func::HostFunction0, sandbox_state::transition::Noop, sandbox_state::sandbox::EvolvableSandbox};

fn main() -&gt; hyperlight_host::Result&lt;()&gt; {
    // Create an uninitialized sandbox with a guest binary
    let mut uninitialized_sandbox = UninitializedSandbox::new(
        hyperlight_host::GuestBinary::FilePath(hyperlight_testing::simple_guest_as_string().unwrap()),
        None, // default configuration
        None, // default run options
        None, // default host print function
    )?;

    // Register a host function
    fn sleep_5_secs() -&gt; hyperlight_host::Result&lt;()&gt; {
        thread::sleep(std::time::Duration::from_secs(5));
        Ok(())
    }

    let host_function = Arc::new(Mutex::new(sleep_5_secs));

    // Registering a host function makes it available to be called by the guest
    host_function.register(&amp;mut uninitialized_sandbox, &quot;Sleep5Secs&quot;)?;
    // Note: This function is unused by the guest code below, it&#039;s just here for demonstration purposes

    // Initialize sandbox to be able to call host functions
    let mut multi_use_sandbox: MultiUseSandbox = uninitialized_sandbox.evolve(Noop::default())?;

    // Call a function in the guest
    let message = &quot;Hello, World! I am executing inside of a VM :)\n&quot;.to_string();
    // in order to call a function it first must be defined in the guest and exposed so that 
    // the host can call it
    let result = multi_use_sandbox.call_guest_function_by_name(
        &quot;PrintOutput&quot;,
        ReturnType::Int,
        Some(vec![ParameterValue::String(message.clone())]),
    );

    assert!(result.is_ok());

    Ok(())
}
```

### Guest

```rust
#![no_std]
#![no_main]
extern crate alloc;

use alloc::string::ToString;
use alloc::vec::Vec;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_call::FunctionCall;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::function_types::{
    ParameterType, ParameterValue, ReturnType,
};
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::guest_error::ErrorCode;
use hyperlight_common::flatbuffer_wrappers::util::get_flatbuffer_result_from_int;

use hyperlight_guest::error::{HyperlightGuestError, Result};
use hyperlight_guest::guest_function_definition::GuestFunctionDefinition;
use hyperlight_guest::guest_function_register::register_function;
use hyperlight_guest::host_function_call::{
    call_host_function, get_host_value_return_as_int,
};

fn print_output(function_call: &amp;FunctionCall) -&gt; Result&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt; {
    if let ParameterValue::String(message) = function_call.parameters.clone().unwrap()[0].clone() {
        call_host_function(
            &quot;HostPrint&quot;,
            Some(Vec::from(&amp;[ParameterValue::String(message.to_string())])),
            ReturnType::Int,
        )?;
        let result = get_host_value_return_as_int()?;
        Ok(get_flatbuffer_result_from_int(result))
    } else {
        Err(HyperlightGuestError::new(
            ErrorCode::GuestFunctionParameterTypeMismatch,
            &quot;Invalid parameters passed to simple_print_output&quot;.to_string(),
        ))
    }
}

#[no_mangle]
pub extern &quot;C&quot; fn hyperlight_main() {
    let print_output_def = GuestFunctionDefinition::new(
        &quot;PrintOutput&quot;.to_string(),
        Vec::from(&amp;[ParameterType::String]),
        ReturnType::Int,
        print_output as i64,
    );
    register_function(print_output_def);
}

#[no_mangle]
pub fn guest_dispatch_function(function_call: FunctionCall) -&gt; Result&lt;Vec&lt;u8&gt;&gt; {
    let function_name = function_call.function_name.clone();
    return Err(HyperlightGuestError::new(
        ErrorCode::GuestFunctionNotFound,
        function_name,
    ));
}
```

For additional examples of using the Hyperlight host Rust library, see
the [./src/hyperlight_host/examples](./src/hyperlight_host/examples) directory.

For examples of guest applications, see the [./src/tests/c_guests](./src/tests/c_guests) directory for C guests and
the [./src/tests/rust_guests](./src/tests/rust_guests) directory for Rust guests.

&gt; Note: Hyperlight guests can be written using the Hyperlight Rust or C Guest libraries.

## Repository Structure

- Hyperlight Host Libraries (i.e., the ones that create and manage the VMs)
    - [src/hyperlight_host](./src/hyperlight_host) - This is the Rust Hyperlight host library.

- Hyperlight Guest Libraries (i.e., the ones to make it easier to create guests that run inside the VMs)
    - [src/hyperlight_guest](./src/hyperlight_guest) - This is the Rust Hyperlight guest library.
    - [src/hyperlight_guest_capi](./src/hyperlight_guest_capi) - This is the C compatible wrapper for the Hyperlight
      guest library.

- Hyperlight Common (functionality used by both the host and the guest)
    - [src/hyperlight_common](./src/hyperlight_common)

- Test Guest Applications:
    - [src/tests/rust_guests](./src/tests/rust_guests) - This directory contains three Hyperlight Guest programs written
      in Rust, which are intended to be launched within partitions as &quot;guests&quot;.
    - [src/tests/c_guests](./src/tests/c_guests) - This directory contains two Hyperlight Guest programs written in C,
      which are intended to be launched within partitions as &quot;guests&quot;.

- Tests:
    - [src/hyperlight-testing](./src/hyperlight_testing) - Shared testing code for Hyperlight projects built in Rust.

## Try it yourself!

You can run Hyperlight on:

- [Linux with KVM][kvm].
- [Windows with Windows Hypervisor Platform (WHP).][whp] -  Note that you need Windows 11 / Windows Server 2022 or later to use hyperlight, if you are running on earlier versions of Windows then you should consider using our devcontainer on [GitHub codespaces]((https://codespaces.new/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight)) or WSL2.
- Windows Subsystem for Linux 2 (see instructions [here](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install) for Windows client and [here](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-on-server) for Windows Server) with KVM.
- Azure Linux with mshv (note that you need mshv to be installed to use Hyperlight)

After having an environment with a hypervisor setup, running the example has the following pre-requisites:

1. On Linux or WSL, you&#039;ll most likely need build essential. For Ubuntu, run `sudo apt install build-essential`. For
   Azure Linux, run `sudo dnf install build-essential`.
2. [Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install). Install toolchain v1.81 or later.

   Also, install the `x86_64-pc-windows-msvc` and `x86_64-unknown-none` targets, these are needed to build the test
   guest binaries. (Note: install both targets on either Linux or Windows: Hyperlight can load ELF or PE files on either
   OS, and the tests/examples are built for both):

    ```sh
    rustup target add x86_64-unknown-none
    rustup target add x86_64-pc-windows-msvc
    ```

3. [just](https://github.com/casey/just). `cargo install just` On Windows you also need [pwsh](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell-on-windows?view=powershell-7.4).
4. [clang and LLVM](https://clang.llvm.org/get_started.html).
    - On Ubuntu, run:

        ```sh
        wget https://apt.llvm.org/llvm.sh
        chmod +x ./llvm.sh
        sudo ./llvm.sh 17 all
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/clang-cl /usr/bin/clang-cl
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/llvm-lib /usr/bin/llvm-lib
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/lld-link /usr/bin/lld-link
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/llvm-ml /usr/bin/llvm-ml
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/ld.lld /usr/bin/ld.lld
        sudo ln -s /usr/lib/llvm-17/bin/clang /usr/bin/clang
        ```

    - On Windows, see [this](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/cpp/build/clang-support-msbuild?view=msvc-170).

    - On Azure Linux, run:

        ```sh
        sudo dnf remove clang -y || true
        sudo dnf install clang17 -y
        sudo dnf install clang17-tools-extra -y
        ```

Then, we are ready to build and run the example:

```sh
just build  # build the Hyperlight library
just rg     # build the rust test guest binaries
cargo run --example hello-world
```

If all worked as expected, you should see the following message in your console:

```text
Hello, World! I am executing inside of a VM :)
```

If you get the error `Error: NoHypervisorFound` and KVM or mshv is set up then this may be a permissions issue. In bash,
you can use `ls -l /dev/kvm` or  `ls -l /dev/mshv` to check which group owns that device and then `groups` to make sure
your user is a member of that group.

For more details on how to verify that KVM is correctly installed and permissions are correct, follow the
guide [here](https://help.ubuntu.com/community/KVM/Installation).

### Or you can use a codespace

[![Open in GitHub Codespaces](https://github.com/codespaces/badge.svg)](https://codespaces.new/hyperlight-dev/hyperlight)

## Contributing to Hyperlight

If you are interested in contributing to Hyperlight, running the entire test-suite is a good way to get started. To do
so, on your console, run the following commands:

```sh
just guests  # build the c and rust test guests
just build  # build the Hyperlight library
just test # runs the tests
```

Also , please review the [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) file for more information on how to contribute to
Hyperlight.

&gt; Note: For general Hyperlight development, you may also need flatc (Flatbuffer compiler): for instructions,
&gt; see [here](https://github.com/google/flatbuffers).

## Join our Community Meetings

This project holds fortnightly community meetings to discuss the project&#039;s progress, roadmap, and any other topics of interest. The meetings are open to everyone, and we encourage you to join us.

- **When**: Every other Wednesday 09:00 (PST/PDT) [Convert to your local time](https://dateful.com/convert/pst-pdt-pacific-time?t=09)
- **Where**: Zoom! - Agenda and information on how to join can be found in the [Hyperlight Community Meeting Notes](https://hackmd.io/blCrncfOSEuqSbRVT9KYkg#Agenda). Please log into hackmd to edit!

## Chat with us on the CNCF Slack

The Hyperlight project Slack is hosted in the CNCF Slack #hyperlight. To join the Slack, [join the CNCF Slack](https://www.cncf.io/membership-faq/#how-do-i-join-cncfs-slack), and join the #hyperlight channel.

## More Information

For more information, please refer to our compilation of documents in the [`docs/` directory](./docs/README.md).

## Code of Conduct

See the [CNCF Code of Conduct](https://github.com/cncf/foundation/blob/main/code-of-conduct.md).

[wsl2]: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install

[kvm]: https://help.ubuntu.com/community/KVM/Installation

[whp]: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/hyper-v-android-emulator-support/#1-enable-hyper-v-and-the-windows-hypervisor-platform
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[signalapp/libsignal]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Home to the Signal Protocol as well as other cryptographic primitives which make Signal possible.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal">signalapp/libsignal</a></h1>
            <p>Home to the Signal Protocol as well as other cryptographic primitives which make Signal possible.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,157</p>
            <p>Forks: 492</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Overview

libsignal contains platform-agnostic APIs used by the official Signal clients and servers, exposed
as a Java, Swift, or TypeScript library. The underlying implementations are written in Rust:

- libsignal-protocol: Implements the Signal protocol, including the [Double Ratchet algorithm][]. A
  replacement for [libsignal-protocol-java][] and [libsignal-metadata-java][].
- signal-crypto: Cryptographic primitives such as AES-GCM. We use [RustCrypto][]&#039;s where we can
  but sometimes have differing needs.
- device-transfer: Support logic for Signal&#039;s device-to-device transfer feature.
- attest: Functionality for remote attestation of [SGX enclaves][] and server-side [HSMs][].
- zkgroup: Functionality for [zero-knowledge groups][] and related features available in Signal.
- zkcredential: An abstraction for the sort of zero-knowledge credentials used by zkgroup, based on the paper &quot;[The Signal Private Group System][]&quot; by Chase, Perrin, and Zaverucha.
- poksho: Utilities for implementing zero-knowledge proofs (such as those used by zkgroup); stands for &quot;proof-of-knowledge, stateful-hash-object&quot;.
- account-keys: Functionality for consistently using [PINs][] as passwords in Signal&#039;s Secure Value Recovery system, as well as other account-wide key operations.
- usernames: Functionality for username generation, hashing, and proofs.
- media: Utilities for manipulating media.

This repository is used by the Signal client apps ([Android][], [iOS][], and [Desktop][]) as well as
server-side. Use outside of Signal is unsupported. In particular, the products of this repository
are the Java, Swift, and TypeScript libraries that wrap the underlying Rust implementations. All
APIs and implementations are subject to change without notice, as are the JNI, C, and Node add-on
&quot;bridge&quot; layers. However, backwards-incompatible changes to the Java, Swift, TypeScript, and
non-bridge Rust APIs will be reflected in the version number on a best-effort basis, including
increases to the minimum supported tools versions.

[Double Ratchet algorithm]: https://signal.org/docs/
[libsignal-protocol-java]: https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal-protocol-java
[libsignal-metadata-java]: https://github.com/signalapp/libsignal-metadata-java
[RustCrypto]: https://github.com/RustCrypto
[Noise protocol]: http://noiseprotocol.org/
[SGX enclaves]: https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/architecture-and-technology/software-guard-extensions.html
[HSMs]: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hardware_security_module
[zero-knowledge groups]: https://signal.org/blog/signal-private-group-system/
[The Signal Private Group System]: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1416.pdf
[PINs]: https://signal.org/blog/signal-pins/
[Android]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-Android
[iOS]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-iOS
[Desktop]: https://github.com/signalapp/Signal-Desktop


# Building

### Toolchain Installation

To build anything in this repository you must have [Rust](https://rust-lang.org) installed,
as well as Clang, libclang, [CMake](https://cmake.org), Make, protoc, and git.

#### Linux/Debian

On a Debian-like system, you can get these extra dependencies through `apt`:

```shell
$ apt-get install clang libclang-dev cmake make protobuf-compiler git
```

#### macOS

On macOS, we have a best-effort maintained script to set up the Rust toolchain you can run by:

```shell
$ bin/mac_setup.sh
```

## Rust

### First Build and Test

The build currently uses a specific version of the Rust nightly compiler, which
will be downloaded automatically by cargo. To build and test the basic protocol
libraries:

```shell
$ cargo build
...
$ cargo test
...
```

### Additional Rust Tools

The basic tools above should get you set up for most libsignal Rust development. 

Eventually, you may find that you need some additional Rust tools like `cbindgen` to modify the bridges to the 
client libraries or `taplo` for code formatting. 

You should always install any Rust tools you need that may affect the build from cargo rather than from your system
package manager (e.g. `apt` or `brew`). Package managers sometimes contain outdated versions of these tools that can break
the build with incompatibility issues (especially cbindgen).

To install the main Rust extra dependencies matching the versions we use, you can run the following commands: 

```shell
$ cargo +stable install cbindgen cargo-fuzz
$ cargo +stable install --version &quot;$(cat ../acknowledgments/cargo-about-version)&quot; --locked cargo-about
$ cargo +stable install --version &quot;$(cat ../.taplo-cli-version)&quot; --locked taplo-cli
```

## Java/Android

To build for Android you must install several additional packages including a JDK,
the Android NDK/SDK, and add the Android targets to the Rust compiler, using

```rustup target add armv7-linux-androideabi aarch64-linux-android i686-linux-android x86_64-linux-android```

To build the Java/Android ``jar`` and ``aar``, and run the tests:

```shell
$ cd java
$ ./gradlew test
$ ./gradlew build # if you need AAR outputs
```

You can pass `-P debugLevelLogs` to Gradle to build without filtering out debug- and verbose-level
logs from Rust.

Alternately, a build system using Docker is available:

```shell
$ cd java
$ make
```

When exposing new APIs to Java, you will need to run `rust/bridge/jni/bin/gen_java_decl.py` in
addition to rebuilding. This requires installing the `cbindgen` Rust tool, as detailed above. 

### Maven Central

Signal publishes Java packages on [Maven Central](https://central.sonatype.org) for its own use,
under the names org.signal:libsignal-server, org.signal:libsignal-client, and
org.signal:libsignal-android. libsignal-client and libsignal-server contain native libraries for
Debian-flavored x86_64 Linux as well as Windows (x86_64) and macOS (x86_64 and arm64).
libsignal-android contains native libraries for armeabi-v7a, arm64-v8a, x86, and x86_64 Android.

When building for Android you need *both* libsignal-android and libsignal-client, but the Windows
and macOS libraries in libsignal-client won&#039;t automatically be excluded from your final app. You can
explicitly exclude them using `packagingOptions`:

```
android {
  // ...
  packagingOptions {
    resources {
      excludes += setOf(&quot;libsignal_jni*.dylib&quot;, &quot;signal_jni*.dll&quot;)
    }
  }
  // ...
}
```

You can additionally exclude `libsignal_jni_testing.so` if you do not plan to use any of the APIs
intended for client testing.


## Swift

To learn about the Swift build process see [``swift/README.md``](swift/)


## Node

You&#039;ll need Node installed to build. If you have [nvm][], you can run `nvm use` to select an
appropriate version automatically.

We use `npm` as our package manager, and `node-gyp` to control building the Rust library.

```shell
$ cd node
$ nvm use
$ npm install
$ npx node-gyp rebuild  # clean-&gt;configure-&gt;build
$ npm run tsc
$ npm run test
```

When testing changes locally, you can use `npm run build` to do an incremental rebuild of the Rust library. Alternately, `npm run build-with-debug-level-logs` will rebuild without filtering out debug- and verbose-level logs.

When exposing new APIs to Node, you will need to run `rust/bridge/node/bin/gen_ts_decl.py` in
addition to rebuilding.

[nvm]: https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm

### NPM

Signal publishes the NPM package `@signalapp/libsignal-client` for its own use, including native
libraries for Windows, macOS, and Debian-flavored Linux. Both x64 and arm64 builds are included for
all three platforms, but the arm64 builds for Windows and Linux are considered experimental, since
there are no official builds of Signal for those architectures.


# Contributions

Signal does accept external contributions to this project. However unless the change is
simple and easily understood, for example fixing a bug or portability issue, adding a new
test, or improving performance, first open an issue to discuss your intended change as not
all changes can be accepted.

Contributions that will not be used directly by one of Signal&#039;s official client apps may still be
considered, but only if they do not pose an undue maintenance burden or conflict with the goals of
the project.

Signing a [CLA (Contributor License Agreement)](https://signal.org/cla/) is required for all contributions.

## Code Formatting and Acknowledgments

You can run the styler on the entire project by running:

```shell
just format-all
```

You can run more extensive tests as well as linters and clippy by running:

```shell
just check-pre-commit
```

When making a PR that adjusts dependencies, you&#039;ll need to regenerate our acknowledgments files. See [``acknowledgments/README.md``](acknowledgments/).

# Legal things
## Cryptography Notice

This distribution includes cryptographic software. The country in which you currently reside may have restrictions on
the import, possession, use, and/or re-export to another country, of encryption software.  BEFORE using any encryption
software, please check your country&#039;s laws, regulations and policies concerning the import, possession, or use, and
re-export of encryption software, to see if this is permitted.  See &lt;http://www.wassenaar.org/&gt; for more information.

The U.S. Government Department of Commerce, Bureau of Industry and Security (BIS), has classified this software as
Export Commodity Control Number (ECCN) 5D002.C.1, which includes information security software using or performing
cryptographic functions with asymmetric algorithms.  The form and manner of this distribution makes it eligible for
export under the License Exception ENC Technology Software Unrestricted (TSU) exception (see the BIS Export
Administration Regulations, Section 740.13) for both object code and source code.

## License

Copyright 2020-2024 Signal Messenger, LLC

Licensed under the GNU AGPLv3: https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[starship/starship]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/starship/starship</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/starship/starship</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[☄🌌️ The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/starship/starship">starship/starship</a></h1>
            <p>☄🌌️ The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 47,801</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,062</p>
            <p>Stars today: 25 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img
    width=&quot;400&quot;
    src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/logo.png&quot;
    alt=&quot;Starship – Cross-shell prompt&quot;
  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/actions&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/starship/starship/workflow.yml?branch=master&amp;label=workflow&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;GitHub Actions workflow status&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/starship&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/starship?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Crates.io version&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/project/starship/versions&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/repology/repositories/starship?label=in%20repositories&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Packaging status&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a
  &gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/starship&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/567163873606500352?label=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Chat on Discord&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StarshipPrompt&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/twitter-@StarshipPrompt-1DA1F3?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Follow @StarshipPrompt on Twitter&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stand-with-ukraine.pp.ua&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vshymanskyy/StandWithUkraine/main/badges/StandWithUkraineFlat.svg&quot;
      alt=&quot;Stand With Ukraine&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;#🚀-installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs/config/&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-us.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;English&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/de-DE/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-de.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Deutsch&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/es-ES/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-es.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Español&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/fr-FR/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-fr.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Français&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/id-ID/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-id.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Bahasa Indonesia&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/it-IT/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-it.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Italiano&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/ja-JP/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-jp.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;日本語&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/pt-BR/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-br.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Português do Brasil&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/ru-RU/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-ru.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Русский&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/uk-UA/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-ua.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Українська&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/vi-VN/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-vn.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Tiếng Việt&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/zh-CN/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-cn.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;简体中文&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/zh-TW/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-tw.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;繁體中文&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;img
  src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/demo.gif&quot;
  alt=&quot;Starship with iTerm2 and the Snazzy theme&quot;
  width=&quot;50%&quot;
  align=&quot;right&quot;
/&gt;

**The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!**

- **Fast:** it&#039;s fast – _really really_ fast! 🚀
- **Customizable:** configure every aspect of your prompt.
- **Universal:** works on any shell, on any operating system.
- **Intelligent:** shows relevant information at a glance.
- **Feature rich:** support for all your favorite tools.
- **Easy:** quick to install – start using it in minutes.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs/config/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore the Starship docs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;▶&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;🚀-installation&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## 🚀 Installation

### Prerequisites

- A [Nerd Font](https://www.nerdfonts.com/) installed and enabled in your terminal (for example, try the [FiraCode Nerd Font](https://www.nerdfonts.com/font-downloads)).

### Step 1. Install Starship

Select your operating system from the list below to view installation instructions:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Android&lt;/summary&gt;

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository | Instructions           |
| ---------- | ---------------------- |
| [Termux]   | `pkg install starship` |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;BSD&lt;/summary&gt;

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Distribution | Repository      | Instructions                      |
| ------------ | --------------- | --------------------------------- |
| **_Any_**    | **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked` |
| FreeBSD      | [FreshPorts]    | `pkg install starship`            |
| NetBSD       | [pkgsrc]        | `pkgin install starship`          |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Linux&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system:

```sh
curl -sS https://starship.rs/install.sh | sh
```

Alternatively, install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Distribution       | Repository              | Instructions                                                  |
| ------------------ | ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------- |
| **_Any_**          | **[crates.io]**         | `cargo install starship --locked`                             |
| _Any_              | [conda-forge]           | `conda install -c conda-forge starship`                       |
| _Any_              | [Linuxbrew]             | `brew install starship`                                       |
| Alpine Linux 3.13+ | [Alpine Linux Packages] | `apk add starship`                                            |
| Arch Linux         | [Arch Linux Extra]      | `pacman -S starship`                                          |
| CentOS 7+          | [Copr]                  | `dnf copr enable atim/starship` &lt;br /&gt; `dnf install starship` |
| Debian 13+         | [Debian Main]           | `apt install starship`                                        |
| Gentoo             | [Gentoo Packages]       | `emerge app-shells/starship`                                  |
| Manjaro            |                         | `pacman -S starship`                                          |
| NixOS              | [nixpkgs]               | `nix-env -iA nixpkgs.starship`                                |
| openSUSE           | [OSS]                   | `zypper in starship`                                          |
| Ubuntu 25.04+      | [Ubuntu Universe]       | `apt install starship`                                        |
| Void Linux         | [Void Linux Packages]   | `xbps-install -S starship`                                    |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;macOS&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system:

```sh
curl -sS https://starship.rs/install.sh | sh
```

Alternatively, install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository      | Instructions                            |
| --------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked`       |
| [conda-forge]   | `conda install -c conda-forge starship` |
| [Homebrew]      | `brew install starship`                 |
| [MacPorts]      | `port install starship`                 |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Windows&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system with the MSI-installers from the [releases section](https://github.com/starship/starship/releases/latest).

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository      | Instructions                            |
| --------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked`       |
| [Chocolatey]    | `choco install starship`                |
| [conda-forge]   | `conda install -c conda-forge starship` |
| [Scoop]         | `scoop install starship`                |
| [winget]        | `winget install --id Starship.Starship` |

&lt;/details&gt;

### Step 2. Set up your shell to use Starship

Configure your shell to initialize starship. Select yours from the list below:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Bash&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.bashrc`:

```sh
eval &quot;$(starship init bash)&quot;
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Cmd&lt;/summary&gt;

You need to use [Clink](https://chrisant996.github.io/clink/clink.html) (v1.2.30+) with Cmd.
Create a file at this path `%LocalAppData%\clink\starship.lua` with the following contents:

```lua
load(io.popen(&#039;starship init cmd&#039;):read(&quot;*a&quot;))()
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Elvish&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.elvish/rc.elv`:

```sh
eval (starship init elvish)
```

Note: Only Elvish v0.18+ is supported

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Fish&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.config/fish/config.fish`:

```fish
starship init fish | source
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Ion&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.config/ion/initrc`:

```sh
eval $(starship init ion)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Nushell&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of your Nushell configuration (find it by running `$nu.config-path` in Nushell):

```sh
mkdir ($nu.data-dir | path join &quot;vendor/autoload&quot;)
starship init nu | save -f ($nu.data-dir | path join &quot;vendor/autoload/starship.nu&quot;)
```

Note: Only Nushell v0.96+ is supported

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;PowerShell&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of your PowerShell configuration (find it by running `$PROFILE`):

```powershell
Invoke-Expression (&amp;starship init powershell)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Tcsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.tcshrc`:

```sh
eval `starship init tcsh`
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Xonsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.xonshrc`:

```python
execx($(starship init xonsh))
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Zsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.zshrc`:

```sh
eval &quot;$(starship init zsh)&quot;
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### Step 3. Configure Starship

Start a new shell instance, and you should see your beautiful new shell prompt.
If you&#039;re happy with the defaults, enjoy!

If you&#039;re looking to further customize Starship:

- **[Configuration](https://starship.rs/config/)** – learn how to configure Starship to tweak your prompt to your liking

- **[Presets](https://starship.rs/presets/)** – get inspired by the pre-built configuration of others

## 🤝 Contributing

We are always looking for contributors of **all skill levels**! If you&#039;re looking to ease your way into the project, try out a [good first issue](https://github.com/starship/starship/labels/🌱%20good%20first%20issue).

If you are fluent in a non-English language, we greatly appreciate any help keeping our docs translated and up-to-date in other languages. If you would like to help, translations can be contributed on the [Starship Crowdin](https://translate.starship.rs/).

If you are interested in helping contribute to starship, please take a look at our [Contributing Guide](https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md). Also, feel free to drop into our [Discord server](https://discord.gg/8Jzqu3T) and say hi. 👋

## 💭 Inspired By

Please check out these previous works that helped inspire the creation of starship. 🙏

- **[denysdovhan/spaceship-prompt](https://github.com/denysdovhan/spaceship-prompt)** – A ZSH prompt for astronauts.

- **[denysdovhan/robbyrussell-node](https://github.com/denysdovhan/robbyrussell-node)** – Cross-shell robbyrussell theme written in JavaScript.

- **[reujab/silver](https://github.com/reujab/silver)** – A cross-shell customizable powerline-like prompt with icons.

## ❤️ Sponsors

Support this project by [becoming a sponsor](https://github.com/sponsors/starship). Your name or logo will show up here with a link to your website.

## 🔒 Code Signing Policy

Free code signing provided by [SignPath.io], certificate by [SignPath Foundation].

Code Signing Roles:

- Reviewers: [Astronauts](https://github.com/orgs/starship/teams/astronauts)
- Approvers and Authors: [Mission Control](https://github.com/orgs/starship/teams/mission-control)

This program will not transfer any information to other networked systems unless specifically requested by the user or the person installing or operating it.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Starship rocket icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 📝 License

Copyright © 2019-present, [Starship Contributors](https://github.com/starship/starship/graphs/contributors).&lt;br&gt;
This project is [ISC](https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/LICENSE) licensed.

[alpine linux packages]: https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/packages?name=starship
[arch linux extra]: https://archlinux.org/packages/extra/x86_64/starship
[chocolatey]: https://community.chocolatey.org/packages/starship
[conda-forge]: https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/starship
[copr]: https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/atim/starship
[crates.io]: https://crates.io/crates/starship
[debian main]: https://sources.debian.org/src/starship/1.22.1-1/
[freshports]: https://www.freshports.org/shells/starship
[gentoo packages]: https://packages.gentoo.org/packages/app-shells/starship
[linuxbrew]: https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/starship
[homebrew]: https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/starship
[macports]: https://ports.macports.org/port/starship
[nixpkgs]: https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/blob/master/pkgs/tools/misc/starship/default.nix
[OSS]: https://software.opensuse.org/package/starship
[pkgsrc]: https://pkgsrc.se/shells/starship
[scoop]: https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/blob/master/bucket/starship.json
[SignPath Foundation]: https://signpath.org
[SignPath.io]: https://signpath.io
[termux]: https://github.com/termux/termux-packages/tree/master/packages/starship
[ubuntu universe]: https://packages.ubuntu.com/source/plucky/starship
[void linux packages]: https://github.com/void-linux/void-packages/tree/master/srcpkgs/starship
[winget]: https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/tree/master/manifests/s/Starship/Starship
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mufeedvh/code2prompt]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A CLI tool to convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt with source tree, prompt templating, and token counting.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt">mufeedvh/code2prompt</a></h1>
            <p>A CLI tool to convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt with source tree, prompt templating, and token counting.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,209</p>
            <p>Forks: 302</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://code2prompt.dev&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img align=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;550px&quot; src=&quot;.assets/logo_dark_v0.0.2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Code2prompt&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Convert your codebase into a single LLM prompt !&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://code2prompt.dev&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.assets/CLI.png&quot; alt=&quot;code2prompt&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

[![crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/code2prompt.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/code2prompt)
[![LICENSE](https://img.shields.io/github/license/mufeedvh/code2prompt.svg#cache1)](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/blob/master/LICENSE)
[![PRs Welcome](https://img.shields.io/badge/PRs-welcome-brightgreen.svg)](https://github.com/user/repo/pulls)
[![Lines of Code](https://tokei.rs/b1/github/mufeedvh/code2prompt)](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/1342336677905039451?logo=discord)](https://discord.com/invite/zxVMKtsFbK)

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Want to engage with us ? Join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/invite/zxVMKtsFbK&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; channel!&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Stay updated on new features&lt;/i&gt; 📢&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Give your insight and suggestion&lt;/i&gt; 💬&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Get help with configuration and usage&lt;/i&gt; 🛠️&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;Report Bug&lt;/i&gt; 🐛&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## Quick Install ⚡

CLI with cargo 🦀

```bash
cargo install code2prompt
```

SDK with pip 🐍

```bash
pip install code2prompt-rs
```

## How is it useful?

**Core**

`code2prompt` is a code ingestion tool that streamline the process of creating LLM prompts for code analysis, generation, and other tasks. It works by traversing directories, building a tree structure, and gathering informations about each file. The core library can easily be integrated into other applications.

**CLI**

`code2prompt` command line interface (CLI) was designed for humans to generate prompts directly from your codebase. The generated prompt is automatically copied to your clipboard and can also be saved to an output file. Furthermore, you can customize the prompt generation using Handlebars templates. Check out the provided prompts in the doc !

**SDK**

`code2prompt` software development kit (SDK) offers python binding to the core library. This is perfect for AI agents or automation scripts that want to interact with codebase seamlessly. The SDK is hosted on Pypi and can be installed via pip.

**MCP**

`code2prompt` is also available as a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, which allows you to run it as a local service. This enables LLMs on steroids by providing them a tool to automatically gather a well-structured context of your codebase.

## Documentation 📚

Check our online [documentation](https://code2prompt.dev/docs/welcome/) for detailed instructions

## Features

Code2Prompt transforms your entire codebase into a well-structured prompt for large language models. Key features include:

- **Automatic Code Processing**: Convert codebases of any size into readable, formatted prompts
- **Smart Filtering**: Include/exclude files using glob patterns and respect `.gitignore` rules
- **Flexible Templating**: Customize prompts with Handlebars templates for different use cases
- **Token Tracking**: Track token usage to stay within LLM context limits
- **Git Integration**: Include diffs, logs, and branch comparisons in your prompts
- **Developer Experience**: Automatic clipboard copy, line numbers, and file organization options

Stop manually copying files and formatting code for LLMs. Code2Prompt handles the tedious work so you can focus on getting insights and solutions from AI models.

## Alternative Installation

Refer to the [documentation](https://code2prompt.dev/docs/cli/how_to/install/) for detailed installation instructions.

### Binary releases

Download the latest binary for your OS from [Releases](https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/releases).

### Source build

Requires:

- [Git](https://git-scm.org/downloads), [Rust](https://rust-lang.org/tools/install) and `Cargo`.

```sh
git clone https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt.git
cd code2prompt/
cargo install --path crates/code2prompt
```

## Star History

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=mufeedvh/code2prompt&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#mufeedvh/code2prompt&amp;Date)

## License

Licensed under the MIT License, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mufeedvh/code2prompt/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for more information.

## Liked the project?

If you liked the project and found it useful, please give it a :star: !

## Contribution

Ways to contribute:

- Suggest a feature
- Report a bug  
- Fix something and open a pull request
- Help me document the code
- Spread the word
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Tinymist [ˈtaɪni mɪst] is an integrated language service for Typst [taɪpst].]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist">Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist</a></h1>
            <p>Tinymist [ˈtaɪni mɪst] is an integrated language service for Typst [taɪpst].</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,339</p>
            <p>Forks: 61</p>
            <p>Stars today: 5 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!-- This file is generated by scripts/link-docs.mjs from docs/tinymist/introduction.typ. Do not edit manually. --&gt;
# Tinymist

Tinymist [ˈtaɪni mɪst] is an integrated language service for [Typst](https://typst.app/) [taɪpst]. You can also call it &quot;微霭&quot; [wēi ǎi] in Chinese.

It contains:
- an analyzing library for Typst, see [tinymist-query](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/crates/tinymist-query).
- a CLI for Typst, see [tinymist](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/crates/tinymist/).
  - which provides a language server for Typst, see [Language Features](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/feature/language.html).
  - which provides a preview server for Typst, see [Preview Feature](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/feature/preview.html).
- a VSCode extension for Typst, see [Tinymist VSCode Extension](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/editors/vscode/).

## Features




Language service (LSP) features:

- [Semantic highlighting](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/semantic-highlight-guide)
  - The &quot;semantic highlighting&quot; is supplementary to [&quot;syntax highlighting&quot;](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/syntax-highlight-guide).

- [Code actions](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#provide-code-actions)
  - Also known as &quot;quick fixes&quot; or &quot;refactorings&quot;.
- [Formatting (Reformatting)](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#format-source-code-in-an-editor)
  - Provide the user with support for formatting whole documents, using [typstfmt](https://github.com/astrale-sharp/typstfmt) or [typstyle](https://github.com/Enter-tainer/typstyle).
- [Document highlight](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#highlight-all-occurrences-of-a-symbol-in-a-document)
  - Highlight all break points in a loop context.
  - (Todo) Highlight all exit points in a function context.
  - (Todo) Highlight all captures in a closure context.
  - (Todo) Highlight all occurrences of a symbol in a document.
- [Document links](https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/specifications/lsp/3.17/specification/#textDocument_documentLink)
  - Renders path or link references in the document, such as `image(&quot;path.png&quot;)` or `bibliography(style: &quot;path.csl&quot;)`.
- [Document symbols](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/getstarted/userinterface#_outline-view)
  - Also known as &quot;document outline&quot; or &quot;table of contents&quot; _in Typst_.
- [Folding ranges](https://burkeholland.gitbook.io/vs-code-can-do-that/exercise-3-navigation-and-refactoring/folding-sections)
  - You can collapse code/content blocks and headings.
- [Goto definitions](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#show-definitions-of-a-symbol)
  - Right-click on a symbol and select &quot;Go to Definition&quot;.
  - Or ctrl+click on a symbol.
- [References](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#find-all-references-to-a-symbol)
  - Right-click on a symbol and select &quot;Go to References&quot; or &quot;Find References&quot;.
  - Or ctrl+click on a symbol.
- [Hover tips](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#show-hovers)
  - Also known as &quot;hovering tooltip&quot;.
  - Render docs according to [tidy](https://github.com/Mc-Zen/tidy) style.
- [Inlay hints](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/inlay-hints.html)
  - Inlay hints are special markers that appear in the editor and provide you with additional information about your code, like the names of the parameters that a called method expects.
- [Color Provider](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#show-color-decorators)
  - View all inlay colorful label for color literals in your document.
  - Change the color literal&#039;s value by a color picker or its code presentation.
- [Code Lens](https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/02/12/code-lens-roundup)
  - Should give contextual buttons along with code. For example, a button for exporting your document to various formats at the start of the document.
- [Rename symbols and embedded paths](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#rename-symbols)
- [Help with function and method signatures](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#help-with-function-and-method-signatures)
- [Workspace Symbols](https://code.visualstudio.com/api/language-extensions/programmatic-language-features#show-all-symbol-definitions-in-folder)
- [Code Action](https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/devenv-code-actions)
  - Increasing/Decreasing heading levels.
  - Turn equation into &quot;inline&quot;, &quot;block&quot; or &quot;multiple-line block&quot; styles.
- [experimental/onEnter](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-analyzer/blob/master/docs/dev/lsp-extensions.md#on-enter)
  - &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; inside triple-slash comments automatically inserts `///`
  - &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; in the middle or after a trailing space in `//` inserts `//`
  - &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; inside `//!` doc comments automatically inserts `//!`
  - &lt;kbd&gt;Enter&lt;/kbd&gt; inside equation markups automatically inserts indents.

Extra features:

- Compiles to PDF on save (configurable to as-you-type, or other options). Check [Docs: Exporting Documents](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/feature/export.html).
- Also compiles to SVG, PNG, HTML, Markdown, Text, and other formats by commands, vscode tasks, or code lenses.
- Provides test, benchmark, coverage collecting on documents and modules. Check [Docs: Testing Features](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/feature/testing.html).
- Provides a status bar item to show the current document&#039;s compilation status and words count.
- [Editor tools](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/tools/editor-tools):
  - View a list of templates in template gallery. (`tinymist.showTemplateGallery`)
  - Click a button in template gallery to initialize a new project with a template. (`tinymist.initTemplate` and `tinymist.initTemplateInPlace`)
  - Trace execution in current document (`tinymist.profileCurrentFile`).


## Versioning and Release Cycle

Tinymist&#039;s versions follow the [Semantic Versioning](https://semver.org/) scheme, in format of `MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH`. Besides, tinymist follows special rules for the version number:
- If a version is suffixed with `-rcN` (&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;./assets/images/introduction.typ-inlined0.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;vertical-align: -0.35em&quot; alt=&quot;typst-block&quot; src=&quot;./assets/images/introduction.typ-inlined1.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;), e.g. `0.11.0-rc1` and `0.12.1-rc1`, it means this version is a release candidate. It is used to test publish script and E2E functionalities. These versions will not be published to the marketplace.
- If the `PATCH` number is odd, e.g. `0.11.1` and `0.12.3`, it means this version is a nightly release. The nightly release will use both [tinymist](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main) and [typst](https://github.com/typst/typst/tree/main) at **main branch**. They will be published as prerelease version to the marketplace. Note that in nightly releases, we change `#sys.version` to the next minor release to help develop documents with nightly features. For example, in tinymist nightly v0.12.1 or v0.12.3, the `#sys.version` is changed to `version(0, 13, 0)`.
- Otherwise, if the `PATCH` number is even, e.g. `0.11.0` and `0.12.2`, it means this version is a regular release. The regular release will always use the recent stable version of tinymist and typst.


The release cycle is as follows:
- If there is a typst version update, a new major or minor version will be released intermediately. This means tinymist will always align the minor version with typst.
- If there is at least a bug or feature added this week, a new patch version will be released.

## Installation

Follow the instructions to enable tinymist in your favorite editor.
- [VS Cod(e,ium)](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/vscode.html)
- [Neovim](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/neovim.html)
- [Emacs](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/emacs.html)
- [Sublime Text](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/sublime-text.html)
- [Helix](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/helix.html)
- [Zed](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/frontend/zed.html)

## Installing Regular/Nightly Prebuilds from GitHub

Note: if you are not knowing what is a regular/nightly release, please don&#039;t follow this section.

Besides published releases specific for each editors, you can also download the latest regular/nightly prebuilts from GitHub and install them manually.

- Regular prebuilts can be found in [GitHub Releases](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/releases).
- Nightly prebuilts can be found in [GitHub Actions](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/actions).
  - (Suggested) Use the [tinymist-nightly-installer](https://github.com/hongjr03/tinymist-nightly-installer) to install the nightly prebuilts automatically.
    - Unix (Bash):
      ```bash
      curl -sSL https://github.com/hongjr03/tinymist-nightly-installer/releases/latest/download/run.sh | bash
      ```
    - Windows (PowerShell):
      ```bash
      iwr https://github.com/hongjr03/tinymist-nightly-installer/releases/latest/download/run.ps1 -UseBasicParsing | iex
      ```
  - The prebuilts for other revisions can also be found manually. For example, if you are seeking a nightly release for the featured [PR: build: bump version to 0.11.17-rc1](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/pull/468), you could click and go to the [action page](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/actions/runs/10120639466) run for the related commits and download the artifacts.

To install extension file (the file with `.vsix` extension) manually, please &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl+Shift+X&lt;/kbd&gt; in the editor window and drop the downloaded vsix file into the opened extensions view.

## Documentation

See [Online Documentation](https://myriad-dreamin.github.io/tinymist/).

## Packaging

Stable Channel:

[![Packaging status](https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/tinymist.svg)](https://repology.org/project/tinymist/versions)

Nightly Channel:

[![Packaging status](https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/tinymist-nightly.svg)](https://repology.org/project/tinymist-nightly/versions)

## Roadmap

### Short Terms

To encourage contributions, we create many [Pull Requests](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/pulls) in draft to navigate short-term plans. They give you a hint of what or where to start in this large repository.

### Long Terms

We are planning to implement the following features in typst v0.14.0 or spare time in weekend:

- Type checking: complete the type checker.
- Static Linter: linting code statically according to feedback of the type checker and succeeding code analysis.
- Periscope renderer: It is disabled since vscode reject to render SVGs containing foreignObjects.
- Inlay hint: It is disabled _by default_ because of performance issues.
- Find references of dictionary fields and named function arguments.
- Improve symbol view&#039;s appearance.
- Improve package view.
  - Navigate to symbols by clicking on the symbol name in the view.
  - Automatically locate the symbol item in the view when viewing local documentation.
  - Remember the recently invoked package commands, e.g. &quot;Open Docs of \@preview/cetz:0.3.1&quot;, &quot;Open directory of \@preview/touying:0.5.3&quot;.
- Improve label view.
  - Group labels.
  - Search labels.
  - Keep (persist) group preferences.
- Improve Typst Preview.
  - Preview for all editors: See [Issue 1237](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/issues/1237).
  - Pin drop-down: Set the file to preview in the drop-down for clients that doesn&#039;t support passing arguments to the preview command.
  - Render in web worker (another thread) to reduce overhead on the electron&#039;s main thread.
- ~~Spell checking: There is already a branch but no suitable (default) spell checking library is found.~~
  - [typos](https://github.com/crate-ci/typos) is great for typst. [harper](harper) looks promise.

If you are interested by any above features, please feel free to send Issues to discuss or PRs to implement to [GitHub.](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist)

## Contributing

Please read the [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md) file for contribution guidelines.

## Localization

Tinymist is localized in multiple languages. You can contribute to the localization of Tinymist by translating or correcting the locale files in the [locales](./locales) folder. This is also a good start of contributing to the project.

## Maintainers

Get list of maintainers from [MAINTAINERS.typ](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/blob/main/MAINTAINERS.typ). Or programmatically by `yarn maintainers`

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; 
&gt;   You can add extra arguments for specific information. For example, `yarn maintainers --input=&quot;action=maintainers&quot;`.


## Acknowledgements

- Partially code is inherited from [typst-lsp](https://github.com/nvarner/typst-lsp)
- The [integrating](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/editors/vscode#symbol-view) **offline** handwritten-stroke recognizer is powered by [Detypify](https://detypify.quarticcat.com/).
- The [integrating](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/editors/vscode#preview-command) preview service is powered by [typst-preview](https://github.com/Enter-tainer/typst-preview).
- The [integrating](https://github.com/Myriad-Dreamin/tinymist/tree/main/editors/vscode#managing-local-packages) local package management functions are adopted from [vscode-typst-sync](https://github.com/OrangeX4/vscode-typst-sync).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MaterializeInc/materialize]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Real-time Data Integration and Transformation: use SQL to transform, deliver, and act on fast-changing data.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize">MaterializeInc/materialize</a></h1>
            <p>Real-time Data Integration and Transformation: use SQL to transform, deliver, and act on fast-changing data.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,931</p>
            <p>Forks: 468</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Build status](https://badge.buildkite.com/97d6604e015bf633d1c2a12d166bb46f3b43a927d3952c999a.svg?branch=main)](https://buildkite.com/materialize/test)
[![Doc reference](https://img.shields.io/badge/doc-reference-orange)](https://materialize.com/docs)
[![Chat on Slack](https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on%20slack-purple)](https://materialize.com/s/chat)

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/assets/23521087/39270ecb-7ac4-4829-b98b-c5b5699a16b8&quot; width=35%&gt;](https://materialize.com)

Materialize is a real-time data integration platform that creates and continually updates consistent views of transactional data from across your organization. Its SQL interface democratizes the ability to serve and access live data. Materialize can be deployed anywhere your infrastructure runs.

Use Materialize to do things like deliver fresh context for AI/RAG pipelines, power operational dashboards, and create more dynamic customer experiences without building time-consuming custom data pipelines.


The three most common patterns for adopting Materialize are the following:

- Query Offload (CQRS) - Scale complex read queries more efficiently than a read replica, and without the headaches of cache invalidation.
- Integration Hub (ODS) - Extract, load, and incrementally transform data from multiple sources. Create live views of your data that can be queried directly or pushed downstream.
- Operational Data Mesh (ODM) - Use SQL to create and deliver real-time, strongly consistent data products to streamline coordination across services and domains.


## Get started

Ready to try out Materialize? You can [sign up](https://materialize.com/register/) for a free cloud trial or [download](https://materialize.com/download/) our community edition, which is free forever for deployments using less than 24 GiB of memory and 48 GiB of disk!

Have questions? We&#039;d love to hear from you:
  * [Join our Slack](https://materialize.com/s/chat)
  * [Send us mail](https://materialize.com/contact/)

## About

Materialize focuses on providing correct and [consistent](https://materialize.com/docs/overview/isolation-level/) answers with minimal latency, and does not ask you to accept either approximate answers or eventual consistency. This guarantee holds even when joining data from [multiple upstream systems](https://materialize.com/blog/strong-consistency-in-materialize/). Whenever Materialize answers a query, that answer is the correct result on some specific (and recent) version of your data. Materialize does all of this by recasting your SQL queries as *dataflows*, which can react efficiently to changes in your data as they happen.

Our fully managed service is cloud-native, featuring **high availability** through multi-active replication, **horizontal scalability** by seamlessly scaling dataflows across multiple machines, and **near-infinite storage** by leveraging cloud object storage (e.g., Amazon S3). You can self-manage Materialize using our Enterprise or Community editions.

We support a large fraction of PostgreSQL features and are actively expanding support for more built-in PostgreSQL functions. Please file an issue if you have an idea for an improvement!

## Get data in

Materialize can read data directly from a [PostgreSQL](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/postgres/) or [MySQL](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/mysql/) replication stream, from [Kafka](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/kafka/) (and other Kafka API-compatible systems like [Redpanda](https://materialize.com/docs/integrations/redpanda/)), or from SaaS applications [via webhooks](https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-source/webhook/).

## Transform, manipulate, and read your data

Once you&#039;ve got the data in, define views and perform reads via the PostgreSQL protocol. Use your favorite SQL client, including the `psql` you probably already have on your system. Customers using Materialize in production tend to use [dbt Core](https://www.getdbt.com/).

Materialize supports a comprehensive variety of SQL features, all using the PostgreSQL dialect and protocol:

-   Joins, joins, joins! Materialize supports multi-column join conditions, multi-way joins, self-joins, cross-joins, inner joins, outer joins, etc.
-   Delta-joins avoid intermediate state blowup compared to systems that can only plan nested binary joins - tested on joins of up to 64 relations.
-   Support for subqueries. Materialize&#039;s SQL optimizer performs subquery decorrelation out-of-the-box, avoiding the need to manually rewrite subqueries into joins.
-   Materialize can incrementally maintain views in the presence of arbitrary inserts, updates, and deletes. No asterisks.
-   All the aggregations: `min`, `max`, `count`, `sum`, `stddev`, etc.
-   `HAVING`
-   `ORDER BY`
-   `LIMIT`
-   `DISTINCT`
-   JSON support in the PostgreSQL dialect including operators and functions like `-&gt;`, `-&gt;&gt;`, `@&gt;`, `?`, `jsonb_array_element`, `jsonb_each`. Materialize automatically plans lateral joins for efficient `jsonb_each` support.
-   Nest views on views on views!
-   Multiple views that have overlapping subplans can share underlying indices for space and compute efficiency, so just declaratively define _what you want_, and we&#039;ll worry about how to efficiently maintain them.

We’ve also extended our SQL support to enable [recursion](https://materialize.com/blog/recursion-in-materialize/) that supports incrementally updating tree and graph structures.

### Just show us what it can do!

Here&#039;s an example join query that works fine in Materialize, `TPC-H` query 15:

```sql
CREATE SOURCE tpch
  FROM LOAD GENERATOR TPCH (SCALE FACTOR 1)
  FOR ALL TABLES;

-- Views define commonly reused subqueries.
CREATE VIEW revenue (supplier_no, total_revenue) AS
    SELECT
        l_suppkey,
        SUM(l_extendedprice * (1 - l_discount))
    FROM
        lineitem
    WHERE
        l_shipdate &gt;= DATE &#039;1996-01-01&#039;
        AND l_shipdate &lt; DATE &#039;1996-01-01&#039; + INTERVAL &#039;3&#039; month
    GROUP BY
        l_suppkey;

-- The MATERIALIZED keyword is the trigger to begin
-- eagerly, consistently, and incrementally maintaining
-- results that are stored directly in durable storage.
CREATE MATERIALIZED VIEW tpch_q15 AS
  SELECT
    s_suppkey,
    s_name,
    s_address,
    s_phone,
    total_revenue
FROM
    supplier,
    revenue
WHERE
    s_suppkey = supplier_no
    AND total_revenue = (
        SELECT
            max(total_revenue)
        FROM
            revenue
    )
ORDER BY
    s_suppkey;

-- Creating an index keeps results always up to date and in memory.
-- In this example, the index will allow for fast point lookups of
-- individual supply keys.
CREATE INDEX tpch_q15_idx ON tpch_q15 (s_suppkey);
```

Stream inserts, updates, and deletes on the underlying tables (`lineitem` and `supplier`), and Materialize keeps the materialized view incrementally updated. You can type `SELECT * FROM tpch_q15` and expect to see the current results immediately!

## Get data out

**Pull based**: Use any PostgreSQL-compatible driver in any language/environment to make `SELECT` queries against your views. Tell them they&#039;re talking to a PostgreSQL database, they don&#039;t ever need to know otherwise. This is particularly helpful for pointing services and BI tools directly at Materialize.

**Push based**: Listen to changes directly using `SUBSCRIBE` or configure Materialize to stream results to a Kafka topic as soon as the views change. You can also copy updates to object storage.

## Documentation

Check out [our documentation](https://materialize.com/docs/).

## License

Materialize is provided as a self-managed product and a fully managed cloud service with
[credit-based pricing](https://materialize.com/pricing/). Included in the price
are proprietary cloud-native features like horizontal scalability, high
availability, and a web management console.

We&#039;re big believers in advancing the frontier of human knowledge. To
that end, the source code of the standalone database engine is publicly
available, in this repository, and [licensed](LICENSE) under the BSL 1.1,
converting to the open-source Apache 2.0 license after 4 years. As stated in the
BSL, use of the standalone database engine on a single node is free forever.

Materialize depends upon many open source Rust crates. We maintain a [list of
these crates and their licenses](https://dev.materialize.com/licenses.html),
including links to their source repositories.

## For developers

Materialize is primarily written in Rust.

Developers can find docs at [doc/developer](doc/developer), and Rust API documentation is hosted at &lt;https://dev.materialize.com/api/rust/&gt;.

Contributions are welcome. Prospective code contributors might find the [D-good
for external
contributors](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/discussions/categories/contribute-to-materialize?discussions_q=is%3Aopen+category%3A%22Contribute+to+Materialize%22+label%3A%22D-good+for+external+contributors%22)
discussion label useful. See
[CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md)
for additional guidance.

## Credits

Materialize is lovingly crafted by [a team of developers](https://github.com/MaterializeInc/materialize/graphs/contributors) and one bot. [Join us](https://materialize.com/careers/).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[lancedb/lance]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/lancedb/lance</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/lancedb/lance</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Modern columnar data format for ML and LLMs implemented in Rust. Convert from parquet in 2 lines of code for 100x faster random access, vector index, and data versioning. Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and PyTorch with more integrations coming..]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/lancedb/lance">lancedb/lance</a></h1>
            <p>Modern columnar data format for ML and LLMs implemented in Rust. Convert from parquet in 2 lines of code for 100x faster random access, vector index, and data versioning. Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and PyTorch with more integrations coming..</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,315</p>
            <p>Forks: 270</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img width=&quot;257&quot; alt=&quot;Lance Logo&quot; src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/917119/199353423-d3e202f7-0269-411d-8ff2-e747e419e492.png&quot;&gt;

**Modern columnar data format for ML. Convert from Parquet in 2-lines of code for 100x faster random access, zero-cost schema evolution, rich secondary indices, versioning, and more.&lt;br/&gt;**
**Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and Ray with more integrations on the way.**

&lt;a href=&quot;https://lancedb.github.io/lance/&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lancedb.com/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/zMM32dvNtd&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/lancedb&quot;&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;

[CI]: https://github.com/lancedb/lance/actions/workflows/rust.yml
[CI Badge]: https://github.com/lancedb/lance/actions/workflows/rust.yml/badge.svg
[Docs]: https://lancedb.github.io/lance/
[Docs Badge]: https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-passing-brightgreen
[crates.io]: https://crates.io/crates/lance
[crates.io badge]: https://img.shields.io/crates/v/lance.svg
[Python versions]: https://pypi.org/project/pylance/
[Python versions badge]: https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/pylance

[![CI Badge]][CI]
[![Docs Badge]][Docs]
[![crates.io badge]][crates.io]
[![Python versions badge]][Python versions]

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

Lance is a modern columnar data format that is optimized for ML workflows and datasets. Lance is perfect for:

1. Building search engines and feature stores.
2. Large-scale ML training requiring high performance IO and shuffles.
3. Storing, querying, and inspecting deeply nested data for robotics or large blobs like images, point clouds, and more.

The key features of Lance include:

* **High-performance random access:** 100x faster than Parquet without sacrificing scan performance.

* **Vector search:** find nearest neighbors in milliseconds and combine OLAP-queries with vector search.

* **Zero-copy, automatic versioning:** manage versions of your data without needing extra infrastructure.

* **Ecosystem integrations:** Apache Arrow, Pandas, Polars, DuckDB, Ray, Spark and more on the way.

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; Lance is in active development and we welcome contributions. Please see our [contributing guide](docs/contributing.rst) for more information.

## Quick Start

**Installation**

```shell
pip install pylance
```

To install a preview release:

```shell
pip install --pre --extra-index-url https://pypi.fury.io/lancedb/ pylance
```

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; Preview releases are released more often than full releases and contain the
&gt; latest features and bug fixes. They receive the same level of testing as full releases.
&gt; We guarantee they will remain published and available for download for at
&gt; least 6 months. When you want to pin to a specific version, prefer a stable release.

**Converting to Lance**

```python
import lance

import pandas as pd
import pyarrow as pa
import pyarrow.dataset

df = pd.DataFrame({&quot;a&quot;: [5], &quot;b&quot;: [10]})
uri = &quot;/tmp/test.parquet&quot;
tbl = pa.Table.from_pandas(df)
pa.dataset.write_dataset(tbl, uri, format=&#039;parquet&#039;)

parquet = pa.dataset.dataset(uri, format=&#039;parquet&#039;)
lance.write_dataset(parquet, &quot;/tmp/test.lance&quot;)
```

**Reading Lance data**
```python
dataset = lance.dataset(&quot;/tmp/test.lance&quot;)
assert isinstance(dataset, pa.dataset.Dataset)
```

**Pandas**
```python
df = dataset.to_table().to_pandas()
df
```

**DuckDB**
```python
import duckdb

# If this segfaults, make sure you have duckdb v0.7+ installed
duckdb.query(&quot;SELECT * FROM dataset LIMIT 10&quot;).to_df()
```

**Vector search**

Download the sift1m subset

```shell
wget ftp://ftp.irisa.fr/local/texmex/corpus/sift.tar.gz
tar -xzf sift.tar.gz
```

Convert it to Lance

```python
import lance
from lance.vector import vec_to_table
import numpy as np
import struct

nvecs = 1000000
ndims = 128
with open(&quot;sift/sift_base.fvecs&quot;, mode=&quot;rb&quot;) as fobj:
    buf = fobj.read()
    data = np.array(struct.unpack(&quot;&lt;128000000f&quot;, buf[4 : 4 + 4 * nvecs * ndims])).reshape((nvecs, ndims))
    dd = dict(zip(range(nvecs), data))

table = vec_to_table(dd)
uri = &quot;vec_data.lance&quot;
sift1m = lance.write_dataset(table, uri, max_rows_per_group=8192, max_rows_per_file=1024*1024)
```

Build the index

```python
sift1m.create_index(&quot;vector&quot;,
                    index_type=&quot;IVF_PQ&quot;,
                    num_partitions=256,  # IVF
                    num_sub_vectors=16)  # PQ
```

Search the dataset

```python
# Get top 10 similar vectors
import duckdb

dataset = lance.dataset(uri)

# Sample 100 query vectors. If this segfaults, make sure you have duckdb v0.7+ installed
sample = duckdb.query(&quot;SELECT vector FROM dataset USING SAMPLE 100&quot;).to_df()
query_vectors = np.array([np.array(x) for x in sample.vector])

# Get nearest neighbors for all of them
rs = [dataset.to_table(nearest={&quot;column&quot;: &quot;vector&quot;, &quot;k&quot;: 10, &quot;q&quot;: q})
      for q in query_vectors]
```

## Directory structure

| Directory          | Description                               |
|--------------------|-------------------------------------------|
| [rust](./rust)     | Core Rust implementation                  |
| [python](./python) | Python bindings (PyO3)                    |
| [java](./java)     | Java bindings (JNI) and Spark integration |
| [docs](./docs)     | Documentation source                      |

## What makes Lance different

Here we will highlight a few aspects of Lance’s design. For more details, see the full [Lance design document](https://lancedb.github.io/lance/format.html).

**Vector index**: Vector index for similarity search over embedding space.
Support both CPUs (``x86_64`` and ``arm``) and GPU (``Nvidia (cuda)`` and ``Apple Silicon (mps)``).

**Encodings**: To achieve both fast columnar scan and sub-linear point queries, Lance uses custom encodings and layouts.

**Nested fields**: Lance stores each subfield as a separate column to support efficient filters like “find images where detected objects include cats”.

**Versioning**: A Manifest can be used to record snapshots. Currently we support creating new versions automatically via appends, overwrites, and index creation .

**Fast updates** (ROADMAP): Updates will be supported via write-ahead logs.

**Rich secondary indices**: Support `BTree`, `Bitmap`, `Full text search`, `Label list`,
`NGrams`, and more.

## Benchmarks

### Vector search

We used the SIFT dataset to benchmark our results with 1M vectors of 128D

1. For 100 randomly sampled query vectors, we get &lt;1ms average response time (on a 2023 m2 MacBook Air)

![avg_latency.png](docs/avg_latency.png)

2. ANNs are always a trade-off between recall and performance

![avg_latency.png](docs/recall_vs_latency.png)

### Vs. parquet

We create a Lance dataset using the Oxford Pet dataset to do some preliminary performance testing of Lance as compared to Parquet and raw image/XMLs. For analytics queries, Lance is 50-100x better than reading the raw metadata. For batched random access, Lance is 100x better than both parquet and raw files.

![](docs/lance_perf.png)

## Why are you building yet another data format?!

The machine learning development cycle involves the steps:

```mermaid
graph LR
    A[Collection] --&gt; B[Exploration];
    B --&gt; C[Analytics];
    C --&gt; D[Feature Engineer];
    D --&gt; E[Training];
    E --&gt; F[Evaluation];
    F --&gt; C;
    E --&gt; G[Deployment];
    G --&gt; H[Monitoring];
    H --&gt; A;
```

People use different data representations to varying stages for the performance or limited by the tooling available.
Academia mainly uses XML / JSON for annotations and zipped images/sensors data for deep learning, which
is difficult to integrated into data infrastructure and slow to train over cloud storage.
While industry uses data lakes (Parquet-based techniques, i.e., Delta Lake, Iceberg) or data warehouses (AWS Redshift
or Google BigQuery) to collect and analyze data, they have to convert the data into training-friendly formats, such
as [Rikai](https://github.com/eto-ai/rikai)/[Petastorm](https://github.com/uber/petastorm)
or [TFRecord](https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/load_data/tfrecord).
Multiple single-purpose data transforms, as well as syncing copies between cloud storage to local training
instances have become a common practice.

While each of the existing data formats excels at the workload it was originally designed for, we need a new data format
tailored for multistage ML development cycles to reduce and data silos.

A comparison of different data formats in each stage of ML development cycle.

|                     | Lance | Parquet &amp; ORC | JSON &amp; XML | TFRecord | Database | Warehouse |
|---------------------|-------|---------------|------------|----------|----------|-----------|
| Analytics           | Fast  | Fast          | Slow       | Slow     | Decent   | Fast      |
| Feature Engineering | Fast  | Fast          | Decent     | Slow     | Decent   | Good      |
| Training            | Fast  | Decent        | Slow       | Fast     | N/A      | N/A       |
| Exploration         | Fast  | Slow          | Fast       | Slow     | Fast     | Decent    |
| Infra Support       | Rich  | Rich          | Decent     | Limited  | Rich     | Rich      |

## Community Highlights

Lance is currently used in production by:
* [LanceDB](https://github.com/lancedb/lancedb), a serverless, low-latency vector database for ML applications
* [LanceDB Enterprise](https://docs.lancedb.com/enterprise/introduction), hyperscale LanceDB with enterprise SLA.
* Leading multimodal Gen AI companies for training over petabyte-scale multimodal data.
* Self-driving car company for large-scale storage, retrieval and processing of multi-modal data.
* E-commerce company for billion-scale+ vector personalized search.
* and more.

## Presentations, Blogs and Talks

* [Designing a Table Format for ML Workloads](https://blog.lancedb.com/designing-a-table-format-for-ml-workloads/), Feb 2025.
* [Transforming Multimodal Data Management with LanceDB, Ray Summit](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xmTFEzAh8ho), Oct 2024.
* [Lance v2: A columnar container format for modern data](https://blog.lancedb.com/lance-v2/), Apr 2024.
* [Lance Deep Dive](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Orh9rK0Mpj9zN_gnQF1eJJFpAc6lStGm/view?usp=drive_link). July 2023.
* [Lance: A New Columnar Data Format](https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1a4nAiQAkPDBtOfXFpPg7lbeDAxcNDVKgoUkw3cUs2rE/edit#slide=id.p), [Scipy 2022, Austin, TX](https://www.scipy2022.scipy.org/posters). July, 2022.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[tokio-rs/axum]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/tokio-rs/axum</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/tokio-rs/axum</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Ergonomic and modular web framework built with Tokio, Tower, and Hyper]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/tokio-rs/axum">tokio-rs/axum</a></h1>
            <p>Ergonomic and modular web framework built with Tokio, Tower, and Hyper</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,992</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,145</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>axum/README.md</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mullvad/mullvadvpn-app]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Mullvad VPN client app for desktop and mobile]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app">mullvad/mullvadvpn-app</a></h1>
            <p>The Mullvad VPN client app for desktop and mobile</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 5,613</p>
            <p>Forks: 384</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Mullvad VPN desktop and mobile app

Welcome to the Mullvad VPN client app source code repository.
This is the VPN client software for the Mullvad VPN service.
For more information about the service, please visit our website,
[mullvad.net](https://mullvad.net) (Also accessible via Tor on our
[onion service](http://o54hon2e2vj6c7m3aqqu6uyece65by3vgoxxhlqlsvkmacw6a7m7kiad.onion/)).

This repository contains all the source code for the
desktop and mobile versions of the app. For desktop this includes the system service/daemon
([`mullvad-daemon`](mullvad-daemon/)), a graphical user interface ([GUI](desktop/)) and a command
line interface ([CLI](mullvad-cli/)). The Android app uses the same backing system service for the
tunnel and security but has a dedicated frontend in [android/](android/). iOS consists of a
completely standalone implementation that resides in [ios/](ios/).

## Releases

There are built and signed releases for macOS, Windows, Linux and Android available on
[our website](https://mullvad.net/download/) and on
[GitHub](https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app/releases/). The Android app is also available
on [Google Play] and [F-Droid] and the iOS version on [App Store].

[Google Play]: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.mullvad.mullvadvpn
[F-Droid]: https://f-droid.org/packages/net.mullvad.mullvadvpn/
[App Store]: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mullvad-vpn/id1488466513

You can find our code signing keys as well as instructions for how to cryptographically verify
your download on [Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page].

### Platform/OS support

These are the operating systems and their versions that the app officially supports. It might
work on many more versions, but we don&#039;t test for those and can&#039;t guarantee the quality or
security.

| OS/Platform | Supported versions |
|-------------|--------------------|
| Windows     | 10 and 11          |
| macOS       | The three latest major releases |
| Linux (Ubuntu)| The two latest LTS releases and the latest non-LTS releases |
| Linux (Fedora) | The versions that are not yet [EOL](https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/End_of_life) |
| Linux (Debian) | 12 and newer    |
| Android     | 8 and newer        |
| iOS         | 15.0 and newer     |

On Linux we test using the Gnome desktop environment. The app should, and probably does work
in other DEs, but we don&#039;t regularly test those.

## Features

Here is a table containing the features of the app across platforms. This is intended to reflect
the current state of the latest code in git, not necessarily any existing release.

|                               | Windows | Linux | macOS | Android | iOS |
|-------------------------------|:-------:|:-----:|:-----:|:-------:|:---:|
| OpenVPN                       |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |         |     |
| WireGuard                     |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Quantum-resistant tunnels     |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| [DAITA]                       |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard multihop            |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard over TCP            |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| WireGuard over Shadowsocks    |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| OpenVPN over Shadowsocks      |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |         |     |
| Split tunneling               |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |     |
| Custom DNS server             |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Content blockers (Ads etc)    |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓  |
| Optional local network access |    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓\* |
| [Externally audited](./audits)|    ✓    |   ✓   |   ✓   |    ✓    |  ✓ |

\* The local network is always accessible on iOS with the current implementation

[DAITA]: https://mullvad.net/en/blog/introducing-defense-against-ai-guided-traffic-analysis-daita

## Security and anonymity

This app is a privacy preserving VPN client. As such it goes to great lengths to stop traffic
leaks. And basically all settings default to the more secure/private option. The user has to
explicitly allow more loose rules if desired. See the [dedicated security document] for details
on what the app blocks and allows, as well as how it does it.

[dedicated security document]: docs/security.md

## Checking out the code

This repository contains submodules needed for building the app. However, some of those submodules
also have further submodules that are quite large and not needed to build the app. So unless
you want the source code for OpenSSL, OpenVPN and a few other projects you should avoid a recursive
clone of the repository. Instead clone the repository normally and then get one level of submodules:
```bash
git clone https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app.git
cd mullvadvpn-app
git submodule update --init
```

On Android, Windows, Linux and macOS you also want to checkout the wireguard-go submodule:
```bash
git submodule update --init wireguard-go-rs/libwg/wireguard-go
```
Further details on why this is necessary can be found in the [wireguard-go-rs crate](./wireguard-go-rs/README.md).

We sign every commit on the `main` branch as well as our release tags. If you would like to verify
your checkout, you can find our developer keys on [Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page].

### Binaries submodule

This repository has a git submodule at `dist-assets/binaries`. This submodule contains binaries and
build scripts for third party code we need to bundle with the app. Such as OpenVPN, Wintun
etc.

This submodule conforms to the same integrity/security standards as this repository. Every merge
commit should be signed. And this main repository should only ever point to a signed merge commit
of the binaries submodule.

See the [binaries submodule&#039;s](https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app-binaries) README for more
details about that repository.

## Building the app

See the [build instructions](BuildInstructions.md) for help building the app on desktop platforms.

For building the Android app, see the [instructions](./android/BuildInstructions.md) for Android.

For building the iOS app, see the [instructions](./ios/BuildInstructions.md) for iOS.

## Releasing the app

See [this](Release.md) for instructions on how to make a new release.

## Environment variables used by the service

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DEBUG` - Helps debugging the firewall. Does different things depending on
  platform:
  * Linux: Set to `&quot;1&quot;` to add packet counters to all firewall rules.
  * macOS: Makes rules log the packets they match to the `pflog0` interface.
    * Set to `&quot;all&quot;` to add logging to all rules.
    * Set to `&quot;pass&quot;` to add logging to rules allowing packets.
    * Set to `&quot;drop&quot;` to add logging to rules blocking packets.

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DONT_SET_SRC_VALID_MARK` - Set this variable to `1` to stop the daemon from
    setting the `net.ipv4.conf.all.src_valid_mark` kernel parameter to `1` on Linux when a tunnel
    is established.
    The kernel config parameter is set by default, because otherwise strict reverse path filtering
    may prevent relay traffic from reaching the daemon. If `rp_filter` is set to `1` on the interface
    that will be receiving relay traffic, and `src_valid_mark` is not set to `1`, the daemon will
    not be able to receive relay traffic.

* `TALPID_FIREWALL_DONT_SET_ARP_IGNORE` - Set this variable to `1` to stop the daemon from
    setting the `net.ipv4.conf.all.arp_ignore` kernel parameter to `2` on Linux when a tunnel
    is established.
    The kernel config parameter is set by default, because otherwise an attacker who can send ARP
    requests to the device running Mullvad can figure out the in-tunnel IP.

* `TALPID_DNS_MODULE` - Allows changing the method that will be used for DNS configuration.
  By default this is automatically detected, but you can set it to one of the options below to
  choose a specific method.

  * Linux
    * `&quot;static-file&quot;`: change the `/etc/resolv.conf` file directly
    * `&quot;resolvconf&quot;`: use the `resolvconf` program
    * `&quot;systemd&quot;`: use systemd&#039;s `resolved` service through DBus
    * `&quot;network-manager&quot;`: use `NetworkManager` service through DBus

  * Windows
    * `iphlpapi`: use the IP helper API
    * `netsh`: use the `netsh` program
    * `tcpip`: set TCP/IP parameters in the registry

* `TALPID_FORCE_USERSPACE_WIREGUARD` - Forces the daemon to use the userspace implementation of
   WireGuard on Linux.

* `TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR` - Forces the daemon to always assume the host is online.

* `TALPID_NET_CLS_MOUNT_DIR` - On Linux, forces the daemon to mount the `net_cls` controller in the
  specified directory if it isn&#039;t mounted already.

* `MULLVAD_MANAGEMENT_SOCKET_GROUP` - On Linux and macOS, this restricts access to the management
  interface UDS socket to users in the specified group. This means that only users in that group can
  use the CLI and GUI. By default, everyone has access to the socket.

* `MULLVAD_BACKTRACE_ON_FAULT` - When enabled, if the daemon encounters a fault (e.g. `SIGSEGV`),
  it will log a backtrace to stdout, and to `daemon.log`. By default, this is disabled in
  release-builds and enabled in debug-builds. Set variable to `1` or `0` to explicitly enable or
  disable this feature. Logging the backtrace cause heap allocation. Allocation is not signal safe,
  but here it runs in the signal handler. This in technically undefined behavior and therefore
  disabled by default. This usually works, but enable at your own risk.

### Development builds only

* `MULLVAD_API_HOST` - Set the hostname to use in API requests. E.g. `api.mullvad.net`.

* `MULLVAD_API_ADDR` - Set the IP address and port to use in API requests. E.g. `10.10.1.2:443`.

* `MULLVAD_API_DISABLE_TLS` - Use plain HTTP for API requests.

* `MULLVAD_CONNCHECK_HOST` - Set the hostname to use in connection check requests. E.g. `am.i.mullvad.net`.

### Setting environment variables

#### Windows

Use `setx` from an elevated shell:

```bat
setx TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE 1 /m
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bat
sc.exe stop mullvadvpn
sc.exe start mullvadvpn
```

#### Linux

Edit the systemd unit file via `systemctl edit mullvad-daemon.service`:

```ini
[Service]
Environment=&quot;TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR=1&quot;
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bash
sudo systemctl restart mullvad-daemon
```

#### macOS

Use `plutil`:

```bash
sudo plutil -replace EnvironmentVariables -json &#039;{&quot;TALPID_DISABLE_OFFLINE_MONITOR&quot;: &quot;1&quot;}&#039; /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
```

For the change to take effect, restart the daemon:

```bash
launchctl unload -w /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
launchctl load -w /Library/LaunchDaemons/net.mullvad.daemon.plist
```

## Environment variables used by the desktop frontend

* `MULLVAD_PATH` - Allows changing the path to the folder with the `mullvad-problem-report` tool
   when running in development mode. Defaults to: `&lt;repo&gt;/target/debug/`.
* `MULLVAD_DISABLE_UPDATE_NOTIFICATION` - If set to `1`, notification will be disabled when
   an update is available.


## Command line tools for Electron app development

- `$ npm run develop` - develop app with live-reload enabled
- `$ npm run lint` - lint code
- `$ npm run pack:&lt;OS&gt;` - prepare app for distribution for your platform. Where `&lt;OS&gt;` can be
  `linux`, `mac` or `win`
- `$ npm test` - run tests


## Tray icon on Linux

The requirements for displaying a tray icon varies between different desktop environments. If the
tray icon doesn&#039;t appear, try installing one of these packages:
- `libappindicator3-1`
- `libappindicator1`
- `libappindicator`

If you&#039;re using GNOME, try installing one of these GNOME Shell extensions:
- `TopIconsFix`
- `TopIcons Plus`


## Repository structure

### Electron app and electron-builder packaging assets
- **desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/**
  - **assets/** - Graphical assets and stylesheets
  - **src/**
    - **main/**
      - **index.ts** - Entry file for the main process
    - **renderer/**
      - **app.tsx** - Entry file for the renderer process
      - **routes.tsx** - Routes configurator
      - **transitions.ts** - Transition rules between views
  - **tasks/** - Gulp tasks used to build app and watch for changes during development
    - **distribution.js** - Configuration for `electron-builder`
  - **test/** - Electron GUI tests
- **dist-assets/** - Icons, binaries and other files used when creating the distributables
  - **binaries/** - Git submodule containing binaries bundled with the app. For example the
    statically linked OpenVPN binary. See the README in the submodule for details
  - **linux/** - Scripts and configuration files for the deb and rpm artifacts
  - **pkg-scripts/** - Scripts bundled with and executed by the macOS pkg installer
  - **windows/** - Windows NSIS installer configuration and assets
  - **ca.crt** - The Mullvad relay server root CA. Bundled with the app and only OpenVPN relays
    signed by this CA are trusted


### Building, testing and misc
- **build-windows-modules.sh** - Compiles the C++ libraries needed on Windows
- **build.sh** - Sanity checks the working directory state and then builds installers for the app

### Mullvad Daemon

The daemon is implemented in Rust and is implemented in several crates. The main, or top level,
crate that builds the final daemon binary is `mullvad-daemon` which then depend on the others.

In general one can look at the daemon as split into two parts, the crates starting with `talpid`
and the crates starting with `mullvad`. The `talpid` crates are supposed to be completely unrelated
to Mullvad specific things. A `talpid` crate is not allowed to know anything about the API through
which the daemon fetch Mullvad account details or download VPN server lists for example. The
`talpid` components should be viewed as a generic VPN client with extra privacy and anonymity
preserving features. The crates having `mullvad` in their name on the other hand make use of the
`talpid` components to build a secure and Mullvad specific VPN client.


- **Cargo.toml** - Main Rust workspace definition. See this file for which folders here are daemon
  Rust crates.
- **mullvad-daemon/** - Main Rust crate building the daemon binary.
- **talpid-core/** - Main crate of the VPN client implementation itself. Completely Mullvad agnostic
  privacy preserving VPN client library.


## Vocabulary

Explanations for some common words used in the documentation and code in this repository.

- **App** - This entire product (everything in this repository) is the &quot;Mullvad VPN App&quot;, or App for
  short.
  - **Daemon** - Refers to the `mullvad-daemon` Rust program. This headless program exposes a
    management interface that can be used to control the daemon
  - **Frontend** - Term used for any program or component that connects to the daemon management
    interface and allows a user to control the daemon.
    - **GUI** - The Electron + React program that is a graphical frontend for the Mullvad VPN App.
    - **CLI** - The Rust program named `mullvad` that is a terminal based frontend for the Mullvad
      VPN app.


## File paths used by Mullvad VPN app

A list of file paths written to and read from by the various components of the Mullvad VPN app

### Daemon

On Windows, when a process runs as a system service the variable `%LOCALAPPDATA%` expands to
`C:\Windows\system32\config\systemprofile\AppData\Local`.

All directory paths are defined in, and fetched from, the `mullvad-paths` crate.

#### Settings

The settings directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_SETTINGS_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/etc/mullvad-vpn/` |
| macOS | `/etc/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `%LOCALAPPDATA%\Mullvad VPN\` |
| Android | [`getFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getFilesDir()) |

#### Logs

The log directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_LOG_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/log/mullvad-vpn/` + systemd |
| macOS | `/var/log/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `C:\ProgramData\Mullvad VPN\` |
| Android | [`getFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getFilesDir()) |

#### Cache

The cache directory can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_CACHE_DIR` environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/cache/mullvad-vpn/` |
| macOS | `/Library/Caches/mullvad-vpn/` |
| Windows | `C:\ProgramData\Mullvad VPN\cache` |
| Android | [`getCacheDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#getCacheDir())  |

#### RPC address file

The full path to the RPC address file can be changed by setting the `MULLVAD_RPC_SOCKET_PATH`
environment variable.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `/var/run/mullvad-vpn` |
| macOS | `/var/run/mullvad-vpn` |
| Windows | `//./pipe/Mullvad VPN` |
| Android | [`getNoBackupFilesDir()`](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/ContextWrapper#getNoBackupFilesDir()) |

### Desktop Electron app

The desktop Electron app has a specific settings file that is configured for each user. The path is
set in the `desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/src/main/gui-settings.ts` file.

| Platform | Path |
|----------|------|
| Linux | `$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/Mullvad VPN/gui_settings.json` |
| macOS | `~/Library/Application Support/Mullvad VPN/gui_settings.json` |
| Windows | `%LOCALAPPDATA%\Mullvad VPN\gui_settings.json` |
| Android | Present in Android&#039;s `logcat` |

## Icons

See [graphics README](graphics/README.md) for information about icons.

## Locales and translations

Instructions for how to handle locales and translations are found
[here](./desktop/packages/mullvad-vpn/locales/README.md).

For instructions specific to the Android app, see [here](./android/README.md).

## Audits, pentests and external security reviews

Mullvad has used external pentesting companies to carry out security audits of this VPN app. Read
more about them in the [audits readme](./audits/README.md).

# License

Copyright (C) 2025  Mullvad VPN AB

This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the
GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of
the License, or (at your option) any later version.

For the full license agreement, see the LICENSE.md file

The source code for the iOS app is GPL-3 licensed like everything else in this repository.
But the distributed app on the Apple App Store is not GPL licensed,
it falls under the [Apple App Store EULA].

[Apple App Store EULA]: https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/dev/stdeula/
[Mullvad&#039;s Open Source page]: https://mullvad.net/en/guides/open-source/
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[eza-community/eza]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/eza-community/eza</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/eza-community/eza</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A modern alternative to ls]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/eza-community/eza">eza-community/eza</a></h1>
            <p>A modern alternative to ls</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,735</p>
            <p>Forks: 273</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2023-2024 Christina Sørensen
SPDX-FileContributor: Christina Sørensen

SPDX-License-Identifier: EUPL-1.2
--&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# eza

A modern replacement for ls.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#eza-community:gitter.im&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gitter&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/gitter/room/eza-community/eza?logo=element&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fapp.gitter.im%2F%23%2Froom%2F%23eza%3Agitter.im&amp;link=Gitter%20matrix%20room%20for%20Eza&quot; width=200&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

[![Built with Nix](https://img.shields.io/badge/Built_With-Nix-5277C3.svg?logo=nixos&amp;labelColor=73C3D5)](https://nixos.org)
[![Contributor Covenant](https://img.shields.io/badge/Contributor%20Covenant-2.1-4baaaa.svg)](CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md)

[![Unit tests](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/actions/workflows/unit-tests.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/actions/workflows/unit-tests.yml)
![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/eza?link=https%3A%2F%2Fcrates.io%2Fcrates%2Feza)
![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/l/eza?link=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Feza-community%2Feza%2Fblob%2Fmain%2FLICENCE)

&lt;/div&gt;

![eza demo gif](docs/images/screenshots.png)

---

**eza** is a modern alternative for the venerable file-listing command-line program `ls` that ships with Unix and Linux operating systems, giving it more features and better defaults.
It uses colours to distinguish file types and metadata.
It knows about symlinks, extended attributes, and Git.
And it’s **small**, **fast**, and just **one single binary**.

By deliberately making some decisions differently, eza attempts to be a more featureful, more user-friendly version of `ls`.

---

**eza** features not in exa (non-exhaustive):

- Fixes [“The Grid Bug”](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/issues/66#issuecomment-1656758327) introduced in exa 2021.
- Hyperlink support.
- Mount point details.
- Selinux context output.
- Git repo status output.
- Human readable relative dates.
- Several security fixes.
- Support for `bright` terminal colours.
- Many smaller bug fixes/changes!
- Configuration `theme.yml` file for customization of colors and icons.

...and like, so much more that it became exhausting to update this all the time.
Like seriously, we have a lot of good stuff.

---

&lt;a id=&quot;try-it&quot;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Try it!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### Nix ❄️

If you already have Nix setup with flake support, you can try out eza with the `nix run` command:

    nix run github:eza-community/eza

Nix will build eza and run it.

If you want to pass arguments this way, use e.g. `nix run github:eza-community/eza -- -ol`.

# Installation

eza is available for Windows, macOS and Linux. Platform and distribution
specific installation instructions can be found in [INSTALL.md](INSTALL.md).

[![Packaging status](https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/eza.svg?columns=3)](https://repology.org/project/eza/versions)

---

&lt;a id=&quot;options&quot;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Command-line options&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

eza’s options are almost, but not quite, entirely unlike `ls`’s. Quick overview:

## Display options

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt;

- **-1**, **--oneline**: display one entry per line
- **-G**, **--grid**: display entries as a grid (default)
- **-l**, **--long**: display extended details and attributes
- **-R**, **--recurse**: recurse into directories
- **-T**, **--tree**: recurse into directories as a tree
- **-x**, **--across**: sort the grid across, rather than downwards
- **-F**, **--classify=(when)**: display type indicator by file names (always, auto, never)
- **--colo[u]r=(when)**: when to use terminal colours (always, auto, never)
- **--colo[u]r-scale=(field)**: highlight levels of `field` distinctly(all, age, size)
- **--color-scale-mode=(mode)**: use gradient or fixed colors in --color-scale. valid options are `fixed` or `gradient`
- **--icons=(when)**: when to display icons (always, auto, never)
- **--hyperlink**: display entries as hyperlinks
- **--absolute=(mode)**: display entries with their absolute path (on, follow, off)
- **-w**, **--width=(columns)**: set screen width in columns

&lt;/details&gt;

## Filtering options

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt;

- **-a**, **--all**: show hidden and &#039;dot&#039; files
- **-d**, **--list-dirs**: list directories like regular files
- **-L**, **--level=(depth)**: limit the depth of recursion
- **-r**, **--reverse**: reverse the sort order
- **-s**, **--sort=(field)**: which field to sort by
- **--group-directories-first**: list directories before other files
- **--group-directories-last**: list directories after other files
- **-D**, **--only-dirs**: list only directories
- **-f**, **--only-files**: list only files
- **--no-symlinks**: don&#039;t show symbolic links
- **--show-symlinks**: explicitly show links (with `--only-dirs`, `--only-files`, to show symlinks that match the filter)
- **--git-ignore**: ignore files mentioned in `.gitignore`
- **-I**, **--ignore-glob=(globs)**: glob patterns (pipe-separated) of files to ignore

Pass the `--all` option twice to also show the `.` and `..` directories.

&lt;/details&gt;

## Long view options

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt;

These options are available when running with `--long` (`-l`):

- **-b**, **--binary**: list file sizes with binary prefixes
- **-B**, **--bytes**: list file sizes in bytes, without any prefixes
- **-g**, **--group**: list each file’s group
- **-h**, **--header**: add a header row to each column
- **-H**, **--links**: list each file’s number of hard links
- **-i**, **--inode**: list each file’s inode number
- **-m**, **--modified**: use the modified timestamp field
- **-M**, **--mounts**: Show mount details (Linux and MacOS only).
- **-S**, **--blocksize**: show size of allocated file system blocks
- **-t**, **--time=(field)**: which timestamp field to use
- **-u**, **--accessed**: use the accessed timestamp field
- **-U**, **--created**: use the created timestamp field
- **-X**, **--dereference**: dereference symlinks for file information
- **-Z**, **--context**: list each file’s security context
- **-@**, **--extended**: list each file’s extended attributes and sizes
- **--changed**: use the changed timestamp field
- **--git**: list each file’s Git status, if tracked or ignored
- **--git-repos**: list each directory’s Git status, if tracked
- **--git-repos-no-status**: list whether a directory is a Git repository, but not its status (faster)
- **--no-git**: suppress Git status (always overrides `--git`, `--git-repos`, `--git-repos-no-status`)
- **--time-style**: how to format timestamps. valid timestamp styles are ‘`default`’, ‘`iso`’, ‘`long-iso`’, ‘`full-iso`’, ‘`relative`’, or a custom style ‘`+&lt;FORMAT&gt;`’ (E.g., ‘`+%Y-%m-%d %H:%M`’ =&gt; ‘`2023-09-30 13:00`’. For more specifications on the format string, see the _`eza(1)` manual page_ and [chrono documentation](https://docs.rs/chrono/latest/chrono/format/strftime/index.html).).
- **--total-size**: show recursive directory size
- **--no-permissions**: suppress the permissions field
- **-o**, **--octal-permissions**: list each file&#039;s permission in octal format
- **--no-filesize**: suppress the filesize field
- **--no-user**: suppress the user field
- **--no-time**: suppress the time field
- **--stdin**: read file names from stdin

Some of the options accept parameters:

- Valid **--colo\[u\]r** options are **always**, **automatic** (or **auto** for short), and **never**.
- Valid sort fields are **accessed**, **changed**, **created**, **extension**, **Extension**, **inode**, **modified**, **name**, **Name**, **size**, **type**, and **none**. Fields starting with a capital letter sort uppercase before lowercase. The modified field has the aliases **date**, **time**, and **newest**, while its reverse has the aliases **age** and **oldest**.
- Valid time fields are **modified**, **changed**, **accessed**, and **created**.
- Valid time styles are **default**, **iso**, **long-iso**, **full-iso**, and **relative**.



See the `man` pages for further documentation of usage. They are available
- online [in the repo](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/tree/main/man)
- in your terminal via `man eza`, as of version [`[0.18.13] - 2024-04-25`](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md#01813---2024-04-25)
&lt;/details&gt;


## Custom Themes
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt;

**Eza** has recently added support for a `theme.yml` file, where you can specify all of the existing theme-ing options
available for the `LS_COLORS` and `EXA_COLORS` environment variables, as well as the option to specify different icons
for different file types and extensions. Any existing environment variables set will continue to work and will take
precedence for backwards compatibility.

#### **New** Pre-made themes
Check out the themes available in the official [eza-themes](https://github.com/eza-community/eza-themes) repository, or contribute your own.

An example theme file is available in `docs/theme.yml`, and needs to either be placed in a directory specified by the 
environment variable `EZA_CONFIG_DIR`, or will looked for by default in `$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/eza`.

Full details are available on the [man page](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/tree/main/man/eza_colors-explanation.5.md) and an example theme file is included [here](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/tree/main/docs/theme.yml)

&lt;/details&gt;


# Hacking on eza

If you wanna contribute to eza, firstly, you&#039;re expected to follow our 
[code of conduct](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/blob/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md). 
After having understood the code of conduct, you can have a look at our
[CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/eza-community/eza/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md) 
for more info about actual hacking.

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=eza-community/eza&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#eza-community/eza&amp;Date)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rust-lang/rust-clippy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A bunch of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your Rust code. Book: https://doc.rust-lang.org/clippy/]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy">rust-lang/rust-clippy</a></h1>
            <p>A bunch of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your Rust code. Book: https://doc.rust-lang.org/clippy/</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,865</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,611</p>
            <p>Stars today: 6 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Clippy

[![License: MIT OR Apache-2.0](https://img.shields.io/crates/l/clippy.svg)](#license)

A collection of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your [Rust](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust) code.

[There are over 750 lints included in this crate!](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html)

Lints are divided into categories, each with a default [lint level](https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/lints/levels.html).
You can choose how much Clippy is supposed to ~~annoy~~ help you by changing the lint level by category.

| Category              | Description                                                                         | Default level |
|-----------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|---------------|
| `clippy::all`         | all lints that are on by default (correctness, suspicious, style, complexity, perf) | **warn/deny** |
| `clippy::correctness` | code that is outright wrong or useless                                              | **deny**      |
| `clippy::suspicious`  | code that is most likely wrong or useless                                           | **warn**      |
| `clippy::style`       | code that should be written in a more idiomatic way                                 | **warn**      |
| `clippy::complexity`  | code that does something simple but in a complex way                                | **warn**      |
| `clippy::perf`        | code that can be written to run faster                                              | **warn**      |
| `clippy::pedantic`    | lints which are rather strict or have occasional false positives                    | allow         |
| `clippy::restriction` | lints which prevent the use of language and library features[^restrict]             | allow         |
| `clippy::nursery`     | new lints that are still under development                                          | allow         |
| `clippy::cargo`       | lints for the cargo manifest                                                        | allow         |

More to come, please [file an issue](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/issues) if you have ideas!

The `restriction` category should, *emphatically*, not be enabled as a whole. The contained
lints may lint against perfectly reasonable code, may not have an alternative suggestion,
and may contradict any other lints (including other categories). Lints should be considered
on a case-by-case basis before enabling.

[^restrict]: Some use cases for `restriction` lints include:
    - Strict coding styles (e.g. [`clippy::else_if_without_else`]).
    - Additional restrictions on CI (e.g. [`clippy::todo`]).
    - Preventing panicking in certain functions (e.g. [`clippy::unwrap_used`]).
    - Running a lint only on a subset of code (e.g. `#[forbid(clippy::float_arithmetic)]` on a module).

[`clippy::else_if_without_else`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#else_if_without_else
[`clippy::todo`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#todo
[`clippy::unwrap_used`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#unwrap_used

---

Table of contents:

* [Usage instructions](#usage)
* [Configuration](#configuration)
* [Contributing](#contributing)
* [License](#license)

## Usage

Below are instructions on how to use Clippy as a cargo subcommand,
in projects that do not use cargo, or in Travis CI.

### As a cargo subcommand (`cargo clippy`)

One way to use Clippy is by installing Clippy through rustup as a cargo
subcommand.

#### Step 1: Install Rustup

You can install [Rustup](https://rustup.rs/) on supported platforms. This will help
us install Clippy and its dependencies.

If you already have Rustup installed, update to ensure you have the latest
Rustup and compiler:

```terminal
rustup update
```

#### Step 2: Install Clippy

Once you have rustup and the latest stable release (at least Rust 1.29) installed, run the following command:

```terminal
rustup component add clippy
```

If it says that it can&#039;t find the `clippy` component, please run `rustup self update`.

#### Step 3: Run Clippy

Now you can run Clippy by invoking the following command:

```terminal
cargo clippy
```

#### Automatically applying Clippy suggestions

Clippy can automatically apply some lint suggestions, just like the compiler. Note that `--fix` implies
`--all-targets`, so it can fix as much code as it can.

```terminal
cargo clippy --fix
```

#### Workspaces

All the usual workspace options should work with Clippy. For example the following command
will run Clippy on the `example` crate:

```terminal
cargo clippy -p example
```

As with `cargo check`, this includes dependencies that are members of the workspace, like path dependencies.
If you want to run Clippy **only** on the given crate, use the `--no-deps` option like this:

```terminal
cargo clippy -p example -- --no-deps
```

### Using `clippy-driver`

Clippy can also be used in projects that do not use cargo. To do so, run `clippy-driver`
with the same arguments you use for `rustc`. For example:

```terminal
clippy-driver --edition 2018 -Cpanic=abort foo.rs
```

Note that `clippy-driver` is designed for running Clippy only and should not be used as a general
replacement for `rustc`. `clippy-driver` may produce artifacts that are not optimized as expected,
for example.

### Travis CI

You can add Clippy to Travis CI in the same way you use it locally:

```yaml
language: rust
rust:
  - stable
  - beta
before_script:
  - rustup component add clippy
script:
  - cargo clippy
  # if you want the build job to fail when encountering warnings, use
  - cargo clippy -- -D warnings
  # in order to also check tests and non-default crate features, use
  - cargo clippy --all-targets --all-features -- -D warnings
  - cargo test
  # etc.
```

Note that adding `-D warnings` will cause your build to fail if **any** warnings are found in your code.
That includes warnings found by rustc (e.g. `dead_code`, etc.). If you want to avoid this and only cause
an error for Clippy warnings, use `#![deny(clippy::all)]` in your code or `-D clippy::all` on the command
line. (You can swap `clippy::all` with the specific lint category you are targeting.)

## Configuration

### Allowing/denying lints

You can add options to your code to `allow`/`warn`/`deny` Clippy lints:

* the whole set of `Warn` lints using the `clippy` lint group (`#![deny(clippy::all)]`).
  Note that `rustc` has additional [lint groups](https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/lints/groups.html).

* all lints using both the `clippy` and `clippy::pedantic` lint groups (`#![deny(clippy::all)]`,
  `#![deny(clippy::pedantic)]`). Note that `clippy::pedantic` contains some very aggressive
  lints prone to false positives.

* only some lints (`#![deny(clippy::single_match, clippy::box_vec)]`, etc.)

* `allow`/`warn`/`deny` can be limited to a single function or module using `#[allow(...)]`, etc.

Note: `allow` means to suppress the lint for your code. With `warn` the lint
will only emit a warning, while with `deny` the lint will emit an error, when
triggering for your code. An error causes Clippy to exit with an error code, so
is useful in scripts like CI/CD.

If you do not want to include your lint levels in your code, you can globally
enable/disable lints by passing extra flags to Clippy during the run:

To allow `lint_name`, run

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -A clippy::lint_name
```

And to warn on `lint_name`, run

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -W clippy::lint_name
```

This also works with lint groups. For example, you
can run Clippy with warnings for all lints enabled:

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -W clippy::pedantic
```

If you care only about a single lint, you can allow all others and then explicitly warn on
the lint(s) you are interested in:

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -A clippy::all -W clippy::useless_format -W clippy::...
```

### Configure the behavior of some lints

Some lints can be configured in a TOML file named `clippy.toml` or `.clippy.toml`. It contains a basic `variable =
value` mapping e.g.

```toml
avoid-breaking-exported-api = false
disallowed-names = [&quot;toto&quot;, &quot;tata&quot;, &quot;titi&quot;]
```

The [table of configurations](https://doc.rust-lang.org/nightly/clippy/lint_configuration.html)
contains all config values, their default, and a list of lints they affect.
Each [configurable lint](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#Configuration)
, also contains information about these values.

For configurations that are a list type with default values such as
[disallowed-names](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#disallowed_names),
you can use the unique value `&quot;..&quot;` to extend the default values instead of replacing them.

```toml
# default of disallowed-names is [&quot;foo&quot;, &quot;baz&quot;, &quot;quux&quot;]
disallowed-names = [&quot;bar&quot;, &quot;..&quot;] # -&gt; [&quot;bar&quot;, &quot;foo&quot;, &quot;baz&quot;, &quot;quux&quot;]
```

&gt; **Note**
&gt;
&gt; `clippy.toml` or `.clippy.toml` cannot be used to allow/deny lints.

To deactivate the “for further information visit *lint-link*” message you can
define the `CLIPPY_DISABLE_DOCS_LINKS` environment variable.

### Specifying the minimum supported Rust version

Projects that intend to support old versions of Rust can disable lints pertaining to newer features by
specifying the minimum supported Rust version (MSRV) in the Clippy configuration file.

```toml
msrv = &quot;1.30.0&quot;
```

Alternatively, the [`rust-version` field](https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/reference/manifest.html#the-rust-version-field)
in the `Cargo.toml` can be used.

```toml
# Cargo.toml
rust-version = &quot;1.30&quot;
```

The MSRV can also be specified as an attribute, like below.

```rust,ignore
#![feature(custom_inner_attributes)]
#![clippy::msrv = &quot;1.30.0&quot;]

fn main() {
  ...
}
```

You can also omit the patch version when specifying the MSRV, so `msrv = 1.30`
is equivalent to `msrv = 1.30.0`.

Note: `custom_inner_attributes` is an unstable feature, so it has to be enabled explicitly.

Lints that recognize this configuration option can be found [here](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#msrv)

## Contributing

If you want to contribute to Clippy, you can find more information in [CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md).

## License

&lt;!-- REUSE-IgnoreStart --&gt;

Copyright 2014-2025 The Rust Project Developers

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 &lt;LICENSE-APACHE or
[https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0](https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0)&gt; or the MIT license
&lt;LICENSE-MIT or [https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT](https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT)&gt;, at your
option. Files in the project may not be
copied, modified, or distributed except according to those terms.

&lt;!-- REUSE-IgnoreEnd --&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[paradigmxyz/reth]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Modular, contributor-friendly and blazing-fast implementation of the Ethereum protocol, in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth">paradigmxyz/reth</a></h1>
            <p>Modular, contributor-friendly and blazing-fast implementation of the Ethereum protocol, in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,503</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,510</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># reth

[![bench status](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/actions/workflows/bench.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/actions/workflows/bench.yml)
[![CI status](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/workflows/unit/badge.svg)][gh-ci]
[![cargo-lint status](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/actions/workflows/lint.yml/badge.svg)][gh-lint]
[![Telegram Chat][tg-badge]][tg-url]

**Modular, contributor-friendly and blazing-fast implementation of the Ethereum protocol**

![](./assets/reth-prod.png)

**[Install](https://paradigmxyz.github.io/reth/installation/installation.html)**
| [User Book](https://reth.rs)
| [Developer Docs](./docs)
| [Crate Docs](https://reth.rs/docs)

[gh-ci]: https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/actions/workflows/unit.yml
[gh-lint]: https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/actions/workflows/lint.yml
[tg-badge]: https://img.shields.io/endpoint?color=neon&amp;logo=telegram&amp;label=chat&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftg.sumanjay.workers.dev%2Fparadigm%5Freth

## What is Reth?

Reth (short for Rust Ethereum, [pronunciation](https://twitter.com/kelvinfichter/status/1597653609411268608)) is a new Ethereum full node implementation that is focused on being user-friendly, highly modular, as well as being fast and efficient. Reth is an Execution Layer (EL) and is compatible with all Ethereum Consensus Layer (CL) implementations that support the [Engine API](https://github.com/ethereum/execution-apis/tree/a0d03086564ab1838b462befbc083f873dcf0c0f/src/engine). It is originally built and driven forward by [Paradigm](https://paradigm.xyz/), and is licensed under the Apache and MIT licenses.

## Goals

As a full Ethereum node, Reth allows users to connect to the Ethereum network and interact with the Ethereum blockchain. This includes sending and receiving transactions/logs/traces, as well as accessing and interacting with smart contracts. Building a successful Ethereum node requires creating a high-quality implementation that is both secure and efficient, as well as being easy to use on consumer hardware. It also requires building a strong community of contributors who can help support and improve the software.

More concretely, our goals are:

1. **Modularity**: Every component of Reth is built to be used as a library: well-tested, heavily documented and benchmarked. We envision that developers will import the node&#039;s crates, mix and match, and innovate on top of them. Examples of such usage include but are not limited to spinning up standalone P2P networks, talking directly to a node&#039;s database, or &quot;unbundling&quot; the node into the components you need. To achieve that, we are licensing Reth under the Apache/MIT permissive license. You can learn more about the project&#039;s components [here](./docs/repo/layout.md).
2. **Performance**: Reth aims to be fast, so we used Rust and the [Erigon staged-sync](https://erigon.substack.com/p/erigon-stage-sync-and-control-flows) node architecture. We also use our Ethereum libraries (including [Alloy](https://github.com/alloy-rs/alloy/) and [revm](https://github.com/bluealloy/revm/)) which we’ve battle-tested and optimized via [Foundry](https://github.com/foundry-rs/foundry/).
3. **Free for anyone to use any way they want**: Reth is free open source software, built for the community, by the community. By licensing the software under the Apache/MIT license, we want developers to use it without being bound by business licenses, or having to think about the implications of GPL-like licenses.
4. **Client Diversity**: The Ethereum protocol becomes more antifragile when no node implementation dominates. This ensures that if there&#039;s a software bug, the network does not finalize a bad block. By building a new client, we hope to contribute to Ethereum&#039;s antifragility.
5. **Support as many EVM chains as possible**: We aspire that Reth can full-sync not only Ethereum, but also other chains like Optimism, Polygon, BNB Smart Chain, and more. If you&#039;re working on any of these projects, please reach out.
6. **Configurability**: We want to solve for node operators that care about fast historical queries, but also for hobbyists who cannot operate on large hardware. We also want to support teams and individuals who want both sync from genesis and via &quot;fast sync&quot;. We envision that Reth will be configurable enough and provide configurable &quot;profiles&quot; for the tradeoffs that each team faces.

## Status

Reth is production ready, and suitable for usage in mission-critical environments such as staking or high-uptime services. We also actively recommend professional node operators to switch to Reth in production for performance and cost reasons in use cases where high performance with great margins is required such as RPC, MEV, Indexing, Simulations, and P2P activities.

More historical context below:
* We released 1.0 &quot;production-ready&quot; stable Reth in June 2024.
    * Reth completed an audit with [Sigma Prime](https://sigmaprime.io/), the developers of [Lighthouse](https://github.com/sigp/lighthouse), the Rust Consensus Layer implementation. Find it [here](./audit/sigma_prime_audit_v2.pdf).
    * Revm (the EVM used in Reth) underwent an audit with [Guido Vranken](https://twitter.com/guidovranken) (#1 [Ethereum Bug Bounty](https://ethereum.org/en/bug-bounty)). We will publish the results soon.
* We released multiple iterative beta versions, up to [beta.9](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/releases/tag/v0.2.0-beta.9) on Monday June 3rd 2024 the last beta release.
* We released [beta](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/releases/tag/v0.2.0-beta.1) on Monday March 4th 2024, our first breaking change to the database model, providing faster query speed, smaller database footprint, and allowing &quot;history&quot; to be mounted on separate drives.
* We shipped iterative improvements until the last alpha release on February 28th 2024, [0.1.0-alpha.21](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/releases/tag/v0.1.0-alpha.21).
* We [initially announced](https://www.paradigm.xyz/2023/06/reth-alpha) [0.1.0-alpha.1](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/releases/tag/v0.1.0-alpha.1) in June 20th 2023.

### Database compatibility

We do not have any breaking database changes since beta.1, and do not plan any in the near future.

Reth [v0.2.0-beta.1](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/releases/tag/v0.2.0-beta.1) includes
a [set of breaking database changes](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/pull/5191) that makes it impossible to use database files produced by earlier versions.

If you had a database produced by alpha versions of Reth, you need to drop it with `reth db drop`
(using the same arguments such as `--config` or `--datadir` that you passed to `reth node`), and resync using the same `reth node` command you&#039;ve used before.

## For Users

See the [Reth Book](https://paradigmxyz.github.io/reth) for instructions on how to install and run Reth.

## For Developers

### Using reth as a library

You can use individual crates of reth in your project.

The crate docs can be found [here](https://paradigmxyz.github.io/reth/docs).

For a general overview of the crates, see [Project Layout](./docs/repo/layout.md).

### Contributing

If you want to contribute, or follow along with contributor discussion, you can use our [main telegram](https://t.me/paradigm_reth) to chat with us about the development of Reth!

- Our contributor guidelines can be found in [`CONTRIBUTING.md`](./CONTRIBUTING.md).
- See our [contributor docs](./docs) for more information on the project. A good starting point is [Project Layout](./docs/repo/layout.md).

### Building and testing

&lt;!--
When updating this, also update:
- clippy.toml
- Cargo.toml
- .github/workflows/lint.yml
--&gt;

The Minimum Supported Rust Version (MSRV) of this project is [1.85.0](https://blog.rust-lang.org/2025/02/20/Rust-1.85.0.html).

See the book for detailed instructions on how to [build from source](https://paradigmxyz.github.io/reth/installation/source.html).

To fully test Reth, you will need to have [Geth installed](https://geth.ethereum.org/docs/getting-started/installing-geth), but it is possible to run a subset of tests without Geth.

First, clone the repository:

```sh
git clone https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth
cd reth
```

Next, run the tests:

```sh
# Without Geth
cargo test --workspace

# With Geth
cargo test --workspace --features geth-tests

# With Ethereum Foundation tests
#
# Note: Requires cloning https://github.com/ethereum/tests
#
#   cd testing/ef-tests &amp;&amp; git clone https://github.com/ethereum/tests ethereum-tests
cargo test -p ef-tests --features ef-tests
```

We recommend using [`cargo nextest`](https://nexte.st/) to speed up testing. With nextest installed, simply substitute `cargo test` with `cargo nextest run`.

&gt; **Note**
&gt;
&gt; Some tests use random number generators to generate test data. If you want to use a deterministic seed, you can set the `SEED` environment variable.

## Getting Help

If you have any questions, first see if the answer to your question can be found in the [book][book].

If the answer is not there:

- Join the [Telegram][tg-url] to get help, or
- Open a [discussion](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/discussions/new) with your question, or
- Open an issue with [the bug](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/issues/new?assignees=&amp;labels=C-bug%2CS-needs-triage&amp;projects=&amp;template=bug.yml)

## Security

See [`SECURITY.md`](./SECURITY.md).

## Acknowledgements

Reth is a new implementation of the Ethereum protocol. In the process of developing the node we investigated the design decisions other nodes have made to understand what is done well, what is not, and where we can improve the status quo.

None of this would have been possible without them, so big shoutout to the teams below:

- [Geth](https://github.com/ethereum/go-ethereum/): We would like to express our heartfelt gratitude to the go-ethereum team for their outstanding contributions to Ethereum over the years. Their tireless efforts and dedication have helped to shape the Ethereum ecosystem and make it the vibrant and innovative community it is today. Thank you for your hard work and commitment to the project.
- [Erigon](https://github.com/ledgerwatch/erigon) (fka Turbo-Geth): Erigon pioneered the [&quot;Staged Sync&quot; architecture](https://erigon.substack.com/p/erigon-stage-sync-and-control-flows) that Reth is using, as well as [introduced MDBX](https://github.com/ledgerwatch/erigon/wiki/Choice-of-storage-engine) as the database of choice. We thank Erigon for pushing the state of the art research on the performance limits of Ethereum nodes.
- [Akula](https://github.com/akula-bft/akula/): Reth uses forks of the Apache versions of Akula&#039;s [MDBX Bindings](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/pull/132), [FastRLP](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/pull/63) and [ECIES](https://github.com/paradigmxyz/reth/pull/80) . Given that these packages were already released under the Apache License, and they implement standardized solutions, we decided not to reimplement them to iterate faster. We thank the Akula team for their contributions to the Rust Ethereum ecosystem and for publishing these packages.

## Warning

The `NippyJar` and `Compact` encoding formats and their implementations are designed for storing and retrieving data internally. They are not hardened to safely read potentially malicious data.

[book]: https://paradigmxyz.github.io/reth/
[tg-url]: https://t.me/paradigm_reth
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[wezterm/wezterm]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by @wez and implemented in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm">wezterm/wezterm</a></h1>
            <p>A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by @wez and implemented in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 19,768</p>
            <p>Forks: 875</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Wez&#039;s Terminal

&lt;img height=&quot;128&quot; alt=&quot;WezTerm Icon&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wezterm/wezterm/main/assets/icon/wezterm-icon.svg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt; *A GPU-accelerated cross-platform terminal emulator and multiplexer written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wez&quot;&gt;@wez&lt;/a&gt; and implemented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;*

User facing docs and guide at: https://wezterm.org/

![Screenshot](docs/screenshots/two.png)

*Screenshot of wezterm on macOS, running vim*

## Installation

https://wezterm.org/installation

## Getting help

This is a spare time project, so please bear with me.  There are a couple of channels for support:

* You can use the [GitHub issue tracker](https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm/issues) to see if someone else has a similar issue, or to file a new one.
* Start or join a thread in our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/wezterm/wezterm/discussions); if you have general
  questions or want to chat with other wezterm users, you&#039;re welcome here!
* There is a [Matrix room via Element.io](https://app.element.io/#/room/#wezterm:matrix.org)
  for (potentially!) real time discussions.

The GitHub Discussions and Element/Gitter rooms are better suited for questions
than bug reports, but don&#039;t be afraid to use whichever you are most comfortable
using and we&#039;ll work it out.

## Supporting the Project

If you use and like WezTerm, please consider sponsoring it: your support helps
to cover the fees required to maintain the project and to validate the time
spent working on it!

[Read more about sponsoring](https://wezterm.org/sponsor.html).

* [![Sponsor WezTerm](https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/wez?label=Sponsor%20WezTerm&amp;logo=github&amp;style=for-the-badge)](https://github.com/sponsors/wez)
* [Patreon](https://patreon.com/WezFurlong)
* [Ko-Fi](https://ko-fi.com/wezfurlong)
* [Liberapay](https://liberapay.com/wez)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[openobserve/openobserve]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🚀 10x easier, 🚀 140x lower storage cost, 🚀 high performance, 🚀 petabyte scale - Elasticsearch/Splunk/Datadog alternative for 🚀 (logs, metrics, traces, RUM, Error tracking, Session replay).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve">openobserve/openobserve</a></h1>
            <p>🚀 10x easier, 🚀 140x lower storage cost, 🚀 high performance, 🚀 petabyte scale - Elasticsearch/Splunk/Datadog alternative for 🚀 (logs, metrics, traces, RUM, Error tracking, Session replay).</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,797</p>
            <p>Forks: 549</p>
            <p>Stars today: 5 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://openobserve.ai&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://openobserve.ai/img/logo/logo_horizontal.svg&quot; alt=&quot;OpenObserve&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;🚀 10x easier, 🚀 140x lower storage cost, 🚀 high performance, 🚀 petabyte scale - Elasticsearch/Splunk/Datadog alternative for 🚀 (logs, metrics, traces).&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/openobserve/openobserve&quot; alt=&quot;Last Commit&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve/stargazers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/openobserve/openobserve&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Stars&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve/issues&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/openobserve/openobserve&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Issues&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve/graphs/contributors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/openobserve/openobserve&quot; alt=&quot;Contributors&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve/releases&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/openobserve/openobserve&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Release&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

OpenObserve (O2 for short) is a cloud-native observability platform built specifically for logs, metrics, traces, analytics, RUM (Real User Monitoring - Performance, Errors, Session Replay) designed to work at petabyte scale.

It is straightforward and easy to operate, in contrast to Elasticsearch, which requires understanding and tuning numerous settings. Get OpenObserve up and running in under 2 minutes.

OpenObserve serves as a seamless replacement for Elasticsearch for users who ingest data using APIs and perform searches. OpenObserve comes with its own user interface, eliminating the need for separate installation.

You can reduce your log storage costs by ~140x compared to Elasticsearch by using OpenObserve. Below, we present the results from pushing logs from our production Kubernetes cluster to both Elasticsearch and OpenObserve using Fluent Bit.

![OpenObserve Vs Elasticsearch](./screenshots/zo_vs_es.png)

## 🎥 Introduction Video

[![OpenObserve Introduction](./screenshots/o2_intro.webp)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3rHxOVgIY6A)

## 🌟 Features:

- **Logs, Metrics, Traces**: Comprehensive support for various data types.
- **OpenTelemetry Support**: Full compatibility with OTLP for logs, metrics, and traces.
- **Real User Monitoring (RUM)**: Includes performance tracking, error logging, and session replay.
- **Dashboards, Reports, Alerts**: Features over 18 different chart types for comprehensive data visualization for on-the-fly analysis and reporting along with alerting.
- **Pipelines**: Enrich, redact, reduce, normalize data on the fly. Stream processing for logs to metrics and more.
- **Advanced Embedded GUI**: Intuitive and user-friendly interface.
- **SQL and PromQL Support**: Query logs and traces with SQL, and metrics with SQL and PromQL.
- **Single Binary or HA Installation**: Install using a single binary for small deployments or in HA mode for large deployments.
- **Versatile Storage Options**: Supports local disk, S3, MinIO, GCS, Azure Blob Storage.
- **High Availability and Clustering**: Ensures reliable and scalable performance.
- **Dynamic Schema**: Adapts to your data structure seamlessly.
- **Built-in Authentication**: Secure and ready to use.
- **Ease of Operation**: Designed for simplicity and efficiency.
- **Seamless Upgrades**: Hassle-free updates.
- **Multilingual UI**: Supports 11 languages, including English, Spanish, German, French, Chinese, and more.

For a full list of features, check the [documentation](https://openobserve.ai/docs/#project-status-features-and-roadmap).

## ⚡️ Quick start

### 🐳 Docker:
```bash
docker run -d \
      --name openobserve \
      -v $PWD/data:/data \
      -p 5080:5080 \
      -e ZO_ROOT_USER_EMAIL=&quot;root@example.com&quot; \
      -e ZO_ROOT_USER_PASSWORD=&quot;Complexpass#123&quot; \
      public.ecr.aws/zinclabs/openobserve:latest
```

### 🐙 Docker Compose:
```yaml
services:
  openobserve:
    image: public.ecr.aws/zinclabs/openobserve:latest
    restart: unless-stopped
    environment:
      ZO_ROOT_USER_EMAIL: &quot;root@example.com&quot;
      ZO_ROOT_USER_PASSWORD: &quot;Complexpass#123&quot;
    ports:
      - &quot;5080:5080&quot;
    volumes:
      - data:/data
volumes:
  data:
```

For other ways to quickly install OpenObserve or use OpenObserve cloud, check [quickstart documentation](https://openobserve.ai/docs/quickstart).

For installing OpenObserve in HA mode, check [HA deployment documentation](https://openobserve.ai/docs/ha_deployment/).

&lt;!-- ## Enterprise Vs Open source Vs Cloud edition

OpenObserve is available in three different editions:


| Feature | Open Source (Self hosted) | Enterprise (Self hosted) | Cloud |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | 
| Logs | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Metrics | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Traces | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| RUM | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Alerts | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Dashboards | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Reports | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| VRL functions | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Pipelines | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| High Availability | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Multitenancy (Organizations) | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Dynamic schema and schema evolution | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Advanced multilingual GUI | ✅ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Single Sign On | ❌ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Role Based Access Control (RBAC) | ❌ | ✅ | ✅ |
| Federated search / Super cluster | ❌ | ✅ | ❌ |
| Query management | ❌ | ✅ | ❌ |
| Workload management (QoS) | ❌ | ✅ | ❌ |
| Audit trail | ❌ | ✅ | ❌ |
| Ability to influence roadmap | ❌ | ✅ | ✅ on enterprise plan |
| License | AGPL | Enterprise | Cloud |
| Support | Community | Enterprise | Cloud |
| Cost | Free | If self hosted, free for up to 200 GB/Day data ingested &lt;br&gt; Paid thereafter  | Free 200 GB/Month data ingested &lt;br&gt; Paid thereafter | --&gt;


## 📷 Screenshots

### Home

![Home](./screenshots/zo_home.png)

### Logs

![Logs](./screenshots/logs.png)

### Traces (OpenTelemetry)

Trace details page
![Traces using OpenTelemetry](./screenshots/traces.png)

Golden metrics based on traces
![Traces golden metrics](./screenshots/traces-overall.png)

### Visualizations and Dashboards

![Dashboard](./screenshots/dashboard.png)
![Dashboard](./screenshots/dashboard2.png)
![Create panel](./screenshots/create-panel.png)
![Map](./screenshots/map.png)

### Front end monitoring

Performance analytics
![Performance](./screenshots/performance.png)

Session replay
![Session replay](./screenshots/session-replay.png)

Error tracking
![Error tracking](./screenshots/error-tracking.png)


### Alerts

![Alerts](./screenshots/alerts.png)


### Streams

![Streams](./screenshots/streams.png)

### Ingestion

![Ingestion](./screenshots/ingestion1.png)

![Ingestion](./screenshots/ingestion2.webp)

### SBOM

Software Bill of Materials for OpenObserve

#### Rust

SBOM can be found [here](./openobserve.cdx.xml). You can analyze it using [dependency track](https://dependencytrack.org/).

In order to generate the SBOM, you can use the following commands:

Install cargo-cyclonedx:

````bash
cargo install cargo-cyclonedx
````

Generate the SBOM:
```bash
cargo-cyclonedx cyclonedx
```

#### JavaScript

SBOM can be found [here](./web/sbom.json ). You can analyze it using [dependency track](https://dependencytrack.org/).

In order to generate the SBOM, you can use the following commands:

Install cyclonedx-npm:

````bash
npm install --global @cyclonedx/cyclonedx-npm
````

Generate the SBOM:
```bash
cd web
cyclonedx-npm &gt; sbom.json         
```


## ⚖️ License

OpenObserve is licensed under the AGPL-3.0 license. For more details, see the [LICENSE](https://github.com/openobserve/openobserve/blob/main/LICENSE).

## 🌍 Community

### 🔗 Join OpenObserve community on Slack

[![Slack](./screenshots/slack.png)](https://short.openobserve.ai/community)

Easiest way to get support is to join the [Slack channel](https://short.openobserve.ai/community).

### 📱 Join OpenObserve community on WeChat

&lt;img src=&quot;./screenshots/wechat_qr.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[databendlabs/databend]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/databendlabs/databend</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/databendlabs/databend</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[𝗗𝗮𝘁𝗮, 𝗔𝗻𝗮𝗹𝘆𝘁𝗶𝗰𝘀 & 𝗔𝗜. Modern alternative to Snowflake. Cost-effective and simple for massive-scale analytics. https://databend.com]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/databendlabs/databend">databendlabs/databend</a></h1>
            <p>𝗗𝗮𝘁𝗮, 𝗔𝗻𝗮𝗹𝘆𝘁𝗶𝗰𝘀 & 𝗔𝗜. Modern alternative to Snowflake. Cost-effective and simple for massive-scale analytics. https://databend.com</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 8,297</p>
            <p>Forks: 771</p>
            <p>Stars today: 3 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Databend: The Next-Gen Cloud [Data+AI] Analytics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;The open-source, on-premise alternative to Snowflake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.databend.com/guides/cloud&quot;&gt;Databend Serverless Cloud (beta)&lt;/a&gt;  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.databend.com/&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://benchmark.clickhouse.com/&quot;&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/a&gt;  |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/issues/11868&quot;&gt;Roadmap (v1.3)&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.databend.com/join-slack&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/slack-databend-0abd59?logo=slack&quot; alt=&quot;slack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.databend.com/join-feishu&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/feishu-databend-0abd59&quot; alt=&quot;feishu&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/actions/workflows/release.yml&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/datafuselabs/databend/release.yml?branch=main&quot; alt=&quot;CI Status&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Platform-Linux%2C%20macOS%2C%20ARM-green.svg?style=flat&quot; alt=&quot;Linux Platform&quot; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://gurubase.io/g/databend&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Gurubase-Ask%20Databend%20Guru-006BFF&quot; alt=&quot;Gurubase&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/assets/172204/9997d8bc-6462-4dbd-90e3-527cf50a709c&quot; alt=&quot;databend&quot; /&gt;

## 🐋 Introduction

**Databend**, built in Rust, is an open-source cloud data warehouse that serves as a cost-effective [alternative to Snowflake](https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/issues/13059). With its focus on fast query execution and data ingestion, it&#039;s designed for complex analysis of the world&#039;s largest datasets.

**Production-Proven Scale:**
- 🤝 **Enterprise Adoption**: Trusted by over **50 organizations** processing more than **100 million queries daily**
- 🗄️ **Massive Scale**: Successfully managing over **800 petabytes** of analytical data

## ⚡ Performance

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[TPC-H Benchmark: Databend Cloud vs. Snowflake](https://docs.databend.com/guides/benchmark/tpch)

&lt;/div&gt;

![Databend vs. Snowflake](https://github.com/databendlabs/wizard/assets/172204/d796acf0-0a66-4b1d-8754-cd2cd1de04c7)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[Data Ingestion Benchmark: Databend Cloud vs. Snowflake](https://docs.databend.com/guides/benchmark/data-ingest)

&lt;/div&gt;

![Databend vs. Snowflake](https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/assets/172204/c61d7a40-f6fe-4fb9-83e8-06ea9599aeb4)


## 🚀 Why Databend

- **Full Control**: Deploy on **cloud** or **on-prem** to suit your needs.

- **Blazing-Fast Performance**: Built with **Rust** for high-speed query execution. 👉 [ClickBench](https://databend.com/blog/clickbench-databend-top)

- **Cost-Effective**: Scalable architecture that boosts **performance** and reduces **costs**. 👉 [TPC-H](https://docs.databend.com/guides/benchmark/tpch)

- **AI-Enhanced Analytics**: Leverage built-in **[AI Functions](https://docs.databend.com/guides/ai-functions/)** for smarter data insights.

- **Simplified ETL**: Direct **data ingestion** without the need for external ETL tools. 👉 [Data Loading](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/)

- **Real-Time Data Updates**: Keep your analytics **up-to-date** with real-time incremental data updates. 👉 [Stream](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/continuous-data-pipelines/stream)

- **Advanced Indexing**: Boost query performance with **[Virtual Column](https://docs.databend.com/guides/performance/virtual-column)**, **[Aggregating Index](https://docs.databend.com/guides/performance/aggregating-index)**, and **[Full-Text Index](https://docs.databend.com/guides/performance/fulltext-index)**.

- **ACID Compliance + Version Control**: Ensure reliable **transactions** with full ACID compliance and Git-like versioning.

- **Schema Flexibility**: Effortlessly handle **semi-structured data** with the flexible **[VARIANT](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-reference/data-types/variant)** data type.

- **Community-Driven Growth**: **Open-source** and continuously evolving with contributions from a global community.



## 📐 Architecture

![Databend Architecture](https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/assets/172204/68b1adc6-0ec1-41d4-9e1d-37b80ce0e5ef)

## 🚀 Try Databend

### 1. Databend Serverless Cloud

The fastest way to try Databend, [Databend Cloud](https://databend.com)

### 2. Install Databend from Docker

Prepare the image (once) from Docker Hub (this will download about 170 MB data):

```shell
docker pull datafuselabs/databend
```

To run Databend quickly:

```shell
docker run --net=host  datafuselabs/databend
```

## 🚀 Getting Started

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Connecting to Databend&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Connecting to Databend with BendSQL](https://docs.databend.com/guides/sql-clients/bendsql)
- [Connecting to Databend with JDBC](https://docs.databend.com/guides/sql-clients/jdbc)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Data Import and Export&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to load Parquet file into a table](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-semistructured/load-parquet)
- [How to export a table to Parquet file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/unload-data/unload-parquet)
- [How to load CSV file into a table](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-semistructured/load-csv)
- [How to export a table to CSV file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/unload-data/unload-csv)
- [How to load TSV file into a table](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-semistructured/load-tsv)
- [How to export a table to TSV file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/unload-data/unload-tsv)
- [How to load NDJSON file into a table](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-semistructured/load-ndjson)
- [How to export a table to NDJSON file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/unload-data/unload-ndjson)
- [How to load ORC file into a table](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-semistructured/load-orc)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Loading Data From Other Databases&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to Sync Full and Incremental MySQL Changes into Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-db/debezium)
- [How to Sync Full and Incremental PostgreSQL Changes into Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-db/flink-cdc)
- [How to Sync Full and Incremental Oracle Changes into Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/load-db/flink-cdc)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Querying Semi-structured Data&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to query directly on Parquet file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/transform/querying-parquet)
- [How to query directly on CSV file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/transform/querying-csv)
- [How to query directly on TSV file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/transform/querying-tsv)
- [How to query directly on NDJSON file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/transform/querying-ndjson)
- [How to query directly on ORC file](https://docs.databend.com/guides/load-data/transform/querying-orc)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Visualize Tools with Databend&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Deepnote](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/deepnote)
- [Grafana](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/grafana)
- [Jupyter Notebook](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/jupyter)
- [Metabase](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/metabase)
- [MindsDB](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/mindsdb)
- [Redash](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/redash)
- [Superset](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/superset)
- [Tableau](https://docs.databend.com/guides/visualize/tableau)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Managing Users&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to Create a User](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/user-create-user)
- [How to Grant Privileges to a User](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/grant#granting-privileges)
- [How to Revoke Privileges from a User](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/revoke#revoking-privileges)
- [How to Create a Role](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/user-create-role)
- [How to Grant Privileges to a Role](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/grant#granting-role)
- [How to Grant Role to a User](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/grant)
- [How to Revoke the Role of a User](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/user/revoke#revoking-role)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Managing Databases&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to Create a Database](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/database/ddl-create-database)
- [How to Drop a Database](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/database/ddl-drop-database)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Managing Tables&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to Create a Table](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/ddl-create-table)
- [How to Drop a Table](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/ddl-drop-table)
- [How to Rename a Table](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/ddl-rename-table)
- [How to Truncate a Table](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/ddl-truncate-table)
- [How to Flash Back a Table](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/flashback-table)
- [How to Add/Drop Table Column](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/table/alter-table-column)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Managing Data&lt;/summary&gt;

- [COPY-INTO](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-copy-into-table)
- [INSERT](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-insert)
- [DELETE](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-delete-from)
- [UPDATE](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-update)
- [REPLACE](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-replace)
- [MERGE-INTO](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/dml/dml-merge)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Managing Views&lt;/summary&gt;

- [How to Create a View](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/view/ddl-create-view)
- [How to Drop a View](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/view/ddl-drop-view)
- [How to Alter a View](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-commands/ddl/view/ddl-alter-view)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;AI Functions&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Generating SQL with AI](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-functions/ai-functions/ai-to-sql)
- [Creating Embedding Vectors](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-functions/ai-functions/ai-embedding-vector)
- [Computing Text Similarities](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-functions/ai-functions/ai-cosine-distance)
- [Text Completion with AI](https://docs.databend.com/sql/sql-functions/ai-functions/ai-text-completion)
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Data Management&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Data Lifecycle in Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/data-management/data-lifecycle)
- [Data Recovery in Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/data-management/data-recovery)
- [Data Protection in Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/data-management/data-protection)
- [Data Purge in Databend](https://docs.databend.com/guides/data-management/data-recycle)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Accessing Data Lake&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Apache Hive](https://docs.databend.com/guides/access-data-lake/hive)
- [Apache Iceberg](https://docs.databend.com/guides/access-data-lake/iceberg/)
- [Delta Lake](https://docs.databend.com/guides/access-data-lake/delta)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Security&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Access Control](https://docs.databend.com/guides/security/access-control)
- [Masking Policy](https://docs.databend.com/guides/security/masking-policy)
- [Network Policy](https://docs.databend.com/guides/security/network-policy)
- [Password Policy](https://docs.databend.com/guides/security/password-policy)

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Performance&lt;/summary&gt;

- [Review Clickbench](https://databend.com/blog/clickbench-databend-top)
- [TPC-H Benchmark: Databend Cloud vs. Snowflake](https://docs.databend.com/guides/benchmark/tpch)
- [Databend vs. Snowflake: Data Ingestion Benchmark](https://docs.databend.com/guides/benchmark/data-ingest)

&lt;/details&gt;

## 🤝 Contributing

Databend thrives on community contributions! Whether it&#039;s through ideas, code, or documentation, every effort helps in enhancing our project. As a token of our appreciation, once your code is merged, your name will be eternally preserved in the **system.contributors** table.

Here are some resources to help you get started:

- [Building Databend From Source](https://docs.databend.com/guides/community/contributor/building-from-source)
- [The First Good Pull Request](https://docs.databend.com/guides/community/contributor/good-pr)

## 👥 Community

For guidance on using Databend, we recommend starting with the official documentation. If you need further assistance, explore the following community channels:

- [Slack](https://link.databend.com/join-slack) (For live discussion with the Community)
- [GitHub](https://github.com/databendlabs/databend) (Feature/Bug reports, Contributions)
- [Twitter](https://twitter.com/DatabendLabs/) (Get the news fast)
- [I&#039;m feeling lucky](https://link.databend.com/i-m-feeling-lucky) (Pick up a good first issue now!)

## 🛣️ Roadmap

Stay updated with Databend&#039;s development journey. Here are our roadmap milestones:

- [Roadmap 2025](https://github.com/databendlabs/databend/issues/14167)

## 📜 License

Databend is released under a combination of two licenses: the [Apache License 2.0](licenses/Apache-2.0.txt) and the [Elastic License 2.0](licenses/Elastic.txt).

When contributing to Databend, you can find the relevant license header in each file.

For more information, see the [LICENSE](LICENSE) file and [Licensing FAQs](https://docs.databend.com/guides/products/dee/license).

## 🙏 Acknowledgement

- **Inspiration**: Databend&#039;s design draws inspiration from industry leaders [ClickHouse](https://github.com/clickhouse/clickhouse) and [Snowflake](https://docs.snowflake.com/en/user-guide/intro-key-concepts.html#snowflake-architecture).

- **Computing Model**: Our computing foundation is built upon apache arrow.

- **Documentation Hosting**: The [Databend documentation website](https://docs.databend.com) proudly runs on [Vercel](https://vercel.com/?utm_source=databend&amp;utm_campaign=oss).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MystenLabs/walrus]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/MystenLabs/walrus</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/MystenLabs/walrus</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A decentralized blob store using Sui for coordination and governance.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/MystenLabs/walrus">MystenLabs/walrus</a></h1>
            <p>A decentralized blob store using Sui for coordination and governance.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 80</p>
            <p>Forks: 19</p>
            <p>Stars today: 10 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Walrus

A decentralized blob store using [Sui](https://github.com/MystenLabs/sui) for coordination and
governance.

## Documentation

Our main documentation is available [as a Walrus Site](https://docs.wal.app) (see [the
documentation](https://docs.wal.app/walrus-sites/intro.html) for further information on what
this means) and on [GitHub Pages](https://mystenlabs.github.io/walrus); it is generated using
[mdBook](https://rust-lang.github.io/mdBook/) from source files in the [`docs/book`](./docs/book)
directory.

You can also build the documentation locally (assuming you have Rust installed):

```sh
cargo install mdbook mdbook-admonish mdbook-katex mdbook-linkcheck mdbook-tabs mdbook-templates --locked
mdbook serve
```

After this, you can browse the documentation at &lt;http://localhost:3000&gt;.

There are some additional documentation resources:

- Usage examples are available under [docs/examples](./docs/examples/).
- Our encoding system, which we call *Red Stuff*, is described in detail in
  [docs/red-stuff.md](docs/red-stuff.md).
- All our code is covered by Rust docs. You can build these and open them in your web browser by
  running the following:

  ```sh
  cargo doc --workspace --open # add `--no-deps` to prevent building docs of all dependencies
  ```

## Repository structure

This repository contains all Walrus-related code, tools, and documentation:

- [`contracts`](./contracts) contains all smart contracts used by Walrus for coordination and governance.
- [`crates`](./crates) contains all Rust crates related to Walrus including binaries for storage nodes
  and clients. See [below](#rust-crates) for further information about those.
- [`docker`](./docker) contains Dockerfiles and docker-compose setups for building and running Walrus.
- [`docs`](./docs) contains high-level technical and design documentation about Walrus.
- [`scripts`](./scripts) contains tools used for evaluating and testing the code. In particular, this
  contains a script to run a local testbed, see [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md#run-a-local-walrus-testbed).
- [`setup`](./setup) contains setup scripts and configuration files.
- [`testnet-contracts`](./testnet-contracts) contains the Walrus contracts deployed for Walrus
  Testnet. The object IDs of the published contracts are included in the `Move.lock` files.

### Rust crates

Our Rust code is split into several crates with different responsibilities. The main code for Walrus
is contained in the following crates:

&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable proper-names --&gt;
- [walrus-core](crates/walrus-core/) contains core types and functionality, including encoding and
  authentication mechanisms.
- [walrus-sdk](crates/walrus-sdk/) contains (client) interactions with storage nodes.
- [walrus-service](crates/walrus-service/) contains client and server functionality including the
  storage backend. This crate also contains all main binaries, in particular `walrus` and
  `walrus-node`.
- [walrus-sui](crates/walrus-sui/) contains all types and interactions with the Sui smart contracts.
- [walrus-utils](crates/walrus-utils/) contains utility functions used in multiple crates.

The following crates contain additional tools that are not part of the main functionality of Walrus
and more extensive tests:

- [checkpoint-downloader](crates/checkpoint-downloader/) contains code to download checkpoints from
  Sui RPC nodes and checkpoint buckets.
- [walrus-e2e-tests](crates/walrus-e2e-tests/) contains end-to-end tests, some of which are also
  run as simulation tests.
- [walrus-orchestrator](crates/walrus-orchestrator/) contains tools to deploy and benchmark
  distributed Walrus networks. This crate is not a default member of the workspace and therefore
  needs to be built explicitly by adding `-p walrus-orchestrator` or `--workspace` to the cargo
  commands.
- [walrus-proc-macros](crates/walrus-proc-macros/) contains procedural macros used in the other
  crates, notably to define simulation tests.
- [walrus-proxy](crates/walrus-proxy/) contains a metrics proxy that authenticates storage nodes and
  collects metrics from them. This crate is not a default member of the workspace and therefore
  needs to be built explicitly by adding `-p walrus-proxy` or `--workspace` to the cargo commands.
- [walrus-simtest](crates/walrus-simtest/) contains simulation tests to ensure that Walrus works
  correctly for all interleavings of concurrent operations and in the presence of crashes.
- [walrus-stress](crates/walrus-stress/) contains a stress client, which is used to put load on
  storage nodes.
- [walrus-test-utils](crates/walrus-test-utils/) contains test macros and other utilities used in
  the other crates.
&lt;!-- markdownlint-enable proper-names --&gt;

## Using the Walrus client

If you just want to use the Walrus Mainnet or Testnet, please follow the [setup instructions in our
documentation](https://docs.wal.app/usage/setup.html). Further information about the usage is
also available in the [public documentation](https://docs.wal.app/usage/interacting.html).

If you want to build the binary from source or run local tests, see the instructions
[below](#building-from-source-and-testing).

## Hardware requirements

- We assume that this code is executed on at least 32-bit hardware; concretely, we assume that a
  `u32` can be converted safely into a `usize`.
- Servers are assumed to use a 64-bit architecture (or higher); concretely, `usize` has at least 64
  bits.
- Our encoding relies on vector instructions to be efficient. Our default builds assume AVX2 and
  SSSE3 support on x86 CPUs and Neon support on ARM CPUs. Walrus binaries can be built for CPUs
  without these features, but will be much slower.
- When a client is executed on a 32-bit architecture, it may panic for blobs above a certain size.
  Given sufficient physical memory (4 GiB), it is generally possible to encode or decode blobs
  smaller than 500 MiB on 32-bit architectures.

## Building from source and testing

To build Walrus you need to install Rust as described in the [Rust
documentation](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install), and the correct Rust toolchain:

```sh
rustup update &amp;&amp; rustup toolchain install
```

Then, you can build Walrus using Cargo:

```sh
cargo build # add `--release` for optimized builds
```

You can directly run a local build of the `walrus` binary as `cargo run --bin walrus`. Arguments and
options can be specified after a `--`, for example `cargo run --bin walrus -- store README.md
--epochs 1`.

You can run our test suite by installing [nextest](https://nexte.st/), and then calling `cargo
nextest run`. See [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md#tests) for further details on our tests and
instructions on how to run a local Walrus testbed.

## Contributing

If you observe a bug or want to request a feature, please search for an existing
[issue](https://github.com/MystenLabs/walrus/issues) on this topic and, if none exists, create a new
one. If you would like to contribute code directly (which we highly appreciate), please familiarize
yourself with our [contributing workflow](./CONTRIBUTING.md).

## License

This project is licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 ([LICENSE](LICENSE) or
&lt;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&gt;).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[servo/servo]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/servo/servo</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/servo/servo</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Servo aims to empower developers with a lightweight, high-performance alternative for embedding web technologies in applications.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/servo/servo">servo/servo</a></h1>
            <p>Servo aims to empower developers with a lightweight, high-performance alternative for embedding web technologies in applications.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 29,948</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,138</p>
            <p>Stars today: 18 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># The Servo Parallel Browser Engine Project

Servo is a prototype web browser engine written in the
[Rust](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust) language. It is currently developed on
64-bit macOS, 64-bit Linux, 64-bit Windows, 64-bit OpenHarmony, and Android.

Servo welcomes contribution from everyone. Check out [The Servo Book](https://book.servo.org) to get started, or go to [servo.org](https://servo.org/) for news and guides.

## Getting started

For more detailed build instructions, see the Servo book under [Setting up your environment], [Building Servo], [Building for Android] and [Building for OpenHarmony].

[Setting up your environment]: https://book.servo.org/hacking/setting-up-your-environment.html
[Building Servo]: https://book.servo.org/hacking/building-servo.html
[Building for Android]: https://book.servo.org/hacking/building-for-android.html
[Building for OpenHarmony]: https://book.servo.org/hacking/building-for-openharmony.html

### macOS

- Download and install [Xcode](https://developer.apple.com/xcode/) and [`brew`](https://brew.sh/).
- Install `uv`: `curl -LsSf https://astral.sh/uv/install.sh | sh` 
- Install `rustup`: `curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh`
- Restart your shell to make sure `cargo` is available
- Install the other dependencies: `./mach bootstrap`
- Build servoshell: `./mach build`

### Linux

- Install `curl`:
  - Arch: `sudo pacman -S --needed curl`
  - Debian, Ubuntu: `sudo apt install curl`
  - Fedora: `sudo dnf install curl`
  - Gentoo: `sudo emerge net-misc/curl`
- Install `uv`: `curl -LsSf https://astral.sh/uv/install.sh | sh` 
- Install `rustup`: `curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh`
- Restart your shell to make sure `cargo` is available
- Install the other dependencies: `./mach bootstrap`
- Build servoshell: `./mach build`

### Windows

- Download [`uv`](https://docs.astral.sh/uv/getting-started/installation/#standalone-installer), [`choco`](https://chocolatey.org/install#individual), and [`rustup`](https://win.rustup.rs/)
  - Be sure to select *Quick install via the Visual Studio Community installer*
- In the Visual Studio Installer, ensure the following components are installed:
  - **Windows 10 SDK (10.0.19041.0)** (`Microsoft.VisualStudio.Component.Windows10SDK.19041`)
  - **MSVC v143 - VS 2022 C++ x64/x86 build tools (Latest)** (`Microsoft.VisualStudio.Component.VC.Tools.x86.x64`)
  - **C++ ATL for latest v143 build tools (x86 &amp; x64)** (`Microsoft.VisualStudio.Component.VC.ATL`)
  - **C++ MFC for latest v143 build tools (x86 &amp; x64)** (`Microsoft.VisualStudio.Component.VC.ATLMFC`)
- Restart your shell to make sure `cargo` is available
- Install the other dependencies: `.\mach bootstrap`
- Build servoshell: `.\mach build`

### Android

- Ensure that the following environment variables are set:
  - `ANDROID_SDK_ROOT`
  - `ANDROID_NDK_ROOT`: `$ANDROID_SDK_ROOT/ndk/26.2.11394342/`
 `ANDROID_SDK_ROOT` can be any directory (such as `~/android-sdk`).
  All of the Android build dependencies will be installed there.
- Install the latest version of the [Android command-line
  tools](https://developer.android.com/studio#command-tools) to
  `$ANDROID_SDK_ROOT/cmdline-tools/latest`.
- Run the following command to install the necessary components:
  ```shell
  sudo $ANDROID_SDK_ROOT/cmdline-tools/latest/bin/sdkmanager --install \
   &quot;build-tools;34.0.0&quot; \
   &quot;emulator&quot; \
   &quot;ndk;26.2.11394342&quot; \
   &quot;platform-tools&quot; \
   &quot;platforms;android-33&quot; \
   &quot;system-images;android-33;google_apis;x86_64&quot;
  ```
- Follow the instructions above for the platform you are building on

### OpenHarmony

- Follow the instructions above for the platform you are building on to prepare the environment.
- Depending on the target distribution (e.g. `HarmonyOS NEXT` vs pure `OpenHarmony`) the build configuration will differ slightly.
- Ensure that the following environment variables are set
  - `DEVECO_SDK_HOME` (Required when targeting `HarmonyOS NEXT`)
  - `OHOS_BASE_SDK_HOME` (Required when targeting `OpenHarmony`)
  - `OHOS_SDK_NATIVE` (e.g. `${DEVECO_SDK_HOME}/default/openharmony/native` or `${OHOS_BASE_SDK_HOME}/${API_VERSION}/native`)
  - `SERVO_OHOS_SIGNING_CONFIG`: Path to json file containing a valid signing configuration for the demo app.
- Review the detailed instructions at [Building for OpenHarmony].
- The target distribution can be modified by passing `--flavor=&lt;default|harmonyos&gt;` to `mach &lt;build|package|install&gt;.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[tree-sitter/tree-sitter]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/tree-sitter/tree-sitter</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/tree-sitter/tree-sitter</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An incremental parsing system for programming tools]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/tree-sitter/tree-sitter">tree-sitter/tree-sitter</a></h1>
            <p>An incremental parsing system for programming tools</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,062</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,720</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># tree-sitter

[![DOI](https://zenodo.org/badge/14164618.svg)](https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/14164618)
[![discord][discord]](https://discord.gg/w7nTvsVJhm)
[![matrix][matrix]](https://matrix.to/#/#tree-sitter-chat:matrix.org)

Tree-sitter is a parser generator tool and an incremental parsing library. It can build a concrete syntax tree for a source file and efficiently update the syntax tree as the source file is edited. Tree-sitter aims to be:

- **General** enough to parse any programming language
- **Fast** enough to parse on every keystroke in a text editor
- **Robust** enough to provide useful results even in the presence of syntax errors
- **Dependency-free** so that the runtime library (which is written in pure C) can be embedded in any application

## Links
- [Documentation](https://tree-sitter.github.io)
- [Rust binding](lib/binding_rust/README.md)
- [WASM binding](lib/binding_web/README.md)
- [Command-line interface](cli/README.md)

[discord]: https://img.shields.io/discord/1063097320771698699?logo=discord&amp;label=discord
[matrix]: https://img.shields.io/matrix/tree-sitter-chat%3Amatrix.org?logo=matrix&amp;label=matrix
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LGUG2Z/komorebi]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A tiling window manager for Windows 🍉]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi">LGUG2Z/komorebi</a></h1>
            <p>A tiling window manager for Windows 🍉</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,696</p>
            <p>Forks: 223</p>
            <p>Stars today: 19 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># komorebi

Tiling Window Management for Windows.

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://techforpalestine.org/learn-more&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Tech for Palestine&quot; src=&quot;https://badge.techforpalestine.org/default&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Workflow Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/LGUG2Z/komorebi/.github/workflows/windows.yaml&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub all releases&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/LGUG2Z/komorebi/total&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub commits since latest release (by date) for a branch&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commits-since/LGUG2Z/komorebi/latest&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Active Individual Commercial Use Licenses&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/dynamic/json?url=https%3A%2F%2Flgug2z-ecstaticmagentacheetah.web.val.run&amp;query=%24.&amp;label=active%20individual%20commercial%20use%20licenses&amp;cacheSeconds=3600&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Flgug2z.com%2Fsoftware%2Fkomorebi&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/mGkn66PHkx&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/898554690126630914&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/LGUG2Z&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Sponsors&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/LGUG2Z&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://ko-fi.com/lgug2z&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Ko-fi&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/kofi-tip-green&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notado.app/feeds/jado/software-development&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Notado Feed&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Notado-Subscribe-informational&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCeai3-do-9O4MNy9_xjO6mg?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;YouTube&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/youtube/channel/subscribers/UCeai3-do-9O4MNy9_xjO6mg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

![screenshot](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13164844/184027064-f5a6cec2-2865-4d65-a549-a1f1da589abf.png)

## Overview

_komorebi_ is a tiling window manager that works as an extension to Microsoft&#039;s
[Desktop Window
Manager](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/dwm/dwm-overview) in
Windows 10 and above.

_komorebi_ allows you to control application windows, virtual workspaces and display monitors with a CLI which can be
used with third-party software such as [`whkd`](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/whkd)
and [AutoHotKey](https://github.com/Lexikos/AutoHotkey_L) to set user-defined keyboard shortcuts.

_komorebi_ aims to make _as few modifications as possible_ to the operating
system and desktop environment by default. Users are free to make such
modifications in their own configuration files for _komorebi_, but these will
remain opt-in and off-by-default for the foreseeable future.

Please refer to the [documentation](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi) for instructions on how
to [install](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi/installation.html) and
[configure](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi/example-configurations.html)
_komorebi_, [common workflows](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi/common-workflows/komorebi-config-home.html), a complete
[configuration schema reference](https://komorebi.lgug2z.com/schema) and a
complete [CLI reference](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi/cli/quickstart.html).

## Community

There is a [Discord server](https://discord.gg/mGkn66PHkx) available for
_komorebi_-related discussion, help, troubleshooting etc. If you have any
specific feature requests or bugs to report, please create an issue in this
repository.

There is a [YouTube
channel](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCeai3-do-9O4MNy9_xjO6mg) where I post
_komorebi_ development videos, feature previews and release overviews. Subscribing
to the channel (which is monetized as part of the YouTube Partner Program) and
watching videos is a really simple and passive way to contribute financially to
the development and maintenance of _komorebi_.

There is an [Awesome List](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/awesome-komorebi) which
showcases the many awesome projects that exist in the _komorebi_ ecosystem.

## Licensing for Personal Use

`komorebi` is [educational source
software](https://lgug2z.com/articles/educational-source-software/).

`komorebi` is licensed under the [Komorebi 1.0.0
license](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi-license), which is a fork of the
[PolyForm Strict 1.0.0
license](https://polyformproject.org/licenses/strict/1.0.0). On a high level
this means that you are free to do whatever you want with `komorebi` for
personal use other than redistribution, or distribution of new works (i.e.
hard-forks) based on the software.

Anyone is free to make their own fork of `komorebi` with changes intended either
for personal use or for integration back upstream via pull requests.

The [Komorebi 1.0.0 License](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi-license) does
not permit any kind of commercial use (i.e. using `komorebi` at work).

## Sponsorship for Personal Use

_komorebi_ is a free and educational source project, and one that encourages you
to make charitable donations if you find the software to be useful and have the
financial means.

I encourage you to make a charitable donation to the [Palestine Children&#039;s
Relief Fund](https://pcrf1.app.neoncrm.com/forms/gaza-recovery) or to contribute
to a [Gaza Funds campaign](https://gazafunds.com) before you consider sponsoring
me on GitHub.

[GitHub Sponsors is enabled for this
project](https://github.com/sponsors/LGUG2Z). Sponsors can claim custom roles on
the Discord server, get shout outs at the end of _komorebi_-related videos on
YouTube, gain the ability to submit feature requests on the issue tracker, and
receive releases of komorebi with &quot;easter eggs&quot; on physical media.

If you would like to tip or sponsor the project but are unable to use GitHub
Sponsors, you may also sponsor through [Ko-fi](https://ko-fi.com/lgug2z), or
make an anonymous Bitcoin donation to `bc1qv73wzspc77k46uty4vp85x8sdp24mphvm58f6q`.

## Licensing for Commercial Use

A dedicated Individual Commercial Use License is available for those who want to
use `komorebi` at work.

The Individual Commerical Use License adds “Commercial Use” as a “Permitted Use”
for the licensed individual only, for the duration of a valid paid license
subscription only. All provisions and restrictions enumerated in the [Komorebi
License](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi-license) continue to apply.

More information, pricing and purchase links for Individual Commercial Use
Licenses [can be found here](https://lgug2z.com/software/komorebi).

# Installation

A [detailed installation and quickstart
guide](https://lgug2z.github.io/komorebi/installation.html) is available which shows how to get started
using `scoop`, `winget` or building from source.

[![Watch the quickstart walkthrough video](https://img.youtube.com/vi/MMZUAtHbTYY/hqdefault.jpg)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MMZUAtHbTYY)

# Comparison With Fancy Zones

Community member [Olge](https://www.youtube.com/@polle5555) has created an
excellent video which compares the default window management features of
Windows 11, Fancy Zones and komorebi.

If you are not familiar with tiling window managers or if you are looking at
komorebi and wondering &quot;how is this different from Fancy Zones? 🤔&quot;, this short
video will answer the majority of your questions.

[![Watch the comparison video](https://img.youtube.com/vi/0LCbS_gm0RA/hqdefault.jpg)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0LCbS_gm0RA)

# Demonstrations

[@amnweb](https://github.com/amnweb) showing _komorebi_ `v0.1.28` running on Windows 11 with window borders,
unfocused window transparency and animations enabled, using a custom status bar integrated using
_komorebi_&#039;s [Window Manager Event Subscriptions](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi?tab=readme-ov-file#window-manager-event-subscriptions).

https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi/assets/13164844/21be8dc4-fa76-4f70-9b37-1d316f4b40c2

[@haxibami](https://github.com/haxibami) showing _komorebi_ running on Windows
11 with a terminal emulator, a web browser and a code editor. The original
video can be viewed
[here](https://twitter.com/haxibami/status/1501560766578659332).

https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13164844/163496447-20c3ff0a-c5d8-40d1-9cc8-156c4cebf12e.mp4

[@aik2mlj](https://github.com/aik2mlj) showing _komorebi_ running on Windows 11
with multiple workspaces, terminal emulators, a web browser, and the
[yasb](https://github.com/DenBot/yasb) status bar with the _komorebi_ workspace
widget enabled. The original video can be viewed
[here](https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/455064481).

https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13164844/163496414-a9cde3d1-b8a7-4a7a-96fb-a8985380bc70.mp4

# Contribution Guidelines

If you would like to contribute to `komorebi` please take the time to carefully
read the guidelines below.

Please see [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) for more information about how
code contributions to `komorebi` are licensed.

## Commit hygiene

- Flatten all `use` statements
- Run `cargo +stable clippy` and ensure that all lints and suggestions have been addressed before committing
- Run `cargo +nightly fmt --all` to ensure consistent formatting before committing
- Use `git cz` with
  the [Commitizen CLI](https://github.com/commitizen/cz-cli#conventional-commit-messages-as-a-global-utility) to prepare
  commit messages
- Provide **at least** one short sentence or paragraph in your commit message body to describe your thought process for
  the changes being committed

## PRs should contain only a single feature or bug fix

It is very difficult to review pull requests which touch multiple unrelated features and parts of the codebase.

Please do not submit pull requests like this; you will be asked to separate them into smaller PRs that deal only with
one feature or bug fix at a time.

If you are working on multiple features and bug fixes, I suggest that you cut a branch called `local-trunk`
from `master` which you keep up to date, and rebase the various independent branches you are working on onto that branch
if you want to test them together or create a build with everything integrated.

## Refactors to the codebase must have prior approval

`komorebi` is a mature codebase with an internal consistency and structure that has developed organically over close to
half a decade.

There are [countless hours of live coding videos](https://youtube.com/@LGUG2Z) demonstrating work on this project and
showing new contributors how to do everything from basic tasks like implementing new `komorebic` commands to
distinguishing monitors by manufacturer hardware identifiers and video card ports.

Refactors to the structure of the codebase are not taken lightly and require prior discussion and approval.

Please do not start refactoring the codebase with the expectation of having your changes integrated until you receive an
explicit approval or a request to do so.

Similarly, when implementing features and bug fixes, please stick to the structure of the codebase as much as possible
and do not take this as an opportunity to do some &quot;refactoring along the way&quot;.

It is extremely difficult to review PRs for features and bug fixes if they are lost in sweeping changes to the structure
of the codebase.

## Breaking changes to user-facing interfaces are unacceptable

This includes but is not limited to:

- All `komorebic` commands
- The `komorebi.json` schema
- The [
  `komorebi-application-specific-configuration`](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi-application-specific-configuration)
  schema

No user should ever find that their configuration file has stopped working after upgrading to a new version
of `komorebi`.

More often than not there are ways to reformulate changes that may initially seem like they require breaking user-facing
interfaces into additive changes.

For some inspiration please take a look
at [this commit](https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi/commit/e7d928a065eb63bb4ea1fb864c69c1cae8cc763b) which added the
ability for users to specify colours in `komorebi.json` in Hex format alongside RGB.

There is also a process in place for graceful, non-breaking, deprecation of configuration options that are no longer
required.

# Development

If you use IntelliJ, you should enable the following settings to ensure that code generated by macros is recognised by
the IDE for completions and navigation:

- Set `Expand declarative macros`
  to `Use new engine` under &quot;Settings &gt; Langauges &amp; Frameworks &gt; Rust&quot;
- Enable the following experimental features:
    - `org.rust.cargo.evaluate.build.scripts`
    - `org.rust.macros.proc`

# Logs and Debugging

Logs from `komorebi` will be appended to `%LOCALAPPDATA%/komorebi/komorebi.log`; this file is never rotated or
overwritten, so it will keep growing until it is deleted by the user.

Whenever running the `komorebic stop` command or sending a Ctrl-C signal to `komorebi` directly, the `komorebi` process
ensures that all hidden windows are restored before termination.

If however, you ever end up with windows that are hidden and cannot be restored, a list of window handles known
to `komorebi` are stored and continuously updated in `%LOCALAPPDATA%/komorebi//komorebi.hwnd.json`.

## Restoring Windows

Running `komorebic restore-windows` will read the list of window handles and forcibly restore them, regardless of
whether the main `komorebi` process is running.

## Panics and Deadlocks

If `komorebi` ever stops responding, it is most likely either due to either a panic or a deadlock. In the case of a
panic, this will be reported in the log. In the case of a deadlock, there will not be any errors in the log, but the
process and the log will appear frozen.

If you believe you have encountered a deadlock, you can compile `komorebi` with `--features deadlock_detection` and try
reproducing the deadlock again. This will check for deadlocks every 5 seconds in the background, and if a deadlock is
found, information about it will appear in the log which can be shared when opening an issue.

# Window Manager State and Integrations

The current state of the window manager can be queried using the `komorebic state` command, which returns a JSON
representation of the `State` struct.

This may also be polled to build further integrations and widgets on top of.

# Window Manager Event Subscriptions

## Named Pipes

It is possible to subscribe to notifications of every `WindowManagerEvent` and `SocketMessage` handled
by `komorebi` using [Named Pipes](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/ipc/named-pipes).

First, your application must create a named pipe. Once the named pipe has been created, run the following command:

```powershell
komorebic.exe subscribe-pipe &lt;your pipe name&gt;
```

Note that you do not have to include the full path of the named pipe, just the name.

If the named pipe exists, `komorebi` will start pushing JSON data of successfully handled events and messages:

```json lines
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;AddSubscriber&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:&quot;yasb&quot;},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusWindow&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:&quot;Left&quot;},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusChange&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:[&quot;SystemForeground&quot;,{&quot;hwnd&quot;:131444,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;komorebi – README.md&quot;,&quot;exe&quot;:&quot;idea64.exe&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:&quot;SunAwtFrame&quot;,&quot;rect&quot;:{&quot;left&quot;:13,&quot;top&quot;:60,&quot;right&quot;:1520,&quot;bottom&quot;:1655}}]},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;MonitorPoll&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:[&quot;ObjectCreate&quot;,{&quot;hwnd&quot;:5572450,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;OLEChannelWnd&quot;,&quot;exe&quot;:&quot;explorer.exe&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:&quot;OleMainThreadWndClass&quot;,&quot;rect&quot;:{&quot;left&quot;:0,&quot;top&quot;:0,&quot;right&quot;:0,&quot;bottom&quot;:0}}]},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusWindow&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:&quot;Right&quot;},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusChange&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:[&quot;SystemForeground&quot;,{&quot;hwnd&quot;:132968,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Windows PowerShell&quot;,&quot;exe&quot;:&quot;WindowsTerminal.exe&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:&quot;CASCADIA_HOSTING_WINDOW_CLASS&quot;,&quot;rect&quot;:{&quot;left&quot;:1539,&quot;top&quot;:60,&quot;right&quot;:1520,&quot;bottom&quot;:821}}]},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusWindow&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:&quot;Down&quot;},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusChange&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:[&quot;SystemForeground&quot;,{&quot;hwnd&quot;:329264,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;den — Mozilla Firefox&quot;,&quot;exe&quot;:&quot;firefox.exe&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:&quot;MozillaWindowClass&quot;,&quot;rect&quot;:{&quot;left&quot;:1539,&quot;top&quot;:894,&quot;right&quot;:1520,&quot;bottom&quot;:821}}]},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusWindow&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:&quot;Up&quot;},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
{&quot;event&quot;:{&quot;type&quot;:&quot;FocusChange&quot;,&quot;content&quot;:[&quot;SystemForeground&quot;,{&quot;hwnd&quot;:132968,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Windows PowerShell&quot;,&quot;exe&quot;:&quot;WindowsTerminal.exe&quot;,&quot;class&quot;:&quot;CASCADIA_HOSTING_WINDOW_CLASS&quot;,&quot;rect&quot;:{&quot;left&quot;:1539,&quot;top&quot;:60,&quot;right&quot;:1520,&quot;bottom&quot;:821}}]},&quot;state&quot;:{}}
```

You may then filter on the `type` key to listen to the events that you are interested in. For a full list of possible
notification types, refer to the enum variants of `WindowManagerEvent` in `komorebi` and `SocketMessage`
in `komorebi::core`.

Below is an example of how you can subscribe to and filter on events using a named pipe in `nodejs`.

```javascript
const { exec } = require(&quot;child_process&quot;);
const net = require(&quot;net&quot;);

const pipeName = &quot;\\\\.\\pipe\\komorebi-js&quot;;
const server = net.createServer((stream) =&gt; {
  console.log(&quot;Client connected&quot;);

  // Every time there is a workspace-related event, let&#039;s log the names of all
  // workspaces on the currently focused monitor, and then log the name of the
  // currently focused workspace on that monitor

  stream.on(&quot;data&quot;, (data) =&gt; {
    let json = JSON.parse(data.toString());
    let event = json.event;

    if (event.type.includes(&quot;Workspace&quot;)) {
      let monitors = json.state.monitors;
      let current_monitor = monitors.elements[monitors.focused];
      let workspaces = monitors.elements[monitors.focused].workspaces;
      let current_workspace = workspaces.elements[workspaces.focused];

      console.log(
        workspaces.elements
          .map((workspace) =&gt; workspace.name)
          .filter((name) =&gt; name !== null)
      );
      console.log(current_workspace.name);
    }
  });

  stream.on(&quot;end&quot;, () =&gt; {
    console.log(&quot;Client disconnected&quot;);
  });
});

server.listen(pipeName, () =&gt; {
  console.log(&quot;Named pipe server listening&quot;);
});

const command = &quot;komorebic subscribe-pipe komorebi-js&quot;;

exec(command, (error, stdout, stderr) =&gt; {
  if (error) {
    console.error(`Error executing command: ${error}`);
    return;
  }
});
```

## Unix Domain Sockets

It is possible to subscribe to notifications of every `WindowManagerEvent` and `SocketMessage` handled
by `komorebi` using [Unix Domain Sockets](https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/af_unix-comes-to-windows/).

UDS are also the only mode of communication between `komorebi` and `komorebic`.

First, your application must create a socket in `$ENV:LocalAppData\komorebi`. Once the socket has been created, run the
following command:

```powershell
komorebic.exe subscribe-socket &lt;your socket name&gt;
```

If the socket exists, komorebi will start pushing JSON data of successfully handled events and messages as in the
example above in the Named Pipes section.

## Rust Client

As of `v0.1.22` it is possible to use the `komorebi-client` crate to subscribe to notifications of
every `WindowManagerEvent` and `SocketMessage` handled by `komorebi` in a Rust codebase.

Below is a simple example of how to use `komorebi-client` in a basic Rust application.

```rust
// komorebi-client = { git = &quot;https://github.com/LGUG2Z/komorebi&quot;, tag = &quot;v0.1.35&quot;}

use anyhow::Result;
use komorebi_client::Notification;
use komorebi_client::NotificationEvent;
use komorebi_client::UnixListener;
use komorebi_client::WindowManagerEvent;
use std::io::BufRead;
use std::io::BufReader;
use std::io::Read;

pub fn main() -&gt; anyhow::Result&lt;()&gt; {
  let socket = komorebi_client::subscribe(NAME)?;

  for incoming in socket.incoming() {
    match incoming {
      Ok(data) =&gt; {
        let reader = BufReader::new(data.try_clone()?);

        for line in reader.lines().flatten() {
          let notification: Notification = match serde_json::from_str(&amp;line) {
            Ok(notification) =&gt; notification,
            Err(error) =&gt; {
              log::debug!(&quot;discarding malformed komorebi notification: {error}&quot;);
              continue;
            }
          };

          // match and filter on desired notifications
        }
      }
      Err(error) =&gt; {
        log::debug!(&quot;{error}&quot;);
      }
    }
  }

}
```

A read-world example can be found
in [komokana](h

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>