<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for rust - Rust Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for rust.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DioxusLabs/dioxus]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fullstack app framework for web, desktop, mobile, and more.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus">DioxusLabs/dioxus</a></h1>
            <p>Fullstack app framework for web, desktop, mobile, and more.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 26,702</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,057</p>
            <p>Stars today: 51 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; &gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/header-light-updated.svg#gh-light-mode-only&quot; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/header-dark-updated.svg#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; &gt; --&gt;
      &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://dioxuslabs.com&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/flat-splash.avif&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/splash-header-darkmode.svg#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/splash-header.svg#gh-light-mode-only&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/image-splash.avif&quot;&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;!-- Crates version --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/dioxus&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/dioxus.svg?style=flat-square&quot;
    alt=&quot;Crates.io version&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- Downloads --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/dioxus&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/d/dioxus.svg?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Download&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- docs --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/dioxus&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-latest-blue.svg?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;docs.rs docs&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- CI --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jkelleyrtp/dioxus/actions&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dioxuslabs/dioxus/actions/workflows/main.yml/badge.svg&quot;
      alt=&quot;CI status&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;!--Awesome --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dioxuslabs.com/awesome&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/sindresorhus/awesome/d7305f38d29fed78fa85652e3a63e154dd8e8829/media/badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Awesome Page&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- Discord --&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/XgGxMSkvUM&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/899851952891002890.svg?logo=discord&amp;style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;Discord Link&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dioxuslabs.com&quot;&gt; Website &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/tree/main/examples&quot;&gt; Examples &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dioxuslabs.com/learn/0.6/guide&quot;&gt; Guide &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/main/translations/zh-cn/README.md&quot;&gt; 中文 &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/main/translations/pt-br/README.md&quot;&gt; PT-BR &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/main/translations/ja-jp/README.md&quot;&gt; 日本語 &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/main/translations/tr-tr&quot;&gt; Türkçe &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/main/translations/ko-kr&quot;&gt; 한국어 &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dioxuslabs.com/blog/release-060/&quot;&gt;✨ Dioxus 0.6 is released - check it out here! ✨&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

Build for web, desktop, and mobile, and more with a single codebase. Zero-config setup, integrated hot-reloading, and signals-based state management. Add backend functionality with Server Functions and bundle with our CLI.

```rust
fn app() -&gt; Element {
    let mut count = use_signal(|| 0);

    rsx! {
        h1 { &quot;High-Five counter: {count}&quot; }
        button { onclick: move |_| count += 1, &quot;Up high!&quot; }
        button { onclick: move |_| count -= 1, &quot;Down low!&quot; }
    }
}
```

## ⭐️ Unique features:

- Cross-platform apps in three lines of code (web, desktop, mobile, server, and more)
- [Ergonomic state management](https://dioxuslabs.com/blog/release-050) combines the best of React, Solid, and Svelte
- Type-safe Routing and server functions to leverage Rust&#039;s powerful compile-time guarantees
- Integrated bundler for deploying to the web, macOS, Linux, and Windows
- And more! [Take a tour of Dioxus](https://dioxuslabs.com/learn/0.6/).

## Instant hot-reloading

With one command, `dx serve` and your app is running. Edit your markup and styles and see the results in real time.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DioxusLabs/screenshots/refs/heads/main/blitz/hotreload-video.webp&quot;&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;video src=&quot;https://private-user-images.githubusercontent.com/10237910/386919031-6da371d5-3340-46da-84ff-628216851ba6.mov&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt; --&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;video src=&quot;https://private-user-images.githubusercontent.com/10237910/386919031-6da371d5-3340-46da-84ff-628216851ba6.mov&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


## First-class Android and iOS support

Dioxus is the fastest way to build native mobile apps with Rust. Simply run `dx serve --platform android` and your app is running in an emulator or on device in seconds. Call directly into JNI and Native APIs.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/android_and_ios2.avif&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Bundle for web, desktop, and mobile

Simply run `dx bundle` and your app will be built and bundled with maximization optimizations. On the web, take advantage of [`.avif` generation, `.wasm` compression, minification](https://dioxuslabs.com/learn/0.6/guides/assets), and more. Build WebApps weighing [less than 50kb](https://github.com/ealmloff/tiny-dioxus/) and desktop/mobile apps less than 5mb.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/bundle.gif&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


## Fantastic documentation

We&#039;ve put a ton of effort into building clean, readable, and comprehensive documentation. All html elements and listeners are documented with MDN docs, and our Docs runs continuous integration with Dioxus itself to ensure that the docs are always up to date. Check out the [Dioxus website](https://dioxuslabs.com/learn/0.6/) for guides, references, recipes, and more. Fun fact: we use the Dioxus website as a testbed for new Dioxus features - [check it out!](https://github.com/dioxusLabs/docsite)

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/docs.avif&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Community

Dioxus is a community-driven project, with a very active [Discord](https://discord.gg/XgGxMSkvUM) and [GitHub](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/issues) community. We&#039;re always looking for help, and we&#039;re happy to answer questions and help you get started. [Our SDK](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus-std) is community-run and we even have a [GitHub organization](https://github.com/dioxus-community/) for the best Dioxus crates that receive free upgrades and support.

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./notes/dioxus-community.avif&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Full-time core team

Dioxus has grown from a side project to a small team of fulltime engineers. Thanks to the generous support of FutureWei, Satellite.im, the GitHub Accelerator program, we&#039;re able to work on Dioxus full-time. Our long term goal is for Dioxus to become self-sustaining by providing paid high-quality enterprise tools. If your company is interested in adopting Dioxus and would like to work with us, please reach out!

## Supported Platforms

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table style=&quot;width:100%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Render directly to the DOM using WebAssembly&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Pre-render with SSR and rehydrate on the client&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Simple &quot;hello world&quot; at about 50kb, comparable to React&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Built-in dev server and hot reloading for quick iteration&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Desktop&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Render using Webview or - experimentally - with WGPU or &lt;a href=&quot;https://freyaui.dev&quot;&gt;Freya&lt;/a&gt; (Skia) &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Zero-config setup. Simply `cargo run` or `dx serve` to build your app &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Full support for native system access without IPC &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Supports macOS, Linux, and Windows. Portable &lt;3mb binaries &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Mobile&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Render using Webview or - experimentally - with WGPU or Skia &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Build .ipa and .apk files for iOS and Android &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Call directly into Java and Objective-C with minimal overhead&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;From &quot;hello world&quot; to running on device in seconds&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Server-side Rendering&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Suspense, hydration, and server-side rendering&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Quickly drop in backend functionality with server functions&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Extractors, middleware, and routing integrations&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Static-site generation and incremental regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Running the examples

&gt; The examples in the main branch of this repository target the git version of dioxus and the CLI. If you are looking for examples that work with the latest stable release of dioxus, check out the [0.6 branch](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/tree/v0.6/examples).

The examples in the top level of this repository can be run with:

```sh
cargo run --example &lt;example&gt;
```

However, we encourage you to download the dioxus-cli. If you are running the git version of dioxus, you can install the matching version of the CLI with:

```sh
cargo install --git https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus dioxus-cli --locked
```

With the CLI, you can also run examples with the web platform. You just need to disable the default desktop feature and enable the web feature with this command:

```sh
dx serve --example &lt;example&gt; --platform web -- --no-default-features
```

## Dioxus vs other frameworks

We love all frameworks and enjoy watching innovation in the Rust ecosystem. In fact, many of our projects are shared with other frameworks. For example, our flex-box library [Taffy](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy) is used by [Bevy](https://bevyengine.org/), [Zed](https://zed.dev/), [Lapce](https://lapce.dev/), [Iced](https://github.com/iced-rs/iced), and many more.

Dioxus places an emphasis on a few key points that make it different from other frameworks:

- **React-like**: we rely on concepts like components, props, and hooks to build UIs, with our state management being closer to Svelte than to SolidJS.
- **HTML and CSS**: we lean completely into HTML and CSS, quirks and all.
- **Renderer-agnostic**: you can swap out the renderer for any platform you want thanks to [our fast VirtualDOM](https://dioxuslabs.com/blog/templates-diffing).
- **Collaborative**: whenever possible, we spin out crates like [Taffy](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy), [manganis](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/manganis), [include_mdbook](https://github.com/DioxusLabs/include_mdbook), and [blitz](http://github.com/dioxusLabs/blitz) so the ecosystem can grow together.

### Dioxus vs Tauri

Tauri is a framework for building desktop mobile apps where your frontend is written in a web-based framework like React, Vue, Svelte, etc. Whenever you need to do native work, you can write Rust functions and call them from your frontend.

- **Natively Rust**: Tauri&#039;s architecture limits your UI to either JavaScript or WebAssembly. With Dioxus, your Rust code is running natively on the user&#039;s machine, letting you do things like spawning threads, accessing the filesystem, without any IPC bridge. This drastically simplifies your app&#039;s architecture and makes it easier to build. You can build a Tauri app with Dioxus-Web as a frontend if you&#039;d like.

- **Different scopes**: Tauri needs to support JavaScript and its complex build tooling, limiting the scope of what you can do with it. Since Dioxus is exclusively focused on Rust, we&#039;re able to provide extra utilities like Server Functions, advanced bundling, and a native renderer.

- **Shared DNA**: While Tauri and Dioxus are separate projects, they do share libraries like Tao and Wry: windowing and webview libraries maintained by the Tauri team.

### Dioxus vs Leptos

Leptos is a library for building fullstack web-apps, similar to SolidJS and SolidStart. The two libraries share similar goals on the web, but have several key differences:

- **Reactivity model**: Leptos uses signals to drive both reactivity and rendering, while Dioxus uses signals just for reactivity. For managing re-renders, Dioxus uses a highly optimized VirtualDOM to support desktop and mobile architectures. Both Dioxus and Leptos are extremely fast.

- **Different scopes**: Dioxus provides renderers for web, desktop, mobile, LiveView, and more. We also maintain community libraries and a cross-platform SDK. Leptos has a tighter focus on the fullstack web with features that Dioxus doesn&#039;t have like islands, `&lt;Form /&gt;` components, and other web-specific utilities.

- **Different DSLs**: Dioxus uses its own custom Rust-like DSL for building UIs while Leptos uses an HTML-like syntax. We chose this to retain compatibility with IDE features like code-folding and syntax highlighting. Generally, Dioxus leans into more &quot;magic&quot; with its DSL including automatic formatting of strings and hot-reloading of simple Rust expressions.

```rust
// dioxus
rsx! {
  div {
    class: &quot;my-class&quot;,
    enabled: true,
    &quot;Hello, {name}&quot;
  }
}

// leptos
view! {
  &lt;div class=&quot;my-class&quot; enabled={true}&gt;
    &quot;Hello &quot;
    {name}
  &lt;/div&gt;
}
```

### Dioxus vs Yew

Yew is a framework for building single-page web apps and initially served as an inspiration for Dioxus. Unfortunately, the architecture of Yew didn&#039;t support the various features we wanted, and thus Dioxus was born.

- **Single-page apps**: Yew is designed exclusively for single-page web apps and is intrinsically tied to the web platform. Dioxus is fullstack and cross-platform, making it suitable for building web, desktop, mobile, and server apps.

- **Developer Tooling**: Dioxus provides a number of utilities like autoformatting, hot-reloading, and a bundler.

- **Ongoing support**: Dioxus is very actively maintained with new features and bug fixes being added on a daily basis.

### Dioxus vs egui

egui is a cross-platform GUI library for Rust powering tools like [Rerun.io](https://www.rerun.io).

- **Immediate vs Retained**: egui is designed to be re-rendered on every frame. This is suitable for games and other interactive applications, but it does not retain style and layout state between frames. Dioxus is a retained UI framework, meaning that the UI is built once and then modified between frames. This enables Dioxus to use native web technologies like HTML and CSS with better battery life and performance.

- **Customizable**: egui brings its own styling and layout solution while Dioxus expects you to use the built-in HTML and CSS. This enables dioxus apps to use any CSS library like Tailwind or Material UI.

- **State management**: egui&#039;s state management is based on a single global state object. Dioxus encourages encapsulation of state by using components and props, making components more reusable.

### Dioxus vs Iced

Iced is a cross-platform GUI library inspired by Elm. Iced renders natively with WGPU and supports the web using DOM nodes.

- **Elm state management**: Iced uses Elm&#039;s state management model, which is based on message passing and reducers. This is simply a different state management model than Dioxus and can be rather verbose at times.

- **Native Feel**: Since Dioxus uses a webview as its renderer, it automatically gets native text input, paste handling, and other native features like accessibility. Iced&#039;s renderer currently doesn&#039;t implement these features, making it feel less native.

- **WGPU**: Dioxus&#039; WGPU renderer is currently quite immature and not yet ready for production use. Iced&#039;s WGPU renderer is much more mature and is being used in production. This enables certain types of apps that need GPU access to be built with Iced that can&#039;t currently be built with Dioxus.

### Dioxus vs Electron

Dioxus and Electron are two entirely different projects with similar goals. Electron makes it possible for developers to build cross-platform desktop apps using web technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- **Lightweight**: Dioxus uses the system&#039;s native WebView - or optionally, a WGPU renderer - to render the UI. This makes a typical Dioxus app about 15mb on macOS in comparison to Electron&#039;s 100mb. Electron also ships an embedded chromium instance which cannot share system resources with the host OS in the same way as Dioxus.

- **Maturity**: Electron is a mature project with a large community and a lot of tooling. Dioxus is still quite young in comparison to Electron. Expect to run into features like deep-linking that require extra work to implement.

## Contributing

- Check out the website [section on contributing](https://dioxuslabs.com/learn/0.6/contributing).
- Report issues on our [issue tracker](https://github.com/dioxuslabs/dioxus/issues).
- [Join](https://discord.gg/XgGxMSkvUM) the discord and ask questions!

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dioxuslabs/dioxus/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=dioxuslabs/dioxus&amp;max=30&amp;columns=10&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

## License

This project is licensed under either the [MIT license] or the [Apache-2 License].

[apache-2 license]: https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/master/LICENSE-APACHE
[mit license]: https://github.com/DioxusLabs/dioxus/blob/master/LICENSE-MIT

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted
for inclusion in Dioxus by you, shall be licensed as MIT or Apache-2, without any additional
terms or conditions.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[meilisearch/meilisearch]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A lightning-fast search engine API bringing AI-powered hybrid search to your sites and applications.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch">meilisearch/meilisearch</a></h1>
            <p>A lightning-fast search engine API bringing AI-powered hybrid search to your sites and applications.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 50,454</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,991</p>
            <p>Stars today: 55 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=logo#gh-light-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/meilisearch-logo-light.svg?sanitize=true#gh-light-mode-only&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=logo#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/meilisearch-logo-dark.svg?sanitize=true#gh-dark-mode-only&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://roadmap.meilisearch.com/tabs/1-under-consideration&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/pricing?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;Meilisearch Cloud&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/docs?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/faq?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; |
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=nav&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://deps.rs/repo/github/meilisearch/meilisearch&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://deps.rs/repo/github/meilisearch/meilisearch/status.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Dependency status&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-informational&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch/queue&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Merge Queues enabled&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Merge_Queues-enabled-%2357cf60?logo=github&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; name=&quot;ph-banner&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/meilisearch-ai&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/ph-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meilisearch AI-powered search general availability announcement on ProductHunt&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;⚡ A lightning-fast search engine that fits effortlessly into your apps, websites, and workflow 🔍&lt;/p&gt;

[Meilisearch](https://www.meilisearch.com?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=intro) helps you shape a delightful search experience in a snap, offering features that work out of the box to speed up your workflow.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; name=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://where2watch.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demo-gif#gh-light-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/demo-light.gif#gh-light-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;A bright colored application for finding movies screening near the user&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://where2watch.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demo-gif#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;assets/demo-dark.gif#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;A dark colored application for finding movies screening near the user&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 🖥 Examples

- [**Movies**](https://where2watch.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=organization) — An application to help you find streaming platforms to watch movies using [hybrid search](https://www.meilisearch.com/solutions/hybrid-search?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos).
- [**Ecommerce**](https://ecommerce.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos) — Ecommerce website using disjunctive [facets](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/faceted_search?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos), range and rating filtering, and pagination.
- [**Songs**](https://music.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos) — Search through 47 million of songs.
- [**SaaS**](https://saas.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos) — Search for contacts, deals, and companies in this [multi-tenant](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/security/multitenancy_tenant_tokens?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=demos) CRM application.

See the list of all our example apps in our [demos repository](https://github.com/meilisearch/demos).

## ✨ Features
- **Hybrid search:** Combine the best of both [semantic](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/experimental/vector_search?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features) &amp; full-text search to get the most relevant results
- **Search-as-you-type:** Find &amp; display results in less than 50 milliseconds to provide an intuitive experience
- **[Typo tolerance](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/relevancy/typo_tolerance_settings?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** get relevant matches even when queries contain typos and misspellings
- **[Filtering](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/filtering?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features) and [faceted search](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/faceted_search?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** enhance your users&#039; search experience with custom filters and build a faceted search interface in a few lines of code
- **[Sorting](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/sorting?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** sort results based on price, date, or pretty much anything else your users need
- **[Synonym support](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/relevancy/synonyms?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** configure synonyms to include more relevant content in your search results
- **[Geosearch](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/geosearch?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** filter and sort documents based on geographic data
- **[Extensive language support](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/what_is_meilisearch/language?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** search datasets in any language, with optimized support for Chinese, Japanese, Hebrew, and languages using the Latin alphabet
- **[Security management](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/security/master_api_keys?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** control which users can access what data with API keys that allow fine-grained permissions handling
- **[Multi-Tenancy](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/security/multitenancy_tenant_tokens?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** personalize search results for any number of application tenants
- **Highly Customizable:** customize Meilisearch to your specific needs or use our out-of-the-box and hassle-free presets
- **[RESTful API](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/reference/api/overview?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=features):** integrate Meilisearch in your technical stack with our plugins and SDKs
- **AI-ready:** works out of the box with [langchain](https://www.meilisearch.com/with/langchain) and the [model context protocol](https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch-mcp)
- **Easy to install, deploy, and maintain**

## 📖 Documentation

You can consult Meilisearch&#039;s documentation at [meilisearch.com/docs](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=docs).

## 🚀 Getting started

For basic instructions on how to set up Meilisearch, add documents to an index, and search for documents, take a look at our [documentation](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=get-started) guide.

## 🌍 Supercharge your Meilisearch experience

Say goodbye to server deployment and manual updates with [Meilisearch Cloud](https://www.meilisearch.com/cloud?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch). Additional features include analytics &amp; monitoring in many regions around the world. No credit card is required.

## 🧰 SDKs &amp; integration tools

Install one of our SDKs in your project for seamless integration between Meilisearch and your favorite language or framework!

Take a look at the complete [Meilisearch integration list](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/what_is_meilisearch/sdks?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=sdks-link).

[![Logos belonging to different languages and frameworks supported by Meilisearch, including React, Ruby on Rails, Go, Rust, and PHP](assets/integrations.png)](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/what_is_meilisearch/sdks?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=sdks-logos)

## ⚙️ Advanced usage

Experienced users will want to keep our [API Reference](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/reference/api/overview?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced) close at hand.

We also offer a wide range of dedicated guides to all Meilisearch features, such as [filtering](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/filtering?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced), [sorting](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/sorting?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced), [geosearch](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/fine_tuning_results/geosearch?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced), [API keys](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/security/master_api_keys?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced), and [tenant tokens](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/security/tenant_tokens?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced).

Finally, for more in-depth information, refer to our articles explaining fundamental Meilisearch concepts such as [documents](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/core_concepts/documents?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced) and [indexes](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/core_concepts/indexes?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=advanced).

## 📊 Telemetry

Meilisearch collects **anonymized** user data to help us improve our product. You can [deactivate this](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/what_is_meilisearch/telemetry?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=telemetry#how-to-disable-data-collection) whenever you want.

To request deletion of collected data, please write to us at [privacy@meilisearch.com](mailto:privacy@meilisearch.com). Remember to include your `Instance UID` in the message, as this helps us quickly find and delete your data.

If you want to know more about the kind of data we collect and what we use it for, check the [telemetry section](https://www.meilisearch.com/docs/learn/what_is_meilisearch/telemetry?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=telemetry#how-to-disable-data-collection) of our documentation.

## 📫 Get in touch!

Meilisearch is a search engine created by [Meili]([https://www.welcometothejungle.com/en/companies/meilisearch](https://www.meilisearch.com/careers)), a software development company headquartered in France and with team members all over the world. Want to know more about us? [Check out our blog!](https://blog.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=contact)

🗞 [Subscribe to our newsletter](https://meilisearch.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=27870f7b71c908a8b359599fb&amp;id=79582d828e) if you don&#039;t want to miss any updates! We promise we won&#039;t clutter your mailbox: we only send one edition every two months.

💌 Want to make a suggestion or give feedback? Here are some of the channels where you can reach us:

- For feature requests, please visit our [product repository](https://github.com/meilisearch/product/discussions)
- Found a bug? Open an [issue](https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch/issues)!
- Want to be part of our Discord community? [Join us!](https://discord.meilisearch.com/?utm_campaign=oss&amp;utm_source=github&amp;utm_medium=meilisearch&amp;utm_content=contact)

Thank you for your support!

## 👩‍💻 Contributing

Meilisearch is, and will always be, open-source! If you want to contribute to the project, please look at [our contribution guidelines](CONTRIBUTING.md).

## 📦 Versioning

Meilisearch releases and their associated binaries are available on the project&#039;s [releases page](https://github.com/meilisearch/meilisearch/releases).

The binaries are versioned following [SemVer conventions](https://semver.org/). To know more, read our [versioning policy](https://github.com/meilisearch/engine-team/blob/main/resources/versioning-policy.md).

Differently from the binaries, crates in this repository are not currently available on [crates.io](https://crates.io/) and do not follow [SemVer conventions](https://semver.org).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[matter-labs/zksync-era]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/matter-labs/zksync-era</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/matter-labs/zksync-era</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[zkSync era]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/matter-labs/zksync-era">matter-labs/zksync-era</a></h1>
            <p>zkSync era</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,166</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,115</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># ZKsync Era: A ZK Rollup For Scaling Ethereum

[![Logo](eraLogo.png)](https://zksync.io/)

ZKsync Era is a layer 2 rollup that uses zero-knowledge proofs to scale Ethereum without compromising on security or
decentralization. Since it&#039;s EVM compatible (Solidity/Vyper), 99% of Ethereum projects can redeploy without refactoring
or re-auditing a single line of code. ZKsync Era also uses an LLVM-based compiler that will eventually let developers
write smart contracts in C++, Rust and other popular languages.

## Documentation

The most recent documentation can be found here:

- [Core documentation](https://matter-labs.github.io/zksync-era/core/latest/)
- [Prover documentation](https://matter-labs.github.io/zksync-era/prover/latest/)

## Policies

- [Security policy](SECURITY.md)
- [Contribution policy](CONTRIBUTING.md)

## License

ZKsync Era is distributed under the terms of either

- Apache License, Version 2.0, ([LICENSE-APACHE](LICENSE-APACHE) or &lt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&gt;)
- MIT license ([LICENSE-MIT](LICENSE-MIT) or &lt;https://opensource.org/blog/license/mit/&gt;)

at your option.

## Official Links

- [Website](https://zksync.io/)
- [GitHub](https://github.com/matter-labs)
- [ZK Credo](https://github.com/zksync/credo)
- [Twitter](https://twitter.com/zksync)
- [Twitter for Developers](https://twitter.com/zkSyncDevs)
- [Discord](https://join.zksync.dev/)
- [Mirror](https://zksync.mirror.xyz/)
- [Youtube](https://www.youtube.com/@zkSync-era)

## Disclaimer

ZKsync Era has been through lots of testing and audits. Although it is live, it is still in alpha state and will go
through more audits and bug bounty programs. We would love to hear our community&#039;s thoughts and suggestions about it! It
is important to state that forking it now can potentially lead to missing important security updates, critical features,
and performance improvements.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[moghtech/komodo]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/moghtech/komodo</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🦎 a tool to build and deploy software on many servers 🦎]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/moghtech/komodo">moghtech/komodo</a></h1>
            <p>🦎 a tool to build and deploy software on many servers 🦎</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,086</p>
            <p>Forks: 97</p>
            <p>Stars today: 14 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[juspay/hyperswitch]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch">juspay/hyperswitch</a></h1>
            <p>An open source payments switch written in Rust to make payments fast, reliable and affordable</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,787</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,591</p>
            <p>Stars today: 20 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-dark.svg#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-logo-light.svg#gh-light-mode-only&quot; alt=&quot;Hyperswitch-Logo&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Open-Source Payments Orchestration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; &gt;
Single API to access the payments ecosystem and its features
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/actions?query=workflow%3ACI+branch%3Amain&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/workflows/CI-push/badge.svg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Made_in-Rust-orange&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;!-- Uncomment when we reach &gt;50% coverage --&gt;
  &lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch&quot; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://codecov.io/github/juspay/hyperswitch/graph/badge.svg&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/hyperswitch/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-hyperswitch-blue?logo=linkedin&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/hyperswitchio&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-%40hyperswitchio-white?logo=x&amp;labelColor=grey&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on_slack-blue?logo=slack&amp;labelColor=grey&amp;color=%233f0e40&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

## Table of Contents

1. [Introduction](#introduction)
2. [Architectural Overview](#architectural-overview) 
3. [Try Hyperswitch](#try-hyperswitch)  
4. [Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs](#support-feature-requests)  
5. [Our Vision](#our-vision)  
6. [Versioning](#versioning)  
7. [Copyright and License](#copyright-and-license)

&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
Juspay, founded in 2012, is a global leader in payment orchestration and checkout solutions, trusted by 400+ leading enterprises and brands worldwide. Hyperswitch is Juspay&#039;s new generation of composable, commercial open-source payments platform for merchant and brands. It is an enterprise-grade, transparent and modular payments platform designed to provide digital businesses access to the best payments infrastructure.

Here are the key components of Hyperswitch that deliver the whole solution:

* [Hyperswitch Backend](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch): Hyperswitch backend enables seamless payment processing with comprehensive support for various payment flows - authorization, authentication, void and capture workflows along with robust management of post-payment processes like refunds and chargeback handling. Additionally, Hyperswitch supports non-payment use cases by enabling connections with external FRM or authentication providers as part of the payment flow. The backend optimizes payment routing with customizable workflows, including success rate-based routing, rule-based routing, volume distribution, fallback handling, and intelligent retry mechanisms for failed payments based on specific error codes.

* [SDK (Frontend)](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-web): The SDK, available for web, [Android, and iOS](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-client-core), unifies the payment experience across various methods such as cards, wallets, BNPL, bank transfers, and more, while supporting the diverse payment flows of underlying PSPs. When paired with the locker, it surfaces the user&#039;s saved payment methods.    

* [Control Center](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch-control-center): The Control Center enables users to manage the entire payments stack without any coding. It allows the creation of workflows for routing, payment retries, and defining conditions to invoke 3DS, fraud risk management (FRM), and surcharge modules. The Control Center provides access to transaction, refund, and chargeback operations across all integrated PSPs, transaction-level logs for initial debugging, and detailed analytics and insights into payment performance.

Read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/).

&lt;a href=&quot;#architectural-overview&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;architectural-overview&quot;&gt;Architectural Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/features.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/non-functional-features.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;./docs/imgs/hyperswitch-architecture-v1.png&quot; /&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;#try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;try-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Try Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

### 1. Local Setup

You can run Hyperswitch on your system using Docker compose after cloning this repository. 
We recommend using Docker Desktop (Or Orbstack) for Windows and Mac OS. On Linux, you can install Docker Engine directly.
```shell
git clone --depth 1 --branch latest https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch
cd hyperswitch
docker compose up -d
# This script verifies the setup and provides links to the individual components.
scripts/docker_output.sh
```
The next step is to [configure a connector][configure-a-connector] with the Hyperswitch Control Center and [try a payment][try-a-payment].

Check out the [local setup guide][local-setup-guide] for more details on setting up the entire stack or component wise.

### 2. Deployment on cloud

The fastest and easiest way to try Hyperswitch on AWS is via our CDK scripts

1. Click on the following button for a quick standalone deployment on AWS, suitable for prototyping.
   No code or setup is required in your system and the deployment is covered within the AWS free-tier setup.

   &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/home?region=us-east-1#/stacks/new?stackName=HyperswitchBootstarp&amp;templateURL=https://hyperswitch-synth.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/hs-starter-config.yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/blob/main/docs/imgs/aws_button.png?raw=true&quot; height=&quot;35&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

2. Sign-in to your AWS console.

3. Follow the instructions provided on the console to successfully deploy Hyperswitch. This takes 30-45mins and gives the following output 

| Service| Host|
|----------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------|
| App server running on                        | `http://hyperswitch-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| HyperloaderJS Hosted at                      | `http://&lt;cloudfront.host-id&gt;/0.103.1/v0/HyperLoader.js` |
| Control center server running on             | `http://hyperswitch-control-center-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with Email: `test@gmail.com` |
| Hyperswitch Demo Store running on            | `http://hyperswitch-sdk-demo-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com` |
| Logs server running on                       | `http://hyperswitch-logs-&lt;host-id.region&gt;.elb.amazonaws.com`, Login with username: `admin`, password: `admin` |

We support deployment on GCP and Azure via Helm charts which takes 30-45mins. You can read more at [Hyperswitch docs](https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/deploy-on-kubernetes-using-helm). 

### 3. Hosted Sandbox

You can experience the product by signing up for our [hosted sandbox](https://app.hyperswitch.io/). The signup process accepts any email ID and provides access to the entire Control Center. You can set up connectors, define workflows for routing and retries, and even try payments from the dashboard.

[docs-link-for-enterprise]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-cloud/quickstart
[docs-link-for-developers]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/overview
[contributing-guidelines]: docs/CONTRIBUTING.md
[dashboard-link]: https://app.hyperswitch.io/
[website-link]: https://hyperswitch.io/
[learning-resources]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/learn-more/payment-flows
[local-setup-guide]: /docs/try_local_system.md
[docker-compose-scheduler-monitoring]: /docs/try_local_system.md#running-additional-services
[configure-a-connector]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/account-setup/using-hyperswitch-control-center#add-a-payment-processor
[try-a-payment]: https://docs.hyperswitch.io/hyperswitch-open-source/account-setup/test-a-payment

&lt;a href=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;support-feature-requests&quot;&gt;Support, Feature requests &amp; Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

For any support, join the conversation in [Slack](https://join.slack.com/t/hyperswitch-io/shared_invite/zt-2jqxmpsbm-WXUENx022HjNEy~Ark7Orw)

For new product features, enhancements, roadmap discussions, or to share queries and ideas, visit our [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/discussions)

For reporting a bug, please read the issue guidelines and search for [existing and closed issues]. If your problem or idea is not addressed yet, please [open a new issue].

[existing and closed issues]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues
[open a new issue]: https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/issues/new/choose

&lt;a href=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;Our Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&gt; Linux for Payments

Payments are evolving rapidly worldwide, with hundreds of processors, fraud detection systems, authentication modules, and new payment methods and flows emerging. Businesses building or managing their own payment stacks often face similar challenges, struggle with comparable issues, and find it hard to innovate at the desired pace.

Hyperswitch serves as a well-architected designed reference platform, built on best-in-class design principles, empowering businesses to own and customize their payment stack. It provides a reusable core payments stack that can be tailored to specific requirements while relying on the Hyperswitch team for enhancements, support, and continuous innovation.

### Our Values

1. Embrace Payments Diversity: It will drive innovation in the ecosystem in
   multiple ways.
2. Make it Open Source: Increases trust; Improves the quality and reusability of
   software.
3. Be community driven: It enables participatory design and development.
4. Build it like Systems Software: This sets a high bar for Reliability,
   Security and Performance SLAs.
5. Maximise Value Creation: For developers, customers &amp; partners.

This project is being created and maintained by [Juspay](https://juspay.io)

&lt;a href=&quot;#versioning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;versioning&quot;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

Check the [CHANGELOG.md](./CHANGELOG.md) file for details.

&lt;a href=&quot;#copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;copyright-and-license&quot;&gt;Copyright and License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

This product is licensed under the [Apache 2.0 License](LICENSE).


&lt;a href=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;team-behind-hyperswitch&quot;&gt;Team behind Hyperswitch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

The core team of 150+ engineers building Hyperswitch. Keep up the great work! 🥂

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juspay/hyperswitch/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=juspay/hyperswitch&quot; alt=&quot;Contributors&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[clap-rs/clap]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/clap-rs/clap</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/clap-rs/clap</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A full featured, fast Command Line Argument Parser for Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/clap-rs/clap">clap-rs/clap</a></h1>
            <p>A full featured, fast Command Line Argument Parser for Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 14,928</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,095</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># clap

&gt; **Command Line Argument Parser for Rust**

[![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/clap?style=flat-square)](https://crates.io/crates/clap)
[![Crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/d/clap?style=flat-square)](https://crates.io/crates/clap)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%202.0-blue?style=flat-square)](LICENSE-APACHE)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue?style=flat-square)](LICENSE-MIT)
[![Build Status](https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/clap-rs/clap/ci.yml?branch=master&amp;style=flat-square)](https://github.com/clap-rs/clap/actions/workflows/ci.yml?query=branch%3Amaster)
[![Coverage Status](https://img.shields.io/coveralls/github/clap-rs/clap/master?style=flat-square)](https://coveralls.io/github/clap-rs/clap?branch=master)
[![Contributors](https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/clap-rs/clap?style=flat-square)](https://github.com/clap-rs/clap/graphs/contributors)

Dual-licensed under [Apache 2.0](LICENSE-APACHE) or [MIT](LICENSE-MIT).

## About

Create your command-line parser, with all of the bells and whistles, declaratively or procedurally.

For more details, see:
- [docs.rs](https://docs.rs/clap/latest/clap/)
- [examples](examples/)

## Sponsors

&lt;!-- omit in TOC --&gt;
### Gold

[![](https://opencollective.com/clap/tiers/gold.svg?avatarHeight=36&amp;width=600)](https://opencollective.com/clap)

&lt;!-- omit in TOC --&gt;
### Silver

[![](https://opencollective.com/clap/tiers/silver.svg?avatarHeight=36&amp;width=600)](https://opencollective.com/clap)

&lt;!-- omit in TOC --&gt;
### Bronze

[![](https://opencollective.com/clap/tiers/bronze.svg?avatarHeight=36&amp;width=600)](https://opencollective.com/clap)

&lt;!-- omit in TOC --&gt;
### Backer

[![](https://opencollective.com/clap/tiers/backer.svg?avatarHeight=36&amp;width=600)](https://opencollective.com/clap)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[surrealdb/surrealdb]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A scalable, distributed, collaborative, document-graph database, for the realtime web]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb">surrealdb/surrealdb</a></h1>
            <p>A scalable, distributed, collaborative, document-graph database, for the realtime web</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 29,099</p>
            <p>Forks: 979</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/img/white/hero.png&quot; alt=&quot;SurrealDB Hero&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com#gh-light-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/img/black/hero.png&quot; alt=&quot;SurrealDB Hero&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/surrealdb/surrealdb?color=ff00a0&amp;include_prereleases&amp;label=version&amp;sort=semver&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/built_with-Rust-dca282.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb/actions&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/surrealdb/surrealdb/nightly.yml?style=flat-square&amp;branch=main&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/surrealdb/license&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-BSL_1.1-00bfff.svg?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/surrealdb/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/surrealdb/surrealdb?label=docker%20pulls&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/d/surrealdb?color=dca282&amp;label=rust&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/surrealdb.js&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dt/surrealdb.js?color=f7df1e&amp;label=javascript&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/surrealdb/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pepy/dt/surrealdb?color=426c99&amp;label=python&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nuget.org/packages/SurrealDb.Net&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/nuget/dt/surrealdb.net?color=4c2dcc&amp;label=.NET&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://packagist.org/packages/surrealdb/surrealdb.php&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/packagist/dt/surrealdb/surrealdb.php?color=4d588b&amp;label=php&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/surrealdb/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/surrealdb/surrealdb/total?color=8259dd&amp;label=github%20downloads&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/discord&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/902568124350599239?label=discord&amp;style=flat-square&amp;color=5a66f6&quot; alt=&quot;Discord&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/x-follow_us-222222.svg?style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;X&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/dev-join_us-86f7b7.svg?style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;Dev&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/surrealdb/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/linkedin-connect_with_us-0a66c2.svg?style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;LinkedIn&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/youtube-subscribe-fc1c1c.svg?style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/blog&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/blog.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Blog&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/surrealdb/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/github.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Github&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/surrealdb/&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/linkedin.svg&quot; alt=&quot;LinkedIn&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/x.svg&quot; alt=&quot;X&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/youtube.svg&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/dev.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Dev&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/discord&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/discord.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Discord&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/surrealdb&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;25&quot; src=&quot;./img/social/stack-overflow.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Stack Overflow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/whatissurreal.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;What is SurrealDB?&lt;/h2&gt;

SurrealDB is an end-to-end cloud-native database designed for modern applications, including web, mobile, serverless, Jamstack, backend, and traditional applications. With SurrealDB, you can simplify your database and API infrastructure, reduce development time, and build secure, performant apps quickly and cost-effectively.

**Key features of SurrealDB include:**

- **Reduces development time**: SurrealDB simplifies your database and API stack by removing the need for most server-side components, allowing you to build secure, performant apps faster and cheaper.
- **Real-time collaborative API backend service:** SurrealDB functions as both a database and an API backend service, enabling real-time collaboration.
- **Support for multiple querying languages:** SurrealDB supports SQL querying from client devices, GraphQL, ACID transactions, WebSocket connections, structured and unstructured data, graph querying, full-text indexing, and geospatial querying.
- **Granular access control**: SurrealDB provides row-level permissions-based access control, giving you the ability to manage data access with precision.

View the [features](https://surrealdb.com/features), the latest [releases](https://surrealdb.com/releases), and [documentation](https://surrealdb.com/docs).

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;./img/interface.png&quot; alt=&quot;Surrealist&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/contents.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

- [Features](#features)
- [Documentation](#documentation)
- [Getting started](#getting-started)
	- [Server side code](#server-side-code)
	- [Client side apps](#client-side-apps)
- [Surreal Cloud](#surreal-cloud)
- [Installation](#installation)
	- [Install on macOS](#install-on-macos)
	- [Install on Linux](#install-on-linux)
	- [Install on Windows](#install-on-windows)
	- [Run using Docker](#run-using-docker)
- [Quick look](#quick-look)
- [Why SurrealDB](#why-surrealdb)
	- [Database, API, and permissions](#database-api-and-permissions)
	- [Tables, documents, and graph](#tables-documents-and-graph)
	- [Advanced inter-document relations](#advanced-inter-document-relations-and-analysis-no-joins-no-pain)
	- [Simple schema definition](#simple-schema-definition-for-frontend-and-backend-development)
	- [Connect directly from web-browsers](#connect-and-query-directly-from-web-browsers-and-client-devices)
	- [Multiple different query methods](#query-the-database-with-the-tools-you-want)
	- [Realtime live queries and data changes](#realtime-live-queries-and-data-changes-direct-to-application)
	- [Scale effortlessly for high-availability](#scale-effortlessly-to-hundreds-of-nodes-for-high-availability-and-scalability)
	- [Extend your database with JavaScript](#extend-your-database-with-javascript-functions)
	- [Designed to be embedded or in the cloud](#designed-to-be-embedded-or-to-run-distributed-in-the-cloud)
- [Community](#community)
- [Contributing](#contributing)
- [Security](#security)
- [License](#license)

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/features.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

- [x] Database server, or embedded library
- [x] Multi-row, multi-table ACID transactions
- [x] Single-node, or highly-scalable distributed mode
- [x] Record links and directed typed graph connections
- [x] Store structured and unstructured data
- [x] Incrementally computed views for pre-computed advanced analytics
- [x] Realtime-api layer, and security permissions built in
- [x] Store and model data in any way with tables, documents, and graph
- [x] Simple schema definition for frontend and backend development
- [x] Connect and query directly from web-browsers and client devices
- [x] Use embedded JavaScript functions for custom advanced functionality

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/documentation.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

For guidance on installation, development, deployment, and administration, take a look at the following resources:

- Documentation: https://surrealdb.com/docs
- SurrealDB University: https://surrealdb.com/learn/fundamentals
- Aeon&#039;s Surreal Renaissance (interative book): https://surrealdb.com/learn/book

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/gettingstarted.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;

Getting started with SurrealDB is as easy as starting up the SurrealDB database server, choosing your platform, and integrating its SDK into your code. You can easily get started with your platform of choice by reading one of our tutorials.

**Server side code**

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/rust&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Rust&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/rust.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;JavaScript&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/javascript.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;WebAssembly&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/webassembly.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Node.js&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/nodejs.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Deno&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/deno.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/python&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Python&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/python.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/golang&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Golang&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/golang.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/dotnet&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;.NET&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/dotnet.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/php&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;PHP&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/php.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/java&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Java&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/java.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

**Client side apps**

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;JavaScript&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/javascript.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;WebAssembly&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/webassembly.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;React&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/reactjs.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Next.js&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/nextjs.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/docs/integration/sdks/ember&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=60 title=&quot;Ember.js&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surrealdb/icons/main/emberjs.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;/img/cloud.svg?raw=true&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Surreal Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/cloud#gh-dark-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/img/white/cloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;Surreal Cloud&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/cloud#gh-light-mode-only&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/img/black/cloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;Surreal Cloud&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

SurrealDB is available as a [hosted platform](https://surrealist.app/cloud). Forget about infrastructure operations, monitoring, backups or capacity planning. [Surreal Cloud](https://surrealdb.com/cloud) allows you to focus on building great products using the power and flexibility of SurrealDB in just a few clicks. Grow from prototype to enterprise-scale. The Surreal Cloud scalable architecture allows your database to evolve as your application grows, ensuring you are always ahead of demand. However if you want to deploy SurrealDB yourself, keep reading below.

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/installation.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

SurrealDB is designed to be simple to install and simple to run - using just one command from your terminal. In addition to traditional installation, SurrealDB can be installed and run with HomeBrew, Docker, or using any other container orchestration tool such as Docker Compose, Docker Swarm, Rancher, or in Kubernetes.

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/install&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/apple.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Install on macOS&lt;/h4&gt;

The quickest way to get going with SurrealDB on macOS is to use Homebrew. This will install both the command-line tools, and the SurrealDB server as a single executable. If you don&#039;t use Homebrew, follow the instructions for Linux below to install SurrealDB.

```bash
brew install surrealdb/tap/surreal
```

If you want to test a version with the latest features, published every night, install the `nightly` version:

```bash
brew install surrealdb/tap/surreal-nightly
```

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/install&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/linux.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Install on Linux&lt;/h4&gt;

The easiest and preferred way to get going with SurrealDB on Unix operating systems is to install and use the SurrealDB command-line tool. Run the following command in your terminal and follow the on-screen instructions.

```bash
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://install.surrealdb.com | sh
```

If you want to run a beta release, before the next version is released, the `beta` version:

```bash
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://install.surrealdb.com | sh -s -- --beta
```

If you want to test a version with the latest features, published every night, install the `nightly` version:

```bash
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://install.surrealdb.com | sh -s -- --nightly
```

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/install&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/windows.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Install on Windows&lt;/h4&gt;

The easiest and preferred way to get going with SurrealDB on Windows is to install and use the SurrealDB command-line tool. Run the following command in your terminal and follow the on-screen instructions.

```ps1
iwr https://windows.surrealdb.com -useb | iex
```

If you want to test a version with the latest features, published every night, install the `nightly` version:

```ps1
iex &quot;&amp; { $(irm https://windows.surrealdb.com) } -Nightly&quot;
```

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surrealdb.com/install&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/docker.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Run using Docker&lt;/h4&gt;

Docker can be used to manage and run SurrealDB database instances without the need to install any command-line tools. The SurrealDB docker container contains the full command-line tools for importing and exporting data from a running server, or for running a server itself.

```bash
docker run --rm --pull always --name surrealdb -p 8000:8000 surrealdb/surrealdb:latest start
```

For just getting started with a development server running in memory, you can pass the container a basic initialization to set the user and password as root and enable logging.

```bash
docker run --rm --pull always --name surrealdb -p 8000:8000 surrealdb/surrealdb:latest start --log info --user root --pass root memory
``` 

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/features.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Quick look&lt;/h2&gt;

With strongly-typed data types, data can be fully modelled right in the database.

```sql
UPDATE person SET
    waist = &lt;int&gt; &quot;34&quot;,
    height = &lt;float&gt; 201,
    score = &lt;decimal&gt; 0.3 + 0.3 + 0.3 + 0.1
;
```

Store dynamically computed fields which are calculated when retrieved.

```sql
CREATE person SET
    birthday = &lt;datetime&gt; &quot;2007-06-22&quot;,
    can_drive = &lt;future&gt; { time::now() &gt; birthday + 18y }
;
```

Easily work with unstructured or structured data, in schema-less or schema-full mode.

```sql
-- Create a schemafull table
DEFINE TABLE user SCHEMAFULL;

-- Specify fields on the user table
DEFINE FIELD name ON TABLE user TYPE object;
DEFINE FIELD name.first ON TABLE user TYPE string;
DEFINE FIELD name.last ON TABLE user TYPE string;
DEFINE FIELD email ON TABLE user TYPE string ASSERT string::is::email($value);

-- Add a unique index on the email field preventing duplicate values
DEFINE INDEX email ON TABLE user COLUMNS email UNIQUE;

-- Create a new event whenever a user changes their email address
DEFINE EVENT email ON TABLE user WHEN $before.email != $after.email THEN (
    CREATE event SET user = $value, time = time::now(), value = $after.email, action = &#039;email_changed&#039;
);
```

Connect records together with fully directed graph edge connections.

```sql
-- Add a graph edge between user:tobie and article:surreal
RELATE user:tobie-&gt;write-&gt;article:surreal
    SET time.written = time::now()
;

-- Add a graph edge between specific users and developers
LET $from = (SELECT users FROM company:surrealdb);
LET $devs = (SELECT * FROM user WHERE tags CONTAINS &#039;developer&#039;);
RELATE $from-&gt;like-&gt;$devs UNIQUE
    SET time.connected = time::now()
;
```

Query data flexibly with advanced expressions and graph queries.

```sql
-- Select a nested array, and filter based on an attribute
SELECT emails[WHERE active = true] FROM person;

-- Select all 1st, 2nd, and 3rd level people who this specific person record knows, or likes, as separate outputs
SELECT -&gt;knows-&gt;(? AS f1)-&gt;knows-&gt;(? AS f2)-&gt;(knows, likes AS e3 WHERE influencer = true)-&gt;(? AS f3) FROM person:tobie;

-- Select all person records (and their recipients), who have sent more than 5 emails
SELECT *, -&gt;sent-&gt;email-&gt;to-&gt;person FROM person WHERE count(-&gt;sent-&gt;email) &gt; 5;

-- Select other products purchased by people who purchased this laptop
SELECT &lt;-purchased&lt;-person-&gt;purchased-&gt;product FROM product:laptop;

-- Select products purchased by people in the last 3 weeks who have purchased the same products that we purchased
SELECT -&gt;purchased-&gt;product&lt;-purchased&lt;-person-&gt;(purchased WHERE created_at &gt; time::now() - 3w)-&gt;product FROM person:tobie;
```

Store GeoJSON geographical data types, including points, lines and polygons.

```sql
UPDATE city:london SET
    centre = (-0.118092, 51.509865),
    boundary = {
        type: &quot;Polygon&quot;,
        coordinates: [[
            [-0.38314819, 51.37692386], [0.1785278, 51.37692386],
            [0.1785278, 51.61460570], [-0.38314819, 51.61460570],
            [-0.38314819, 51.37692386]
        ]]
    }
;
```

Write custom embedded logic using JavaScript functions.

```sql
CREATE film SET
    ratings = [
        { rating: 6, user: user:bt8e39uh1ouhfm8ko8s0 },
        { rating: 8, user: user:bsilfhu88j04rgs0ga70 },
    ],
    featured = function() {
        return this.ratings.filter(r =&gt; {
            return r.rating &gt;= 7;
        }).map(r =&gt; {
            return { ...r, rating: r.rating * 10 };
        });
    }
;
```

Specify granular access permissions for client and application access.

```sql
-- Specify access permissions for the &#039;post&#039; table
DEFINE TABLE post SCHEMALESS
    PERMISSIONS
        FOR select
            -- Published posts can be selected
            WHERE published = true
            -- A user can select all their own posts
            OR user = $auth.id
        FOR create, update
            -- A user can create or update their own posts
            WHERE user = $auth.id
        FOR delete
            -- A user can delete their own posts
            WHERE user = $auth.id
            -- Or an admin can delete any posts
            OR $auth.admin = true
;
```

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;./img/features.svg&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Why SurrealDB?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;49%&quot; src=&quot;./img/illustrations/database-api-security.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img width=&quot;49%&quot; src=&quot;./img/illustrations/multi

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[embassy-rs/embassy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Modern embedded framework, using Rust and async.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy">embassy-rs/embassy</a></h1>
            <p>Modern embedded framework, using Rust and async.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,610</p>
            <p>Forks: 989</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Embassy

Embassy is the next-generation framework for embedded applications. Write safe, correct and energy-efficient embedded code faster, using the Rust programming language, its async facilities, and the Embassy libraries.

## &lt;a href=&quot;https://embassy.dev/book/index.html&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/&quot;&gt;API reference&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://embassy.dev/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#embassy-rs:matrix.org&quot;&gt;Chat&lt;/a&gt;
## Rust + async ❤️ embedded

The Rust programming language is blazingly fast and memory-efficient, with no runtime, garbage collector or OS. It catches a wide variety of bugs at compile time, thanks to its full memory- and thread-safety, and expressive type system. 

Rust&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://rust-lang.github.io/async-book/&quot;&gt;async/await&lt;/a&gt; allows for unprecedentedly easy and efficient multitasking in embedded systems. Tasks get transformed at compile time into state machines that get run cooperatively. It requires no dynamic memory allocation, and runs on a single stack,  so no per-task stack size tuning is required. It obsoletes the need for a traditional RTOS with kernel context switching, and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tweedegolf.nl/en/blog/65/async-rust-vs-rtos-showdown&quot;&gt;faster and smaller than one!&lt;/a&gt;

## Batteries included

- **Hardware Abstraction Layers** - HALs implement safe, idiomatic Rust APIs to use the hardware capabilities, so raw register manipulation is not needed. The Embassy project maintains HALs for select hardware, but you can still use HALs from other projects with Embassy.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-stm32/&quot;&gt;embassy-stm32&lt;/a&gt;, for all STM32 microcontroller families.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-nrf/&quot;&gt;embassy-nrf&lt;/a&gt;, for the Nordic Semiconductor nRF52, nRF53, nRF54 and nRF91 series.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-rp/&quot;&gt;embassy-rp&lt;/a&gt;, for the Raspberry Pi RP2040 and RP23xx microcontrollers.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-mspm0/&quot;&gt;embassy-mspm0&lt;/a&gt;, for the Texas Instruments MSPM0 microcontrollers.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/esp-rs&quot;&gt;esp-rs&lt;/a&gt;, for the Espressif Systems ESP32 series of chips.
    - Embassy HAL support for Espressif chips, as well as Async WiFi, Bluetooth and ESP-NOW,  is being developed in the [esp-rs/esp-hal](https://github.com/esp-rs/esp-hal) repository.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ch32-rs/ch32-hal&quot;&gt;ch32-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the WCH 32-bit RISC-V(CH32V) series of chips.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AlexCharlton/mpfs-hal&quot;&gt;mpfs-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the Microchip PolarFire SoC.
  - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/py32-rs/py32-hal&quot;&gt;py32-hal&lt;/a&gt;, for the Puya Semiconductor PY32 series of microcontrollers.

- **Time that Just Works** - 
No more messing with hardware timers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-time&quot;&gt;embassy_time&lt;/a&gt; provides Instant, Duration and Timer types that are globally available and never overflow.

- **Real-time ready** - 
Tasks on the same async executor run cooperatively, but you can create multiple executors with different priorities, so that higher priority tasks preempt lower priority ones. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/blob/master/examples/nrf52840/src/bin/multiprio.rs&quot;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;.

- **Low-power ready** - 
Easily build devices with years of battery life. The async executor automatically puts the core to sleep when there&#039;s no work to do. Tasks are woken by interrupts, there is no busy-loop polling while waiting.
 
- **Networking** - 
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-net/&quot;&gt;embassy-net&lt;/a&gt; network stack implements extensive networking functionality, including Ethernet, IP, TCP, UDP, ICMP and DHCP. Async drastically simplifies managing timeouts and serving multiple connections concurrently.

- **Bluetooth**
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/trouble&quot;&gt;trouble&lt;/a&gt; crate provides a Bluetooth Low Energy 4.x and 5.x Host that runs on any microcontroller implementing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/bt-hci&quot;&gt;bt-hci&lt;/a&gt; traits (currently `nRF52`, `rp2040`, `rp23xx` and `esp32` and `serial` controllers are supported).
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/nrf-softdevice&quot;&gt;nrf-softdevice&lt;/a&gt; crate provides Bluetooth Low Energy 4.x and 5.x support for nRF52 microcontrollers.
  - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/tree/main/embassy-stm32-wpan&quot;&gt;embassy-stm32-wpan&lt;/a&gt; crate provides Bluetooth Low Energy 5.x support for stm32wb microcontrollers.

- **LoRa** - The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lora-rs/lora-rs&quot;&gt;lora-rs&lt;/a&gt; project provides an async LoRa and LoRaWAN stack that works well on Embassy.

- **USB** - 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.embassy.dev/embassy-usb/&quot;&gt;embassy-usb&lt;/a&gt; implements a device-side USB stack. Implementations for common classes such as USB serial (CDC ACM) and USB HID are available, and a rich builder API allows building your own.

- **Bootloader and DFU** - 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/tree/master/embassy-boot&quot;&gt;embassy-boot&lt;/a&gt; is a lightweight bootloader supporting firmware application upgrades in a power-fail-safe way, with trial boots and rollbacks.


## Sneak peek

```rust,ignore
use defmt::info;
use embassy_executor::Spawner;
use embassy_time::{Duration, Timer};
use embassy_nrf::gpio::{AnyPin, Input, Level, Output, OutputDrive, Pin, Pull};
use embassy_nrf::{Peri, Peripherals};

// Declare async tasks
#[embassy_executor::task]
async fn blink(pin: Peri&lt;&#039;static, AnyPin&gt;) {
    let mut led = Output::new(pin, Level::Low, OutputDrive::Standard);

    loop {
        // Timekeeping is globally available, no need to mess with hardware timers.
        led.set_high();
        Timer::after_millis(150).await;
        led.set_low();
        Timer::after_millis(150).await;
    }
}

// Main is itself an async task as well.
#[embassy_executor::main]
async fn main(spawner: Spawner) {
    let p = embassy_nrf::init(Default::default());

    // Spawned tasks run in the background, concurrently.
    spawner.spawn(blink(p.P0_13.into())).unwrap();

    let mut button = Input::new(p.P0_11, Pull::Up);
    loop {
        // Asynchronously wait for GPIO events, allowing other tasks
        // to run, or the core to sleep.
        button.wait_for_low().await;
        info!(&quot;Button pressed!&quot;);
        button.wait_for_high().await;
        info!(&quot;Button released!&quot;);
    }
}
```

## Examples

Examples are found in the `examples/` folder separated by the chip manufacturer they are designed to run on. For example:

*   `examples/nrf52840` run on the `nrf52840-dk` board (PCA10056) but should be easily adaptable to other nRF52 chips and boards.
*   `examples/nrf5340` run on the `nrf5340-dk` board (PCA10095).
*   `examples/stm32xx` for the various STM32 families.
*   `examples/rp` are for the RP2040 chip.
*   `examples/std` are designed to run locally on your PC.

### Running examples

- Install `probe-rs` following the instructions at &lt;https://probe.rs&gt;.
- Change directory to the sample&#039;s base directory. For example:

```bash
cd examples/nrf52840
```

- Ensure `Cargo.toml` sets the right feature for the name of the chip you are programming.
  If this name is incorrect, the example may fail to run or immediately crash
  after being programmed.

- Ensure `.cargo/config.toml` contains the name of the chip you are programming.

- Run the example

For example:

```bash
cargo run --release --bin blinky
```

For more help getting started, see [Getting Started][1] and [Running the Examples][2].

## Developing Embassy with Rust Analyzer based editors

The [Rust Analyzer](https://rust-analyzer.github.io/) is used by [Visual Studio Code](https://code.visualstudio.com/)
and others. Given the multiple targets that Embassy serves, there is no Cargo workspace file. Instead, the Rust Analyzer
must be told of the target project to work with. In the case of Visual Studio Code,
please refer to the `.vscode/settings.json` file&#039;s `rust-analyzer.linkedProjects`setting.

## Minimum supported Rust version (MSRV)

Embassy is guaranteed to compile on stable Rust 1.75 and up. It *might*
compile with older versions but that may change in any new patch release.

## Why the name?

EMBedded ASYnc! :)

## License

Embassy is licensed under either of

- Apache License, Version 2.0 ([LICENSE-APACHE](LICENSE-APACHE) or
  &lt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&gt;)
- MIT license ([LICENSE-MIT](LICENSE-MIT) or &lt;http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&gt;)

at your option.

## Contribution

Unless you explicitly state otherwise, any contribution intentionally submitted
for inclusion in the work by you, as defined in the Apache-2.0 license, shall be
dual licensed as above, without any additional terms or conditions.

[1]: https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/wiki/Getting-Started
[2]: https://github.com/embassy-rs/embassy/wiki/Running-the-Examples
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ast-grep/ast-grep]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ast-grep/ast-grep</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ast-grep/ast-grep</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[⚡A CLI tool for code structural search, lint and rewriting. Written in Rust]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ast-grep/ast-grep">ast-grep/ast-grep</a></h1>
            <p>⚡A CLI tool for code structural search, lint and rewriting. Written in Rust</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 8,494</p>
            <p>Forks: 214</p>
            <p>Stars today: 7 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://ast-grep.github.io/logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;ast-grep&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/ast-grep/ast-grep/actions/workflows/coverage.yaml/badge.svg&quot; alt=&quot;coverage badge&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.codecov.io/gh/ast-grep/ast-grep&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codecov.io/gh/ast-grep/ast-grep/branch/main/graph/badge.svg?token=37VX8H2EWV&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/4YZjf6htSQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/1107749847722889217?label=Discord&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/project/ast-grep/versions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Repology&quot; src=&quot;https://repology.org/badge/tiny-repos/ast-grep.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/ast-grep/ast-grep?style=social&quot; alt=&quot;Badge&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/ast-grep/ast-grep?style=social&quot; alt=&quot;Badge&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Sponsors&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/sponsors/HerringtonDarkholme?style=social&quot;&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://gurubase.io/g/ast-grep&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gurubase&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Gurubase-Ask%20ast--grep%20Guru-006BFF&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


## ast-grep(sg)

ast-grep(sg) is a CLI tool for code structural search, lint, and rewriting.

## Introduction
ast-grep is an [abstract syntax tree](https://dev.to/balapriya/abstract-syntax-tree-ast-explained-in-plain-english-1h38) based tool to search code by pattern code. Think of it as your old-friend [`grep`](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grep#:~:text=grep%20is%20a%20command%2Dline,which%20has%20the%20same%20effect.), but matching AST nodes instead of text.
You can write patterns as if you are writing ordinary code. It will match all code that has the same syntactical structure.
You can use `$` sign + upper case letters as a [wildcard](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wildcard_character), e.g. `$MATCH`, to match any single AST node. Think of it as [regular expression dot](https://regexone.com/lesson/wildcards_dot) `.`, except it is not textual.

Try the [online playground](https://ast-grep.github.io/playground.html) for a taste!

## Screenshot
![demo](https://ast-grep.github.io/image/search-replace.png)

See more screenshots on the [website](https://ast-grep.github.io/).

## Installation
You can install it from [npm](https://docs.npmjs.com/downloading-and-installing-node-js-and-npm), [pip](https://pypi.org/), [cargo](https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/getting-started/installation.html),  [cargo-binstall](https://github.com/cargo-bins/cargo-binstall), [homebrew](https://brew.sh/), [scoop](https://scoop.sh/) or [MacPorts](https://www.macports.org)!

```bash
npm install --global @ast-grep/cli
pip install ast-grep-cli
brew install ast-grep
```


&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Click for more installation methods&lt;/summary&gt;

```bash
cargo install ast-grep --locked
cargo binstall ast-grep

# install via scoop, thank @brian6932
scoop install main/ast-grep

# install via MacPorts
sudo port install ast-grep

# try ast-grep in nix-shell
nix-shell -p ast-grep
```
&lt;/details&gt;

Or you can build ast-grep from source. You need to install rustup, clone the repository and then
```bash
cargo install --path ./crates/cli --locked
```
[Packages](https://repology.org/project/ast-grep/versions) are available on other platforms too.


## Command line usage example

ast-grep has following form.
```
sg --pattern &#039;var code = $PATTERN&#039; --rewrite &#039;let code = new $PATTERN&#039; --lang ts
```

### Example

* [Rewrite code in null coalescing operator](https://twitter.com/Hchan_mgn/status/1547061516993699841?s=20&amp;t=ldDoj4U2nq-FRKQkU5GWXA)

```bash
sg -p &#039;$A &amp;&amp; $A()&#039; -l ts -r &#039;$A?.()&#039;
```

* [Rewrite](https://twitter.com/Hchan_mgn/status/1561802312846278657) [Zodios](https://github.com/ecyrbe/zodios#migrate-to-v8)
```bash
sg -p &#039;new Zodios($URL,  $CONF as const,)&#039; -l ts -r &#039;new Zodios($URL, $CONF)&#039; -i
```

* [Implement eslint rule using YAML.](https://twitter.com/Hchan_mgn/status/1560108625460355073)


## Sponsor
![Sponsors](https://raw.githubusercontent.com/HerringtonDarkholme/sponsors/main/sponsorkit/sponsors.svg)

If you find ast-grep interesting and useful for your work, please [buy me a coffee](https://github.com/sponsors/HerringtonDarkholme)
so I can spend more time on the project!

## Feature Highlight

ast-grep&#039;s core is an algorithm to search and replace code based on abstract syntax tree produced by tree-sitter.
It can help you to do lightweight static analysis and massive scale code manipulation in an intuitive way.

Key highlights:

* An intuitive pattern to find and replace AST.
ast-grep&#039;s pattern looks like ordinary code you would write every day (you could say the pattern is isomorphic to code).

* jQuery like API for AST traversal and manipulation.

* YAML configuration to write new linting rules or code modification.

* Written in compiled language, with tree-sitter based parsing and utilizing multiple cores.

* Beautiful command line interface :)

ast-grep&#039;s vision is to democratize abstract syntax tree magic and to liberate one from cumbersome AST programming!

* If you are an open-source library author, ast-grep can help your library users adopt breaking changes more easily.
* if you are a tech lead in your team, ast-grep can help you enforce code best practice tailored to your business need.
* If you are a security researcher, ast-grep can help you write rules much faster.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[lancedb/lance]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/lancedb/lance</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/lancedb/lance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Modern columnar data format for ML and LLMs implemented in Rust. Convert from parquet in 2 lines of code for 100x faster random access, vector index, and data versioning. Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and PyTorch with more integrations coming..]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/lancedb/lance">lancedb/lance</a></h1>
            <p>Modern columnar data format for ML and LLMs implemented in Rust. Convert from parquet in 2 lines of code for 100x faster random access, vector index, and data versioning. Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and PyTorch with more integrations coming..</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 4,469</p>
            <p>Forks: 279</p>
            <p>Stars today: 26 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

&lt;img width=&quot;257&quot; alt=&quot;Lance Logo&quot; src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/917119/199353423-d3e202f7-0269-411d-8ff2-e747e419e492.png&quot;&gt;

**Modern columnar data format for ML. Convert from Parquet in 2-lines of code for 100x faster random access, zero-cost schema evolution, rich secondary indices, versioning, and more.&lt;br/&gt;**
**Compatible with Pandas, DuckDB, Polars, Pyarrow, and Ray with more integrations on the way.**

&lt;a href=&quot;https://lancedb.github.io/lance/&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lancedb.com/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/zMM32dvNtd&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; •
&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/lancedb&quot;&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;

[CI]: https://github.com/lancedb/lance/actions/workflows/rust.yml
[CI Badge]: https://github.com/lancedb/lance/actions/workflows/rust.yml/badge.svg
[Docs]: https://lancedb.github.io/lance/
[Docs Badge]: https://img.shields.io/badge/docs-passing-brightgreen
[crates.io]: https://crates.io/crates/lance
[crates.io badge]: https://img.shields.io/crates/v/lance.svg
[Python versions]: https://pypi.org/project/pylance/
[Python versions badge]: https://img.shields.io/pypi/pyversions/pylance

[![CI Badge]][CI]
[![Docs Badge]][Docs]
[![crates.io badge]][crates.io]
[![Python versions badge]][Python versions]

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

Lance is a modern columnar data format that is optimized for ML workflows and datasets. Lance is perfect for:

1. Building search engines and feature stores.
2. Large-scale ML training requiring high performance IO and shuffles.
3. Storing, querying, and inspecting deeply nested data for robotics or large blobs like images, point clouds, and more.

The key features of Lance include:

* **High-performance random access:** 100x faster than Parquet without sacrificing scan performance.

* **Vector search:** find nearest neighbors in milliseconds and combine OLAP-queries with vector search.

* **Zero-copy, automatic versioning:** manage versions of your data without needing extra infrastructure.

* **Ecosystem integrations:** Apache Arrow, Pandas, Polars, DuckDB, Ray, Spark and more on the way.

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; Lance is in active development and we welcome contributions. Please see our [contributing guide](docs/contributing.rst) for more information.

## Quick Start

**Installation**

```shell
pip install pylance
```

To install a preview release:

```shell
pip install --pre --extra-index-url https://pypi.fury.io/lancedb/ pylance
```

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; Preview releases are released more often than full releases and contain the
&gt; latest features and bug fixes. They receive the same level of testing as full releases.
&gt; We guarantee they will remain published and available for download for at
&gt; least 6 months. When you want to pin to a specific version, prefer a stable release.

**Converting to Lance**

```python
import lance

import pandas as pd
import pyarrow as pa
import pyarrow.dataset

df = pd.DataFrame({&quot;a&quot;: [5], &quot;b&quot;: [10]})
uri = &quot;/tmp/test.parquet&quot;
tbl = pa.Table.from_pandas(df)
pa.dataset.write_dataset(tbl, uri, format=&#039;parquet&#039;)

parquet = pa.dataset.dataset(uri, format=&#039;parquet&#039;)
lance.write_dataset(parquet, &quot;/tmp/test.lance&quot;)
```

**Reading Lance data**
```python
dataset = lance.dataset(&quot;/tmp/test.lance&quot;)
assert isinstance(dataset, pa.dataset.Dataset)
```

**Pandas**
```python
df = dataset.to_table().to_pandas()
df
```

**DuckDB**
```python
import duckdb

# If this segfaults, make sure you have duckdb v0.7+ installed
duckdb.query(&quot;SELECT * FROM dataset LIMIT 10&quot;).to_df()
```

**Vector search**

Download the sift1m subset

```shell
wget ftp://ftp.irisa.fr/local/texmex/corpus/sift.tar.gz
tar -xzf sift.tar.gz
```

Convert it to Lance

```python
import lance
from lance.vector import vec_to_table
import numpy as np
import struct

nvecs = 1000000
ndims = 128
with open(&quot;sift/sift_base.fvecs&quot;, mode=&quot;rb&quot;) as fobj:
    buf = fobj.read()
    data = np.array(struct.unpack(&quot;&lt;128000000f&quot;, buf[4 : 4 + 4 * nvecs * ndims])).reshape((nvecs, ndims))
    dd = dict(zip(range(nvecs), data))

table = vec_to_table(dd)
uri = &quot;vec_data.lance&quot;
sift1m = lance.write_dataset(table, uri, max_rows_per_group=8192, max_rows_per_file=1024*1024)
```

Build the index

```python
sift1m.create_index(&quot;vector&quot;,
                    index_type=&quot;IVF_PQ&quot;,
                    num_partitions=256,  # IVF
                    num_sub_vectors=16)  # PQ
```

Search the dataset

```python
# Get top 10 similar vectors
import duckdb

dataset = lance.dataset(uri)

# Sample 100 query vectors. If this segfaults, make sure you have duckdb v0.7+ installed
sample = duckdb.query(&quot;SELECT vector FROM dataset USING SAMPLE 100&quot;).to_df()
query_vectors = np.array([np.array(x) for x in sample.vector])

# Get nearest neighbors for all of them
rs = [dataset.to_table(nearest={&quot;column&quot;: &quot;vector&quot;, &quot;k&quot;: 10, &quot;q&quot;: q})
      for q in query_vectors]
```

## Directory structure

| Directory          | Description                               |
|--------------------|-------------------------------------------|
| [rust](./rust)     | Core Rust implementation                  |
| [python](./python) | Python bindings (PyO3)                    |
| [java](./java)     | Java bindings (JNI) and Spark integration |
| [docs](./docs)     | Documentation source                      |

## What makes Lance different

Here we will highlight a few aspects of Lance’s design. For more details, see the full [Lance design document](https://lancedb.github.io/lance/format.html).

**Vector index**: Vector index for similarity search over embedding space.
Support both CPUs (``x86_64`` and ``arm``) and GPU (``Nvidia (cuda)`` and ``Apple Silicon (mps)``).

**Encodings**: To achieve both fast columnar scan and sub-linear point queries, Lance uses custom encodings and layouts.

**Nested fields**: Lance stores each subfield as a separate column to support efficient filters like “find images where detected objects include cats”.

**Versioning**: A Manifest can be used to record snapshots. Currently we support creating new versions automatically via appends, overwrites, and index creation .

**Fast updates** (ROADMAP): Updates will be supported via write-ahead logs.

**Rich secondary indices**: Support `BTree`, `Bitmap`, `Full text search`, `Label list`,
`NGrams`, and more.

## Benchmarks

### Vector search

We used the SIFT dataset to benchmark our results with 1M vectors of 128D

1. For 100 randomly sampled query vectors, we get &lt;1ms average response time (on a 2023 m2 MacBook Air)

![avg_latency.png](docs/avg_latency.png)

2. ANNs are always a trade-off between recall and performance

![avg_latency.png](docs/recall_vs_latency.png)

### Vs. parquet

We create a Lance dataset using the Oxford Pet dataset to do some preliminary performance testing of Lance as compared to Parquet and raw image/XMLs. For analytics queries, Lance is 50-100x better than reading the raw metadata. For batched random access, Lance is 100x better than both parquet and raw files.

![](docs/lance_perf.png)

## Why are you building yet another data format?!

The machine learning development cycle involves the steps:

```mermaid
graph LR
    A[Collection] --&gt; B[Exploration];
    B --&gt; C[Analytics];
    C --&gt; D[Feature Engineer];
    D --&gt; E[Training];
    E --&gt; F[Evaluation];
    F --&gt; C;
    E --&gt; G[Deployment];
    G --&gt; H[Monitoring];
    H --&gt; A;
```

People use different data representations to varying stages for the performance or limited by the tooling available.
Academia mainly uses XML / JSON for annotations and zipped images/sensors data for deep learning, which
is difficult to integrated into data infrastructure and slow to train over cloud storage.
While industry uses data lakes (Parquet-based techniques, i.e., Delta Lake, Iceberg) or data warehouses (AWS Redshift
or Google BigQuery) to collect and analyze data, they have to convert the data into training-friendly formats, such
as [Rikai](https://github.com/eto-ai/rikai)/[Petastorm](https://github.com/uber/petastorm)
or [TFRecord](https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/load_data/tfrecord).
Multiple single-purpose data transforms, as well as syncing copies between cloud storage to local training
instances have become a common practice.

While each of the existing data formats excels at the workload it was originally designed for, we need a new data format
tailored for multistage ML development cycles to reduce and data silos.

A comparison of different data formats in each stage of ML development cycle.

|                     | Lance | Parquet &amp; ORC | JSON &amp; XML | TFRecord | Database | Warehouse |
|---------------------|-------|---------------|------------|----------|----------|-----------|
| Analytics           | Fast  | Fast          | Slow       | Slow     | Decent   | Fast      |
| Feature Engineering | Fast  | Fast          | Decent     | Slow     | Decent   | Good      |
| Training            | Fast  | Decent        | Slow       | Fast     | N/A      | N/A       |
| Exploration         | Fast  | Slow          | Fast       | Slow     | Fast     | Decent    |
| Infra Support       | Rich  | Rich          | Decent     | Limited  | Rich     | Rich      |

## Community Highlights

Lance is currently used in production by:
* [LanceDB](https://github.com/lancedb/lancedb), a serverless, low-latency vector database for ML applications
* [LanceDB Enterprise](https://docs.lancedb.com/enterprise/introduction), hyperscale LanceDB with enterprise SLA.
* Leading multimodal Gen AI companies for training over petabyte-scale multimodal data.
* Self-driving car company for large-scale storage, retrieval and processing of multi-modal data.
* E-commerce company for billion-scale+ vector personalized search.
* and more.

## Presentations, Blogs and Talks

* [Designing a Table Format for ML Workloads](https://blog.lancedb.com/designing-a-table-format-for-ml-workloads/), Feb 2025.
* [Transforming Multimodal Data Management with LanceDB, Ray Summit](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xmTFEzAh8ho), Oct 2024.
* [Lance v2: A columnar container format for modern data](https://blog.lancedb.com/lance-v2/), Apr 2024.
* [Lance Deep Dive](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Orh9rK0Mpj9zN_gnQF1eJJFpAc6lStGm/view?usp=drive_link). July 2023.
* [Lance: A New Columnar Data Format](https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1a4nAiQAkPDBtOfXFpPg7lbeDAxcNDVKgoUkw3cUs2rE/edit#slide=id.p), [Scipy 2022, Austin, TX](https://www.scipy2022.scipy.org/posters). July, 2022.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[starship/starship]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/starship/starship</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/starship/starship</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[☄🌌️ The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/starship/starship">starship/starship</a></h1>
            <p>☄🌌️ The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 48,128</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,082</p>
            <p>Stars today: 32 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img
    width=&quot;400&quot;
    src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/logo.png&quot;
    alt=&quot;Starship – Cross-shell prompt&quot;
  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/actions&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/starship/starship/workflow.yml?branch=master&amp;label=workflow&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;GitHub Actions workflow status&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/starship&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/starship?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Crates.io version&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/project/starship/versions&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/repology/repositories/starship?label=in%20repositories&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Packaging status&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a
  &gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/starship&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/567163873606500352?label=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Chat on Discord&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StarshipPrompt&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/twitter-@StarshipPrompt-1DA1F3?style=flat-square&quot;
      alt=&quot;Follow @StarshipPrompt on Twitter&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stand-with-ukraine.pp.ua&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vshymanskyy/StandWithUkraine/main/badges/StandWithUkraineFlat.svg&quot;
      alt=&quot;Stand With Ukraine&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;#🚀-installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;
  ·
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs/config/&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-us.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;English&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/de-DE/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-de.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Deutsch&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/es-ES/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-es.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Español&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/fr-FR/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-fr.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Français&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/id-ID/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-id.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Bahasa Indonesia&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/it-IT/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-it.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Italiano&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/ja-JP/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-jp.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;日本語&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/pt-BR/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-br.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Português do Brasil&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/ru-RU/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-ru.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Русский&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/uk-UA/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-ua.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Українська&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/vi-VN/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-vn.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;Tiếng Việt&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/zh-CN/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-cn.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;简体中文&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/docs/zh-TW/guide/README.md&quot;
    &gt;&lt;img
      height=&quot;20&quot;
      src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/flag-tw.png&quot;
      alt=&quot;繁體中文&quot;
  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;img
  src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/demo.gif&quot;
  alt=&quot;Starship with iTerm2 and the Snazzy theme&quot;
  width=&quot;50%&quot;
  align=&quot;right&quot;
/&gt;

**The minimal, blazing-fast, and infinitely customizable prompt for any shell!**

- **Fast:** it&#039;s fast – _really really_ fast! 🚀
- **Customizable:** configure every aspect of your prompt.
- **Universal:** works on any shell, on any operating system.
- **Intelligent:** shows relevant information at a glance.
- **Feature rich:** support for all your favorite tools.
- **Easy:** quick to install – start using it in minutes.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://starship.rs/config/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore the Starship docs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;▶&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a name=&quot;🚀-installation&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## 🚀 Installation

### Prerequisites

- A [Nerd Font](https://www.nerdfonts.com/) installed and enabled in your terminal (for example, try the [FiraCode Nerd Font](https://www.nerdfonts.com/font-downloads)).

### Step 1. Install Starship

Select your operating system from the list below to view installation instructions:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Android&lt;/summary&gt;

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository | Instructions           |
| ---------- | ---------------------- |
| [Termux]   | `pkg install starship` |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;BSD&lt;/summary&gt;

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Distribution | Repository      | Instructions                      |
| ------------ | --------------- | --------------------------------- |
| **_Any_**    | **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked` |
| FreeBSD      | [FreshPorts]    | `pkg install starship`            |
| NetBSD       | [pkgsrc]        | `pkgin install starship`          |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Linux&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system:

```sh
curl -sS https://starship.rs/install.sh | sh
```

Alternatively, install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Distribution       | Repository              | Instructions                                                  |
| ------------------ | ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------- |
| **_Any_**          | **[crates.io]**         | `cargo install starship --locked`                             |
| _Any_              | [conda-forge]           | `conda install -c conda-forge starship`                       |
| _Any_              | [Linuxbrew]             | `brew install starship`                                       |
| Alpine Linux 3.13+ | [Alpine Linux Packages] | `apk add starship`                                            |
| Arch Linux         | [Arch Linux Extra]      | `pacman -S starship`                                          |
| CentOS 7+          | [Copr]                  | `dnf copr enable atim/starship` &lt;br /&gt; `dnf install starship` |
| Debian 13+         | [Debian Main]           | `apt install starship`                                        |
| Gentoo             | [Gentoo Packages]       | `emerge app-shells/starship`                                  |
| Manjaro            |                         | `pacman -S starship`                                          |
| NixOS              | [nixpkgs]               | `nix-env -iA nixpkgs.starship`                                |
| openSUSE           | [OSS]                   | `zypper in starship`                                          |
| Ubuntu 25.04+      | [Ubuntu Universe]       | `apt install starship`                                        |
| Void Linux         | [Void Linux Packages]   | `xbps-install -S starship`                                    |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;macOS&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system:

```sh
curl -sS https://starship.rs/install.sh | sh
```

Alternatively, install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository      | Instructions                            |
| --------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked`       |
| [conda-forge]   | `conda install -c conda-forge starship` |
| [Homebrew]      | `brew install starship`                 |
| [MacPorts]      | `port install starship`                 |

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Windows&lt;/summary&gt;

Install the latest version for your system with the MSI-installers from the [releases section](https://github.com/starship/starship/releases/latest).

Install Starship using any of the following package managers:

| Repository      | Instructions                            |
| --------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| **[crates.io]** | `cargo install starship --locked`       |
| [Chocolatey]    | `choco install starship`                |
| [conda-forge]   | `conda install -c conda-forge starship` |
| [Scoop]         | `scoop install starship`                |
| [winget]        | `winget install --id Starship.Starship` |

&lt;/details&gt;

### Step 2. Set up your shell to use Starship

Configure your shell to initialize starship. Select yours from the list below:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Bash&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.bashrc`:

```sh
eval &quot;$(starship init bash)&quot;
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Cmd&lt;/summary&gt;

You need to use [Clink](https://chrisant996.github.io/clink/clink.html) (v1.2.30+) with Cmd.
Create a file at this path `%LocalAppData%\clink\starship.lua` with the following contents:

```lua
load(io.popen(&#039;starship init cmd&#039;):read(&quot;*a&quot;))()
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Elvish&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.elvish/rc.elv`:

```sh
eval (starship init elvish)
```

Note: Only Elvish v0.18+ is supported

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Fish&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.config/fish/config.fish`:

```fish
starship init fish | source
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Ion&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.config/ion/initrc`:

```sh
eval $(starship init ion)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Nushell&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of your Nushell configuration (find it by running `$nu.config-path` in Nushell):

```sh
mkdir ($nu.data-dir | path join &quot;vendor/autoload&quot;)
starship init nu | save -f ($nu.data-dir | path join &quot;vendor/autoload/starship.nu&quot;)
```

Note: Only Nushell v0.96+ is supported

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;PowerShell&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of your PowerShell configuration (find it by running `$PROFILE`):

```powershell
Invoke-Expression (&amp;starship init powershell)
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Tcsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.tcshrc`:

```sh
eval `starship init tcsh`
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Xonsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.xonshrc`:

```python
execx($(starship init xonsh))
```

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Zsh&lt;/summary&gt;

Add the following to the end of `~/.zshrc`:

```sh
eval &quot;$(starship init zsh)&quot;
```

&lt;/details&gt;

### Step 3. Configure Starship

Start a new shell instance, and you should see your beautiful new shell prompt.
If you&#039;re happy with the defaults, enjoy!

If you&#039;re looking to further customize Starship:

- **[Configuration](https://starship.rs/config/)** – learn how to configure Starship to tweak your prompt to your liking

- **[Presets](https://starship.rs/presets/)** – get inspired by the pre-built configuration of others

## 🤝 Contributing

We are always looking for contributors of **all skill levels**! If you&#039;re looking to ease your way into the project, try out a [good first issue](https://github.com/starship/starship/labels/🌱%20good%20first%20issue).

If you are fluent in a non-English language, we greatly appreciate any help keeping our docs translated and up-to-date in other languages. If you would like to help, translations can be contributed on the [Starship Crowdin](https://translate.starship.rs/).

If you are interested in helping contribute to starship, please take a look at our [Contributing Guide](https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md). Also, feel free to drop into our [Discord server](https://discord.gg/8Jzqu3T) and say hi. 👋

## 💭 Inspired By

Please check out these previous works that helped inspire the creation of starship. 🙏

- **[denysdovhan/spaceship-prompt](https://github.com/denysdovhan/spaceship-prompt)** – A ZSH prompt for astronauts.

- **[denysdovhan/robbyrussell-node](https://github.com/denysdovhan/robbyrussell-node)** – Cross-shell robbyrussell theme written in JavaScript.

- **[reujab/silver](https://github.com/reujab/silver)** – A cross-shell customizable powerline-like prompt with icons.

## ❤️ Sponsors

Support this project by [becoming a sponsor](https://github.com/sponsors/starship). Your name or logo will show up here with a link to your website.

## 🔒 Code Signing Policy

Free code signing provided by [SignPath.io], certificate by [SignPath Foundation].

Code Signing Roles:

- Reviewers: [Astronauts](https://github.com/orgs/starship/teams/astronauts)
- Approvers and Authors: [Mission Control](https://github.com/orgs/starship/teams/mission-control)

This program will not transfer any information to other networked systems unless specifically requested by the user or the person installing or operating it.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/starship/starship/master/media/icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Starship rocket icon&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 📝 License

Copyright © 2019-present, [Starship Contributors](https://github.com/starship/starship/graphs/contributors).&lt;br&gt;
This project is [ISC](https://github.com/starship/starship/blob/master/LICENSE) licensed.

[alpine linux packages]: https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/packages?name=starship
[arch linux extra]: https://archlinux.org/packages/extra/x86_64/starship
[chocolatey]: https://community.chocolatey.org/packages/starship
[conda-forge]: https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/starship
[copr]: https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/atim/starship
[crates.io]: https://crates.io/crates/starship
[debian main]: https://sources.debian.org/src/starship/1.22.1-1/
[freshports]: https://www.freshports.org/shells/starship
[gentoo packages]: https://packages.gentoo.org/packages/app-shells/starship
[linuxbrew]: https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/starship
[homebrew]: https://formulae.brew.sh/formula/starship
[macports]: https://ports.macports.org/port/starship
[nixpkgs]: https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/blob/master/pkgs/tools/misc/starship/default.nix
[OSS]: https://software.opensuse.org/package/starship
[pkgsrc]: https://pkgsrc.se/shells/starship
[scoop]: https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/blob/master/bucket/starship.json
[SignPath Foundation]: https://signpath.org
[SignPath.io]: https://signpath.io
[termux]: https://github.com/termux/termux-packages/tree/master/packages/starship
[ubuntu universe]: https://packages.ubuntu.com/source/plucky/starship
[void linux packages]: https://github.com/void-linux/void-packages/tree/master/srcpkgs/starship
[winget]: https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/tree/master/manifests/s/Starship/Starship
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An operating system designed for hosting containers]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket">bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket</a></h1>
            <p>An operating system designed for hosting containers</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,080</p>
            <p>Forks: 529</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Bottlerocket OS

Welcome to Bottlerocket!

Bottlerocket is a free and open-source Linux-based operating system meant for hosting containers.

To learn more about Bottlerocket, visit the [official Bottlerocket website and documentation](https://bottlerocket.dev/).
Otherwise, if you’re ready to jump right in, read one of our setup guides for running Bottlerocket in [Amazon EKS](QUICKSTART-EKS.md), [Amazon ECS](QUICKSTART-ECS.md), or [VMware](QUICKSTART-VMWARE.md).
If you&#039;re interested in running Bottlerocket on bare metal servers, please refer to the [provisioning guide](PROVISIONING-METAL.md) to get started.

Bottlerocket focuses on security and maintainability, providing a reliable, consistent, and safe platform for container-based workloads.
This is a reflection of what we&#039;ve learned building operating systems and services at Amazon.
You can read more about what drives us in [our charter](CHARTER.md).

The base operating system has just what you need to run containers reliably, and is built with standard open-source components.
Bottlerocket-specific additions focus on reliable updates and on the API.
Instead of making configuration changes manually, you can change settings with an API call, and these changes are automatically migrated through updates.

Some notable features include:

* [API access](#api) for configuring your system, with secure out-of-band [access methods](#exploration) when you need them.
* [Updates](#updates) based on partition flips, for fast and reliable system updates.
* [Modeled configuration](#settings) that&#039;s automatically migrated through updates.
* [Security](#security) as a top priority.

## Participate in the Community

There are many ways to take part in the Bottlerocket community:

- [Join us on Meetup](https://www.meetup.com/bottlerocket-community/) to hear about the latest Bottlerocket (virtual/in-person) events and community meetings.
  Community meetings are typically every other week.

  Details can be found under the [Events section on Meetup](https://www.meetup.com/bottlerocket-community/events/), and you will receive email notifications if you become a member of the Meetup group. (It&#039;s free to join!)

- [Start or join a discussion](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket/discussions) if you have questions about Bottlerocket.
- If you&#039;re interested in contributing, thank you!
  Please see our [contributor&#039;s guide](CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Contact us

If you find a security issue, please [contact our security team](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket/security/policy) rather than opening an issue.

We use GitHub issues to track other bug reports and feature requests.
You can look at [existing issues](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket/issues) to see whether your concern is already known.

If not, you can select from a few templates and get some guidance on the type of information that would be most helpful.
[Contact us with a new issue here.](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket/issues/new/choose)

We don&#039;t have other communication channels set up quite yet, but don&#039;t worry about making an issue or a discussion thread!
You can let us know about things that seem difficult, or even ways you might like to help.

## Variants

To start, we&#039;re focusing on the use of Bottlerocket as a host OS in AWS EKS Kubernetes clusters and Amazon ECS clusters.
We’re excited to get early feedback and to continue working on more use cases!

Bottlerocket is architected such that different cloud environments and container orchestrators can be supported in the future.
A build of Bottlerocket that supports different features or integration characteristics is known as a &#039;variant&#039;.
The artifacts of a build will include the architecture and variant name.
For example, an `x86_64` build of the `aws-k8s-1.32` variant will produce an image named `bottlerocket-aws-k8s-1.32-x86_64-&lt;version&gt;-&lt;commit&gt;.img`.

The following variants support EKS, as described above:

* `aws-k8s-1.25`
* `aws-k8s-1.26`
* `aws-k8s-1.27`
* `aws-k8s-1.28`
* `aws-k8s-1.29`
* `aws-k8s-1.30`
* `aws-k8s-1.31`
* `aws-k8s-1.32`
* `aws-k8s-1.25-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.26-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.27-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.28-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.29-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.30-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.31-nvidia`
* `aws-k8s-1.32-nvidia`

The following variants support ECS:

* `aws-ecs-1`
* `aws-ecs-1-nvidia`
* `aws-ecs-2`
* `aws-ecs-2-nvidia`

We also have variants that are designed to be Kubernetes worker nodes in VMware:

* `vmware-k8s-1.28`
* `vmware-k8s-1.29`
* `vmware-k8s-1.30`
* `vmware-k8s-1.31`
* `vmware-k8s-1.32`

The following variants are no longer supported:

* All Kubernetes variants using Kubernetes 1.24 and earlier
* VMware variants using Kubernetes 1.27 and earlier
* Bare metal variants for Kubernetes

We recommend users replace nodes running these variants with the [latest variant compatible with their cluster](variants/).

## Architectures

Our supported architectures include `x86_64` and `aarch64` (written as `arm64` in some contexts).

## Setup

:walking: :running:

Bottlerocket is best used with a container orchestrator.
To get started with Kubernetes in Amazon EKS, please see [QUICKSTART-EKS](QUICKSTART-EKS.md).
To get started with Kubernetes in VMware, please see [QUICKSTART-VMWARE](QUICKSTART-VMWARE.md).
To get started with Amazon ECS, please see [QUICKSTART-ECS](QUICKSTART-ECS.md).
These guides describe:

* how to set up a cluster with the orchestrator, so your Bottlerocket instance can run containers
* how to launch a Bottlerocket instance in EC2 or VMware

To see how to provision Bottlerocket on bare metal, see [PROVISIONING-METAL](PROVISIONING-METAL.md).

To build your own Bottlerocket images, please see [BUILDING](BUILDING.md).
It describes:

* how to build an image
* how to register an EC2 AMI from an image

To publish your built Bottlerocket images, please see [PUBLISHING](PUBLISHING.md).
It describes:

* how to make TUF repos including your image
* how to copy your AMI across regions
* how to mark your AMIs public or grant access to specific accounts
* how to make your AMIs discoverable using [SSM parameters](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/latest/userguide/systems-manager-parameter-store.html)

## Exploration

To improve security, there&#039;s no SSH server in a Bottlerocket image, and not even a shell.

Don&#039;t panic!

There are a couple out-of-band access methods you can use to explore Bottlerocket like you would a typical Linux system.
Either option will give you a shell within Bottlerocket.
From there, you can [change settings](#settings), manually [update Bottlerocket](#updates), debug problems, and generally explore.

**Note:** These methods require that your instance has permission to access the ECR repository where these containers live; the appropriate policy to add to your instance&#039;s IAM role is `AmazonEC2ContainerRegistryReadOnly`.

### Control container

Bottlerocket has a [&quot;control&quot; container](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-control-container), enabled by default, that runs outside of the orchestrator in a separate instance of containerd.
This container runs the [AWS SSM agent](https://github.com/aws/amazon-ssm-agent) that lets you run commands, or start shell sessions, on Bottlerocket instances in EC2.
(You can easily replace this control container with your own just by changing the URI; see [Settings](#settings).)

In AWS, you need to give your instance the SSM role for this to work; see the [setup guide](QUICKSTART-EKS.md#enabling-ssm).
Outside of AWS, you can use [AWS Systems Manager for hybrid environments](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/latest/userguide/systems-manager-managedinstances.html).
There&#039;s more detail about hybrid environments in the [control container documentation](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-control-container/#connecting-to-aws-systems-manager-ssm).

Once the instance is started, you can start a session:

* Go to AWS SSM&#039;s [Session Manager](https://console.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/session-manager/sessions)
* Select &quot;Start session&quot; and choose your Bottlerocket instance
* Select &quot;Start session&quot; again to get a shell

If you prefer a command-line tool, you can start a session with a recent [AWS CLI](https://aws.amazon.com/cli/) and the [session-manager-plugin](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/systems-manager/latest/userguide/session-manager-working-with-install-plugin.html).
Then you&#039;d be able to start a session using only your instance ID, like this:

```shell
aws ssm start-session --target INSTANCE_ID --region REGION_CODE
```

With the [default control container](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-control-container), you can make [API calls](#api) to configure and manage your Bottlerocket host.
To do even more, read the next section about the [admin container](#admin-container).
You can access the admin container from the control container like this:

```shell
enter-admin-container
```

### Admin container

Bottlerocket has an [administrative container](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-admin-container), disabled by default, that runs outside of the orchestrator in a separate instance of containerd.
This container has an SSH server that lets you log in as `ec2-user` using your EC2-registered SSH key.
Outside of AWS, you can [pass in your own SSH keys](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-admin-container#authenticating-with-the-admin-container).
(You can easily replace this admin container with your own just by changing the URI; see [Settings](#settings).

To enable the container, you can change the setting in user data when starting Bottlerocket, for example EC2 instance user data:

```toml
[settings.host-containers.admin]
enabled = true
```

If Bottlerocket is already running, you can enable the admin container from the default [control container](#control-container) like this:

```shell
enable-admin-container
```

Or you can start an interactive session immediately like this:

```shell
enter-admin-container
```

If you&#039;re using a custom control container, or want to make the API calls directly, you can enable the admin container like this instead:

```shell
apiclient set host-containers.admin.enabled=true
```

Once you&#039;ve enabled the admin container, you can either access it through SSH or execute commands from the control container like this:

```shell
apiclient exec admin bash
```

Once you&#039;re in the admin container, you can run `sheltie` to get a full root shell in the Bottlerocket host.
Be careful; while you can inspect and change even more as root, Bottlerocket&#039;s filesystem and dm-verity setup will prevent most changes from persisting over a restart - see [Security](#security).

## Updates

Rather than a package manager that updates individual pieces of software, Bottlerocket downloads a full filesystem image and reboots into it.
It can automatically roll back if boot failures occur, and workload failures can trigger manual rollbacks.

The update process uses images secured by [TUF](https://theupdateframework.github.io/).
For more details, see the [update system documentation](sources/updater/).

### Update methods

There are several ways of updating your Bottlerocket hosts.
We provide tools for automatically updating hosts, as well as an API for direct control of updates.

#### Automated updates

For EKS variants of Bottlerocket, we recommend using the [Bottlerocket update operator](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-update-operator) for automated updates.

For the ECS variant of Bottlerocket, we recommend using the [Bottlerocket ECS updater](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-ecs-updater/) for automated updates.

#### Update API

The [Bottlerocket API](#api) includes methods for checking and starting system updates.
You can read more about the update APIs in our [update system documentation](sources/updater/README.md#update-api).

apiclient knows how to handle those update APIs for you, and you can run it from the [control](#control-container) or [admin](#admin-container) containers.

To see what updates are available:

```shell
apiclient update check
```

If an update is available, it will show up in the `chosen_update` field.
The `available_updates` field will show the full list of available versions, including older versions, because Bottlerocket supports safely rolling back.

To apply the latest update:

```shell
apiclient update apply
```

The next time you reboot, you&#039;ll start up in the new version, and system configuration will be automatically [migrated](sources/api/migration/).
To reboot right away:

```shell
apiclient reboot
```

If you&#039;re confident about updating, the `apiclient update apply` command has `--check` and `--reboot` flags to combine the above actions, so you can accomplish all of the above steps like this:

```shell
apiclient update apply --check --reboot
```

See the [apiclient documentation](sources/api/apiclient/) for more details.

### Update rollback

The system will automatically roll back if it&#039;s unable to boot.
If the update is not functional for a given container workload, you can do a manual rollback:

```shell
signpost rollback-to-inactive
reboot
```

This doesn&#039;t require any external communication, so it&#039;s quicker than `apiclient`, and it&#039;s made to be as reliable as possible.

## Settings

Here we&#039;ll describe the settings you can configure on your Bottlerocket instance, and how to do it.

(API endpoints are defined in our [OpenAPI spec](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-core-kit/tree/develop/sources/api/openapi.yaml) if you want more detail.)

### Interacting with settings

#### Using the API client

You can see the current settings with an API request:

```shell
apiclient get settings
```

This will return all of the current settings in JSON format.
For example, here&#039;s an abbreviated response:

```json
{&quot;motd&quot;: &quot;...&quot;, {&quot;kubernetes&quot;: {}}}
```

You can change settings like this:

```shell
apiclient set motd=&quot;hi there&quot; kubernetes.node-labels.environment=test
```

You can also use a JSON input mode to help change many related settings at once, and a &quot;raw&quot; mode if you want more control over how the settings are committed and applied to the system.
See the [apiclient README](https://github.com/bottlerocket-os/bottlerocket-core-kit/tree/develop/sources/api/apiclient/) for details.

#### Using user data

If you know what settings you want to change when you start your Bottlerocket instance, you can send them in the user data.

In user data, we structure the settings in TOML form to make things a bit simpler.
Here&#039;s the user data to change the message of the day setting, as we did in the last section:

```toml
[settings]
motd = &quot;my own value!&quot;
```

If your user data is over the size limit of the platform (e.g. 16KiB for EC2) you can compress the contents with gzip.
(With [aws-cli](https://aws.amazon.com/cli/), you can use `--user-data fileb:///path/to/gz-file` to pass binary data.)

### Description of settings

Here we&#039;ll describe each setting you can change.

**Note:** You can see the default values (for any settings that are not generated at runtime) by looking in the `defaults.d` directory for a variant, for example [aws-ecs-2](sources/models/src/aws-ecs-2/defaults.d/).

When you&#039;re sending settings to the API, or receiving settings from the API, they&#039;re in a structured JSON format.
This allows modification of any number of keys at once.
It also lets us ensure that they fit the definition of the Bottlerocket data model - requests with invalid settings won&#039;t even parse correctly, helping ensure safety.

Here, however, we&#039;ll use the shortcut &quot;dotted key&quot; syntax for referring to keys.
This is used in some API endpoints with less-structured requests or responses.
It&#039;s also more compact for our needs here.

In this format, &quot;settings.kubernetes.cluster-name&quot; refers to the same key as in the JSON `{&quot;settings&quot;: {&quot;kubernetes&quot;: {&quot;cluster-name&quot;: &quot;value&quot;}}}`.

**NOTE:** [bottlerocket.dev](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/) now contains a complete, versioned setting reference.
This documents retains the headings below for existing link and bookmark compatability.
Please update your bookmarks and check out [bottlerocket.dev](https://bottlerocket.dev/) for future updates to the setting reference.

#### Top-level settings

See the [`settings.motd` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/motd/).

#### Kubernetes settings

See the [`settings.kubernetes.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/kubernetes/).

#### Amazon ECS settings

See the [`settings.ecs.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/ecs/).

#### CloudFormation signal helper settings

See the [`settings.cloudformation.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/cloudformation/).

#### Auto Scaling group settings

See the [`settings.autoscaling.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/autoscaling/).

#### OCI Hooks settings

See the [`settings.oci-hooks.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/oci-hooks/).

#### OCI Defaults settings

See the [`settings.oci-defaults.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/oci-defaults/).

##### OCI Defaults: Capabilities

See the [&quot;Capabilities Settings&quot; section in the `settings.oci-defaults.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/oci-defaults/).

##### OCI Defaults: Resource Limits

See the [&quot;Resource Limits Settings&quot; section in the `settings.oci-defaults.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/oci-defaults/).

#### Container image registry settings

See the [`settings.container-registry.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/container-registry/).

#### Container runtime settings

See the [`settings.container-runtime.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/container-runtime/).

#### Updates settings

See the [`settings.updates.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/updates/).

#### Network settings

See the [`settings.network.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/network/).

##### Proxy settings

See the [&quot;Proxy Settings&quot; section in the `settings.networks.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/network/).

#### Metrics settings

See the [`settings.metrics.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/metrics/).

#### Time settings

See the [`settings.ntp.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/ntp/).

#### Kernel settings

See the [`settings.kernel.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/kernel/).

#### Boot-related settings

See the [`settings.boot.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/boot/).

#### Custom CA certificates settings

See the [`settings.pki.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/pki/).

#### Host containers settings

See the [`settings.host-containers.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/host-containers/).

##### Custom host containers

See the [Host Containers documentation](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/concepts/host-containers/).

#### Bootstrap commands settings

See the [`settings.bootstrap-commands.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/bootstrap-commands/) as well as the [Bootstrap Commands documentation](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/concepts/bootstrap-commands/)

#### Bootstrap containers settings

See the [`settings.bootstrap-containers.*` reference](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/api/settings/bootstrap-containers/) as well as the [Bootstrap Containers documentation](https://bottlerocket.dev/en/os/latest/#/concepts/bootstrap-containers/)

##### Mount propagations in bootstrap and superpowe

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[cloudflare/quiche]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🥧 Savoury implementation of the QUIC transport protocol and HTTP/3]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche">cloudflare/quiche</a></h1>
            <p>🥧 Savoury implementation of the QUIC transport protocol and HTTP/3</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,052</p>
            <p>Forks: 802</p>
            <p>Stars today: 13 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>![quiche](quiche.svg)

[![crates.io](https://img.shields.io/crates/v/quiche.svg)](https://crates.io/crates/quiche)
[![docs.rs](https://docs.rs/quiche/badge.svg)](https://docs.rs/quiche)
[![license](https://img.shields.io/github/license/cloudflare/quiche.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/BSD-2-Clause)
![build](https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/cloudflare/quiche/stable.yml?branch=master)

[quiche] is an implementation of the QUIC transport protocol and HTTP/3 as
specified by the [IETF]. It provides a low level API for processing QUIC packets
and handling connection state. The application is responsible for providing I/O
(e.g. sockets handling) as well as an event loop with support for timers.

For more information on how quiche came about and some insights into its design
you can read a [post] on Cloudflare&#039;s blog that goes into some more detail.

[quiche]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/
[ietf]: https://quicwg.org/
[post]: https://blog.cloudflare.com/enjoy-a-slice-of-quic-and-rust/

Who uses quiche?
----------------

### Cloudflare

quiche powers Cloudflare edge network&#039;s [HTTP/3 support][cloudflare-http3]. The
[cloudflare-quic.com](https://cloudflare-quic.com) website can be used for
testing and experimentation.

### Android

Android&#039;s DNS resolver uses quiche to [implement DNS over HTTP/3][android-http3].

### curl

quiche can be [integrated into curl][curl-http3] to provide support for HTTP/3.

[cloudflare-http3]: https://blog.cloudflare.com/http3-the-past-present-and-future/
[android-http3]: https://security.googleblog.com/2022/07/dns-over-http3-in-android.html
[curl-http3]: https://github.com/curl/curl/blob/master/docs/HTTP3.md#quiche-version

Getting Started
---------------

### Command-line apps

Before diving into the quiche API, here are a few examples on how to use the
quiche tools provided as part of the [quiche-apps](apps/) crate.

After cloning the project according to the command mentioned in the [building](#building) section, the client can be run as follows:

```bash
 $ cargo run --bin quiche-client -- https://cloudflare-quic.com/
```

while the server can be run as follows:

```bash
 $ cargo run --bin quiche-server -- --cert apps/src/bin/cert.crt --key apps/src/bin/cert.key
```

(note that the certificate provided is self-signed and should not be used in
production)

Use the `--help` command-line flag to get a more detailed description of each
tool&#039;s options.

### Configuring connections

The first step in establishing a QUIC connection using quiche is creating a
[`Config`] object:

```rust
let mut config = quiche::Config::new(quiche::PROTOCOL_VERSION)?;
config.set_application_protos(&amp;[b&quot;example-proto&quot;]);

// Additional configuration specific to application and use case...
```

The [`Config`] object controls important aspects of the QUIC connection such
as QUIC version, ALPN IDs, flow control, congestion control, idle timeout
and other properties or features.

QUIC is a general-purpose transport protocol and there are several
configuration properties where there is no reasonable default value. For
example, the permitted number of concurrent streams of any particular type
is dependent on the application running over QUIC, and other use-case
specific concerns.

quiche defaults several properties to zero, applications most likely need
to set these to something else to satisfy their needs using the following:

- [`set_initial_max_streams_bidi()`]
- [`set_initial_max_streams_uni()`]
- [`set_initial_max_data()`]
- [`set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_local()`]
- [`set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_remote()`]
- [`set_initial_max_stream_data_uni()`]

[`Config`] also holds TLS configuration. This can be changed by mutators on
the an existing object, or by constructing a TLS context manually and
creating a configuration using [`with_boring_ssl_ctx_builder()`].

A configuration object can be shared among multiple connections.

### Connection setup

On the client-side the [`connect()`] utility function can be used to create
a new connection, while [`accept()`] is for servers:

```rust
// Client connection.
let conn = quiche::connect(Some(&amp;server_name), &amp;scid, local, peer, &amp;mut config)?;

// Server connection.
let conn = quiche::accept(&amp;scid, None, local, peer, &amp;mut config)?;
```

### Handling incoming packets

Using the connection&#039;s [`recv()`] method the application can process
incoming packets that belong to that connection from the network:

```rust
let to = socket.local_addr().unwrap();

loop {
    let (read, from) = socket.recv_from(&amp;mut buf).unwrap();

    let recv_info = quiche::RecvInfo { from, to };

    let read = match conn.recv(&amp;mut buf[..read], recv_info) {
        Ok(v) =&gt; v,

        Err(e) =&gt; {
            // An error occurred, handle it.
            break;
        },
    };
}
```

### Generating outgoing packets

Outgoing packet are generated using the connection&#039;s [`send()`] method
instead:

```rust
loop {
    let (write, send_info) = match conn.send(&amp;mut out) {
        Ok(v) =&gt; v,

        Err(quiche::Error::Done) =&gt; {
            // Done writing.
            break;
        },

        Err(e) =&gt; {
            // An error occurred, handle it.
            break;
        },
    };

    socket.send_to(&amp;out[..write], &amp;send_info.to).unwrap();
}
```

When packets are sent, the application is responsible for maintaining a
timer to react to time-based connection events. The timer expiration can be
obtained using the connection&#039;s [`timeout()`] method.

```rust
let timeout = conn.timeout();
```

The application is responsible for providing a timer implementation, which
can be specific to the operating system or networking framework used. When
a timer expires, the connection&#039;s [`on_timeout()`] method should be called,
after which additional packets might need to be sent on the network:

```rust
// Timeout expired, handle it.
conn.on_timeout();

// Send more packets as needed after timeout.
loop {
    let (write, send_info) = match conn.send(&amp;mut out) {
        Ok(v) =&gt; v,

        Err(quiche::Error::Done) =&gt; {
            // Done writing.
            break;
        },

        Err(e) =&gt; {
            // An error occurred, handle it.
            break;
        },
    };

    socket.send_to(&amp;out[..write], &amp;send_info.to).unwrap();
}
```

#### Pacing

It is recommended that applications [pace] sending of outgoing packets to
avoid creating packet bursts that could cause short-term congestion and
losses in the network.

quiche exposes pacing hints for outgoing packets through the [`at`] field
of the [`SendInfo`] structure that is returned by the [`send()`] method.
This field represents the time when a specific packet should be sent into
the network.

Applications can use these hints by artificially delaying the sending of
packets through platform-specific mechanisms (such as the [`SO_TXTIME`]
socket option on Linux), or custom methods (for example by using user-space
timers).

[pace]: https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc9002#section-7.7
[`SO_TXTIME`]: https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man8/tc-etf.8.html

### Sending and receiving stream data

After some back and forth, the connection will complete its handshake and
will be ready for sending or receiving application data.

Data can be sent on a stream by using the [`stream_send()`] method:

```rust
if conn.is_established() {
    // Handshake completed, send some data on stream 0.
    conn.stream_send(0, b&quot;hello&quot;, true)?;
}
```

The application can check whether there are any readable streams by using
the connection&#039;s [`readable()`] method, which returns an iterator over all
the streams that have outstanding data to read.

The [`stream_recv()`] method can then be used to retrieve the application
data from the readable stream:

```rust
if conn.is_established() {
    // Iterate over readable streams.
    for stream_id in conn.readable() {
        // Stream is readable, read until there&#039;s no more data.
        while let Ok((read, fin)) = conn.stream_recv(stream_id, &amp;mut buf) {
            println!(&quot;Got {} bytes on stream {}&quot;, read, stream_id);
        }
    }
}
```

### HTTP/3

The quiche [HTTP/3 module] provides a high level API for sending and
receiving HTTP requests and responses on top of the QUIC transport protocol.

[`Config`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Config.html
[`set_initial_max_streams_bidi()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_streams_bidi
[`set_initial_max_streams_uni()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_streams_uni
[`set_initial_max_data()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_data
[`set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_local()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_local
[`set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_remote()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_stream_data_bidi_remote
[`set_initial_max_stream_data_uni()`]: https://docs.rs/quiche/latest/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.set_initial_max_stream_data_uni
[`with_boring_ssl_ctx_builder()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Config.html#method.with_boring_ssl_ctx_builder
[`connect()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/fn.connect.html
[`accept()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/fn.accept.html
[`recv()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.recv
[`send()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.send
[`timeout()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.timeout
[`on_timeout()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.on_timeout
[`stream_send()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.stream_send
[`readable()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.readable
[`stream_recv()`]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/struct.Connection.html#method.stream_recv
[HTTP/3 module]: https://docs.quic.tech/quiche/h3/index.html

Have a look at the [quiche/examples/] directory for more complete examples on
how to use the quiche API, including examples on how to use quiche in C/C++
applications (see below for more information).

[examples/]: quiche/examples/

Calling quiche from C/C++
-------------------------

quiche exposes a [thin C API] on top of the Rust API that can be used to more
easily integrate quiche into C/C++ applications (as well as in other languages
that allow calling C APIs via some form of FFI). The C API follows the same
design of the Rust one, modulo the constraints imposed by the C language itself.

When running ``cargo build``, a static library called ``libquiche.a`` will be
built automatically alongside the Rust one. This is fully stand-alone and can
be linked directly into C/C++ applications.

Note that in order to enable the FFI API, the ``ffi`` feature must be enabled (it
is disabled by default), by passing ``--features ffi`` to ``cargo``.

[thin C API]: https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche/blob/master/quiche/include/quiche.h

Building
--------

quiche requires Rust 1.81 or later to build. The latest stable Rust release can
be installed using [rustup](https://rustup.rs/).

Once the Rust build environment is setup, the quiche source code can be fetched
using git:

```bash
 $ git clone --recursive https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche
```

and then built using cargo:

```bash
 $ cargo build --examples
```

cargo can also be used to run the testsuite:

```bash
 $ cargo test
```

Note that [BoringSSL], which is used to implement QUIC&#039;s cryptographic handshake
based on TLS, needs to be built and linked to quiche. This is done automatically
when building quiche using cargo, but requires the `cmake` command to be
available during the build process. On Windows you also need
[NASM](https://www.nasm.us/). The [official BoringSSL
documentation](https://github.com/google/boringssl/blob/master/BUILDING.md) has
more details.

In alternative you can use your own custom build of BoringSSL by configuring
the BoringSSL directory with the ``QUICHE_BSSL_PATH`` environment variable:

```bash
 $ QUICHE_BSSL_PATH=&quot;/path/to/boringssl&quot; cargo build --examples
```

Alternatively you can use [OpenSSL/quictls]. To enable quiche to use this vendor
the ``openssl`` feature can be added to the ``--feature`` list. Be aware that
``0-RTT`` is not supported if this vendor is used.

[BoringSSL]: https://boringssl.googlesource.com/boringssl/

[OpenSSL/quictls]: https://github.com/quictls/openssl

### Building for Android

Building quiche for Android (NDK version 19 or higher, 21 recommended), can be
done using [cargo-ndk] (v2.0 or later).

First the [Android NDK] needs to be installed, either using Android Studio or
directly, and the `ANDROID_NDK_HOME` environment variable needs to be set to the
NDK installation path, e.g.:

```bash
 $ export ANDROID_NDK_HOME=/usr/local/share/android-ndk
```

Then the Rust toolchain for the Android architectures needed can be installed as
follows:

```bash
 $ rustup target add aarch64-linux-android armv7-linux-androideabi i686-linux-android x86_64-linux-android
```

Note that the minimum API level is 21 for all target architectures.

[cargo-ndk] (v2.0 or later) also needs to be installed:

```bash
 $ cargo install cargo-ndk
```

Finally the quiche library can be built using the following procedure. Note that
the `-t &lt;architecture&gt;` and `-p &lt;NDK version&gt;` options are mandatory.

```bash
 $ cargo ndk -t arm64-v8a -p 21 -- build --features ffi
```

See [build_android_ndk19.sh] for more information.

[Android NDK]: https://developer.android.com/ndk
[cargo-ndk]: https://docs.rs/crate/cargo-ndk
[build_android_ndk19.sh]: https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche/blob/master/tools/android/build_android_ndk19.sh

### Building for iOS

To build quiche for iOS, you need the following:

- Install Xcode command-line tools. You can install them with Xcode or with the
  following command:

```bash
 $ xcode-select --install
```

- Install the Rust toolchain for iOS architectures:

```bash
 $ rustup target add aarch64-apple-ios x86_64-apple-ios
```

- Install `cargo-lipo`:

```bash
 $ cargo install cargo-lipo
```

To build libquiche, run the following command:

```bash
 $ cargo lipo --features ffi
```

or

```bash
 $ cargo lipo --features ffi --release
```

iOS build is tested in Xcode 10.1 and Xcode 11.2.

### Building Docker images

In order to build the Docker images, simply run the following command:

```bash
 $ make docker-build
```

You can find the quiche Docker images on the following Docker Hub repositories:

- [cloudflare/quiche](https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/cloudflare/quiche)
- [cloudflare/quiche-qns](https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/cloudflare/quiche-qns)

The `latest` tag will be updated whenever quiche master branch updates.

**cloudflare/quiche**

Provides a server and client installed in /usr/local/bin.

**cloudflare/quiche-qns**

Provides the script to test quiche within the [quic-interop-runner](https://github.com/marten-seemann/quic-interop-runner).

Copyright
---------

Copyright (C) 2018-2019, Cloudflare, Inc.

See [COPYING] for the license.

[COPYING]: https://github.com/cloudflare/quiche/tree/master/COPYING
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rolldown/rolldown]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fast Rust bundler for JavaScript/TypeScript with Rollup-compatible API.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown">rolldown/rolldown</a></h1>
            <p>Fast Rust bundler for JavaScript/TypeScript with Rollup-compatible API.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 10,733</p>
            <p>Forks: 566</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolldown.rs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;https://rolldown.rs/rolldown-round.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Rolldown logo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![MIT licensed][badge-license]][url-license]
[![NPM version][badge-npm-version]][url-npm]
[![NPM Unpacked Size (with version)](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/rolldown/latest?label=npm)][url-npm]
[![Build Status][badge-ci]][url-ci]
[![Code Coverage][badge-code-coverage]][url-code-coverage]
[![CodSpeed Badge](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://codspeed.io/badge.json)](https://codspeed.io/rolldown/rolldown)
[![Discord chat][badge-discord]][discord-url]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![NPM Unpacked Size darwin-arm64](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-darwin-arm64/latest?label=darwin-arm64)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rolldown/binding-darwin-arm64)
[![NPM Unpacked Size darwin-x64](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-darwin-x64/latest?label=darwin-x64)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rolldown/binding-darwin-x64)
[![NPM Unpacked Size linux-x64-gnu](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-linux-x64-gnu/latest?label=linux-x64-gnu)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rolldown/binding-linux-x64-gnu)
[![NPM Unpacked Size win32-x64](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-win32-x64-msvc/latest?label=win32-x64)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rolldown/binding-win32-x64-msvc)
[![NPM Unpacked Size wasm32-wasi](https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-wasm32-wasi/latest?label=wasm32-wasi)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@rolldown/binding-wasm32-wasi)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![rolldown-starter-stackblitz](https://developer.stackblitz.com/img/open_in_stackblitz.svg)](https://stackblitz.com/github/rolldown/rolldown-starter-stackblitz)

&lt;/div&gt;

&gt; 🚧 **Work in Progress**
&gt;
&gt; Rolldown is currently in active development and not usable for production yet.

# Rolldown

Rolldown is a JavaScript/TypeScript bundler written in Rust intended to serve as the future bundler used in [Vite](https://vitejs.dev/). It provides Rollup-compatible APIs and plugin interface, but will be more similar to esbuild in scope.

For more information, please check out the documentation at [rolldown.rs](https://rolldown.rs/about).

## VoidZero Inc.

Rolldown is a project of [VoidZero](https://voidzero.dev/), see our announcement [Announcing VoidZero - Next Generation Toolchain for JavaScript](https://voidzero.dev/posts/announcing-voidzero-inc).

If you have requirements for JavaScript tools at scale, please [get in touch](https://forms.gle/WQgjyzYJpwurpxWKA)!

## Contributing

We would love to have more contributors involved!

To get started, please read our [Contributing Guide](https://rolldown.rs/contrib-guide/).

## Credits

The Rolldown project is heavily inspired by:

- [Rollup](https://github.com/rollup/rollup), created by [Rich Harris](https://github.com/Rich-Harris) and maintained by [Lukas Taegert-Atkinson](https://github.com/lukastaegert).
- [esbuild](https://github.com/evanw/esbuild), created by [Evan Wallace](https://github.com/evanw).

And supported by:

- [napi-rs](https://github.com/napi-rs/napi-rs) for Node.js add-ons in Rust via Node-API.
- [oxc](https://github.com/oxc-project/oxc) for the underlying parser, resolver, and sourcemap support.

## Licenses

This project is licensed under the [MIT License](LICENSE).

This project also partially contains code derived or copied from the following projects:

- [rollup(MIT)](https://github.com/rollup/rollup/blob/680912e2ceb42c8d5e571e01c6ece0e4889aecbb/LICENSE-CORE.md)
- [esbuild(MIT)](https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/blob/0c8a0a901d9a6c7bbff9b4dd347c8a3f65f6c6dd/LICENSE.md)

Licenses of these projects are listed in [THIRD-PARTY-LICENSE](/THIRD-PARTY-LICENSE)

[badge-discord]: https://img.shields.io/discord/1079625926024900739?logo=discord&amp;label=Discord
[discord-url]: https://chat.rolldown.rs
[badge-license]: https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg
[url-license]: https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown/blob/main/LICENSE
[badge-ci]: https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg?event=push&amp;branch=main
[url-ci]: https://github.com/rolldown/rolldown/actions/workflows/ci.yml?query=event%3Apush+branch%3Amain
[badge-code-coverage]: https://codecov.io/github/rolldown/rolldown/branch/main/graph/badge.svg
[url-code-coverage]: https://codecov.io/gh/rolldown/rolldown
[badge-npm-version]: https://img.shields.io/npm/v/rolldown/latest?color=brightgreen
[url-npm]: https://www.npmjs.com/package/rolldown/v/latest
[badge-binary-size-windows]: [https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-win32-x64-msvc/latest]
[badge-binary-size-macos]: [https://img.shields.io/npm/unpacked-size/%40rolldown%2Fbinding-darwin-arm64/latest]
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rustdesk/rustdesk-server]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[RustDesk Server Program]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server">rustdesk/rustdesk-server</a></h1>
            <p>RustDesk Server Program</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 7,625</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,702</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-build-manually&quot;&gt;Manually&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#docker-images&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#s6-overlay-based-images&quot;&gt;S6-overlay&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-create-a-keypair&quot;&gt;Keypair&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#deb-packages&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#env-variables&quot;&gt;Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  [&lt;a href=&quot;README-DE.md&quot;&gt;Deutsch&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-NL.md&quot;&gt;Nederlands&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-TW.md&quot;&gt;繁體中文&lt;/a&gt;] | [&lt;a href=&quot;README-ZH.md&quot;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

# RustDesk Server Program

[![build](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/actions/workflows/build.yaml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/actions/workflows/build.yaml)

[**Download**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases)

[**Manual**](https://rustdesk.com/docs/en/self-host/)

[**FAQ**](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk/wiki/FAQ)

Self-host your own RustDesk server, it is free and open source.

## How to build manually

```bash
cargo build --release
```

Three executables will be generated in target/release.

- hbbs - RustDesk ID/Rendezvous server
- hbbr - RustDesk relay server
- rustdesk-utils - RustDesk CLI utilities

You can find updated binaries on the [Releases](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases) page.

If you want extra features, [RustDesk Server Pro](https://rustdesk.com/pricing.html) might suit you better.

If you want to develop your own server, [rustdesk-server-demo](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server-demo) might be a better and simpler start for you than this repo.

## Docker images

Docker images are automatically generated and published to [Docker Hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk?tab=packages&amp;repo_name=rustdesk-server) on every GitHub release. We have 2 kind of images.

### Classic image

These images are built from scratch with two main binaries (`hbbs` and `hbbr`). They&#039;re available on [Docker Hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) with these architectures:

* amd64
* arm64v8
* armv7

You could use `latest` tag or major version tag `1` with supported architectures:

| Version       | image:tag                         |
| ------------- | --------------------------------- |
| latest        | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest` |
| Major version | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server:1`      |


You can start these images directly with `docker run` with these commands:

```bash
docker run --name hbbs --net=host -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbs -r &lt;relay-server-ip[:port]&gt; 
docker run --name hbbr --net=host -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbr 
```

or without `--net=host`, but P2P direct connection can not work.

For systems using SELinux, replacing `/root` by `/root:z` is required for the containers to run correctly. Alternatively, SELinux container separation can be disabled completely adding the option `--security-opt label=disable`.

```bash
docker run --name hbbs -p 21115:21115 -p 21116:21116 -p 21116:21116/udp -p 21118:21118 -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbs -r &lt;relay-server-ip[:port]&gt; 
docker run --name hbbr -p 21117:21117 -p 21119:21119 -v &quot;$PWD/data:/root&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest hbbr 
```

The `relay-server-ip` parameter is the IP address (or dns name) of the server running these containers. The **optional** `port` parameter has to be used if you use a port different than **21117** for `hbbr`.

You can also use docker-compose, using this configuration as a template:

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

networks:
  rustdesk-net:
    external: false

services:
  hbbs:
    container_name: hbbs
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21118:21118
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest
    command: hbbs -r rustdesk.example.com:21117
    volumes:
      - ./data:/root
    networks:
      - rustdesk-net
    depends_on:
      - hbbr
    restart: unless-stopped

  hbbr:
    container_name: hbbr
    ports:
      - 21117:21117
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest
    command: hbbr
    volumes:
      - ./data:/root
    networks:
      - rustdesk-net
    restart: unless-stopped
```

Edit line 16 to point to your relay server (the one listening on port 21117). You can also edit the volume lines (line 18 and line 33) if you need.

(docker-compose credit goes to @lukebarone and @QuiGonLeong)

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; The rustdesk/rustdesk-server:latest in China may be replaced with the latest version number on Docker Hub, such as `rustdesk-server:1.1.10-3`. Otherwise, the old version may be pulled due to image acceleration.

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; If you are experiencing issues pulling from Docker Hub, try pulling from the [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) instead.

## S6-overlay based images

These images are build against `busybox:stable` with the addition of the binaries (both `hbbs` and `hbbr`) and [S6-overlay](https://github.com/just-containers/s6-overlay). They&#039;re available on [Docker hub](https://hub.docker.com/r/rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6/) and [GitHub Container Registry](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/pkgs/container/rustdesk-server) with these architectures:

* amd64
* i386
* arm64v8
* armv7

You could use `latest` tag or major version tag `1` with supported architectures:

| Version       | image:tag                            |
| ------------- | ------------------------------------ |
| latest        | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest` |
| Major version | `rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:1`      |

The S6-overlay acts as a supervisor and keeps both process running, so with this image, there&#039;s no need to have two separate running containers.

You can start these images directly with `docker run` with this command:

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \ 
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/data:/data&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

or without `--net=host`, but P2P direct connection cannot work.

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \
  -p 21115:21115 -p 21116:21116 -p 21116:21116/udp \
  -p 21117:21117 -p 21118:21118 -p 21119:21119 \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/data:/data&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

Or you can use a docker-compose file:

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./data:/data
    restart: unless-stopped
```

For this container image, you can use these environment variables, **in addition** to the ones specified in the following **ENV variables** section:

| variable | optional | description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| RELAY | no | the IP address/DNS name of the machine running this container |
| ENCRYPTED_ONLY | yes | if set to **&quot;1&quot;** unencrypted connection will not be accepted |
| KEY_PUB | yes | public part of the key pair |
| KEY_PRIV | yes | private part of the key pair |

### Secret management in S6-overlay based images

You can obviously keep the key pair in a docker volume, but the best practices tells you to not write the keys on the filesystem; so we provide a couple of options.

On container startup, the presence of the keypair is checked (`/data/id_ed25519.pub` and `/data/id_ed25519`) and if one of these keys doesn&#039;t exist, it&#039;s recreated from ENV variables or docker secrets.
Then the validity of the keypair is checked: if public and private keys doesn&#039;t match, the container will stop.
If you provide no keys, `hbbs` will generate one for you, and it&#039;ll place it in the default location.

#### Use ENV to store the key pair

You can use docker environment variables to store the keys. Just follow this examples:

```bash
docker run --name rustdesk-server \ 
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -e &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot; \
  -e &quot;KEY_PRIV=FR2j78IxfwJNR+HjLluQ2Nh7eEryEeIZCwiQDPVe+PaITKyShphHAsPLn7So0OqRs92nGvSRdFJnE2MSyrKTIQ==&quot; \
  -e &quot;KEY_PUB=iEyskoaYRwLDy5+0qNDqkbPdpxr0kXRSZxNjEsqykyE=&quot; \
  -v &quot;$PWD/db:/db&quot; -d rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
      - &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot;
      - &quot;KEY_PRIV=FR2j78IxfwJNR+HjLluQ2Nh7eEryEeIZCwiQDPVe+PaITKyShphHAsPLn7So0OqRs92nGvSRdFJnE2MSyrKTIQ==&quot;
      - &quot;KEY_PUB=iEyskoaYRwLDy5+0qNDqkbPdpxr0kXRSZxNjEsqykyE=&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./db:/db
    restart: unless-stopped
```

#### Use Docker secrets to store the key pair

You can alternatively use docker secrets to store the keys.
This is useful if you&#039;re using **docker-compose** or **Docker Swarm**.
Just follow this examples:

```bash
cat secrets/id_ed25519.pub | docker secret create key_pub -
cat secrets/id_ed25519 | docker secret create key_priv -
docker service create --name rustdesk-server \
  --secret key_priv --secret key_pub \
  --net=host \
  -e &quot;RELAY=rustdeskrelay.example.com&quot; \
  -e &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot; \
  -e &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot; \
  --mount &quot;type=bind,source=$PWD/db,destination=/db&quot; \
  rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
```

```yaml
version: &#039;3&#039;

services:
  rustdesk-server:
    container_name: rustdesk-server
    ports:
      - 21115:21115
      - 21116:21116
      - 21116:21116/udp
      - 21117:21117
      - 21118:21118
      - 21119:21119
    image: rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest
    environment:
      - &quot;RELAY=rustdesk.example.com:21117&quot;
      - &quot;ENCRYPTED_ONLY=1&quot;
      - &quot;DB_URL=/db/db_v2.sqlite3&quot;
    volumes:
      - ./db:/db
    restart: unless-stopped
    secrets:
      - key_pub
      - key_priv

secrets:
  key_pub:
    file: secrets/id_ed25519.pub
  key_priv:
    file: secrets/id_ed25519      
```

## How to create a keypair

A keypair is needed for encryption; you can provide it, as explained before, but you need a way to create one.

You can use this command to generate a keypair:

```bash
/usr/bin/rustdesk-utils genkeypair
```

If you don&#039;t have (or don&#039;t want) the `rustdesk-utils` package installed on your system, you can invoke the same command with docker:

```bash
docker run --rm --entrypoint /usr/bin/rustdesk-utils  rustdesk/rustdesk-server-s6:latest genkeypair
```

The output will be something like this:

```text
Public Key:  8BLLhtzUBU/XKAH4mep3p+IX4DSApe7qbAwNH9nv4yA=
Secret Key:  egAVd44u33ZEUIDTtksGcHeVeAwywarEdHmf99KM5ajwEsuG3NQFT9coAfiZ6nen4hfgNICl7upsDA0f2e/jIA==
```

## .deb packages

Separate .deb packages are available for each binary, you can find them in the [Releases](https://github.com/rustdesk/rustdesk-server/releases).
These packages are meant for the following distributions:

- Ubuntu 24.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 22.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 20.04 LTS
- Ubuntu 18.04 LTS
- Debian 12 bookworm
- Debian 11 bullseye
- Debian 10 buster

## ENV variables

`hbbs` and `hbbr` can be configured using these ENV variables.
You can specify the variables as usual or use an `.env` file.

| variable | binary | description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| ALWAYS_USE_RELAY | hbbs | if set to **&quot;Y&quot;** disallows direct peer connection |
| DB_URL | hbbs | path for database file |
| DOWNGRADE_START_CHECK | hbbr | delay (in seconds) before downgrade check |
| DOWNGRADE_THRESHOLD | hbbr | threshold of downgrade check (bit/ms) |
| KEY | hbbs/hbbr | if set force the use of a specific key, if set to **&quot;_&quot;** force the use of any key |
| LIMIT_SPEED | hbbr | speed limit (in Mb/s) |
| PORT | hbbs/hbbr | listening port (21116 for hbbs - 21117 for hbbr) |
| RELAY | hbbs | IP address/DNS name of the machines running hbbr (separated by comma) |
| RUST_LOG | all | set debug level (error\|warn\|info\|debug\|trace) |
| SINGLE_BANDWIDTH | hbbr | max bandwidth for a single connection (in Mb/s) |
| TOTAL_BANDWIDTH | hbbr | max total bandwidth (in Mb/s) |
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[aws/amazon-q-developer-cli]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[✨ Add autocomplete and AI to your existing terminal on macOS & Linux]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli">aws/amazon-q-developer-cli</a></h1>
            <p>✨ Add autocomplete and AI to your existing terminal on macOS & Linux</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 392</p>
            <p>Forks: 68</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./.github/media/amazon-q-logo.avif&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Q&quot;
        width=&quot;200px&quot;
      &gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Amazon Q CLI brings IDE-style autocomplete and agentic capabilities to your terminal.
&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/graphs/commit-activity&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub commit activity&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/issues&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub open issues&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Rust Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/rust.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/rust.yml)
[![Typos Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typos.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typos.yml)
[![Typescript Test](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typescript.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-developer-cli/actions/workflows/typescript.yml)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;./.github/media/amazon-q-cli-features.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon Q CLI Features&quot;
      &gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 😍 Features
-   🔮 [**Auto Completion**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete.html): IDE-style completions to hundreds of popular CLIs like `git`, `npm`, `docker`, and `aws`.
-   💬 [**Natural Language Chat**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-chat.html): Interact with your terminal using natural language to ask questions, debug issues, or explore the codebase.
-   🧠 [**Contextual Awareness**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-chat.html#command-line-chat-context-integration): Integrates context from your local development environment, so answers are tailored to your specific code and setup.
-   🤖 [**Agentic Execution**](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete.html): Let Amazon Q take action: generate code, edit files, automate Git workflows, resolve merge conflicts, and more — with your permission.

## ⚡️ Installation

- **macOS**:
  - **DMG**: Download from AWS:
    [aws.amazon.com](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-getting-started-installing.html)
  - **Homebrew**: `brew install amazon-q`
- **Linux**:
  - [Ubuntu/Debian](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-ubuntu)
  - [AppImage](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-appimage)
  - [Alternative Linux builds](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-alternative-linux)
- **Windows**:
  - Follow the discussions for
    [Windows](https://github.com/aws/q-command-line-discussions/discussions/15)
  - Or [use it on Windows with WSL](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-installing.html#command-line-installing-windows)
- **Remote machines**
  - [Autocomplete in SSH](https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazonq/latest/qdeveloper-ug/command-line-autocomplete-ssh.html)


## 🚀 Start Contributing

### Prerequisites

- MacOS
  - Xcode 13 or later
  - Brew

### 1. Clone repo

```shell
git clone https://github.com/aws/amazon-q-for-command-line.git
```

### 2. Setup
Hassle-free setup:
```shell
npm run setup
```

Or if you&#039;d like to DIY:

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Manual Setup&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

### 1. Install platform dependencies

For Debian/Ubuntu:

```shell
sudo apt update
sudo apt install build-essential pkg-config jq dpkg curl wget cmake clang libssl-dev libgtk-3-dev libayatana-appindicator3-dev librsvg2-dev libdbus-1-dev libwebkit2gtk-4.1-dev libjavascriptcoregtk-4.1-dev valac libibus-1.0-dev libglib2.0-dev sqlite3 libxdo-dev protobuf-compiler
```
### 2. Install Rust toolchain using [Rustup](https://rustup.rs):

```shell
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh
rustup default stable
```

For pre-commit hooks, the following commands are required:

```shell
rustup toolchain install nightly
cargo install typos-cli
```

For MacOS development make sure the right targets are installed:

```shell
rustup target add x86_64-apple-darwin
rustup target add aarch64-apple-darwin
```

### 3. Setup Python and Node using [`mise`](https://mise.jdx.dev)

Add mise integrations to your shell:

For zsh:
```shell
echo &#039;eval &quot;$(mise activate zsh)&quot;&#039; &gt;&gt; &quot;${ZDOTDIR-$HOME}/.zshrc&quot;
```

For bash:
```shell
echo &#039;eval &quot;$(mise activate bash)&quot;&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc
```

For fish:
```shell
echo &#039;mise activate fish | source&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.config/fish/config.fish
```

Install the Python and Node toolchains using:

```shell
mise trust
mise install
```

### 4. Setup precommit hooks

Run `pnpm` in root directory to add pre-commit hooks:

```shell
pnpm install --ignore-scripts
```

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;


### 3. Start Local Development
To compile and view changes made to `q chat`:
```shell
cargo run --bin q_cli -- chat
```

&gt; If you are working on other q commands, just replace `chat` with the command name 

To run tests for the Q CLI crate:
```shell
cargo test -p q_cli
```

To format Rust files:
```shell
cargo +nightly fmt
```

To run clippy:
```shell
cargo clippy --locked --workspace --color always -- -D warnings
```



### 💡 Quick Tip for Onboarding

Use Q CLI to help you onboard Q CLI! 

Start a `q chat` session:

```shell
q chat
```

Once inside `q chat`, you can supply project context by adding the [`codebase-summary.md`](codebase-summary.md) file:

```shell
/context add codebase-summary.md
```

This enables Q to answer onboarding questions like:

- “What does this crate do?”

- “Where is X implemented?”

- “How do these components interact?”

Great for speeding up your ramp-up and navigating the repo more effectively.




## 🏗️ Project Layout

Several projects live here:

- [`autocomplete`](packages/autocomplete/) - The autocomplete react app
- [`dashboard`](packages/dashboard-app/) - The dashboard react app
- [`figterm`](crates/figterm/) - figterm, our headless terminal/pseudoterminal that
  intercepts the user’s terminal edit buffer.
- [`q_cli`](crates/q_cli/) - the `q` CLI, allows users to interface with Amazon Q Developer from
  the command line
- [`fig_desktop`](crates/fig_desktop/) - the Rust desktop app, uses
  [`tao`](https://docs.rs/tao/latest/tao/)/[`wry`](https://docs.rs/wry/latest/wry/)
  for windowing/webviews
- [`fig_input_method`](crates/fig_input_method/) - The input method used to get cursor
  position on macOS
- [`vscode`](extensions/vscode/) - Contains the VSCode plugin needed
  for the Amazon Q Developer for command line to work in VSCode
- [`jetbrains`](extensions/jetbrains/) - Contains the VSCode plugin
  needed for the Amazon Q Developer for command line to work in Jetbrains IDEs

Other folder to be aware of

- [`build-scripts/`](build-scripts/) - Contains all python scripts to build,
  sign, and test the project on macOS and Linux
- [`crates/`](crates/) - Contains all internal rust crates
- [`packages/`](packages/) - Contains all internal npm packages
- [`proto/`](proto/) -
  [protocol buffer](https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/) message
  specification for inter-process communication
- [`tests/`](tests/) - Contain integration tests for the projects

Below is a high level architecture of how the different components of the app and
their IPC:

![architecture](docs/assets/architecture.svg)




## 🛡️ Security

See [CONTRIBUTING](CONTRIBUTING.md#security-issue-notifications) for more information.

## 📜 Licensing

This repo is dual licensed under MIT and Apache 2.0 licenses.

“Amazon Web Services” and all related marks, including logos, graphic designs, and service names, are trademarks or trade dress of AWS in the U.S. and other countries. AWS’s trademarks and trade dress may not be used in connection with any product or service that is not AWS’s, in any manner that is likely to cause confusion among customers, or in any manner that disparages or discredits AWS.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[microsoft/windows-rs]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/microsoft/windows-rs</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/microsoft/windows-rs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Rust for Windows]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/windows-rs">microsoft/windows-rs</a></h1>
            <p>Rust for Windows</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,177</p>
            <p>Forks: 543</p>
            <p>Stars today: 2 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[neondatabase/neon]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/neondatabase/neon</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/neondatabase/neon</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Neon: Serverless Postgres. We separated storage and compute to offer autoscaling, code-like database branching, and scale to zero.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/neondatabase/neon">neondatabase/neon</a></h1>
            <p>Neon: Serverless Postgres. We separated storage and compute to offer autoscaling, code-like database branching, and scale to zero.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,789</p>
            <p>Forks: 530</p>
            <p>Stars today: 8 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>[![Neon](https://github.com/neondatabase/neon/assets/11527560/f15a17f0-836e-40c5-b35d-030606a6b660)](https://neon.tech)



# Neon

Neon is a serverless open-source alternative to AWS Aurora Postgres. It separates storage and compute and substitutes the PostgreSQL storage layer by redistributing data across a cluster of nodes.

## Quick start
Try the [Neon Free Tier](https://neon.tech/github) to create a serverless Postgres instance. Then connect to it with your preferred Postgres client (psql, dbeaver, etc) or use the online [SQL Editor](https://neon.tech/docs/get-started-with-neon/query-with-neon-sql-editor/). See [Connect from any application](https://neon.tech/docs/connect/connect-from-any-app/) for connection instructions.

Alternatively, compile and run the project [locally](#running-local-installation).

## Architecture overview

A Neon installation consists of compute nodes and the Neon storage engine. Compute nodes are stateless PostgreSQL nodes backed by the Neon storage engine.

The Neon storage engine consists of two major components:
- Pageserver: Scalable storage backend for the compute nodes.
- Safekeepers: The safekeepers form a redundant WAL service that received WAL from the compute node, and stores it durably until it has been processed by the pageserver and uploaded to cloud storage.

See developer documentation in [SUMMARY.md](/docs/SUMMARY.md) for more information.

## Running a local development environment

Neon can be run on a workstation for small experiments and to test code changes, by
following these instructions.

#### Installing dependencies on Linux
1. Install build dependencies and other applicable packages

* On Ubuntu or Debian, this set of packages should be sufficient to build the code:
```bash
apt install build-essential libtool libreadline-dev zlib1g-dev flex bison libseccomp-dev \
libssl-dev clang pkg-config libpq-dev cmake postgresql-client protobuf-compiler \
libprotobuf-dev libcurl4-openssl-dev openssl python3-poetry lsof libicu-dev
```
* On Fedora, these packages are needed:
```bash
dnf install flex bison readline-devel zlib-devel openssl-devel \
  libseccomp-devel perl clang cmake postgresql postgresql-contrib protobuf-compiler \
  protobuf-devel libcurl-devel openssl poetry lsof libicu-devel libpq-devel python3-devel \
  libffi-devel
```
* On Arch based systems, these packages are needed:
```bash
pacman -S base-devel readline zlib libseccomp openssl clang \
postgresql-libs cmake postgresql protobuf curl lsof
```

Building Neon requires 3.15+ version of `protoc` (protobuf-compiler). If your distribution provides an older version, you can install a newer version from [here](https://github.com/protocolbuffers/protobuf/releases).

2. [Install Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install)
```
# recommended approach from https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh
```

#### Installing dependencies on macOS (12.3.1)
1. Install XCode and dependencies
```
xcode-select --install
brew install protobuf openssl flex bison icu4c pkg-config m4

# add openssl to PATH, required for ed25519 keys generation in neon_local
echo &#039;export PATH=&quot;$(brew --prefix openssl)/bin:$PATH&quot;&#039; &gt;&gt; ~/.zshrc
```

If you get errors about missing `m4` you may have to install it manually:
```
brew install m4
brew link --force m4
```

2. [Install Rust](https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install)
```
# recommended approach from https://www.rust-lang.org/tools/install
curl --proto &#039;=https&#039; --tlsv1.2 -sSf https://sh.rustup.rs | sh
```

3. Install PostgreSQL Client
```
# from https://stackoverflow.com/questions/44654216/correct-way-to-install-psql-without-full-postgres-on-macos
brew install libpq
brew link --force libpq
```

#### Rustc version

The project uses [rust toolchain file](./rust-toolchain.toml) to define the version it&#039;s built with in CI for testing and local builds.

This file is automatically picked up by [`rustup`](https://rust-lang.github.io/rustup/overrides.html#the-toolchain-file) that installs (if absent) and uses the toolchain version pinned in the file.

rustup users who want to build with another toolchain can use the [`rustup override`](https://rust-lang.github.io/rustup/overrides.html#directory-overrides) command to set a specific toolchain for the project&#039;s directory.

non-rustup users most probably are not getting the same toolchain automatically from the file, so are responsible to manually verify that their toolchain matches the version in the file.
Newer rustc versions most probably will work fine, yet older ones might not be supported due to some new features used by the project or the crates.

#### Building on Linux

1. Build neon and patched postgres
```
# Note: The path to the neon sources can not contain a space.

git clone --recursive https://github.com/neondatabase/neon.git
cd neon

# The preferred and default is to make a debug build. This will create a
# demonstrably slower build than a release build. For a release build,
# use &quot;BUILD_TYPE=release make -j`nproc` -s&quot;
# Remove -s for the verbose build log

make -j`nproc` -s
```

#### Building on OSX

1. Build neon and patched postgres
```
# Note: The path to the neon sources can not contain a space.

git clone --recursive https://github.com/neondatabase/neon.git
cd neon

# The preferred and default is to make a debug build. This will create a
# demonstrably slower build than a release build. For a release build,
# use &quot;BUILD_TYPE=release make -j`sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu` -s&quot;
# Remove -s for the verbose build log

make -j`sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu` -s
```

#### Dependency installation notes
To run the `psql` client, install the `postgresql-client` package or modify `PATH` and `LD_LIBRARY_PATH` to include `pg_install/bin` and `pg_install/lib`, respectively.

To run the integration tests or Python scripts (not required to use the code), install
Python (3.11 or higher), and install the python3 packages using `./scripts/pysync` (requires [poetry&gt;=1.8](https://python-poetry.org/)) in the project directory.


#### Running neon database
1. Start pageserver and postgres on top of it (should be called from repo root):
```sh
# Create repository in .neon with proper paths to binaries and data
# Later that would be responsibility of a package install script
&gt; cargo neon init
Initializing pageserver node 1 at &#039;127.0.0.1:64000&#039; in &quot;.neon&quot;

# start pageserver, safekeeper, and broker for their intercommunication
&gt; cargo neon start
Starting neon broker at 127.0.0.1:50051.
storage_broker started, pid: 2918372
Starting pageserver node 1 at &#039;127.0.0.1:64000&#039; in &quot;.neon&quot;.
pageserver started, pid: 2918386
Starting safekeeper at &#039;127.0.0.1:5454&#039; in &#039;.neon/safekeepers/sk1&#039;.
safekeeper 1 started, pid: 2918437

# create initial tenant and use it as a default for every future neon_local invocation
&gt; cargo neon tenant create --set-default
tenant 9ef87a5bf0d92544f6fafeeb3239695c successfully created on the pageserver
Created an initial timeline &#039;de200bd42b49cc1814412c7e592dd6e9&#039; at Lsn 0/16B5A50 for tenant: 9ef87a5bf0d92544f6fafeeb3239695c
Setting tenant 9ef87a5bf0d92544f6fafeeb3239695c as a default one

# create postgres compute node
&gt; cargo neon endpoint create main

# start postgres compute node
&gt; cargo neon endpoint start main
Starting new endpoint main (PostgreSQL v14) on timeline de200bd42b49cc1814412c7e592dd6e9 ...
Starting postgres at &#039;postgresql://cloud_admin@127.0.0.1:55432/postgres&#039;

# check list of running postgres instances
&gt; cargo neon endpoint list
 ENDPOINT  ADDRESS          TIMELINE                          BRANCH NAME  LSN        STATUS
 main      127.0.0.1:55432  de200bd42b49cc1814412c7e592dd6e9  main         0/16B5BA8  running
```

2. Now, it is possible to connect to postgres and run some queries:
```text
&gt; psql -p 55432 -h 127.0.0.1 -U cloud_admin postgres
postgres=# CREATE TABLE t(key int primary key, value text);
CREATE TABLE
postgres=# insert into t values(1,1);
INSERT 0 1
postgres=# select * from t;
 key | value
-----+-------
   1 | 1
(1 row)
```

3. And create branches and run postgres on them:
```sh
# create branch named migration_check
&gt; cargo neon timeline branch --branch-name migration_check
Created timeline &#039;b3b863fa45fa9e57e615f9f2d944e601&#039; at Lsn 0/16F9A00 for tenant: 9ef87a5bf0d92544f6fafeeb3239695c. Ancestor timeline: &#039;main&#039;

# check branches tree
&gt; cargo neon timeline list
(L) main [de200bd42b49cc1814412c7e592dd6e9]
(L) ┗━ @0/16F9A00: migration_check [b3b863fa45fa9e57e615f9f2d944e601]

# create postgres on that branch
&gt; cargo neon endpoint create migration_check --branch-name migration_check

# start postgres on that branch
&gt; cargo neon endpoint start migration_check
Starting new endpoint migration_check (PostgreSQL v14) on timeline b3b863fa45fa9e57e615f9f2d944e601 ...
Starting postgres at &#039;postgresql://cloud_admin@127.0.0.1:55434/postgres&#039;

# check the new list of running postgres instances
&gt; cargo neon endpoint list
 ENDPOINT         ADDRESS          TIMELINE                          BRANCH NAME      LSN        STATUS
 main             127.0.0.1:55432  de200bd42b49cc1814412c7e592dd6e9  main             0/16F9A38  running
 migration_check  127.0.0.1:55434  b3b863fa45fa9e57e615f9f2d944e601  migration_check  0/16F9A70  running

# this new postgres instance will have all the data from &#039;main&#039; postgres,
# but all modifications would not affect data in original postgres
&gt; psql -p 55434 -h 127.0.0.1 -U cloud_admin postgres
postgres=# select * from t;
 key | value
-----+-------
   1 | 1
(1 row)

postgres=# insert into t values(2,2);
INSERT 0 1

# check that the new change doesn&#039;t affect the &#039;main&#039; postgres
&gt; psql -p 55432 -h 127.0.0.1 -U cloud_admin postgres
postgres=# select * from t;
 key | value
-----+-------
   1 | 1
(1 row)
```

4. If you want to run tests afterwards (see below), you must stop all the running pageserver, safekeeper, and postgres instances
   you have just started. You can terminate them all with one command:
```sh
&gt; cargo neon stop
```

More advanced usages can be found at [Local Development Control Plane (`neon_local`))](./control_plane/README.md).

#### Handling build failures

If you encounter errors during setting up the initial tenant, it&#039;s best to stop everything (`cargo neon stop`) and remove the `.neon` directory. Then fix the problems, and start the setup again.

## Running tests

### Rust unit tests

We are using [`cargo-nextest`](https://nexte.st/) to run the tests in Github Workflows.
Some crates do not support running plain `cargo test` anymore, prefer `cargo nextest run` instead.
You can install `cargo-nextest` with `cargo install cargo-nextest`.

### Integration tests

Ensure your dependencies are installed as described [here](https://github.com/neondatabase/neon#dependency-installation-notes).

```sh
git clone --recursive https://github.com/neondatabase/neon.git

CARGO_BUILD_FLAGS=&quot;--features=testing&quot; make

./scripts/pytest
```

By default, this runs both debug and release modes, and all supported postgres versions. When
testing locally, it is convenient to run just one set of permutations, like this:

```sh
DEFAULT_PG_VERSION=17 BUILD_TYPE=release ./scripts/pytest
```

## Flamegraphs

You may find yourself in need of flamegraphs for software in this repository.
You can use [`flamegraph-rs`](https://github.com/flamegraph-rs/flamegraph) or the original [`flamegraph.pl`](https://github.com/brendangregg/FlameGraph). Your choice!

&gt;[!IMPORTANT]
&gt; If you&#039;re using `lld` or `mold`, you need the `--no-rosegment` linker argument.
&gt; It&#039;s a [general thing with Rust / lld / mold](https://crbug.com/919499#c16), not specific to this repository.
&gt; See [this PR for further instructions](https://github.com/neondatabase/neon/pull/6764).

## Cleanup

For cleaning up the source tree from build artifacts, run `make clean` in the source directory.

For removing every artifact from build and configure steps, run `make distclean`, and also consider removing the cargo binaries in the `target` directory, as well as the database in the `.neon` directory. Note that removing the `.neon` directory will remove your database, with all data in it. You have been warned!

## Documentation

[docs](/docs) Contains a top-level overview of all available markdown documentation.

- [sourcetree.md](/docs/sourcetree.md) contains overview of source tree layout.

To view your `rustdoc` documentation in a browser, try running `cargo doc --no-deps --open`

See also README files in some source directories, and `rustdoc` style documentation comments.

Other resources:

- [SELECT &#039;Hello, World&#039;](https://neon.tech/blog/hello-world/): Blog post by Nikita Shamgunov on the high level architecture
- [Architecture decisions in Neon](https://neon.tech/blog/architecture-decisions-in-neon/): Blog post by Heikki Linnakangas
- [Neon: Serverless PostgreSQL!](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rES0yzeERns): Presentation on storage system by Heikki Linnakangas in the CMU Database Group seminar series

### Postgres-specific terms

Due to Neon&#039;s very close relation with PostgreSQL internals, numerous specific terms are used.
The same applies to certain spelling: i.e. we use MB to denote 1024 * 1024 bytes, while MiB would be technically more correct, it&#039;s inconsistent with what PostgreSQL code and its documentation use.

To get more familiar with this aspect, refer to:

- [Neon glossary](/docs/glossary.md)
- [PostgreSQL glossary](https://www.postgresql.org/docs/14/glossary.html)
- Other PostgreSQL documentation and sources (Neon fork sources can be found [here](https://github.com/neondatabase/postgres))

## Join the development

- Read [CONTRIBUTING.md](/CONTRIBUTING.md) to learn about project code style and practices.
- To get familiar with a source tree layout, use [sourcetree.md](/docs/sourcetree.md).
- To learn more about PostgreSQL internals, check http://www.interdb.jp/pg/index.html
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rust-lang/rust-clippy]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A bunch of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your Rust code. Book: https://doc.rust-lang.org/clippy/]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy">rust-lang/rust-clippy</a></h1>
            <p>A bunch of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your Rust code. Book: https://doc.rust-lang.org/clippy/</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,909</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,626</p>
            <p>Stars today: 4 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Clippy

[![License: MIT OR Apache-2.0](https://img.shields.io/crates/l/clippy.svg)](#license)

A collection of lints to catch common mistakes and improve your [Rust](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust) code.

[There are over 750 lints included in this crate!](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html)

Lints are divided into categories, each with a default [lint level](https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/lints/levels.html).
You can choose how much Clippy is supposed to ~~annoy~~ help you by changing the lint level by category.

| Category              | Description                                                                         | Default level |
|-----------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|---------------|
| `clippy::all`         | all lints that are on by default (correctness, suspicious, style, complexity, perf) | **warn/deny** |
| `clippy::correctness` | code that is outright wrong or useless                                              | **deny**      |
| `clippy::suspicious`  | code that is most likely wrong or useless                                           | **warn**      |
| `clippy::style`       | code that should be written in a more idiomatic way                                 | **warn**      |
| `clippy::complexity`  | code that does something simple but in a complex way                                | **warn**      |
| `clippy::perf`        | code that can be written to run faster                                              | **warn**      |
| `clippy::pedantic`    | lints which are rather strict or have occasional false positives                    | allow         |
| `clippy::restriction` | lints which prevent the use of language and library features[^restrict]             | allow         |
| `clippy::nursery`     | new lints that are still under development                                          | allow         |
| `clippy::cargo`       | lints for the cargo manifest                                                        | allow         |

More to come, please [file an issue](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/issues) if you have ideas!

The `restriction` category should, *emphatically*, not be enabled as a whole. The contained
lints may lint against perfectly reasonable code, may not have an alternative suggestion,
and may contradict any other lints (including other categories). Lints should be considered
on a case-by-case basis before enabling.

[^restrict]: Some use cases for `restriction` lints include:
    - Strict coding styles (e.g. [`clippy::else_if_without_else`]).
    - Additional restrictions on CI (e.g. [`clippy::todo`]).
    - Preventing panicking in certain functions (e.g. [`clippy::unwrap_used`]).
    - Running a lint only on a subset of code (e.g. `#[forbid(clippy::float_arithmetic)]` on a module).

[`clippy::else_if_without_else`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#else_if_without_else
[`clippy::todo`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#todo
[`clippy::unwrap_used`]: https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#unwrap_used

---

Table of contents:

* [Usage instructions](#usage)
* [Configuration](#configuration)
* [Contributing](#contributing)
* [License](#license)

## Usage

Below are instructions on how to use Clippy as a cargo subcommand,
in projects that do not use cargo, or in Travis CI.

### As a cargo subcommand (`cargo clippy`)

One way to use Clippy is by installing Clippy through rustup as a cargo
subcommand.

#### Step 1: Install Rustup

You can install [Rustup](https://rustup.rs/) on supported platforms. This will help
us install Clippy and its dependencies.

If you already have Rustup installed, update to ensure you have the latest
Rustup and compiler:

```terminal
rustup update
```

#### Step 2: Install Clippy

Once you have rustup and the latest stable release (at least Rust 1.29) installed, run the following command:

```terminal
rustup component add clippy
```

If it says that it can&#039;t find the `clippy` component, please run `rustup self update`.

#### Step 3: Run Clippy

Now you can run Clippy by invoking the following command:

```terminal
cargo clippy
```

#### Automatically applying Clippy suggestions

Clippy can automatically apply some lint suggestions, just like the compiler. Note that `--fix` implies
`--all-targets`, so it can fix as much code as it can.

```terminal
cargo clippy --fix
```

#### Workspaces

All the usual workspace options should work with Clippy. For example the following command
will run Clippy on the `example` crate:

```terminal
cargo clippy -p example
```

As with `cargo check`, this includes dependencies that are members of the workspace, like path dependencies.
If you want to run Clippy **only** on the given crate, use the `--no-deps` option like this:

```terminal
cargo clippy -p example -- --no-deps
```

### Using `clippy-driver`

Clippy can also be used in projects that do not use cargo. To do so, run `clippy-driver`
with the same arguments you use for `rustc`. For example:

```terminal
clippy-driver --edition 2018 -Cpanic=abort foo.rs
```

Note that `clippy-driver` is designed for running Clippy only and should not be used as a general
replacement for `rustc`. `clippy-driver` may produce artifacts that are not optimized as expected,
for example.

### Travis CI

You can add Clippy to Travis CI in the same way you use it locally:

```yaml
language: rust
rust:
  - stable
  - beta
before_script:
  - rustup component add clippy
script:
  - cargo clippy
  # if you want the build job to fail when encountering warnings, use
  - cargo clippy -- -D warnings
  # in order to also check tests and non-default crate features, use
  - cargo clippy --all-targets --all-features -- -D warnings
  - cargo test
  # etc.
```

Note that adding `-D warnings` will cause your build to fail if **any** warnings are found in your code.
That includes warnings found by rustc (e.g. `dead_code`, etc.). If you want to avoid this and only cause
an error for Clippy warnings, use `#![deny(clippy::all)]` in your code or `-D clippy::all` on the command
line. (You can swap `clippy::all` with the specific lint category you are targeting.)

## Configuration

### Allowing/denying lints

You can add options to your code to `allow`/`warn`/`deny` Clippy lints:

* the whole set of `Warn` lints using the `clippy` lint group (`#![deny(clippy::all)]`).
  Note that `rustc` has additional [lint groups](https://doc.rust-lang.org/rustc/lints/groups.html).

* all lints using both the `clippy` and `clippy::pedantic` lint groups (`#![deny(clippy::all)]`,
  `#![deny(clippy::pedantic)]`). Note that `clippy::pedantic` contains some very aggressive
  lints prone to false positives.

* only some lints (`#![deny(clippy::single_match, clippy::box_vec)]`, etc.)

* `allow`/`warn`/`deny` can be limited to a single function or module using `#[allow(...)]`, etc.

Note: `allow` means to suppress the lint for your code. With `warn` the lint
will only emit a warning, while with `deny` the lint will emit an error, when
triggering for your code. An error causes Clippy to exit with an error code, so
is useful in scripts like CI/CD.

If you do not want to include your lint levels in your code, you can globally
enable/disable lints by passing extra flags to Clippy during the run:

To allow `lint_name`, run

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -A clippy::lint_name
```

And to warn on `lint_name`, run

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -W clippy::lint_name
```

This also works with lint groups. For example, you
can run Clippy with warnings for all lints enabled:

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -W clippy::pedantic
```

If you care only about a single lint, you can allow all others and then explicitly warn on
the lint(s) you are interested in:

```terminal
cargo clippy -- -A clippy::all -W clippy::useless_format -W clippy::...
```

### Configure the behavior of some lints

Some lints can be configured in a TOML file named `clippy.toml` or `.clippy.toml`. It contains a basic `variable =
value` mapping e.g.

```toml
avoid-breaking-exported-api = false
disallowed-names = [&quot;toto&quot;, &quot;tata&quot;, &quot;titi&quot;]
```

The [table of configurations](https://doc.rust-lang.org/nightly/clippy/lint_configuration.html)
contains all config values, their default, and a list of lints they affect.
Each [configurable lint](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#Configuration)
, also contains information about these values.

For configurations that are a list type with default values such as
[disallowed-names](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#disallowed_names),
you can use the unique value `&quot;..&quot;` to extend the default values instead of replacing them.

```toml
# default of disallowed-names is [&quot;foo&quot;, &quot;baz&quot;, &quot;quux&quot;]
disallowed-names = [&quot;bar&quot;, &quot;..&quot;] # -&gt; [&quot;bar&quot;, &quot;foo&quot;, &quot;baz&quot;, &quot;quux&quot;]
```

&gt; **Note**
&gt;
&gt; `clippy.toml` or `.clippy.toml` cannot be used to allow/deny lints.

To deactivate the “for further information visit *lint-link*” message you can
define the `CLIPPY_DISABLE_DOCS_LINKS` environment variable.

### Specifying the minimum supported Rust version

Projects that intend to support old versions of Rust can disable lints pertaining to newer features by
specifying the minimum supported Rust version (MSRV) in the Clippy configuration file.

```toml
msrv = &quot;1.30.0&quot;
```

Alternatively, the [`rust-version` field](https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/reference/manifest.html#the-rust-version-field)
in the `Cargo.toml` can be used.

```toml
# Cargo.toml
rust-version = &quot;1.30&quot;
```

The MSRV can also be specified as an attribute, like below.

```rust,ignore
#![feature(custom_inner_attributes)]
#![clippy::msrv = &quot;1.30.0&quot;]

fn main() {
  ...
}
```

You can also omit the patch version when specifying the MSRV, so `msrv = 1.30`
is equivalent to `msrv = 1.30.0`.

Note: `custom_inner_attributes` is an unstable feature, so it has to be enabled explicitly.

Lints that recognize this configuration option can be found [here](https://rust-lang.github.io/rust-clippy/master/index.html#msrv)

## Contributing

If you want to contribute to Clippy, you can find more information in [CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-clippy/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md).

## License

&lt;!-- REUSE-IgnoreStart --&gt;

Copyright 2014-2025 The Rust Project Developers

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 &lt;LICENSE-APACHE or
[https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0](https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0)&gt; or the MIT license
&lt;LICENSE-MIT or [https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT](https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT)&gt;, at your
option. Files in the project may not be
copied, modified, or distributed except according to those terms.

&lt;!-- REUSE-IgnoreEnd --&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[flxzt/rnote]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/flxzt/rnote</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/flxzt/rnote</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Sketch and take handwritten notes.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/flxzt/rnote">flxzt/rnote</a></h1>
            <p>Sketch and take handwritten notes.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,340</p>
            <p>Forks: 337</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/crates/rnote-ui/data/icons/scalable/apps/rnote.svg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/actions/workflows/ci.yml&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;CI&quot;src=&quot;https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://liberapay.com/flxzt/donate&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Donate using Liberapay&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/assets/liberapay-donate-button.svg&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; height=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


# Rnote

&gt; Sketch and take handwritten notes.  

Rnote is an open-source vector-based drawing app for sketching, handwritten notes and to annotate documents and pictures.
It is targeted at students, teachers and those who own a drawing tablet and provides features like Pdf and picture import and export,
an infinite canvas and an adaptive UI for big and small screens.

Written in Rust and GTK4.

**Features**

- Adaptive UI focused on stylus input
- Pressure-sensitive stylus input with different and configurable stroke styles
- Create many different shapes with the shape tool
- Move, rotate, resize and modify existing content with the selection tool
- Different document expansion layouts ( fixed pages, continuous vertical, infinite in every direction, .. )
- Customizable background colors, patterns, sizes
- Customizable page format
- (Optional) pen sounds
- Reconfigurable stylus button shortcuts
- An integrated workspace browser for quick access to related files
- Drag &amp; Drop, clipboard support
- Pdf, Bitmap and Svg image import
- Documents can be exported to Svg, Pdf and Xopp. Document pages and selections to Svg, Png and Jpeg.
- Save and load the documents in the native `.rnote` file format
- Tabs to work on multiple documents at the same time
- Autosave, printing

**Disclaimer**

The file format is still unstable. It might change and break compatibility between versions.

## Website

Rnote has a project website: [rnote.flxzt.net](https://rnote.flxzt.net/)

## Installation

### Linux

Download the official flatpak on Flathub [here](https://flathub.org/apps/details/com.github.flxzt.rnote).

&lt;div align=&quot;start&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#039;https://flathub.org/apps/details/com.github.flxzt.rnote&#039;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;250&quot; alt=&#039;Download on Flathub&#039; src=&#039;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/assets/flathub-badge.svg&#039;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;

### MacOS

Thanks to @dehesselle the app is available on MacOS as an app bundle.  
Check out the [repository](https://gitlab.com/dehesselle/rnote_macos), the latest release can be downloaded [here](https://gitlab.com/dehesselle/rnote_macos/-/releases/permalink/latest).

&lt;div align=&quot;start&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#039;https://gitlab.com/dehesselle/rnote_macos/-/releases/permalink/latest&#039;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;150&quot; alt=&#039;Download MacOS app bundle&#039; src=&#039;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/assets/rnote-macos-app-bundle-badge.png&#039;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;

### Windows

Download the Windows installer from the latest release which can be found [here](https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/releases/latest).

&lt;div align=&quot;start&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#039;https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/releases/latest&#039;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;250&quot; alt=&#039;Download Windows installer&#039; src=&#039;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/assets/windows-installer-badge.svg&#039;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;

Install using [Winget](https://github.com/microsoft/winget-pkgs/tree/master/manifests/f/flxzt/rnote):

```
winget install flxzt.rnote
```

### Downgrading

Because the file format still is unstable, downgrading to a specific version might be necessary.

List all available past versions on flathub:

```bash
flatpak remote-info --log flathub com.github.flxzt.rnote
```

Pick the commit from the desired version and downgrade with:

```bash
sudo flatpak update --commit=&lt;commit-hash&gt; com.github.flxzt.rnote 
```

After downgrading, the flatpak version can be pinned or unpinned with:

```
$ flatpak mask com.github.flxzt.rnote
$ flatpak mask --remove com.github.flxzt.rnote
```

To update to the latest version again, unpin and run `flatpak update`.

## Screenshots

![overview](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/overview.png)  
![selection](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/selection.png)  
![typewriter](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/typewriter.png)  
![focus-mode](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/focus-mode.png)  
![workspaces](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/workspaces.png)  
![document-settings](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/document-settings.png)  
![action-shortcuts](./crates/rnote-ui/data/screenshots/action-shortcuts.png)  

## Pitfalls &amp; Known Issues

* Drag &amp; Drop not working -  
    Make sure Rnote has permissions to the locations you are dragging files from. Can be granted in Flatseal (a Flatpak permissions manager)

* Odd location for current file -  
    When the directory displayed in the header title is something like `/run/user/1000/../`, rnote does not have permissions to access the directory. Again, granting them in Flatseal fixes this issue.

* Stylus buttons move canvas / are not functional -  
    Make sure that the `xf86-input-wacom`, drivers on X11 and `libinput` on Wayland and `libwacom` are installed and loaded.

* While hovering with the stylus, other input events are blocked in some regions of the screen -  
    Supposed to be palm rejection, but might be undesirable. If there is a left- / righthanded system tablet setting, make sure it is set correctly. Rnote can&#039;t disable this unfortunately. ( discussed in issue [#329](https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/issues/329) )

* One of the stylus buttons shortcut mapping does not work as intended -  
On some devices one stylus button is mapped to a dedicated &quot;Eraser&quot; mode (which is the back-side on other styli). The buttons in the shortcuts settings could then be inconsistent ( the secondary / upper button is actually the primary / lower button , or reverse ). To change the tool that is mapped to this &quot;Eraser&quot; mode, do the following:  
    * Hover over the canvas, and press and hold the button that is suspected to be mapped to the &quot;Eraser&quot; mode
    * Switch to the desired pen style while keeping the button pressed
    * When releasing the pressed button, it should switch back to the previous pen style
    * The pen style in the &quot;Eraser&quot; mode should now be remembered

## Translations

&lt;a href=&quot;https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/rnote/&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/rnote/-/repo/multi-auto.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Translation status&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

If you want to start contribute by translating, take a look into the [translations section](./CONTRIBUTING.md#Translations)
of the CONTRIBUTING document.

## Fonts

The following fonts are bundled with the application:

- [Grape Nuts](https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Grape+Nuts): Grape Nuts is a simple handwritten casual font.
- [OpenDyslexic-Regular](https://github.com/antijingoist/opendyslexic): OpenDyslexic is a typeface designed against some
    common symptoms of dyslexia.
- [TT2020Base-Regular](https://github.com/ctrlcctrlv/TT2020): TT2020 is an advanced, open source, hyperrealistic,
    multilingual typewriter font for a new decade.
- [Virgil](https://virgil.excalidraw.com/): The font that powers Excalidraw.

## File Format

The `.rnote` file format is a gzipped json file.

So far breaking changes in the format happened in versions:

- `v0.2.0`
- `v0.3.0`
- `v0.4.0`
- `v0.5.0`

To be able to open and export older files that are incompatible with the newest version, look under **Installation** /**Downgrading** to install older versions of Rnote.

## License

Rnote is available under GPL-3.0-or-later. See the LICENSE file for more info.

    Copyright (C) 2023  The Rnote Authors

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
    (at your option) any later version.

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see &lt;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.

## Credits

- A huge thanks to the contributors, translators and to all that donated. You are the ones that help keep the project going!
- [Freesound](https://freesound.org/) is the source for the pen sounds. The individual sounds are credited in `sounds/Licenses.md`
- [Rough.js](https://roughjs.com/) provides the algorithms for implementation of Rnote&#039;s rough shapes.
- [Pizarra](https://pizarra.categulario.xyz/en/) is an innovative drawing app with advanced shaping and featuring an infinite zoom. It is a great inspiration of the architecture of Rnote. Go check it out!


## Community

If you have any questions or want to start a general discussion, open a topic in the [Github Discussions](https://github.com/flxzt/rnote/discussions) section.

There are also two Matrix chat rooms:
- for users: [#rnote:matrix.org](https://matrix.to/#/#rnote:matrix.org)
- for developers: [#rnote-dev:matrix.org](https://matrix.to/#/#rnote-dev:matrix.org)

## Drawings Created With Rnote

If you have drawn something cool in Rnote and want to share it, submit a PR to add it here. :)  

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; spacing=&quot;20px&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Pikachu&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/drawings/pikachu.png&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Love&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/drawings/love.png&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Suits&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/drawings/suits.png&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Nature&#039;s cat&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flxzt/rnote/main/misc/drawings/natureza_gato.png&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;

## Building

Build instructions for Linux are documented in [BUILDING.md](./BUILDING.md) and for other platforms [here](./misc/building)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[zed-industries/zed]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/zed-industries/zed</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/zed-industries/zed</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Code at the speed of thought – Zed is a high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of Atom and Tree-sitter.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/zed-industries/zed">zed-industries/zed</a></h1>
            <p>Code at the speed of thought – Zed is a high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of Atom and Tree-sitter.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 57,106</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,909</p>
            <p>Stars today: 47 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Zed

[![CI](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/actions/workflows/ci.yml)

Welcome to Zed, a high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of [Atom](https://github.com/atom/atom) and [Tree-sitter](https://github.com/tree-sitter/tree-sitter).

---

### Installation

&lt;a href=&quot;https://repology.org/project/zed-editor/versions&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://repology.org/badge/vertical-allrepos/zed-editor.svg?minversion=0.143.5&quot; alt=&quot;Packaging status&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

On macOS and Linux you can [download Zed directly](https://zed.dev/download) or [install Zed via your local package manager](https://zed.dev/docs/linux#installing-via-a-package-manager).

Other platforms are not yet available:

- Windows ([tracking issue](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/issues/5394))
- Web ([tracking issue](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/issues/5396))

### Developing Zed

- [Building Zed for macOS](./docs/src/development/macos.md)
- [Building Zed for Linux](./docs/src/development/linux.md)
- [Building Zed for Windows](./docs/src/development/windows.md)
- [Running Collaboration Locally](./docs/src/development/local-collaboration.md)

### Contributing

See [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) for ways you can contribute to Zed.

Also... we&#039;re hiring! Check out our [jobs](https://zed.dev/jobs) page for open roles.

### Licensing

License information for third party dependencies must be correctly provided for CI to pass.

We use [`cargo-about`](https://github.com/EmbarkStudios/cargo-about) to automatically comply with open source licenses. If CI is failing, check the following:

- Is it showing a `no license specified` error for a crate you&#039;ve created? If so, add `publish = false` under `[package]` in your crate&#039;s Cargo.toml.
- Is the error `failed to satisfy license requirements` for a dependency? If so, first determine what license the project has and whether this system is sufficient to comply with this license&#039;s requirements. If you&#039;re unsure, ask a lawyer. Once you&#039;ve verified that this system is acceptable add the license&#039;s SPDX identifier to the `accepted` array in `script/licenses/zed-licenses.toml`.
- Is `cargo-about` unable to find the license for a dependency? If so, add a clarification field at the end of `script/licenses/zed-licenses.toml`, as specified in the [cargo-about book](https://embarkstudios.github.io/cargo-about/cli/generate/config.html#crate-configuration).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YaLTeR/niri]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A scrollable-tiling Wayland compositor.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri">YaLTeR/niri</a></h1>
            <p>A scrollable-tiling Wayland compositor.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,789</p>
            <p>Forks: 227</p>
            <p>Stars today: 20 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;niri&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;A scrollable-tiling Wayland compositor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/#niri:matrix.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Matrix&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/matrix-%23niri-blue?logo=matrix&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub License&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/YaLTeR/niri&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/releases&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Release&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/YaLTeR/niri?logo=github&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Getting-Started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Configuration:-Overview&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/discussions/325&quot;&gt;Setup&amp;nbsp;Showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

![niri with a few windows open](https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/d142e57d-a25d-4ddb-ab46-311417458211)

## About

Windows are arranged in columns on an infinite strip going to the right.
Opening a new window never causes existing windows to resize.

Every monitor has its own separate window strip.
Windows can never &quot;overflow&quot; onto an adjacent monitor.

Workspaces are dynamic and arranged vertically.
Every monitor has an independent set of workspaces, and there&#039;s always one empty workspace present all the way down.

The workspace arrangement is preserved across disconnecting and connecting monitors where it makes sense.
When a monitor disconnects, its workspaces will move to another monitor, but upon reconnection they will move back to the original monitor.

## Features

- Built from the ground up for scrollable tiling
- [Dynamic workspaces](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Workspaces) like in GNOME
- Built-in screenshot UI
- Monitor and window screencasting through xdg-desktop-portal-gnome
    - You can [block out](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Configuration:-Window-Rules#block-out-from) sensitive windows from screencasts
- [Touchpad](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/assets/1794388/946a910e-9bec-4cd1-a923-4a9421707515) and [mouse](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/assets/1794388/8464e65d-4bf2-44fa-8c8e-5883355bd000) gestures
- Group windows into [tabs](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Tabs)
- Configurable layout: gaps, borders, struts, window sizes
- [Gradient borders](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Configuration:-Layout#gradients) with Oklab and Oklch support
- [Animations](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/assets/1794388/ce178da2-af9e-4c51-876f-8709c241d95e) with support for [custom shaders](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/assets/1794388/27a238d6-0a22-4692-b794-30dc7a626fad)
- Live-reloading config

## Video Demo

https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/assets/1794388/bce834b0-f205-434e-a027-b373495f9729

## Status

Niri is stable for day-to-day use and does most things expected of a Wayland compositor.
Many people are daily-driving niri, and are happy to help in our [Matrix channel].

Give it a try!
Follow the instructions on the [Getting Started](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Getting-Started) wiki page.
Have your [waybar]s and [fuzzel]s ready: niri is not a complete desktop environment.

Here are some points you may have questions about:

- **Multi-monitor**: yes, a core part of the design from the very start. Mixed DPI works.
- **Fractional scaling**: yes, plus all niri UI stays pixel-perfect.
- **NVIDIA**: seems to work fine.
- **Floating windows**: yes, starting from niri 25.01.
- **Input devices**: niri supports tablets, touchpads, and touchscreens.
You can map the tablet to a specific monitor, or use [OpenTabletDriver].
We have touchpad gestures, but no touchscreen gestures yet.
- **Wlr protocols**: yes, we have most of the important ones like layer-shell, gamma-control, screencopy.
You can check on [wayland.app](https://wayland.app) at the bottom of each protocol&#039;s page.
- **Performance**: while I run niri on beefy machines, I try to stay conscious of performance.
I&#039;ve seen someone use it fine on an Eee PC 900 from 2008, of all things.
- **Xwayland**: no built-in support, but xwayland-satellite is [easy to set up](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Xwayland#using-xwayland-satellite) and works very well.
    - Steam and games, including Proton: work perfectly through xwayland-satellite.
    - JetBrains IDEs, Ghidra: work well through xwayland-satellite.
    - Discord and other Electron apps: work well through xwayland-satellite.
    - Chromium and VSCode: work perfectly natively on Wayland with the right flags.
    - X11 apps that want to position windows or bars at specific screen coordinates: won&#039;t work well; you can run them in a nested compositor like [labwc](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Xwayland#using-the-labwc-wayland-compositor) or [rootful Xwayland](https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri/wiki/Xwayland#directly-running-xwayland-in-rootful-mode).
    - Display scaling (integer or fractional) will make X11 apps look blurry; this needs to be supported in xwayland-satellite.
    For games, you can run them in [gamescope] at native resolution, even with display scaling.

## Inspiration

Niri is heavily inspired by [PaperWM] which implements scrollable tiling on top of GNOME Shell.

One of the reasons that prompted me to try writing my own compositor is being able to properly separate the monitors.
Being a GNOME Shell extension, PaperWM has to work against Shell&#039;s global window coordinate space to prevent windows from overflowing.

## Tile Scrollably Elsewhere

Here are some other projects which implement a similar workflow:

- [PaperWM]: scrollable tiling on top of GNOME Shell.
- [karousel]: scrollable tiling on top of KDE.
- [papersway]: scrollable tiling on top of sway/i3.
- [hyprscroller] and [hyprslidr]: scrollable tiling on top of Hyprland.
- [PaperWM.spoon]: scrollable tiling on top of macOS.

## Media

[niri: Making a Wayland compositor in Rust](https://youtu.be/Kmz8ODolnDg?list=PLRdS-n5seLRqrmWDQY4KDqtRMfIwU0U3T)

My talk from the 2024 Moscow RustCon about niri, and how I do randomized property testing and profiling, and measure input latency.
The talk is in Russian, but I prepared full English subtitles that you can find in YouTube&#039;s subtitle language selector.

## Contact

We have a Matrix chat, feel free to join and ask a question: https://matrix.to/#/#niri:matrix.org

[PaperWM]: https://github.com/paperwm/PaperWM
[waybar]: https://github.com/Alexays/Waybar
[fuzzel]: https://codeberg.org/dnkl/fuzzel
[karousel]: https://github.com/peterfajdiga/karousel
[papersway]: https://spwhitton.name/tech/code/papersway/
[hyprscroller]: https://github.com/dawsers/hyprscroller
[hyprslidr]: https://gitlab.com/magus/hyprslidr
[PaperWM.spoon]: https://github.com/mogenson/PaperWM.spoon
[Matrix channel]: https://matrix.to/#/#niri:matrix.org
[OpenTabletDriver]: https://opentabletdriver.net/
[gamescope]: https://github.com/ValveSoftware/gamescope
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[cloudflare/pingora]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/cloudflare/pingora</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/cloudflare/pingora</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A library for building fast, reliable and evolvable network services.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/cloudflare/pingora">cloudflare/pingora</a></h1>
            <p>A library for building fast, reliable and evolvable network services.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 23,815</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,350</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Pingora

![Pingora banner image](./docs/assets/pingora_banner.png)

## What is Pingora
Pingora is a Rust framework to [build fast, reliable and programmable networked systems](https://blog.cloudflare.com/pingora-open-source).

Pingora is battle tested as it has been serving more than 40 million Internet requests per second for [more than a few years](https://blog.cloudflare.com/how-we-built-pingora-the-proxy-that-connects-cloudflare-to-the-internet).

## Feature highlights
* Async Rust: fast and reliable
* HTTP 1/2 end to end proxy
* TLS over OpenSSL, BoringSSL or rustls(experimental).
* gRPC and websocket proxying
* Graceful reload
* Customizable load balancing and failover strategies
* Support for a variety of observability tools

## Reasons to use Pingora
* **Security** is your top priority: Pingora is a more memory safe alternative for services that are written in C/C++
* Your service is **performance-sensitive**: Pingora is fast and efficient
* Your service requires extensive **customization**: The APIs Pingora proxy framework provides are highly programmable

# Getting started

See our [quick starting guide](./docs/quick_start.md) to see how easy it is to build a load balancer.

Our [user guide](./docs/user_guide/index.md) covers more topics such as how to configure and run Pingora servers, as well as how to build custom HTTP servers and proxy logic on top of Pingora&#039;s framework.

API docs are also available for all the crates.

# Notable crates in this workspace
* Pingora: the &quot;public facing&quot; crate to build networked systems and proxies
* Pingora-core: this crate defines the protocols, functionalities and basic traits
* Pingora-proxy: the logic and APIs to build HTTP proxies
* Pingora-error: the common error type used across Pingora crates
* Pingora-http: the HTTP header definitions and APIs
* Pingora-openssl &amp; pingora-boringssl: SSL related extensions and APIs
* Pingora-ketama: the [Ketama](https://github.com/RJ/ketama) consistent algorithm
* Pingora-limits: efficient counting algorithms
* Pingora-load-balancing: load balancing algorithm extensions for pingora-proxy
* Pingora-memory-cache: Async in-memory caching with cache lock to prevent cache stampede
* Pingora-timeout: A more efficient async timer system
* TinyUfo: The caching algorithm behind pingora-memory-cache

# System requirements

## Systems
Linux is our tier 1 environment and main focus.

We will try our best for most code to compile for Unix environments. This is for developers and users to have an easier time developing with Pingora in Unix-like environments like macOS (though some features might be missing)

Windows support is preliminary by community&#039;s best effort only.

Both x86_64 and aarch64 architectures will be supported.

## Rust version

Pingora keeps a rolling MSRV (minimum supported Rust version) policy of 6 months. This means we will accept PRs that upgrade the MSRV as long as the new Rust version used is at least 6 months old.

Our current MSRV is 1.72.

Building with the optional feature `boringssl` with Boring &gt;= 4.14 requires Rust 1.80.

## Build Requirements

Some of the crates in this repository have dependencies on additional tools and
libraries that must be satisfied in order to build them:

* Make sure that [Clang] is installed on your system (for boringssl)
* Make sure that [Perl 5] is installed on your system (for openssl)

[Clang]:https://clang.llvm.org/
[Perl 5]:https://www.perl.org/

# Contributing
Please see our [contribution guidelines](./.github/CONTRIBUTING.md).

# License
This project is Licensed under [Apache License, Version 2.0](./LICENSE).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[rust-lang/book]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/rust-lang/book</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/rust-lang/book</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Rust Programming Language]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/book">rust-lang/book</a></h1>
            <p>The Rust Programming Language</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 15,981</p>
            <p>Forks: 3,592</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># The Rust Programming Language

![Build Status](https://github.com/rust-lang/book/workflows/CI/badge.svg)

This repository contains the source of &quot;The Rust Programming Language&quot; book.

[The book is available in dead-tree form from No Starch Press][nostarch].

[nostarch]: https://nostarch.com/rust-programming-language-2nd-edition

You can also read the book for free online. Please see the book as shipped with
the latest [stable], [beta], or [nightly] Rust releases. Be aware that issues
in those versions may have been fixed in this repository already, as those
releases are updated less frequently.

[stable]: https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/book/
[beta]: https://doc.rust-lang.org/beta/book/
[nightly]: https://doc.rust-lang.org/nightly/book/

See the [releases] to download just the code of all the code listings that appear in the book.

[releases]: https://github.com/rust-lang/book/releases

## Requirements

Building the book requires [mdBook], ideally the same version that
rust-lang/rust uses in [this file][rust-mdbook]. To get it:

[mdBook]: https://github.com/rust-lang/mdBook
[rust-mdbook]: https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/src/tools/rustbook/Cargo.toml

```bash
$ cargo install mdbook --locked --version &lt;version_num&gt;
```

The book also uses two mdbook plugins which are part of this repository. If you
do not install them, you will see warnings when building and the output will not
look right, but you _will_ still be able to build the book. To use the plugins,
you should run:

```bash
$ cargo install --locked --path packages/mdbook-trpl
```

## Building

To build the book, type:

```bash
$ mdbook build
```

The output will be in the `book` subdirectory. To check it out, open it in
your web browser.

_Firefox:_

```bash
$ firefox book/index.html                       # Linux
$ open -a &quot;Firefox&quot; book/index.html             # OS X
$ Start-Process &quot;firefox.exe&quot; .\book\index.html # Windows (PowerShell)
$ start firefox.exe .\book\index.html           # Windows (Cmd)
```

_Chrome:_

```bash
$ google-chrome book/index.html                 # Linux
$ open -a &quot;Google Chrome&quot; book/index.html       # OS X
$ Start-Process &quot;chrome.exe&quot; .\book\index.html  # Windows (PowerShell)
$ start chrome.exe .\book\index.html            # Windows (Cmd)
```

To run the tests:

```bash
$ cd packages/trpl
$ mdbook test --library-path packages/trpl/target/debug/deps
```

## Contributing

We&#039;d love your help! Please see [CONTRIBUTING.md][contrib] to learn about the
kinds of contributions we&#039;re looking for.

[contrib]: https://github.com/rust-lang/book/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md

Because the book is [printed][nostarch], and because we want
to keep the online version of the book close to the print version when
possible, it may take longer than you&#039;re used to for us to address your issue
or pull request.

So far, we&#039;ve been doing a larger revision to coincide with [Rust Editions](https://doc.rust-lang.org/edition-guide/). Between those larger
revisions, we will only be correcting errors. If your issue or pull request
isn&#039;t strictly fixing an error, it might sit until the next time that we&#039;re
working on a large revision: expect on the order of months or years. Thank you
for your patience!

### Translations

We&#039;d love help translating the book! See the [Translations] label to join in
efforts that are currently in progress. Open a new issue to start working on
a new language! We&#039;re waiting on [mdbook support] for multiple languages
before we merge any in, but feel free to start!

[Translations]: https://github.com/rust-lang/book/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+label%3ATranslations
[mdbook support]: https://github.com/rust-lang/mdBook/issues/5

## Spellchecking

To scan source files for spelling errors, you can use the `spellcheck.sh`
script available in the `ci` directory. It needs a dictionary of valid words,
which is provided in `ci/dictionary.txt`. If the script produces a false
positive (say, you used the word `BTreeMap` which the script considers invalid),
you need to add this word to `ci/dictionary.txt` (keep the sorted order for
consistency).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[slint-ui/slint]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/slint-ui/slint</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/slint-ui/slint</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Slint is a declarative GUI toolkit to build native user interfaces for Rust, C++, or JavaScript apps.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/slint-ui/slint">slint-ui/slint</a></h1>
            <p>Slint is a declarative GUI toolkit to build native user interfaces for Rust, C++, or JavaScript apps.</p>
            <p>Language: Rust</p>
            <p>Stars: 18,845</p>
            <p>Forks: 657</p>
            <p>Stars today: 13 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!-- Copyright © SixtyFPS GmbH &lt;info@slint.dev&gt; ; SPDX-License-Identifier: GPL-3.0-only OR LicenseRef-Slint-Royalty-free-2.0 OR LicenseRef-Slint-Software-3.0 --&gt;

![Slint](./logo/slint-logo-full-light.svg#gh-light-mode-only) ![Slint](./logo/slint-logo-full-dark.svg#gh-dark-mode-only)

[![Build Status](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/workflows/CI/badge.svg)](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/actions)
[![REUSE status](https://api.reuse.software/badge/github.com/slint-ui/slint)](https://api.reuse.software/info/github.com/slint-ui/slint)
[![Discussions](https://img.shields.io/github/discussions/slint-ui/slint)](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/discussions)

Slint is a declarative GUI toolkit to build native user interfaces for embedded,
desktop, and mobile applications written in Rust, C++, JavaScript, or Python.

The name *Slint* is derived from our design goals:

- **Scalable**: Slint should support responsive UI design, allow cross-platform
    usage across operating systems and processor architectures and support
    multiple programming languages.
- **Lightweight**: Slint should require minimal resources, in terms of memory
    and processing power, and yet deliver a smooth, smartphone-like user
    experience on any device.
- **Intuitive**: Designers and developers should feel productive while enjoying
    the GUI design and development process. The design creation tools should be
    intuitive to use for the designers. Similarly for the developers, the APIs
    should be consistent and easy to use, no matter which programming language
    they choose.
- **Native**: GUI built with Slint should match the end users&#039; expectations of a
    native application irrespective of the platform - desktop, mobile, web or
    embedded system. The UI design should be compiled to machine code and provide
    flexibility that only a native application can offer: Access full operating
    system APIs, utilize all CPU and GPU cores, connect to any peripheral.

Visit [#MadeWithSlint](https://madewithslint.com) to view some of the projects
using Slint. We invite you to use Slint and be part of its community.

## Current Status

Slint is in active development. The state of support for each platform is as
follows:

- **Embedded**: *Ready*. Slint is being used by customers in production on embedded
    devices running embedded Linux and Windows. The Slint run-time requires less than
    300KiB of RAM and can run on different processor architectures such as ARM Cortex M, ARM Cortex A, RISC-V, Intel x86, etc.
    Refer to &lt;https://slint.dev/supported-boards&gt; for list of supported boards.
- **Desktop**: *In Progress*. While Slint is a good fit on Windows, Linux and Mac,
    we are working on improving the platform support in subsequent releases.
- **Web**: *In Progress*. Slint apps can be compiled to WebAssembly and can run
    in a web browser. As there are many other web frameworks, the web platform
    is not one of our primary target platforms. The web support is currently
    limited to demo purposes.
- **Mobile**
  - Android: *In Progress*. Track the progress of work here &lt;https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/issues/46&gt;.
  - iOS: *Todo*. Support for iOS will commence after the initial support for Android is completed.

### Accessibility

Slint supports keyboard based navigation of many widgets, and user interfaces
are scalable. The basic infrastructure for assistive technology like screen
readers is in place. We&#039;re aware that more work is needed to get best-of-class
support for users with special needs.

## Demos

### Embedded

| RaspberryPi                          | STM32                         | RP2040                         |
| ------------------------------------ | ----------------------------- | ------------------------------ |
| [Video of Slint on Raspberry Pi][#1] | [Video of Slint on STM32][#2] | [Video of Slint on RP2040][#3] |

### Desktop

| Windows                                     | macOS                                     | Linux                                     |
| ------------------------------------------- | ----------------------------------------- | ----------------------------------------- |
| ![Screenshot of the Gallery on Windows][#4] | ![Screenshot of the Gallery on macOS][#5] | ![Screenshot of the Gallery on Linux][#6] |

### Web using WebAssembly

| Printer Demo                                | Slide Puzzle                                 | Energy Monitor                                       | Widget Gallery                                | Weather demo                                  |
| ------------------------------------------- | -------------------------------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------- | --------------------------------------------- | --------------------------------------------- |
| [![Screenshot of the Printer Demo][#7]][#8] | [![Screenshot of the Slide Puzzle][#9]][#10] | [![Screenshot of the Energy Monitor Demo][#11]][#12] | [![Screenshot of the Gallery Demo][#13]][#14] | [![Screenshot of the weather Demo][#29]][#30] |

More examples and demos in the [examples folder](examples#examples)

## Get Started

### Hello World

The UI is defined in a Domain Specific Language that is declarative, easy to use,
intuitive, and provides a powerful way to describe graphical elements, their
placement, their hierarchy, property bindings, and the flow of data through the
different states.

Here&#039;s the obligatory &quot;Hello World&quot;:

```slint
export component HelloWorld inherits Window {
    width: 400px;
    height: 400px;

    Text {
       y: parent.width / 2;
       x: parent.x + 200px;
       text: &quot;Hello, world&quot;;
       color: blue;
    }
}
```

### Documentation

For more details, check out the [Slint Language Documentation](https://slint.dev/docs/slint).

The [examples](examples) folder contains examples and demos, showing how to
use the Slint markup language and how to interact with a Slint user interface
from supported programming languages.

The `docs` folder contains a lot more information, including
[build instructions](docs/building.md), and
[internal developer docs](docs/development.md).

Refer to the README of each language directory in the `api` folder:

- [C++](api/cpp) ([Documentation][#15] | [Getting Started Template][#17])
- [Rust](api/rs/slint) [![Crates.io][#18]][#19] ([Documentation][#20] | [Tutorial Video][#22] | [Getting Started Template][#23])
- [JavaScript/NodeJS (Beta)](api/node) [![npm][#24]][#25] ([Documentation][#26] | [Getting Started Template][#28])
- [Python (Beta)](api/python) [![pypi][#31]][#32] ([Documentation][#33] | [Getting Started Template][#34])

## Architecture

An application is composed of the business logic written in Rust, C++, or
JavaScript and the `.slint` user interface design markup, which is compiled to
native code.

![Architecture Overview](https://slint.dev/resources/architecture.drawio.svg)

### Compiler

The `.slint` files are compiled ahead of time. The expressions in the `.slint`
are pure functions that the compiler can optimize. For example, the compiler
could choose to &quot;inline&quot; properties and remove those that are constant or
unchanged. In the future we hope to improve rendering time on low end devices by
pre-processing images and text. The compiler could determine that a `Text` or an
`Image` element is always on top of another `Image` in the same location.
Consequently both elements could be rendered ahead of time into a single
element, thus cutting down on rendering time.

The compiler uses the typical compiler phases of lexing, parsing, optimization,
and finally code generation. It provides different back-ends for code generation
in the target language. The C++ code generator produces a C++ header file, the
Rust generator produces Rust code, and so on. An interpreter for dynamic
languages is also included.

### Runtime

The runtime library consists of an engine that supports properties declared in
the `.slint` language. Components with their elements, items, and properties are
laid out in a single memory region, to reduce memory allocations.

Rendering backends and styles are configurable at compile time:

- The `femtovg` renderer uses OpenGL ES 2.0 for rendering.
- The `skia` renderer uses [Skia](https://skia.org) for rendering.
- The `software` renderer uses the CPU with no additional dependencies.

NOTE: When Qt is installed on the system, the `qt` style becomes available,
using Qt&#039;s QStyle to achieve native looking widgets.

### Tooling

We have a few tools to help with the development of .slint files:

- A [**LSP Server**](./tools/lsp) that adds features like auto-complete and live
  preview of the .slint files to many editors.
- It is bundled in a [**Visual Studio Code Extension**](./editors/vscode)
  available from the market place.
- A [**slint-viewer**](./tools/viewer) tool which displays the .slint files. The
  `--auto-reload` argument makes it easy to preview your UI while you are
  working on it (when using the LSP preview is not possible).
- [**SlintPad**](https://slintpad.com/), an online editor to try out .slint syntax
  without installing anything ([sources](./tools/slintpad)).
- An [**updater**](./tools/updater) to convert the .slint files from
  previous versions to newer versions.
- A [**Figma to Slint**](https://www.figma.com/community/plugin/1474418299182276871/figma-to-slint) plugin.

Please check our [Editors README](./editors/README.md) for tips on how to
configure your favorite editor to work well with Slint.

## License

You can use Slint under ***any*** of the following licenses, at your choice:

1. Build proprietary desktop, mobile, or web applications for free with the [Royalty-free License](LICENSES/LicenseRef-Slint-Royalty-free-2.0.md),
2. Build open source embedded, desktop, mobile, or web applications for free with the [GNU GPLv3](LICENSES/GPL-3.0-only.txt),
3. Build proprietary embedded, desktop, mobile, or web applications with the [Paid license](LICENSES/LicenseRef-Slint-Software-3.0.md).

See the [Slint licensing options on the website](https://slint.dev/pricing.html) and the [Licensing FAQ](FAQ.md#licensing).

## Contributions

We welcome your contributions: in the form of code, bug reports or feedback.

- If you see an [RFC tag](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/labels/rfc) on an
  issue, feel free to chime in.
- For contribution guidelines see [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md).

## Frequently Asked Questions

Please see our separate [FAQ](FAQ.md).

## About us (SixtyFPS GmbH)

We are passionate about software - API design, cross-platform software
development and user interface components. Our aim is to make developing user
interfaces fun for everyone: from Python, JavaScript, C++, or Rust developers all the
way to UI/UX designers. We believe that software grows organically and keeping
it open source is the best way to sustain that growth. Our team members are
located remotely in Germany, Finland, and US.

### Stay up to date

- Follow [@slint_ui](https://twitter.com/slint_ui) on X/Twitter.
- Follow [@slint@fosstodon.org](https://mastodon.social/@slint@fosstodon.org) on Mastodon.
- Follow [@slint-ui](https://www.linkedin.com/company/slint-ui/) on LinkedIn.
- Follow [@slint.dev](https://bsky.app/profile/slint.dev) on Bluesky
- Subscribe to our [YouTube channel](https://www.youtube.com/@Slint-UI)

### Contact us

Feel free to join [Github discussions](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/discussions)
for general chat or questions. Use [Github issues](https://github.com/slint-ui/slint/issues)
to report public suggestions or bugs.

We chat in [our Mattermost instance](https://chat.slint.dev) where you are
welcome to listen in or ask your questions.

You can of course also contact us privately via email to [info@slint.dev](mailto://info@slint.dev).

[#1]: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_BDbNHrjK7g
[#2]: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NNNOJJsOAis
[#3]: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkBwNocItGs
[#4]: https://slint.dev/resources/gallery_win_screenshot.png &quot;Gallery&quot;
[#5]: https://slint.dev/resources/gallery_mac_screenshot.png &quot;Gallery&quot;
[#6]: https://slint.dev/resources/gallery_linux_screenshot.png &quot;Gallery&quot;
[#7]: https://slint.dev/resources/printerdemo_screenshot.png &quot;Printer Demo&quot;
[#8]: https://slint.dev/demos/printerdemo/
[#9]: https://slint.dev/resources/puzzle_screenshot.png &quot;Slide Puzzle&quot;
[#10]: https://slint.dev/demos/slide_puzzle/
[#11]: https://slint.dev/resources/energy-monitor-screenshot.png &quot;Energy Monitor Demo&quot;
[#12]: https://slint.dev/demos/energy-monitor/
[#13]: https://slint.dev/resources/gallery_screenshot.png &quot;Gallery Demo&quot;
[#14]: https://slint.dev/demos/gallery/
[#15]: https://slint.dev/latest/docs/cpp
[#17]: https://github.com/slint-ui/slint-cpp-template
[#18]: https://img.shields.io/crates/v/slint
[#19]: https://crates.io/crates/slint
[#20]: https://slint.dev/latest/docs/rust/slint/
[#22]: https://youtu.be/WBcv4V-whHk
[#23]: https://github.com/slint-ui/slint-rust-template
[#24]: https://img.shields.io/npm/v/slint-ui
[#25]: https://www.npmjs.com/package/slint-ui
[#26]: https://slint.dev/latest/docs/node
[#28]: https://github.com/slint-ui/slint-nodejs-template
[#29]: ./demos/weather-demo/docs/img/desktop-preview.png &quot;Weather Demo&quot;
[#30]: https://slint.dev/demos/weather-demo/
[#31]: https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/slint
[#32]: https://pypi.org/project/slint/
[#33]: http://snapshots.slint.dev/master/docs/python/
[#34]: https://github.com/slint-ui/slint-python-template
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>Rust</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>