<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GitHub Trending Today for typescript - TypeScript Daily</title>
        <link>https://github.com/trending</link>
        <description>The most popular GitHub repositories today for typescript.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>GitHub Trending RSS Generator</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2025, GitHub</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[humanlayer/humanlayer]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The best way to get AI coding agents to solve hard problems in complex codebases.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer">humanlayer/humanlayer</a></h1>
            <p>The best way to get AI coding agents to solve hard problems in complex codebases.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,927</p>
            <p>Forks: 316</p>
            <p>Stars today: 269 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

![Wordmark Logo of HumanLayer](./docs/images/wordmark-light.svg)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

# Close your editor forever.

**CodeLayer is an open source IDE that lets you orchestrate AI coding agents.**

It comes with battle-tested workflows that enable AI to solve hard problems in large, complex codebases.

Built on Claude Code. Open source. Scale from your laptop to your entire team.

[![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/humanlayer/humanlayer)](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
[![License: Apache-2](https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache-green.svg)](https://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2)

&lt;h3&gt;

[Join Waitlist](https://humanlayer.dev/code) | [Discord](https://humanlayer.dev/discord)

&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;img referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer-when-downgrade&quot; src=&quot;https://static.scarf.sh/a.png?x-pxid=fcfc0926-d841-47fb-b8a6-6aba3a6c3228&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

---

&gt; &quot;Our entire company is using CodeLayer now. We&#039;re shipping one banger PR after the other. It is so f-ing good. Unbelievable dude.&quot;
&gt;
&gt; **– René Brandel, Founder @ Casco (YC X25)**

---

- **Superhuman for Claude Code** - Keyboard-first workflows designed for builders who value speed and control.

- **Advanced Context Engineering** - Scale AI-first dev to your entire team, without devolving into a chaotic slop-fest.

- **M U L T I C L A U D E** - Run Claude Code sessions in parallel. Worktrees? Done. Remote cloud workers? You got it.

---

&gt; &quot;This has improved my productivity (and token consumption) by at least 50%. Taking a superhuman style approach just makes soo much sense. Also, its so freaking cool to look back at all the work you&#039;ve done in a day.&quot;
&gt;
&gt; **– Tyler Brown, Founder @ Revlo.ai**

---

## From the team that brought you &quot;Context Engineering&quot;

Leading experts on getting the most out of today&#039;s models.

#### [Advanced Context Engineering for Coding Agents](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
This talk, given at YC on August 20th, 2025 lays out the groundwork for using AI to solve hard problems in complex codebases.
- [GitHub](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
- [YouTube](https://humanlayer.dev/youtube)

#### [12 Factor Agents](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
A set of principles for building reliable and scalable LLM applications, inspired by the original 12-Factor App methodology.
- [GitHub](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
- [YouTube](https://humanlayer.dev/youtube)

The original repo that coined the term &quot;context engineering&quot; back in April 2025.

#### [🦄 AI That Works](https://humanlayer.dev/podcast)
A weekly conversation about how we can all get the most juice out of todays models with @hellovai &amp; @dexhorthy
- [GitHub](https://github.com/humanlayer/humanlayer)
- [Podcast](https://humanlayer.dev/podcast)

---

## For Teams

**Invest in outcomes, not tools.**

Want to scale AI-first development to your entire org? Get tailored workflows, custom integrations, and cutting-edge advice.

HumanLayer&#039;s expert engineers will ship in the trenches with you and your team until everyone is a 100x engineer.

📧 Shoot us an email at **contact@humanlayer.dev**, mention your team size and current AI development stack.

---

## Quick Start

```bash
# Coming soon - join the waitlist for early access
npx humanlayer join-waitlist --email ...
```

---

## Legacy Documentation

Looking for the HumanLayer SDK documentation? See [humanlayer.md](./humanlayer.md)

## Contributing

CodeLayer and the HumanLayer SDK are open-source and we welcome contributions in the form of issues, documentation, pull requests, and more. See [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) for more details.

## License

The HumanLayer SDK and CodeLayer sources in this repo are licensed under the Apache 2 License.

---

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

[![Star History Chart](https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=humanlayer/humanlayer&amp;type=Date)](https://star-history.com/#humanlayer/humanlayer&amp;Date)

&lt;/div&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[coinbase/x402]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/coinbase/x402</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/coinbase/x402</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A payments protocol for the internet. Built on HTTP.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/coinbase/x402">coinbase/x402</a></h1>
            <p>A payments protocol for the internet. Built on HTTP.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 1,566</p>
            <p>Forks: 259</p>
            <p>Stars today: 46 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># x402 payments protocol

&gt; &quot;1 line of code to accept digital dollars. No fee, 2 second settlement, $0.001 minimum payment.&quot;

```typescript
app.use(
  // How much you want to charge, and where you want the funds to land
  paymentMiddleware(&quot;0xYourAddress&quot;, { &quot;/your-endpoint&quot;: &quot;$0.01&quot; })
);
// That&#039;s it! See examples/typescript/servers/express.ts for a complete example. Instruction below for running on base-sepolia.
```

## Philosophy

Payments on the internet are fundamentally flawed. Credit Cards are high friction, hard to accept, have minimum payments that are far too high, and don&#039;t fit into the programmatic nature of the internet.
It&#039;s time for an open, internet-native form of payments. A payment rail that doesn&#039;t have high minimums + % based fee. Payments that are amazing for humans and AI agents.

## Principles

- **Open standard:** the x402 protocol will never force reliance on a single party
- **HTTP Native:** x402 is meant to seamlessly complement the existing HTTP request made by traditional web services, it should not mandate additional requests outside the scope of a typical client / server flow.
- **Chain and token agnostic:** we welcome contributions that add support for new chains, signing standards, or schemes, so long as they meet our acceptance criteria laid out in [CONTRIBUTING.md](https://github.com/coinbase/x402/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md)
- **Trust minimizing:** all payment schemes must not allow for the facilitator or resource server to move funds, other than in accordance with client intentions
- **Easy to use:** x402 needs to be 10x better than existing ways to pay on the internet. This means abstracting as many details of crypto as possible away from the client and resource server, and into the facilitator. This means the client/server should not need to think about gas, rpc, etc.

## Ecosystem

The x402 ecosystem is growing! Check out our [ecosystem page](https://x402.org/ecosystem) to see projects building with x402, including:

- Client-side integrations
- Services and endpoints
- Ecosystem infrastructure and tooling
- Learning and community resources

Want to add your project to the ecosystem? See our [demo site README](https://github.com/coinbase/x402/tree/main/typescript/site#adding-your-project-to-the-ecosystem) for detailed instructions on how to submit your project.

**Roadmap:** see [ROADMAP.md](https://github.com/coinbase/x402/blob/main/ROADMAP.md)

## Terms:

- `resource`: Something on the internet. This could be a webpage, file server, RPC service, API, any resource on the internet that accepts HTTP / HTTPS requests.
- `client`: An entity wanting to pay for a resource.
- `facilitator server`: A server that facilitates verification and execution of on-chain payments.
- `resource server`: An HTTP server that provides an API or other resource for a client.

## Technical Goals:

- Permissionless and secure for clients and servers
- Gasless for client and resource servers
- Minimal integration for the resource server and client (1 line for the server, 1 function for the client)
- Ability to trade off speed of response for guarantee of payment
- Extensible to different payment flows and chains

## V1 Protocol

The `x402` protocol is a chain agnostic standard for payments on top of HTTP, leverage the existing `402 Payment Required` HTTP status code to indicate that a payment is required for access to the resource.

It specifies:

1. A schema for how servers can respond to clients to facilitate payment for a resource (`PaymentRequirements`)
2. A standard header `X-PAYMENT` that is set by clients paying for resources
3. A standard schema and encoding method for data in the `X-PAYMENT` header
4. A recommended flow for how payments should be verified and settled by a resource server
5. A REST specification for how a resource server can perform verification and settlement against a remote 3rd party server (`facilitator`)
6. A specification for a `X-PAYMENT-RESPONSE` header that can be used by resource servers to communicate blockchain transactions details to the client in their HTTP response

### V1 Protocol Sequencing

![](./static/x402-protocol-flow.png)

The following outlines the flow of a payment using the `x402` protocol. Note that steps (1) and (2) are optional if the client already knows the payment details accepted for a resource.

1. `Client` makes an HTTP request to a `resource server`.

2. `Resource server` responds with a `402 Payment Required` status and a `Payment Required Response` JSON object in the response body.

3. `Client` selects one of the `paymentRequirements` returned by the server response and creates a `Payment Payload` based on the `scheme` of the `paymentRequirements` they have selected.

4. `Client` sends the HTTP request with the `X-PAYMENT` header containing the `Payment Payload` to the resource server.

5. `Resource server` verifies the `Payment Payload` is valid either via local verification or by POSTing the `Payment Payload` and `Payment Requirements` to the `/verify` endpoint of a `facilitator server`.

6. `Facilitator server` performs verification of the object based on the `scheme` and `network` of the `Payment Payload` and returns a `Verification Response`.

7. If the `Verification Response` is valid, the resource server performs the work to fulfill the request. If the `Verification Response` is invalid, the resource server returns a `402 Payment Required` status and a `Payment Required Response` JSON object in the response body.

8. `Resource server` either settles the payment by interacting with a blockchain directly, or by POSTing the `Payment Payload` and `Payment PaymentRequirements` to the `/settle` endpoint of a `facilitator server`.

9. `Facilitator server` submits the payment to the blockchain based on the `scheme` and `network` of the `Payment Payload`.

10. `Facilitator server` waits for the payment to be confirmed on the blockchain.

11. `Facilitator server` returns a `Payment Execution Response` to the resource server.

12. `Resource server` returns a `200 OK` response to the `Client` with the resource they requested as the body of the HTTP response, and a `X-PAYMENT-RESPONSE` header containing the `Settlement Response` as Base64 encoded JSON if the payment was executed successfully.

### Type Specifications

#### Data types

**Payment Required Response**

```json5
{
  // Version of the x402 payment protocol
  x402Version: int,

  // List of payment requirements that the resource server accepts. A resource server may accept on multiple chains, or in multiple currencies.
  accepts: [paymentRequirements]

  // Message from the resource server to the client to communicate errors in processing payment
  error: string
}
```

**paymentRequirements**

```json5
{
  // Scheme of the payment protocol to use
  scheme: string;

  // Network of the blockchain to send payment on
  network: string;

  // Maximum amount required to pay for the resource in atomic units of the asset
  maxAmountRequired: uint256 as string;

  // URL of resource to pay for
  resource: string;

  // Description of the resource
  description: string;

  // MIME type of the resource response
  mimeType: string;

  // Output schema of the resource response
  outputSchema?: object | null;

  // Address to pay value to
  payTo: string;

  // Maximum time in seconds for the resource server to respond
  maxTimeoutSeconds: number;

  // Address of the EIP-3009 compliant ERC20 contract
  asset: string;

  // Extra information about the payment details specific to the scheme
  // For `exact` scheme on a EVM network, expects extra to contain the records `name` and `version` pertaining to asset
  extra: object | null;
}
```

**`Payment Payload`** (included as the `X-PAYMENT` header in base64 encoded json)

```json5
{
  // Version of the x402 payment protocol
  x402Version: number;

  // scheme is the scheme value of the accepted `paymentRequirements` the client is using to pay
  scheme: string;

  // network is the network id of the accepted `paymentRequirements` the client is using to pay
  network: string;

  // payload is scheme dependent
  payload: &lt;scheme dependent&gt;;
}
```

#### Facilitator Types &amp; Interface

A `facilitator server` is a 3rd party service that can be used by a `resource server` to verify and settle payments, without the `resource server` needing to have access to a blockchain node or wallet.

**POST /verify**. Verify a payment with a supported scheme and network:

- Request body JSON:
  ```json5
  {
    x402Version: number;
    paymentHeader: string;
    paymentRequirements: paymentRequirements;
  }
  ```
- Response:
  ```json5
  {
    isValid: boolean;
    invalidReason: string | null;
  }
  ```

**POST /settle**. Settle a payment with a supported scheme and network:

- Request body JSON:

  ```json5
  {
    x402Version: number;
    paymentHeader: string;
    paymentRequirements: paymentRequirements;
  }
  ```

- Response:

  ```json5
  {
    // Whether the payment was successful
    success: boolean;

    // Error message from the facilitator server
    error: string | null;

    // Transaction hash of the settled payment
    txHash: string | null;

    // Network id of the blockchain the payment was settled on
    networkId: string | null;
  }
  ```

**GET /supported**. Get supported payment schemes and networks:

- Response:
  ```json5
  {
    kinds: [
      {
        &quot;scheme&quot;: string,
        &quot;network&quot;: string,
      }
    ]
  }
  ```

### Schemes

A scheme is a logical way of moving money.

Blockchains allow for a large number of flexible ways to move money. To help facilitate an expanding number of payment use cases, the `x402` protocol is extensible to different ways of settling payments via its `scheme` field.

Each payment scheme may have different operational functionality depending on what actions are necessary to fulfill the payment.
For example `exact`, the first scheme shipping as part of the protocol, would have different behavior than `upto`. `exact` transfers a specific amount (ex: pay $1 to read an article), while a theoretical `upto` would transfer up to an amount, based on the resources consumed during a request (ex: generating tokens from an LLM).

See `specs/schemes` for more details on schemes, and see `specs/schemes/exact/scheme_exact_evm.md` to see the first proposed scheme for exact payment on EVM chains.

### Schemes vs Networks

Because a scheme is a logical way of moving money, the way a scheme is implemented can be different for different blockchains. (ex: the way you need to implement `exact` on Ethereum is very different from the way you need to implement `exact` on Solana).

Clients and facilitators must explicitly support different `(scheme, network)` pairs in order to be able to create proper payloads and verify / settle payments.

## Running example

**Requirements:** Node.js v24 or higher

1. From `examples/typescript` run `pnpm install` and `pnpm build` to ensure all dependent packages and examples are setup.

2. Select a server, i.e. express, and `cd` into that example. Add your server&#039;s ethereum address to get paid to into the `.env` file, and then run `pnpm dev` in that directory.

3. Select a client, i.e. axios, and `cd` into that example. Add your private key for the account making payments into the `.env` file, and then run `pnpm dev` in that directory.

You should see activities in the client terminal, which will display a weather report.

## Running tests

1. Navigate to the typescript directory: `cd typescript`
2. Install dependencies: `pnpm install`
3. Run the unit tests: `pnpm test`

This will run the unit tests for the x402 packages.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The official TypeScript SDK for Model Context Protocol servers and clients]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk">modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk</a></h1>
            <p>The official TypeScript SDK for Model Context Protocol servers and clients</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 9,966</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,286</p>
            <p>Stars today: 11 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># MCP TypeScript SDK ![NPM Version](https://img.shields.io/npm/v/%40modelcontextprotocol%2Fsdk) ![MIT licensed](https://img.shields.io/npm/l/%40modelcontextprotocol%2Fsdk)

## Table of Contents

- [Overview](#overview)
- [Installation](#installation)
- [Quickstart](#quick-start)
- [What is MCP?](#what-is-mcp)
- [Core Concepts](#core-concepts)
  - [Server](#server)
  - [Resources](#resources)
  - [Tools](#tools)
  - [Prompts](#prompts)
  - [Completions](#completions)
  - [Sampling](#sampling)
- [Running Your Server](#running-your-server)
  - [stdio](#stdio)
  - [Streamable HTTP](#streamable-http)
  - [Testing and Debugging](#testing-and-debugging)
- [Examples](#examples)
  - [Echo Server](#echo-server)
  - [SQLite Explorer](#sqlite-explorer)
- [Advanced Usage](#advanced-usage)
  - [Dynamic Servers](#dynamic-servers)
  - [Low-Level Server](#low-level-server)
  - [Writing MCP Clients](#writing-mcp-clients)
  - [Proxy Authorization Requests Upstream](#proxy-authorization-requests-upstream)
  - [Backwards Compatibility](#backwards-compatibility)
- [Documentation](#documentation)
- [Contributing](#contributing)
- [License](#license)

## Overview

The Model Context Protocol allows applications to provide context for LLMs in a standardized way, separating the concerns of providing context from the actual LLM interaction. This TypeScript SDK implements the full MCP specification, making it easy to:

- Build MCP clients that can connect to any MCP server
- Create MCP servers that expose resources, prompts and tools
- Use standard transports like stdio and Streamable HTTP
- Handle all MCP protocol messages and lifecycle events

## Installation

```bash
npm install @modelcontextprotocol/sdk
```

&gt; ⚠️ MCP requires Node.js v18.x or higher to work fine.

## Quick Start

Let&#039;s create a simple MCP server that exposes a calculator tool and some data:

```typescript
import { McpServer, ResourceTemplate } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/mcp.js&quot;;
import { StdioServerTransport } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/stdio.js&quot;;
import { z } from &quot;zod&quot;;

// Create an MCP server
const server = new McpServer({
  name: &quot;demo-server&quot;,
  version: &quot;1.0.0&quot;
});

// Add an addition tool
server.registerTool(&quot;add&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;Addition Tool&quot;,
    description: &quot;Add two numbers&quot;,
    inputSchema: { a: z.number(), b: z.number() }
  },
  async ({ a, b }) =&gt; ({
    content: [{ type: &quot;text&quot;, text: String(a + b) }]
  })
);

// Add a dynamic greeting resource
server.registerResource(
  &quot;greeting&quot;,
  new ResourceTemplate(&quot;greeting://{name}&quot;, { list: undefined }),
  { 
    title: &quot;Greeting Resource&quot;,      // Display name for UI
    description: &quot;Dynamic greeting generator&quot;
  },
  async (uri, { name }) =&gt; ({
    contents: [{
      uri: uri.href,
      text: `Hello, ${name}!`
    }]
  })
);

// Start receiving messages on stdin and sending messages on stdout
const transport = new StdioServerTransport();
await server.connect(transport);
```

## What is MCP?

The [Model Context Protocol (MCP)](https://modelcontextprotocol.io) lets you build servers that expose data and functionality to LLM applications in a secure, standardized way. Think of it like a web API, but specifically designed for LLM interactions. MCP servers can:

- Expose data through **Resources** (think of these sort of like GET endpoints; they are used to load information into the LLM&#039;s context)
- Provide functionality through **Tools** (sort of like POST endpoints; they are used to execute code or otherwise produce a side effect)
- Define interaction patterns through **Prompts** (reusable templates for LLM interactions)
- And more!

## Core Concepts

### Server

The McpServer is your core interface to the MCP protocol. It handles connection management, protocol compliance, and message routing:

```typescript
const server = new McpServer({
  name: &quot;my-app&quot;,
  version: &quot;1.0.0&quot;
});
```

### Resources

Resources are how you expose data to LLMs. They&#039;re similar to GET endpoints in a REST API - they provide data but shouldn&#039;t perform significant computation or have side effects:

```typescript
// Static resource
server.registerResource(
  &quot;config&quot;,
  &quot;config://app&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;Application Config&quot;,
    description: &quot;Application configuration data&quot;,
    mimeType: &quot;text/plain&quot;
  },
  async (uri) =&gt; ({
    contents: [{
      uri: uri.href,
      text: &quot;App configuration here&quot;
    }]
  })
);

// Dynamic resource with parameters
server.registerResource(
  &quot;user-profile&quot;,
  new ResourceTemplate(&quot;users://{userId}/profile&quot;, { list: undefined }),
  {
    title: &quot;User Profile&quot;,
    description: &quot;User profile information&quot;
  },
  async (uri, { userId }) =&gt; ({
    contents: [{
      uri: uri.href,
      text: `Profile data for user ${userId}`
    }]
  })
);

// Resource with context-aware completion
server.registerResource(
  &quot;repository&quot;,
  new ResourceTemplate(&quot;github://repos/{owner}/{repo}&quot;, {
    list: undefined,
    complete: {
      // Provide intelligent completions based on previously resolved parameters
      repo: (value, context) =&gt; {
        if (context?.arguments?.[&quot;owner&quot;] === &quot;org1&quot;) {
          return [&quot;project1&quot;, &quot;project2&quot;, &quot;project3&quot;].filter(r =&gt; r.startsWith(value));
        }
        return [&quot;default-repo&quot;].filter(r =&gt; r.startsWith(value));
      }
    }
  }),
  {
    title: &quot;GitHub Repository&quot;,
    description: &quot;Repository information&quot;
  },
  async (uri, { owner, repo }) =&gt; ({
    contents: [{
      uri: uri.href,
      text: `Repository: ${owner}/${repo}`
    }]
  })
);
```

### Tools

Tools let LLMs take actions through your server. Unlike resources, tools are expected to perform computation and have side effects:

```typescript
// Simple tool with parameters
server.registerTool(
  &quot;calculate-bmi&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;BMI Calculator&quot;,
    description: &quot;Calculate Body Mass Index&quot;,
    inputSchema: {
      weightKg: z.number(),
      heightM: z.number()
    }
  },
  async ({ weightKg, heightM }) =&gt; ({
    content: [{
      type: &quot;text&quot;,
      text: String(weightKg / (heightM * heightM))
    }]
  })
);

// Async tool with external API call
server.registerTool(
  &quot;fetch-weather&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;Weather Fetcher&quot;,
    description: &quot;Get weather data for a city&quot;,
    inputSchema: { city: z.string() }
  },
  async ({ city }) =&gt; {
    const response = await fetch(`https://api.weather.com/${city}`);
    const data = await response.text();
    return {
      content: [{ type: &quot;text&quot;, text: data }]
    };
  }
);

// Tool that returns ResourceLinks
server.registerTool(
  &quot;list-files&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;List Files&quot;,
    description: &quot;List project files&quot;,
    inputSchema: { pattern: z.string() }
  },
  async ({ pattern }) =&gt; ({
    content: [
      { type: &quot;text&quot;, text: `Found files matching &quot;${pattern}&quot;:` },
      // ResourceLinks let tools return references without file content
      {
        type: &quot;resource_link&quot;,
        uri: &quot;file:///project/README.md&quot;,
        name: &quot;README.md&quot;,
        mimeType: &quot;text/markdown&quot;,
        description: &#039;A README file&#039;
      },
      {
        type: &quot;resource_link&quot;,
        uri: &quot;file:///project/src/index.ts&quot;,
        name: &quot;index.ts&quot;,
        mimeType: &quot;text/typescript&quot;,
        description: &#039;An index file&#039;
      }
    ]
  })
);
```

#### ResourceLinks

Tools can return `ResourceLink` objects to reference resources without embedding their full content. This is essential for performance when dealing with large files or many resources - clients can then selectively read only the resources they need using the provided URIs.

### Prompts

Prompts are reusable templates that help LLMs interact with your server effectively:

```typescript
import { completable } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/completable.js&quot;;

server.registerPrompt(
  &quot;review-code&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;Code Review&quot;,
    description: &quot;Review code for best practices and potential issues&quot;,
    argsSchema: { code: z.string() }
  },
  ({ code }) =&gt; ({
    messages: [{
      role: &quot;user&quot;,
      content: {
        type: &quot;text&quot;,
        text: `Please review this code:\n\n${code}`
      }
    }]
  })
);

// Prompt with context-aware completion
server.registerPrompt(
  &quot;team-greeting&quot;,
  {
    title: &quot;Team Greeting&quot;,
    description: &quot;Generate a greeting for team members&quot;,
    argsSchema: {
      department: completable(z.string(), (value) =&gt; {
        // Department suggestions
        return [&quot;engineering&quot;, &quot;sales&quot;, &quot;marketing&quot;, &quot;support&quot;].filter(d =&gt; d.startsWith(value));
      }),
      name: completable(z.string(), (value, context) =&gt; {
        // Name suggestions based on selected department
        const department = context?.arguments?.[&quot;department&quot;];
        if (department === &quot;engineering&quot;) {
          return [&quot;Alice&quot;, &quot;Bob&quot;, &quot;Charlie&quot;].filter(n =&gt; n.startsWith(value));
        } else if (department === &quot;sales&quot;) {
          return [&quot;David&quot;, &quot;Eve&quot;, &quot;Frank&quot;].filter(n =&gt; n.startsWith(value));
        } else if (department === &quot;marketing&quot;) {
          return [&quot;Grace&quot;, &quot;Henry&quot;, &quot;Iris&quot;].filter(n =&gt; n.startsWith(value));
        }
        return [&quot;Guest&quot;].filter(n =&gt; n.startsWith(value));
      })
    }
  },
  ({ department, name }) =&gt; ({
    messages: [{
      role: &quot;assistant&quot;,
      content: {
        type: &quot;text&quot;,
        text: `Hello ${name}, welcome to the ${department} team!`
      }
    }]
  })
);
```

### Completions

MCP supports argument completions to help users fill in prompt arguments and resource template parameters. See the examples above for [resource completions](#resources) and [prompt completions](#prompts).

#### Client Usage

```typescript
// Request completions for any argument
const result = await client.complete({
  ref: {
    type: &quot;ref/prompt&quot;,  // or &quot;ref/resource&quot;
    name: &quot;example&quot;      // or uri: &quot;template://...&quot;
  },
  argument: {
    name: &quot;argumentName&quot;,
    value: &quot;partial&quot;     // What the user has typed so far
  },
  context: {             // Optional: Include previously resolved arguments
    arguments: {
      previousArg: &quot;value&quot;
    }
  }
});

```

### Display Names and Metadata

All resources, tools, and prompts support an optional `title` field for better UI presentation. The `title` is used as a display name, while `name` remains the unique identifier.

**Note:** The `register*` methods (`registerTool`, `registerPrompt`, `registerResource`) are the recommended approach for new code. The older methods (`tool`, `prompt`, `resource`) remain available for backwards compatibility.

#### Title Precedence for Tools

For tools specifically, there are two ways to specify a title:
- `title` field in the tool configuration
- `annotations.title` field (when using the older `tool()` method with annotations)

The precedence order is: `title` → `annotations.title` → `name`

```typescript
// Using registerTool (recommended)
server.registerTool(&quot;my_tool&quot;, {
  title: &quot;My Tool&quot;,              // This title takes precedence
  annotations: {
    title: &quot;Annotation Title&quot;    // This is ignored if title is set
  }
}, handler);

// Using tool with annotations (older API)
server.tool(&quot;my_tool&quot;, &quot;description&quot;, {
  title: &quot;Annotation Title&quot;      // This is used as title
}, handler);
```

When building clients, use the provided utility to get the appropriate display name:

```typescript
import { getDisplayName } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/shared/metadataUtils.js&quot;;

// Automatically handles the precedence: title → annotations.title → name
const displayName = getDisplayName(tool);
```

### Sampling

MCP servers can request LLM completions from connected clients that support sampling.

```typescript
import { McpServer } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/mcp.js&quot;;
import { StdioServerTransport } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/stdio.js&quot;;
import { z } from &quot;zod&quot;;

const mcpServer = new McpServer({
  name: &quot;tools-with-sample-server&quot;,
  version: &quot;1.0.0&quot;,
});

// Tool that uses LLM sampling to summarize any text
mcpServer.registerTool(
  &quot;summarize&quot;,
  {
    description: &quot;Summarize any text using an LLM&quot;,
    inputSchema: {
      text: z.string().describe(&quot;Text to summarize&quot;),
    },
  },
  async ({ text }) =&gt; {
    // Call the LLM through MCP sampling
    const response = await mcpServer.server.createMessage({
      messages: [
        {
          role: &quot;user&quot;,
          content: {
            type: &quot;text&quot;,
            text: `Please summarize the following text concisely:\n\n${text}`,
          },
        },
      ],
      maxTokens: 500,
    });

    return {
      content: [
        {
          type: &quot;text&quot;,
          text: response.content.type === &quot;text&quot; ? response.content.text : &quot;Unable to generate summary&quot;,
        },
      ],
    };
  }
);

async function main() {
  const transport = new StdioServerTransport();
  await mcpServer.connect(transport);
  console.error(&quot;MCP server is running...&quot;);
}

main().catch((error) =&gt; {
  console.error(&quot;Server error:&quot;, error);
  process.exit(1);
});
```


## Running Your Server

MCP servers in TypeScript need to be connected to a transport to communicate with clients. How you start the server depends on the choice of transport:

### stdio

For command-line tools and direct integrations:

```typescript
import { McpServer } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/mcp.js&quot;;
import { StdioServerTransport } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/stdio.js&quot;;

const server = new McpServer({
  name: &quot;example-server&quot;,
  version: &quot;1.0.0&quot;
});

// ... set up server resources, tools, and prompts ...

const transport = new StdioServerTransport();
await server.connect(transport);
```

### Streamable HTTP

For remote servers, set up a Streamable HTTP transport that handles both client requests and server-to-client notifications.

#### With Session Management

In some cases, servers need to be stateful. This is achieved by [session management](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/specification/2025-03-26/basic/transports#session-management).

```typescript
import express from &quot;express&quot;;
import { randomUUID } from &quot;node:crypto&quot;;
import { McpServer } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/mcp.js&quot;;
import { StreamableHTTPServerTransport } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/streamableHttp.js&quot;;
import { isInitializeRequest } from &quot;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/types.js&quot;



const app = express();
app.use(express.json());

// Map to store transports by session ID
const transports: { [sessionId: string]: StreamableHTTPServerTransport } = {};

// Handle POST requests for client-to-server communication
app.post(&#039;/mcp&#039;, async (req, res) =&gt; {
  // Check for existing session ID
  const sessionId = req.headers[&#039;mcp-session-id&#039;] as string | undefined;
  let transport: StreamableHTTPServerTransport;

  if (sessionId &amp;&amp; transports[sessionId]) {
    // Reuse existing transport
    transport = transports[sessionId];
  } else if (!sessionId &amp;&amp; isInitializeRequest(req.body)) {
    // New initialization request
    transport = new StreamableHTTPServerTransport({
      sessionIdGenerator: () =&gt; randomUUID(),
      onsessioninitialized: (sessionId) =&gt; {
        // Store the transport by session ID
        transports[sessionId] = transport;
      },
      // DNS rebinding protection is disabled by default for backwards compatibility. If you are running this server
      // locally, make sure to set:
      // enableDnsRebindingProtection: true,
      // allowedHosts: [&#039;127.0.0.1&#039;],
    });

    // Clean up transport when closed
    transport.onclose = () =&gt; {
      if (transport.sessionId) {
        delete transports[transport.sessionId];
      }
    };
    const server = new McpServer({
      name: &quot;example-server&quot;,
      version: &quot;1.0.0&quot;
    });

    // ... set up server resources, tools, and prompts ...

    // Connect to the MCP server
    await server.connect(transport);
  } else {
    // Invalid request
    res.status(400).json({
      jsonrpc: &#039;2.0&#039;,
      error: {
        code: -32000,
        message: &#039;Bad Request: No valid session ID provided&#039;,
      },
      id: null,
    });
    return;
  }

  // Handle the request
  await transport.handleRequest(req, res, req.body);
});

// Reusable handler for GET and DELETE requests
const handleSessionRequest = async (req: express.Request, res: express.Response) =&gt; {
  const sessionId = req.headers[&#039;mcp-session-id&#039;] as string | undefined;
  if (!sessionId || !transports[sessionId]) {
    res.status(400).send(&#039;Invalid or missing session ID&#039;);
    return;
  }
  
  const transport = transports[sessionId];
  await transport.handleRequest(req, res);
};

// Handle GET requests for server-to-client notifications via SSE
app.get(&#039;/mcp&#039;, handleSessionRequest);

// Handle DELETE requests for session termination
app.delete(&#039;/mcp&#039;, handleSessionRequest);

app.listen(3000);
```

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; When using this in a remote environment, make sure to allow the header parameter `mcp-session-id` in CORS. Otherwise, it may result in a `Bad Request: No valid session ID provided` error. Read the following section for examples.


#### CORS Configuration for Browser-Based Clients

If you&#039;d like your server to be accessible by browser-based MCP clients, you&#039;ll need to configure CORS headers. The `Mcp-Session-Id` header must be exposed for browser clients to access it:

```typescript
import cors from &#039;cors&#039;;

// Add CORS middleware before your MCP routes
app.use(cors({
  origin: &#039;*&#039;, // Configure appropriately for production, for example:
  // origin: [&#039;https://your-remote-domain.com&#039;, &#039;https://your-other-remote-domain.com&#039;],
  exposedHeaders: [&#039;Mcp-Session-Id&#039;],
  allowedHeaders: [&#039;Content-Type&#039;, &#039;mcp-session-id&#039;],
}));
```

This configuration is necessary because:
- The MCP streamable HTTP transport uses the `Mcp-Session-Id` header for session management
- Browsers restrict access to response headers unless explicitly exposed via CORS
- Without this configuration, browser-based clients won&#039;t be able to read the session ID from initialization responses

#### Without Session Management (Stateless)

For simpler use cases where session management isn&#039;t needed:

```typescript
const app = express();
app.use(express.json());

app.post(&#039;/mcp&#039;, async (req: Request, res: Response) =&gt; {
  // In stateless mode, create a new instance of transport and server for each request
  // to ensure complete isolation. A single instance would cause request ID collisions
  // when multiple clients connect concurrently.
  
  try {
    const server = getServer(); 
    const transport: StreamableHTTPServerTransport = new StreamableHTTPServerTransport({
      sessionIdGenerator: undefined,
    });
    res.on(&#039;close&#039;, () =&gt; {
      console.log(&#039;Request closed&#039;);
      transport.close();
      server.close();
    });
    await server.connect(transport);
    await transport.handleRequest(req, res, req.body);
  } catch (error) {
    console.error(&#039;Error handling MCP request:&#039;, error);
    if (!res.headersSent) {
      res.status(500).json({
        jsonrpc: &#039;2.0&#039;,
        error: {
          code: -32603,
          message: &#039;Internal server error&#039;,
        },
        id: null,
      });
    }
  }
});

// SSE notifications not supported in stateless mode
app.get(&#039;/mcp&#039;, async (req: Request, res: Response) =&gt; {
  console.log(&#039;Received GET MCP request&#039;);
  res.writeHead(405).end(JSON.stringify({
    jsonrpc: &quot;2.0&quot;,
    error: {
      code: -32000,
      message: &quot;Method not allowed.&quot;
    },
    id: null
  }));
});

// Session termination not needed in stateless mode
app.delete(&#039;/mcp&#039;, async (req: Request, res: Response) =&gt; {
  console.log(&#039;Received DELETE MCP request&#039;);
  res.writeHead(405).end(JSON.stringify({
    jsonrpc: &quot;2.0&quot;,
    error: {
      code: -32000,
      message: &quot;Method not allowed.&quot;
    },
    id: null
  }));
});


// Start the server
const PORT = 3000;
setupServer().then(() =&gt; {
  app.listen(PORT, (error) =&gt; {
    if (error) {
      console.error(&#039;Failed to start server:&#039;, error);
      process.exit(1);
    }
    console.log(`MCP Stateless Streamable HTTP Server listening on port ${PORT}`);
  });
}).catch(error =&gt; {
  console.error(&#039;Failed to set up the server:&#039;, error);
  process.exi

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[人人都能用英语]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english">ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english</a></h1>
            <p>人人都能用英语</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 30,442</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,345</p>
            <p>Stars today: 826 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/assets/icon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Clash&quot; width=&quot;128&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
AI 是当今世界上最好的外语老师，Enjoy 做 AI 最好的助教。
&lt;/h3&gt;

[![Deploy 1000h website](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/deploy-1000h.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/deploy-1000h.yml)
[![Test Enjoy App](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/test-enjoy-app.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/test-enjoy-app.yml)
[![Release Enjoy App](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/release-enjoy-app.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/ZuodaoTech/everyone-can-use-english/actions/workflows/release-enjoy-app.yml)
![Latest Version](https://img.shields.io/badge/dynamic/json?url=https%3A%2F%2Fenjoy.bot%2Fapi%2Fconfig%2Fapp_version&amp;query=%24.version&amp;label=Latest&amp;link=https%3A%2F%2F1000h.org%2Fenjoy-app%2Finstall.html)
![Recording Duration](https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fenjoy.bot%2Fapi%2Fbadges%2Frecordings)

---

## 网页版

Enjoy 网页版已经上线，可访问 [https://enjoy.bot](https://enjoy.bot) 直接使用。

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;display:flex;overflow:auto;gap:10px;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-audios.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Audios&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-add-audio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Add Audio&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-audio-shadow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shadow&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-audio-assessment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-new-chat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Chat&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/web-chat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chat&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

---

## 桌面版安装及使用

下载及使用相关说明，请参阅 [文档](https://1000h.org/enjoy-app/)。

## 预览

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;display:flex;overflow:auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/home.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/shadow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/assessment.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/document.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;./enjoy/snapshots/chat.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## 桌面版开发

```bash
yarn install
yarn enjoy:start
```

## 相关阅读

### 一千小时（2024）

- [简要说明](https://1000h.org/intro.html)
- [训练任务](https://1000h.org/training-tasks/kick-off.html)
- [语音塑造](https://1000h.org/sounds-of-american-english/0-intro.html)
- [大脑内部](https://1000h.org/in-the-brain/01-inifinite.html)
- [自我训练](https://1000h.org/self-training/00-intro.html)

### 人人都能用英语（2010）

- [简介](./book/README.md)
- [第一章：起点](./book/chapter1.md)
- [第二章：口语](./book/chapter2.md)
- [第三章：语音](./book/chapter3.md)
- [第四章：朗读](./book/chapter4.md)
- [第五章：词典](./book/chapter5.md)
- [第六章：语法](./book/chapter6.md)
- [第七章：精读](./book/chapter7.md)
- [第八章：叮嘱](./book/chapter8.md)
- [后记](./book/end.md)

## 常见问题

请查询 [文档 FAQ](https://1000h.org/enjoy-app/faq.html)。
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[directus/directus]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/directus/directus</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/directus/directus</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The flexible backend for all your projects 🐰 Turn your DB into a headless CMS, admin panels, or apps with a custom UI, instant APIs, auth & more.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/directus/directus">directus/directus</a></h1>
            <p>The flexible backend for all your projects 🐰 Turn your DB into a headless CMS, admin panels, or apps with a custom UI, instant APIs, auth & more.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 32,550</p>
            <p>Forks: 4,397</p>
            <p>Stars today: 23 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>README not available. Either the repository does not have a README or it could not be accessed.</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mastra-ai/mastra]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The TypeScript AI agent framework. ⚡ Assistants, RAG, observability. Supports any LLM: GPT-4, Claude, Gemini, Llama.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra">mastra-ai/mastra</a></h1>
            <p>The TypeScript AI agent framework. ⚡ Assistants, RAG, observability. Supports any LLM: GPT-4, Claude, Gemini, Llama.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 16,908</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,126</p>
            <p>Stars today: 15 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Mastra

[![npm version](https://badge.fury.io/js/@mastra%2Fcore.svg)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/core)
[![CodeQl](https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra/actions/workflows/github-code-scanning/codeql/badge.svg)](https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra/actions/workflows/github-code-scanning/codeql)
[![GitHub Repo stars](https://img.shields.io/github/stars/mastra-ai/mastra)](https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra/stargazers)
[![Discord](https://img.shields.io/discord/1309558646228779139?logo=discord&amp;label=Discord&amp;labelColor=white&amp;color=7289DA)](https://discord.gg/BTYqqHKUrf)
[![Twitter Follow](https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/mastra_ai?style=social)](https://x.com/mastra_ai)
[![NPM Downloads](https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/%40mastra%252Fcore)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/core)
[![Static Badge](https://img.shields.io/badge/Y%20Combinator-W25-orange)](https://www.ycombinator.com/companies?batch=W25)

Mastra is the Typescript framework for building AI agents and assistants. It’s used by some of the largest companies in the world to build internal AI automation tooling and customer-facing agents.

You can run Mastra on your local machine, bundle it into a Node.js server with Hono, or deploy to a serverless cloud.

The main Mastra features are:

| Features                                               | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| ------------------------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| LLM Models                                             | Mastra uses the [Vercel AI SDK](https://sdk.vercel.ai/docs/introduction) for model routing, providing a unified interface to interact with any LLM provider including OpenAI, Anthropic, and Google Gemini. You can choose the specific model and provider, and decide whether to stream the response. |
| [Agents](https://mastra.ai/docs/agents/overview)       | Agents are systems where the language model chooses a sequence of actions. In Mastra, agents provide LLM models with tools, workflows, and synced data. Agents can call your own functions or APIs of third-party integrations and access knowledge bases you build.                                   |
| [Tools](https://mastra.ai/docs/agents/adding-tools)    | Tools are typed functions that can be executed by agents or workflows, with built-in integration access and parameter validation. Each tool has a schema that defines its inputs, an executor function that implements its logic, and access to configured integrations.                               |
| [Workflows](https://mastra.ai/docs/workflows/overview) | Workflows are durable graph-based state machines. They have loops, branching, wait for human input, embed other workflows, do error handling, retries, parsing and so on. They can be built in code or with a visual editor. Each step in a workflow has built-in OpenTelemetry tracing.               |
| [RAG](https://mastra.ai/docs/rag/overview)             | Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) lets you construct a knowledge base for agents. RAG is an ETL pipeline with specific querying techniques, including chunking, embedding, and vector search.                                                                                                       |
| [Integrations](https://mastra.ai/docs/integrations)    | In Mastra, integrations are auto-generated, type-safe API clients for third-party services that can be used as tools for agents or steps in workflows.                                                                                                                                                 |
| [Evals](https://mastra.ai/docs/08-running-evals)       | Evals are automated tests that evaluate LLM outputs using model-graded, rule-based, and statistical methods. Each eval returns a normalized score between 0-1 that can be logged and compared. Evals can be customized with your own prompts and scoring functions.                                    |

## Quick Start

### Prerequisites

- Node.js (v20.0+)

## Get an LLM provider API key

If you don&#039;t have an API key for an LLM provider, you can get one from the following services:

- [OpenAI](https://platform.openai.com/)
- [Anthropic](https://console.anthropic.com/settings/keys)
- [Google Gemini](https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs)
- [Groq](https://console.groq.com/docs/overview)
- [Cerebras](https://inference-docs.cerebras.ai/introduction)

If you don&#039;t have an account with these providers, you can sign up and get an API key. Anthropic require a credit card to get an API key. Some OpenAI models and Gemini do not and have a generous free tier for its API.

## Create a new project

The easiest way to get started with Mastra is by using `create-mastra`. This CLI tool enables you to quickly start building a new Mastra application, with everything set up for you.

```bash
npx create-mastra@latest
```

### Run the script

Finally, run `mastra dev` to open the Mastra playground.

```bash copy
npm run dev
```

If you&#039;re using Anthropic, set the `ANTHROPIC_API_KEY`. If you&#039;re using Gemini, set the `GOOGLE_GENERATIVE_AI_API_KEY`.

# MCP Server ([@mastra/mcp-docs-server](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/mcp-docs-server))

Use our MCP server [@mastra/mcp-docs-server](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/mcp-docs-server) to teach your LLM how to use Mastra.

This is a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server that provides AI assistants with direct access to Mastra.ai&#039;s complete knowledge base.

## In Cursor

Create or update .cursor/mcp.json in your project root:

### MacOS/Linux

```
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;mastra&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@mastra/mcp-docs-server&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

### Windows

```
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;mastra&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;cmd&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;/c&quot;, &quot;npx&quot;, &quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@mastra/mcp-docs-server&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

This will make all Mastra documentation tools available in your Cursor workspace. Note that the MCP server wont be enabled by default. You&#039;ll need to go to Cursor settings -&gt; MCP settings and click &quot;enable&quot; on the Mastra MCP server.

## In Windsurf

Create or update ~/.codeium/windsurf/mcp_config.json:

### MacOS/Linux

```
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;mastra&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;@mastra/mcp-docs-server&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

For more installation options visit [https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/mcp-docs-server](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mastra/mcp-docs-server)

### In Claude Code

After installing Claude Code run:

```sh
claude mcp add mastra-docs -- npx -y @mastra/mcp-docs-server
```

## Contributing

Looking to contribute? All types of help are appreciated, from coding to testing and feature specification.

If you are a developer and would like to contribute with code, please open an issue to discuss before opening a Pull Request.

Information about the project setup can be found in the [development documentation](./DEVELOPMENT.md)

## Support

We have an [open community Discord](https://discord.gg/BTYqqHKUrf). Come and say hello and let us know if you have any questions or need any help getting things running.

It&#039;s also super helpful if you leave the project a star here at the [top of the page](https://github.com/mastra-ai/mastra)

## Security

We are committed to maintaining the security of this repo and of Mastra as a whole. If you discover a security finding
we ask you to please responsibly disclose this to us at [security@mastra.ai](mailto:security@mastra.ai) and we will get
back to you.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TanStack/router]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/TanStack/router</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/TanStack/router</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[🤖 Fully typesafe Router for React (and friends) w/ built-in caching, 1st class search-param APIs, client-side cache integration and isomorphic rendering.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/TanStack/router">TanStack/router</a></h1>
            <p>🤖 Fully typesafe Router for React (and friends) w/ built-in caching, 1st class search-param APIs, client-side cache integration and isomorphic rendering.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 11,385</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,230</p>
            <p>Stars today: 30 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.scarf.sh/a.png?x-pxid=d988eb79-b0fc-4a2b-8514-6a1ab932d188&quot; /&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img
src=&quot;./media/header_router.png&quot;
alt=&quot;TanStack Router&quot;
/&gt;

## TanStack Router

A modern router designed for type safety, data‑driven navigation, and seamless developer experience.

- End‑to‑end type safety (routes, params, loaders)
- Schema‑driven search params with validation
- Built‑in caching, prefetching &amp; invalidation
- Nested layouts, transitions &amp; error boundaries

### [Read the Router Docs →](https://tanstack.com/router)

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img
src=&quot;./media/header_start.png&quot;
alt=&quot;TanStack Start&quot;
/&gt;

## TanStack Start

A full‑stack framework built on Router, designed for server rendering, streaming, and production‑ready deployments.

- Full‑document SSR &amp; streaming
- Server functions &amp; end‑to‑end type safety
- Deployment‑ready bundling &amp; builds
- All the power of TanStack Router, plus full‑stack features

### [Read the Start Docs →](https://tanstack.com/start)

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://npmjs.com/package/@tanstack/react-router&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dm/@tanstack/react-router.svg&quot; alt=&quot;npm downloads&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/router&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/tanstack/router.svg?style=social&amp;label=Star&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub stars&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://bundlephobia.com/result?p=@tanstack/react-router&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://badgen.net/bundlephobia/minzip/@tanstack/react-router&quot; alt=&quot;Bundle size&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#badge&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;semantic-release&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/%20%20%F0%9F%93%A6%F0%9F%9A%80-semantic--release-e10079.svg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://bestofjs.org/projects/tanstack-router&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Best of JS&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://bestofjs-serverless.now.sh/api/project-badge?fullName=TanStack%2Frouter%26since=daily&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tan_stack&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/tan_stack.svg?style=social&quot; alt=&quot;Follow @TanStack&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

### [Become a Sponsor!](https://github.com/sponsors/tannerlinsley/)

&lt;/div&gt;

## Get Involved

- We welcome issues and pull requests!
- Participate in [GitHub discussions](https://github.com/TanStack/router/discussions)
- Chat with the community on [Discord](https://discord.com/invite/WrRKjPJ)
- See [CONTRIBUTING.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md) for setup instructions

## Partners

&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coderabbit.ai/?via=tanstack&amp;dub_id=aCcEEdAOqqutX6OS&quot;&gt;
			&lt;picture&gt;
			  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/coderabbit-dark-CMcuvjEy.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
			  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/coderabbit-light-DVMJ2jHi.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
			  &lt;img src=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/coderabbit-dark-CMcuvjEy.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; alt=&quot;CodeRabbit&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;/picture&gt;        
		&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td padding=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com?utm_source=tanstack&quot;&gt;
         &lt;picture&gt;
    		  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/cloudflare-white-DQDB7UaL.svg&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;
    		  &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/cloudflare-black-CPufaW0B.svg&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;
    		  &lt;img src=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/cloudflare-black-CPufaW0B.svg&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; alt=&quot;Cloudflare&quot; /&gt;
    		&lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://netlify.com?utm_source=tanstack&quot;&gt;
      &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanstack/tanstack.com/main/src/images/netlify-dark.svg&quot; height=&quot;70&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/netlify.svg&quot; height=&quot;70&quot;/&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanstack/tanstack.com/main/src/images/netlify-dark.svg&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; alt=&quot;Netlify&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://neon.tech?utm_source=tanstack&quot;&gt;
		  &lt;picture&gt;
	        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanstack/tanstack.com/main/src/images/neon-dark.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
	        &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/neon.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
	        &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/neon.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; alt=&quot;Neon&quot; /&gt;
		  &lt;/picture&gt;
	  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.clerk.com/wOwHtuJ&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/clerk-logo-dark-CRE22T_2.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/clerk.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/clerk-logo-dark-CRE22T_2.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; alt=&quot;Clerk&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://convex.dev?utm_source=tanstack&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanstack/tanstack.com/main/src/images/convex-white.svg&quot; height=&quot;30&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/convex.svg&quot; height=&quot;30&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/convex.svg&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Convex&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://sentry.io?utm_source=tanstack&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
           &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanstack/tanstack.com/main/src/images/sentry-wordmark-light.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/sentry.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tannerlinsley/files/master/partners/sentry.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; alt=&quot;Sentry&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prisma.io?utm_source=tanstack&amp;via=tanstack&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/prisma-dark-DwgDxLwn.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/prisma-light-Cloa3Onm.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/prisma-dark-DwgDxLwn.svg&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; alt=&quot;Prisma&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://strapi.link/tanstack-start&quot;&gt;
        &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/strapi-dark-CQ84tQTk.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/strapi-light-6x7linao.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://tanstack.com/assets/strapi-dark-CQ84tQTk.svg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; alt=&quot;Strapi&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./media/partner_logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Router &amp; you?&quot; height=&quot;65&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We&#039;re looking for TanStack Router &amp; Start Partners to join our mission! Partner with us to push the boundaries of TanStack Router &amp; Start and build amazing things together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:partners@tanstack.com?subject=TanStack Router &amp; Start Partnership&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;LET&#039;S CHAT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Explore the TanStack Ecosystem

- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/config&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Config&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Tooling for JS/TS packages
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/db&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack DB&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Reactive sync client store
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/devtools&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack DevTools&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Unified devtools panel
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/form&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Form&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Type‑safe form state
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/pacer&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Pacer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Debouncing, throttling, batching &lt;br/&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/query&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Query&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Async state &amp; caching
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/ranger&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Ranger&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Range &amp; slider primitives
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/store&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Store&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Reactive data store
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/table&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Table&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Headless datagrids
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanstack/virtual&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack Virtual&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Virtualized rendering

… and more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://tanstack.com&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;TanStack.com »&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;!-- Use the force, Luke --&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viren070/AIOStreams]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[One addon to rule them all. AIOStreams consolidates multiple Stremio addons and debrid services into a single, highly customisable super-addon.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams">Viren070/AIOStreams</a></h1>
            <p>One addon to rule them all. AIOStreams consolidates multiple Stremio addons and debrid services into a single, highly customisable super-addon.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 778</p>
            <p>Forks: 610</p>
            <p>Stars today: 15 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;
          &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/selfhst/icons/png/aiostreams-light.png&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img alt=&quot;AIOStreams Logo&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/selfhst/icons/png/aiostreams.png&quot; width=256 height=256&gt;
    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;AIOStreams&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;One addon to rule them all.&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
  AIOStreams consolidates multiple Stremio addons and debrid services - including its own suite of built-in addons - into a single, highly customisable super-addon.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/actions/workflows/deploy-docker.yml&quot;&gt; 
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/viren070/aiostreams/deploy-docker.yml?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/releases/latest&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/viren070/aiostreams?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;Latest Release&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/stargazers&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/Viren070/AIOStreams?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=github&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Stars&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/viren070/aiostreams&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/viren070/aiostreams?style=for-the-badge&amp;logo=docker&quot; alt=&quot;Docker Pulls&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.viren070.me&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join_Chat-7289DA?logo=discord&amp;logoColor=white&amp;style=for-the-badge&quot; alt=&quot;Discord Server&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

---

## ✨ What is AIOStreams?

AIOStreams was created to give users ultimate control over their Stremio experience. Instead of juggling multiple addons with different configurations and limitations, AIOStreams acts as a central hub. It fetches results from all your favorite sources, then filters, sorts, and formats them according to *your* rules before presenting them in a single, clean list.

Whether you&#039;re a casual user who wants a simple, unified stream list or a power user who wants to fine-tune every aspect of your results, AIOStreams has you covered.


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/6179efdb-abc9-4e0c-ae11-fb0e3ca9606a&quot; alt=&quot;AIOStreams in action&quot;  width=&quot;750&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 🚀 Key Features

### 🔌 All Your Addons, One Interface
- **Unified Results**: Aggregate streams from multiple addons into one consistently sorted and formatted list.
- **Simplified Addon Management**: AIOStreams features a built-in addon marketplace. Many addons require you to install them multiple times to support different debrid services. AIOStreams handles this automatically. Just enable an addon from the marketplace, and AIOStreams dynamically applies your debrid keys, so you only have to configure it once.
- **Automatic Updates**: Because addon manifests are generated dynamically, you get the latest updates and fixes without ever needing to reconfigure or reinstall.
- **Custom Addon Support**: Add *any* Stremio addon by providing its configured URL. If it works in Stremio, it works here.
- **Full Stremio Support**: AIOStreams doesn&#039;t just manage streams; it supports all Stremio resources, including catalogs, metadata, and even addon catalogs.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/eb47063c-7519-4619-804f-ad84a34d6591&quot; alt=&quot;Addon Configuration&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### 🧩 Built-in Addons
Think of &quot;built-in addons&quot; as independent addons bundled exclusively with AIOStreams. When you host AIOStreams, you&#039;re also hosting these addons, ready to be added to your configuration just like any other community addon (e.g., Comet, Torrentio).

AIOStreams includes over 10 built-in addons that search various sources and deliver results that can usually be streamed through your debrid service. 

&gt; [!NOTE]
&gt; At this time, these addons require a debrid service and do not yet support P2P streaming. All built-in addons come with anime support and support Kitsu/MAL catalogs.

The suite of built-in addons includes:
- **Stremio GDrive**: Connect your Google Drive to Stremio.
- **TorBox Search**: An alternative to the official TorBox addon with more customisability and support for more debrid services.
- **Knaben**: Scrapes Knaben, an indexer proxy for several popular torrent sites including The Pirate Bay, 1337x, and Nyaa.si.
- **Zilean**: Scrapes an instance of Zilean - A DMM hashlist scraper.
- **AnimeTosho**: Searches AnimeTosho, which mirrors most anime from Nyaa.si and TokyoTosho.
- **Torrent Galaxy**: Searches Torrent Galaxy for results.
- **Bitmagnet**: Scrape your self-hosted Bitmagnet instance - a BitTorrent indexer and DHT crawler. Set `BUILTIN_BITMAGNET_URL` for the addon to appear.
- **Jackett**: Connect and scrape your Jackett instance by providing its URL and API key.
- **Prowlarr**: Connect and scrape your Prowlarr instance by providing its URL and API key.
- **NZBHydra**: Stream results from your Usenet indexers with TorBox by connecting your NZBHydra instance.
- **Newznab**: Directly configure and scrape your Usenet indexers for results with TorBox using a Newznab API.
- **Torznab**: Configure any Torznab API to scrape torrent results, allowing individual indexers from Jackett to be added separately.

### 🔬 Advanced Filtering &amp; Sorting Engine
Because all addons are routed through AIOStreams, you only have to **configure your filters and sorting rules once**. This powerful, centralized engine offers far more options and flexibility than any individual addon.

- **Granular Filtering**: Define `include` (prevents filtering), `required`, or `excluded` rules for a huge range of properties:
    - **Video/Audio**: Resolution, quality, encodes, visual tags (`HDR`, `DV`), audio tags (`Atmos`), and channels.
    - **Source**: Stream type (`Debrid`, `Usenet`, `P2P`), language, seeder ranges, and cached/uncached status (can be applied to specific addons/services).
- **Preferred Lists**: Manually define and order a list of preferred properties to prioritize certain results, for example, always showing `HDR` streams first.
- **Keyword &amp; Regex Filtering**: Filter by simple keywords or complex regex patterns matched against filenames, indexers and release groups for ultimate precision.
- **Accurate Title Matching**: Leverages the TMDB API to precisely match titles, years, and season/episode numbers, ensuring you always get the right content. This can be granularly applied to specific addons or content types.
- **Powerful Conditional Engine**: Create dynamic rules with a simple yet powerful expression language.
    - *Example*: Only exclude 720p streams if more than five 1080p streams are available: `count(resolution(streams, &#039;1080p&#039;)) &gt; 5 ? resolution(streams, &#039;720p&#039;) : false`.
    - Check the wiki for a [full function reference](https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/wiki/Stream-Expression-Language).
- **Customisable Deduplication**: Choose how duplicate streams are detected: by filename, infohash, and a unique &quot;smart detect&quot; hash generated from certain file attributes.
- **Sophisticated Sorting**:
    - Build your perfect sort order using any combination of criteria.
    - Define separate sorting logic for movies, series, anime, and even for cached vs. uncached results.
    - The sorting system automatically uses the rankings from your &quot;Preferred Lists&quot;.

### 🗂️ Unified Catalog Management
Take control of your Stremio home page. AIOStreams lets you manage catalogs from all your addons in one place.
- **Rename**: Rename both the name and the type of the catalog to whatever you want. (e.g. Changing Cinemeta&#039;s `Popular - Movies` to `Popular - 📺`)
- **Reorder &amp; Disable**: Arrange catalogs in your preferred order or hide the ones you don&#039;t use.
- **Shuffle Catalogs**: Discover new content by shuffling the results of any catalog. You can even persist the shuffle for a set period.
- **Enhanced Posters**: Automatically apply high-quality posters from [RPDB](https://rpdb.net/) to catalogs that provide a supported metadata source, even if the original addon doesn&#039;t support it.

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/12c26705-a373-42b4-9164-0c23b9e9cbe6&quot; alt=&quot;Filtering and Sorting Rules&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

### 🎨 Total Customization
- **Custom Stream Formatting**: Design exactly how stream information is displayed using a powerful templating system.
- **Live Preview**: See your custom format changes in real-time as you build them.
- **Predefined Formats**: Get started quickly with built-in formats, some created by me and others inspired by other popular addons like Torrentio and the TorBox Stremio Addon.
- **[Custom Formatter Wiki](https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/wiki/Custom-Formatter)**: Dive deep into the documentation to create your perfect stream title.


&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/906cc3fc-16d1-4702-99c7-425b2445387b&quot; alt=&quot;Custom Formatter UI&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;sub&gt;
    This format was created by one of our community members in the 
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.viren070.me&quot;&gt;Discord Server&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


### 🛡️ Proxy &amp; Performance
- **Proxy Integration**: Seamlessly proxy streams through **[MediaFlow Proxy](https://github.com/mhdzumair/mediaflow-proxy)** or **[StremThru](https://github.com/MunifTanjim/stremthru)**.
- **Bypass IP Restrictions**: Essential for services that limit simultaneous connections from different IP addresses.
- **Improve Compatibility**: Fixes playback issues with certain players (like Infuse) and addons.

And much much more...

## 🚀 Getting Started

Setting up AIOStreams is simple.

1.  **Choose a Hosting Method**
    - **🔓 Public Instance**: Use the **[Community Instance (Hosted by ElfHosted)](https://aiostreams.elfhosted.com/configure)**. It&#039;s free, but rate-limited and has Torrentio disabled.
    - **🛠️ Self-Host / Paid Hosting**: For full control and no rate limits, host it yourself (Docker) or use a paid service like **[ElfHosted](https://store.elfhosted.com/product/aiostreams/elf/viren070/)** (using this link supports the project!).

2.  **Configure Your Addon**
    - Open the `/stremio/configure` page of your AIOStreams instance in a web browser.
    - Enable the addons you use, add your debrid API keys, and set up your filtering, sorting, and formatting rules.

3.  **Install**
    - Click the &quot;Install&quot; button. This will open your Stremio addon compatible app and add your newly configured AIOStreams addon.

For detailed instructions, check out the Wiki:
- **[Deployment Guide](https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/wiki/Deployment)**
- **[Configuration Guide](https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams/wiki/Configuration)**

## ❤️ Support the Project

AIOStreams is a passion project developed and maintained for free. If you find it useful, please consider supporting its development.

- ⭐ **Star the Repository** on [GitHub](https://github.com/Viren070/AIOStreams).
- ⭐ **Star the Addon** in the [Stremio Community Catalog](https://beta.stremio-addons.net/addons/aiostreams).
- 🤝 **Contribute**: Report issues, suggest features, or submit pull requests.
- ☕ **Donate**:
  - **[Ko-fi](https://ko-fi.com/viren070)**
  - **[GitHub Sponsors](https://github.com/sponsors/Viren070)**

---

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt; ⭐ Star History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=Viren070/AIOStreams&amp;type=Date&quot; href=&quot;https://www.star-history.com/#Viren070/AIOStreams&amp;Date&quot; alt=&quot;Filtering and Sorting Rules&quot; width=&quot;750&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

---

## ⚠️ Disclaimer

AIOStreams is a tool for aggregating and managing data from other Stremio addons. It does not host, store, or distribute any content. The developer does not endorse or promote access to copyrighted content. Users are solely responsible for complying with all applicable laws and the terms of service for any addons or services they use with AIOStreams.

## 🙏 Credits

This project wouldn&#039;t be possible without the foundational work of many others in the community, especially those who develop the addons that AIOStreams integrates. Special thanks to the developers of all the integrated addons, the creators of [mhdzumair/mediaflow-proxy](https://github.com/mhdzumair/mediaflow-proxy) and [MunifTanjim/stremthru](https://github.com/MunifTanjim/stremthru), and the open-source projects that inspired parts of AIOStreams&#039; design:

* UI Components and issue templates adapted with permission from [5rahim/seanime](https://github.com/5rahim/seanime) (which any anime enthusiast should definitely check out!)
* [sleeyax/stremio-easynews-addon](https://github.com/sleeyax/stremio-easynews-addon) for the projects initial structure
* Custom formatter system inspired by and adapted from [diced/zipline](https://github.com/diced/zipline).
* Condition engine powered by [expr-eval](https://github.com/silentmatt/expr-eval)
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[payloadcms/payload]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/payloadcms/payload</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/payloadcms/payload</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Payload is the open-source, fullstack Next.js framework, giving you instant backend superpowers. Get a full TypeScript backend and admin panel instantly. Use Payload as a headless CMS or for building powerful applications.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/payloadcms/payload">payloadcms/payload</a></h1>
            <p>Payload is the open-source, fullstack Next.js framework, giving you instant backend superpowers. Get a full TypeScript backend and admin panel instantly. Use Payload as a headless CMS or for building powerful applications.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 37,691</p>
            <p>Forks: 2,934</p>
            <p>Stars today: 17 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;a href=&quot;https://payloadcms.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://l4wlsi8vxy8hre4v.public.blob.vercel-storage.com/github-banner-new-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Payload headless CMS Admin panel built with React&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/actions&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Workflow Status&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/actions/workflow/status/payloadcms/payload/main.yml?style=flat-square&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/payload&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Discord&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/967097582721572934?label=Discord&amp;color=7289da&amp;style=flat-square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/payload&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;npm&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/dw/payload?style=flat-square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;npm&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors-anon/payloadcms/payload?color=yellow&amp;style=flat-square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/payload&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;npm&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/payload?style=flat-square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/payloadcms&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/follow-payloadcms-1DA1F2?logo=twitter&amp;style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;Payload Twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://payloadcms.com/docs/getting-started/what-is-payload&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore the Docs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;·&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://payloadcms.com/community-help&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;·&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/discussions/1539&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roadmap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;·&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.g2.com/products/payload-cms/reviews#reviews&quot; rel=&quot;dofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View G2 Reviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;

&gt; [!IMPORTANT]
&gt; 🎉 &lt;strong&gt;We&#039;ve released 3.0!&lt;/strong&gt; Star this repo or keep an eye on it to follow along.

Payload is the first-ever Next.js native CMS that can install directly in your existing `/app` folder. It&#039;s the start of a new era for headless CMS.

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits over a regular CMS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deploy anywhere, including serverless on Vercel for free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine your front+backend in the same &lt;code&gt;/app&lt;/code&gt; folder if you want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don&#039;t sign up for yet another SaaS - Payload is open source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Query your database in React Server Components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both admin and backend are 100% extensible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No vendor lock-in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never touch ancient WP code again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build faster, never hit a roadblock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

## Quickstart

Before beginning to work with Payload, make sure you have all of the [required software](https://payloadcms.com/docs/getting-started/installation).

```text
pnpx create-payload-app@latest
```

**If you&#039;re new to Payload, you should start with the website template** (`pnpx create-payload-app@latest -t website`). It shows how to do _everything_ - including custom Rich Text blocks, on-demand revalidation, live preview, and more. It comes with a frontend built with Tailwind all in one `/app` folder.

## One-click templates

Jumpstart your next project by starting with a pre-made template. These are production-ready, end-to-end solutions designed to get you to market as fast as possible.

### [🌐 Website](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/tree/main/templates/website)

Build any kind of website, blog, or portfolio from small to enterprise. Comes with a fully functional front-end built with RSCs and Tailwind.

We&#039;re constantly adding more templates to our [Templates Directory](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/tree/main/templates). If you maintain your own template, consider adding the `payload-template` topic to your GitHub repository for others to find.

- [Official Templates](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/tree/main/templates)
- [Community Templates](https://github.com/topics/payload-template)

## ✨ Features

- Completely free and open-source
- Next.js native, built to run inside _your_ `/app` folder
- Use server components to extend Payload UI
- Query your database directly in server components, no need for REST / GraphQL
- Fully TypeScript with automatic types for your data
- [Auth out of the box](https://payloadcms.com/docs/authentication/overview)
- [Versions and drafts](https://payloadcms.com/docs/versions/overview)
- [Localization](https://payloadcms.com/docs/configuration/localization)
- [Block-based layout builder](https://payloadcms.com/docs/fields/blocks)
- [Customizable React admin](https://payloadcms.com/docs/admin/overview)
- [Lexical rich text editor](https://payloadcms.com/docs/fields/rich-text)
- [Conditional field logic](https://payloadcms.com/docs/fields/overview#conditional-logic)
- Extremely granular [Access Control](https://payloadcms.com/docs/access-control/overview)
- [Document and field-level hooks](https://payloadcms.com/docs/hooks/overview) for every action Payload provides
- Intensely fast API
- Highly secure thanks to HTTP-only cookies, CSRF protection, and more

&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/discussions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request Feature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## 🗒️ Documentation

Check out the [Payload website](https://payloadcms.com/docs/getting-started/what-is-payload) to find in-depth documentation for everything that Payload offers.

Migrating from v2 to v3? Check out the [3.0 Migration Guide](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/blob/main/docs/migration-guide/overview.mdx) on how to do it.

## 🙋 Contributing

If you want to add contributions to this repository, please follow the instructions in [contributing.md](./CONTRIBUTING.md).

## 📚 Examples

The [Examples Directory](./examples) is a great resource for learning how to setup Payload in a variety of different ways, but you can also find great examples in our blog and throughout our social media.

If you&#039;d like to run the examples, you can use `create-payload-app` to create a project from one:

```sh
npx create-payload-app --example example_name
```

You can see more examples at:

- [Examples Directory](./examples)
- [Payload Blog](https://payloadcms.com/blog)
- [Payload YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/@payloadcms)

## 🔌 Plugins

Payload is highly extensible and allows you to install or distribute plugins that add or remove functionality. There are both officially-supported and community-supported plugins available. If you maintain your own plugin, consider adding the `payload-plugin` topic to your GitHub repository for others to find.

- [Official Plugins](https://github.com/orgs/payloadcms/repositories?q=topic%3Apayload-plugin)
- [Community Plugins](https://github.com/topics/payload-plugin)

## 🚨 Need help?

There are lots of good conversations and resources in our Github Discussions board and our Discord Server. If you&#039;re struggling with something, chances are, someone&#039;s already solved what you&#039;re up against. :point_down:

- [GitHub Discussions](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/discussions)
- [GitHub Issues](https://github.com/payloadcms/payload/issues)
- [Discord](https://t.co/30APlsQUPB)
- [Community Help](https://payloadcms.com/community-help)

## ⭐ Like what we&#039;re doing? Give us a star

![payload-github-star](https://cms.payloadcms.com/media/payload-github-star.gif)

## 👏 Thanks to all our contributors

&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;https://contributors-img.web.app/image?repo=payloadcms/payload&quot;/&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[calcom/cal.com]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/calcom/cal.com</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/calcom/cal.com</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Scheduling infrastructure for absolutely everyone.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/calcom/cal.com">calcom/cal.com</a></h1>
            <p>Scheduling infrastructure for absolutely everyone.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 38,178</p>
            <p>Forks: 10,596</p>
            <p>Stars today: 15 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;!-- PROJECT LOGO --&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/8019099/210054112-5955e812-a76e-4160-9ddd-58f2c72f1cce.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;h3 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Cal.com (formerly Calendso)&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    The open-source Calendly successor.
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more »&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/discussions&quot;&gt;Discussions&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/issues&quot;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt;
    ·
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/products/cal-com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Product%20Hunt-%231%20Product%20of%20the%20Month-%23DA552E&quot; alt=&quot;Product Hunt&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://api.checklyhq.com/v1/badges/groups/1120718?style=flat&amp;theme=default&quot; alt=&quot;Checkly QA&quot;&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://status.cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20px&quot; src=&quot;https://betteruptime.com/status-badges/v1/monitor/a9kf.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Uptime&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/stargazers&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/calcom/cal.com&quot; alt=&quot;Github Stars&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34507672&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Hacker%20News-%231-%23FF6600&quot; alt=&quot;Hacker News&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/blob/main/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-AGPLv3-purple&quot; alt=&quot;License&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/pulse&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/calcom/cal.com&quot; alt=&quot;Commits-per-month&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/pricing&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Pricing-Free-brightgreen&quot; alt=&quot;Pricing&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://jitsu.com?utm_source=github/calcom/cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Metrics_tracked_by-JITSU-AA00FF?logo=data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAAOCAYAAAAfSC3RAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAACKSURBVHgBrZDRCYAwDEQv6gCOoKO4hOCXI9QVnEZwiY5iF5GaVClaBNtioCSUvCR3tMJaxIfZgW4AGUoEPVwgPZoS0Dmgg3NBVDFNbMIsmYCak3J1jDk9iCQvsKJvkzr71N81Gj6vDT/LU2P6RhY63jcafk3YJEbgeZpiFyc/5HJKv8Ef273NSfABGbQfUZhnOSAAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&quot; alt=&quot;Jitsu Tracked&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;https://api.checklyhq.com/v1/badges/checks/5e048048-1b51-47ba-9209-60607507622e?responseTime=true&quot; alt=&quot;Checkly Availability&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/r/calcom/cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/calcom/cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitch.tv/calcomtv&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/twitch/status/calcomtv?style=flat&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/issues?q=is:issue+is:open+label:%22%F0%9F%99%8B%F0%9F%8F%BB%E2%80%8D%E2%99%82%EF%B8%8Fhelp+wanted%22&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Help%20Wanted-Contribute-blue&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/figma&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Figma-Design%20System-blueviolet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct/ &quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Contributor%20Covenant-1.4-purple&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://console.algora.io/org/cal/bounties?status=open&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https%3A%2F%2Fconsole.algora.io%2Fapi%2Fshields%2Fcal%2Fbounties%3Fstatus%3Dopen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ABOUT THE PROJECT --&gt;

## About the Project

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;booking-screen&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/assets/8019099/407e727e-ff19-4ca4-bcae-049dca05cf02&quot;&gt;

# Scheduling infrastructure for absolutely everyone

The open source Calendly successor. You are in charge
of your own data, workflow, and appearance.

Calendly and other scheduling tools are awesome. It made our lives massively easier. We&#039;re using it for business meetings, seminars, yoga classes, and even calls with our families. However, most tools are very limited in terms of control and customization.

That&#039;s where Cal.com comes in. Self-hosted or hosted by us. White-label by design. API-driven and ready to be deployed on your own domain. Full control of your events and data.

## Recognition

#### [Hacker News](https://news.ycombinator.com/from?site=cal.com)

&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34507672&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img
    style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot;
    alt=&quot;Featured on Hacker News&quot;
    src=&quot;https://hackernews-badge.vercel.app/api?id=34507672&quot;
  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26817795&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img
    style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot;
    alt=&quot;Featured on Hacker News&quot;
    src=&quot;https://hackernews-badge.vercel.app/api?id=26817795&quot;
  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

#### [Product Hunt](https://producthunt.com/products/cal-com?utm_source=badge-top-post-badge&amp;utm_medium=badge)

&lt;a href=&quot;https://producthunt.com/posts/calendso?utm_source=badge-top-post-badge&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_souce=badge-calendso&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/top-post-badge.svg?post_id=291910&amp;theme=light&amp;period=monthly&quot; alt=&quot;Cal.com - The open source Calendly alternative | Product Hunt&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://producthunt.com/posts/calendso?utm_source=badge-featured&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_souce=badge-calendso&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/featured.svg?post_id=291910&amp;theme=light&quot; alt=&quot;Cal.com - The open source Calendly alternative | Product Hunt&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://producthunt.com/stories/how-this-open-source-calendly-alternative-rocketed-to-product-of-the-day&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cal.com/maker-grant.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Cal.com - The open source Calendly alternative | Product Hunt&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height: 54px;&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

This project is tested with browserstack

### Built With

- [Next.js](https://nextjs.org/?ref=cal.com)
- [tRPC](https://trpc.io/?ref=cal.com)
- [React.js](https://reactjs.org/?ref=cal.com)
- [Tailwind CSS](https://tailwindcss.com/?ref=cal.com)
- [Prisma.io](https://prisma.io/?ref=cal.com)
- [Daily.co](https://go.cal.com/daily)

## Contact us

Meet our sales team for any commercial inquiries.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/sales&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cal.com/book-with-cal-dark.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Book us with Cal.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Stay Up-to-Date

Cal.com officially launched as v.1.0 on the 15th of September 2021 and we&#039;ve come a long way so far. Watch **releases** of this repository to be notified of future updates:

![cal-star-github](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/8019099/154853944-a9e3c999-3da3-4048-b149-b4f73893c6fb.gif)

&lt;!-- GETTING STARTED --&gt;

## Getting Started

To get a local copy up and running, please follow these simple steps.

### Prerequisites

Here is what you need to be able to run Cal.com.

- Node.js (Version: &gt;=18.x)
- PostgreSQL (Version: &gt;=13.x)
- Yarn _(recommended)_

&gt; If you want to enable any of the available integrations, you may want to obtain additional credentials for each one. More details on this can be found below under the [integrations section](#integrations).

## Development

### Setup

1. Clone the repo into a public GitHub repository (or fork https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/fork). If you plan to distribute the code, keep the source code public to comply with [AGPLv3](https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/blob/main/LICENSE). To clone in a private repository, [acquire a commercial license](https://cal.com/sales)

   ```sh
   git clone https://github.com/calcom/cal.com.git
   ```

   &gt; If you are on Windows, run the following command on `gitbash` with admin privileges: &lt;br&gt; &gt; `git clone -c core.symlinks=true https://github.com/calcom/cal.com.git` &lt;br&gt;
   &gt; See [docs](https://cal.com/docs/how-to-guides/how-to-troubleshoot-symbolic-link-issues-on-windows#enable-symbolic-links) for more details.

2. Go to the project folder

   ```sh
   cd cal.com
   ```

3. Install packages with yarn

   ```sh
   yarn
   ```

4. Set up your `.env` file

   - Duplicate `.env.example` to `.env`
   - Use `openssl rand -base64 32` to generate a key and add it under `NEXTAUTH_SECRET` in the `.env` file.
   - Use `openssl rand -base64 32` to generate a key and add it under `CALENDSO_ENCRYPTION_KEY` in the `.env` file.

5. Setup Node
   If your Node version does not meet the project&#039;s requirements as instructed by the docs, &quot;nvm&quot; (Node Version Manager) allows using Node at the version required by the project:

   ```sh
   nvm use
   ```

   You first might need to install the specific version and then use it:

   ```sh
   nvm install &amp;&amp; nvm use
   ```

   You can install nvm from [here](https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm).

#### Quick start with `yarn dx`

&gt; - **Requires Docker and Docker Compose to be installed**
&gt; - Will start a local Postgres instance with a few test users - the credentials will be logged in the console

```sh
yarn dx
```

#### Development tip
1. Add `export NODE_OPTIONS=“--max-old-space-size=16384”` to your shell script to increase the memory limit for the node process. Alternatively, you can run this in your terminal before running the app. Replace 16384 with the amount of RAM you want to allocate to the node process.

2. Add `NEXT_PUBLIC_LOGGER_LEVEL={level}` to your .env file to control the logging verbosity for all tRPC queries and mutations.\
   Where {level} can be one of the following:

   `0` for silly \
   `1` for trace \
   `2` for debug \
   `3` for info \
   `4` for warn \
   `5` for error \
   `6` for fatal

   When you set `NEXT_PUBLIC_LOGGER_LEVEL={level}` in your .env file, it enables logging at that level and higher. Here&#039;s how it works:

   The logger will include all logs that are at the specified level or higher. For example: \

   - If you set `NEXT_PUBLIC_LOGGER_LEVEL=2`, it will log from level 2 (debug) upwards, meaning levels 2 (debug), 3 (info), 4 (warn), 5 (error), and (fatal) will be logged. \
   - If you set `NEXT_PUBLIC_LOGGER_LEVEL=3`, it will log from level 3 (info) upwards, meaning levels 3 (info), 4 (warn), 5 (error), and 6 (fatal) will be logged, but level 2 (debug) and level 1 (trace) will be ignored. \

```sh
echo &#039;NEXT_PUBLIC_LOGGER_LEVEL=3&#039; &gt;&gt; .env
```

for Logger level to be set at info, for example.

#### Gitpod Setup

1. Click the button below to open this project in Gitpod.

2. This will open a fully configured workspace in your browser with all the necessary dependencies already installed.

[![Open in Gitpod](https://gitpod.io/button/open-in-gitpod.svg)](https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/calcom/cal.com)

#### Manual setup

1. Configure environment variables in the `.env` file. Replace `&lt;user&gt;`, `&lt;pass&gt;`, `&lt;db-host&gt;`, and `&lt;db-port&gt;` with their applicable values

   ```
   DATABASE_URL=&#039;postgresql://&lt;user&gt;:&lt;pass&gt;@&lt;db-host&gt;:&lt;db-port&gt;&#039;
   ```

   &lt;details&gt;
   &lt;summary&gt;If you don&#039;t know how to configure the DATABASE_URL, then follow the steps here to create a quick local DB&lt;/summary&gt;

   1. [Download](https://www.postgresql.org/download/) and install postgres in your local (if you don&#039;t have it already).

   2. Create your own local db by executing `createDB &lt;DB name&gt;`

   3. Now open your psql shell with the DB you created: `psql -h localhost -U postgres -d &lt;DB name&gt;`

   4. Inside the psql shell execute `\conninfo`. And you will get the following info.  
      ![image](https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/39329182/236612291-51d87f69-6dc1-4a23-bf4d-1ca1754e0a35.png)

   5. Now extract all the info and add it to your DATABASE_URL. The url would look something like this
      `postgresql://postgres:postgres@localhost:5432/Your-DB-Name`. The port is configurable and does not have to be 5432.

   &lt;/details&gt;

   If you don&#039;t want to create a local DB. Then you can also consider using services like railway.app or render.

   - [Setup postgres DB with railway.app](https://docs.railway.app/guides/postgresql)
   - [Setup postgres DB with render](https://render.com/docs/databases)

1. Copy and paste your `DATABASE_URL` from `.env` to `.env.appStore`.

1. Set up the database using the Prisma schema (found in `packages/prisma/schema.prisma`)

   In a development environment, run:

   ```sh
   yarn workspace @calcom/prisma db-migrate
   ```

   In a production environment, run:

   ```sh
   yarn workspace @calcom/prisma db-deploy
   ```

1. Run [mailhog](https://github.com/mailhog/MailHog) to view emails sent during development

   &gt; **_NOTE:_** Required when `E2E_TEST_MAILHOG_ENABLED` is &quot;1&quot;

   ```sh
   docker pull mailhog/mailhog
   docker run -d -p 8025:8025 -p 1025:1025 mailhog/mailhog
   ```

1. Run (in development mode)

   ```sh
   yarn dev
   ```

#### Setting up your first user

##### Approach 1

1. Open [Prisma Studio](https://prisma.io/studio) to look at or modify the database content:

   ```sh
   yarn db-studio
   ```

1. Click on the `User` model to add a new user record.
1. Fill out the fields `email`, `username`, `password`, and set `metadata` to empty `{}` (remembering to encrypt your password with [BCrypt](https://bcrypt-generator.com/)) and click `Save 1 Record` to create your first user.
   &gt; New users are set on a `TRIAL` plan by default. You might want to adjust this behavior to your needs in the `packages/prisma/schema.prisma` file.
1. Open a browser to [http://localhost:3000](http://localhost:3000) and login with your just created, first user.

##### Approach 2

Seed the local db by running

```sh
cd packages/prisma
yarn db-seed
```

The above command will populate the local db with dummy users.

### E2E-Testing

Be sure to set the environment variable `NEXTAUTH_URL` to the correct value. If you are running locally, as the documentation within `.env.example` mentions, the value should be `http://localhost:3000`.

```sh
# In a terminal just run:
yarn test-e2e

# To open the last HTML report run:
yarn playwright show-report test-results/reports/playwright-html-report
```

#### Resolving issues

##### E2E test browsers not installed

Run `npx playwright install` to download test browsers and resolve the error below when running `yarn test-e2e`:

```
Executable doesn&#039;t exist at /Users/alice/Library/Caches/ms-playwright/chromium-1048/chrome-mac/Chromium.app/Contents/MacOS/Chromium
```

### Upgrading from earlier versions

1. Pull the current version:

   ```sh
   git pull
   ```

1. Check if dependencies got added/updated/removed

   ```sh
   yarn
   ```

1. Apply database migrations by running &lt;b&gt;one of&lt;/b&gt; the following commands:

   In a development environment, run:

   ```sh
   yarn workspace @calcom/prisma db-migrate
   ```

   (This can clear your development database in some cases)

   In a production environment, run:

   ```sh
   yarn workspace @calcom/prisma db-deploy
   ```

1. Check for `.env` variables changes

   ```sh
   yarn predev
   ```

1. Start the server. In a development environment, just do:

   ```sh
   yarn dev
   ```

   For a production build, run for example:

   ```sh
   yarn build
   yarn start
   ```

1. Enjoy the new version.
&lt;!-- DEPLOYMENT --&gt;

## Deployment

### Docker

The Docker configuration for Cal.com is an effort powered by people within the community.

If you want to contribute to the Docker repository, [reply here](https://github.com/calcom/docker/discussions/32).

The Docker configuration can be found [in our docker repository](https://github.com/calcom/docker).

Issues with Docker? Find your answer or open a new discussion [here](https://github.com/calcom/docker/discussions) to ask the community.

Cal.com, Inc. does not provide official support for Docker, but we will accept fixes and documentation. Use at your own risk.

### Railway

[![Deploy on Railway](https://railway.app/button.svg)](https://railway.app/new/template/cal)

You can deploy Cal.com on [Railway](https://railway.app) using the button above. The team at Railway also have a [detailed blog post](https://blog.railway.app/p/calendso) on deploying Cal.com on their platform.

### Vercel

Currently Vercel Pro Plan is required to be able to Deploy this application with Vercel, due to limitations on the number of serverless functions on the free plan.

[![Deploy with Vercel](https://vercel.com/button)](https://vercel.com/new/clone?repository-url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fcalcom%2Fcal.com&amp;env=DATABASE_URL,NEXT_PUBLIC_WEBAPP_URL,NEXTAUTH_URL,NEXTAUTH_SECRET,CRON_API_KEY,CALENDSO_ENCRYPTION_KEY&amp;envDescription=See%20all%20available%20env%20vars&amp;envLink=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fcalcom%2Fcal.com%2Fblob%2Fmain%2F.env.example&amp;project-name=cal&amp;repo-name=cal.com&amp;build-command=cd%20../..%20%26%26%20yarn%20build&amp;root-directory=apps%2Fweb%2F)

### Render

[![Deploy to Render](https://render.com/images/deploy-to-render-button.svg)](https://render.com/deploy?repo=https://github.com/calcom/docker)

### Elestio

[![Deploy on Elestio](https://elest.io/images/logos/deploy-to-elestio-btn.png)](https://elest.io/open-source/cal.com)

&lt;!-- ROADMAP --&gt;

## Roadmap

&lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/roadmap&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/8019099/176388295-25081ca4-207e-4468-8079-37b195fa8e59.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cal.com Roadmap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

See the [roadmap project](https://cal.com/roadmap) for a list of proposed features (and known issues). You can change the view to see planned tagged releases.

&lt;!-- LICENSE --&gt;

## License

Cal.com, Inc. is a commercial open source company, which means some parts of this open source repository require a commercial license. The concept is called &quot;Open Core&quot; where the core technology (99%) is fully open source, licensed under [AGPLv3](https://opensource.org/license/agpl-v3) and the last 1% is covered under a commercial license ([&quot;/ee&quot; Enterprise Edition](https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/tree/main/packages/features/ee)) which we believe is entirely relevant for larger organisations that require enterprise features. Enterprise features are built by the core engineering team of Cal.com, Inc. which is hired in full-time. Find their compensation on https://cal.com/open.

&gt; [!NOTE]  
&gt; Our philosophy is simple, all &quot;Singleplayer APIs&quot; are open-source under AGPLv3. All commercial &quot;Multiplayer APIs&quot; are under a commercial license.

|                                   | AGPLv3 | EE  |
| --------------------------------- | ------ | --- |
| Self-host for commercial purposes | ✅     | ✅  |
| Clone privately                   | ✅     | ✅  |
| Fork publicly                     | ✅     | ✅  |
| Requires CLA                      | ✅     | ✅  |
|  Official Support                 | ❌     | ✅  |
| Derivative work privately         | ❌     | ✅  |
|  SSO                              | ❌     | ✅  |
| Admin Panel                       | ❌     | ✅  |
| Impersonation                     | ❌     | ✅  |
| Managed Event Types               | ❌     | ✅  |
| Organizations                     | ❌     | ✅  |
| Payments                          | ❌     | ✅  |
| Platform                          | ❌     | ✅  |
| Teams                             | ❌     | ✅  |
| Users                             | ❌     | ✅  |
| Video                             | ❌     | ✅  |
| Workflows                         | ❌     | ✅  |

&gt; [!TIP]
&gt; We work closely with the community and always invite feedback about what should be open and what is fine to be commercial. This list is not set and stone and we have moved things from commercial to open in the past. Please open a [discussion](https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/discussions) if you feel like something is wrong.

## Repo Activity

&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://repobeats.axiom.co/api/embed/6bfca2f20f39738048b6e70ca205efde46352c3d.svg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;!-- CONTRIBUTING --&gt;

## Contributing

Please see our [contributing guide](/CONTRIBUTING.md).

### Good First Issues

We have a list of [help wanted](https://github.com/calcom/cal.com/issues?q=is:issue+is:open+label:%22%F0%9F%99%8B%F0%9F%8F%BB%E

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Allow LLMs to control a browser with Browserbase and Stagehand]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase">browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase</a></h1>
            <p>Allow LLMs to control a browser with Browserbase and Stagehand</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,649</p>
            <p>Forks: 290</p>
            <p>Stars today: 9 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Browserbase MCP Server

[![smithery badge](https://smithery.ai/badge/@browserbasehq/mcp-browserbase)](https://smithery.ai/server/@browserbasehq/mcp-browserbase)

![cover](assets/cover-mcp.png)

[The Model Context Protocol (MCP)](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/introduction) is an open protocol that enables seamless integration between LLM applications and external data sources and tools. Whether you&#039;re building an AI-powered IDE, enhancing a chat interface, or creating custom AI workflows, MCP provides a standardized way to connect LLMs with the context they need.

This server provides cloud browser automation capabilities using [Browserbase](https://www.browserbase.com/) and [Stagehand](https://github.com/browserbase/stagehand). It enables LLMs to interact with web pages, take screenshots, extract information, and perform automated actions with atomic precision.

## Features

| Feature            | Description                                                 |
| ------------------ | ----------------------------------------------------------- |
| Browser Automation | Control and orchestrate cloud browsers via Browserbase      |
| Data Extraction    | Extract structured data from any webpage                    |
| Web Interaction    | Navigate, click, and fill forms with ease                   |
| Screenshots        | Capture full-page and element screenshots                   |
| Model Flexibility  | Supports multiple models (OpenAI, Claude, Gemini, and more) |
| Vision Support     | Use annotated screenshots for complex DOMs                  |
| Session Management | Create, manage, and close browser sessions                  |
| Multi-Session      | Run multiple browser sessions in parallel                   |

## How to Setup

### Quickstarts:

#### Add to Cursor

Copy and Paste this link in your Browser:

```text
cursor://anysphere.cursor-deeplink/mcp/install?name=browserbase&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoibnB4IEBicm93c2VyYmFzZWhxL21jcCIsImVudiI6eyJCUk9XU0VSQkFTRV9BUElfS0VZIjoiIiwiQlJPV1NFUkJBU0VfUFJPSkVDVF9JRCI6IiIsIkdFTUlOSV9BUElfS0VZIjoiIn19
```

We currently support 2 transports for our MCP server, STDIO and SHTTP. We recommend you use SHTTP with our remote hosted url to take advantage of the server at full capacity.

## SHTTP:

To use the Browserbase MCP Server through our remote hosted URL, add the following to your configuration.

Go to [smithery.ai](https://smithery.ai/server/@browserbasehq/mcp-browserbase) and enter your API keys and configuration to get a remote hosted URL.
When using our remote hosted server, we provide the LLM costs for Gemini, the [best performing model](https://www.stagehand.dev/evals) in [Stagehand](https://www.stagehand.dev).

![Smithery Image](assets/smithery.jpg)

If your client supports SHTTP:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;your-smithery-url.com&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

If your client doesn&#039;t support SHTTP:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;mcp-remote&quot;, &quot;your-smithery-url.com&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

## STDIO:

You can either use our Server hosted on NPM or run it completely locally by cloning this repo.

&gt; **❗️ Important:** If you want to use a different model you have to add --modelName to the args and provide that respective key as an arg. More info below.

### To run on NPM (Recommended)

Go into your MCP Config JSON and add the Browserbase Server:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

That&#039;s it! Reload your MCP client and Claude will be able to use Browserbase.

### To run 100% local:

```bash
# Clone the Repo
git clone https://github.com/browserbase/mcp-server-browserbase.git
cd mcp-server-browserbase

# Install the dependencies and build the project
npm install &amp;&amp; npm run build
```

Then in your MCP Config JSON run the server. To run locally we can use STDIO or self-host SHTTP.

### STDIO:

To your MCP Config JSON file add the following:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;node&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;/path/to/mcp-server-browserbase/cli.js&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

Then reload your MCP client and you should be good to go!

## Configuration

The Browserbase MCP server accepts the following command-line flags:

| Flag                       | Description                                                                 |
| -------------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| `--proxies`                | Enable Browserbase proxies for the session                                  |
| `--advancedStealth`        | Enable Browserbase Advanced Stealth (Only for Scale Plan Users)             |
| `--keepAlive`              | Enable Browserbase Keep Alive Session                                       |
| `--contextId &lt;contextId&gt;`  | Specify a Browserbase Context ID to use                                     |
| `--persist`                | Whether to persist the Browserbase context (default: true)                  |
| `--port &lt;port&gt;`            | Port to listen on for HTTP/SHTTP transport                                  |
| `--host &lt;host&gt;`            | Host to bind server to (default: localhost, use 0.0.0.0 for all interfaces) |
| `--cookies [json]`         | JSON array of cookies to inject into the browser                            |
| `--browserWidth &lt;width&gt;`   | Browser viewport width (default: 1024)                                      |
| `--browserHeight &lt;height&gt;` | Browser viewport height (default: 768)                                      |
| `--modelName &lt;model&gt;`      | The model to use for Stagehand (default: google/gemini-2.0-flash)           |
| `--modelApiKey &lt;key&gt;`      | API key for the custom model provider (required when using custom models)   |
| `--experimental`           | Enable experimental features (default: false)                               |

These flags can be passed directly to the CLI or configured in your MCP configuration file.

### NOTE:

Currently, these flags can only be used with the local server (npx @browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase).

## Configuration Examples

### Proxies

Here are our docs on [Proxies](https://docs.browserbase.com/features/proxies).

To use proxies, set the --proxies flag in your MCP Config:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;, &quot;--proxies&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### Advanced Stealth

Here are our docs on [Advanced Stealth](https://docs.browserbase.com/features/stealth-mode#advanced-stealth-mode).

To use advanced stealth, set the --advancedStealth flag in your MCP Config:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;, &quot;--advancedStealth&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### Contexts

Here are our docs on [Contexts](https://docs.browserbase.com/features/contexts)

To use contexts, set the --contextId flag in your MCP Config:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;,
        &quot;--contextId&quot;,
        &quot;&lt;YOUR_CONTEXT_ID&gt;&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### Browser Viewport Sizing

The default viewport sizing for a browser session is 1024 x 768. You can adjust the Browser viewport sizing with browserWidth and browserHeight flags.

Here&#039;s how to use it for custom browser sizing. We recommend to stick with 16:9 aspect ratios (ie: 1920 x 1080, 1280 x 720, 1024 x 768)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;,
        &quot;--browserHeight 1080&quot;,
        &quot;--browserWidth 1920&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;GEMINI_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

### Model Configuration

Stagehand defaults to using Google&#039;s Gemini 2.0 Flash model, but you can configure it to use other models like GPT-4o, Claude, or other providers.

**Important**: When using any custom model (non-default), you must provide your own API key for that model provider using the `--modelApiKey` flag.

Here&#039;s how to configure different models:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;browserbase&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@browserbasehq/mcp-server-browserbase&quot;,
        &quot;--modelName&quot;,
        &quot;anthropic/claude-3-5-sonnet-latest&quot;,
        &quot;--modelApiKey&quot;,
        &quot;your-anthropic-api-key&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;&quot;,
        &quot;BROWSERBASE_PROJECT_ID&quot;: &quot;&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

_Note: The model must be supported in Stagehand. Check out the docs [here](https://docs.stagehand.dev/examples/custom_llms#supported-llms). When using any custom model, you must provide your own API key for that provider._

### Resources

The server provides access to screenshot resources:

1. **Screenshots** (`screenshot://&lt;screenshot-name&gt;`)
   - PNG images of captured screenshots

## Key Features

- **AI-Powered Automation**: Natural language commands for web interactions
- **Multi-Model Support**: Works with OpenAI, Claude, Gemini, and more
- **Advanced Session Management**: Single and multi-session support for parallel browser automation
- **Screenshot Capture**: Full-page and element-specific screenshots
- **Data Extraction**: Intelligent content extraction from web pages
- **Proxy Support**: Enterprise-grade proxy capabilities
- **Stealth Mode**: Advanced anti-detection features
- **Context Persistence**: Maintain authentication and state across sessions
- **Parallel Workflows**: Run multiple browser sessions simultaneously for complex automation tasks

For more information about the Model Context Protocol, visit:

- [MCP Documentation](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/docs)
- [MCP Specification](https://spec.modelcontextprotocol.io/)

For the official MCP Docs:

- [Browserbase MCP](https://docs.browserbase.com/integrations/mcp/introduction)

## License

Licensed under the Apache 2.0 License.

Copyright 2025 Browserbase, Inc.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[shadcn-ui/ui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/shadcn-ui/ui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/shadcn-ui/ui</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A set of beautifully-designed, accessible components and a code distribution platform. Works with your favorite frameworks. Open Source. Open Code.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/shadcn-ui/ui">shadcn-ui/ui</a></h1>
            <p>A set of beautifully-designed, accessible components and a code distribution platform. Works with your favorite frameworks. Open Source. Open Code.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 95,505</p>
            <p>Forks: 6,797</p>
            <p>Stars today: 65 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># shadcn/ui

Accessible and customizable components that you can copy and paste into your apps. Free. Open Source. **Use this to build your own component library**.

![hero](apps/www/public/og.jpg)

## Documentation

Visit http://ui.shadcn.com/docs to view the documentation.

## Contributing

Please read the [contributing guide](/CONTRIBUTING.md).

## License

Licensed under the [MIT license](https://github.com/shadcn/ui/blob/main/LICENSE.md).
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[exa-labs/exa-mcp-server]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/exa-labs/exa-mcp-server</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/exa-labs/exa-mcp-server</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Exa MCP for web search and web crawling!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/exa-labs/exa-mcp-server">exa-labs/exa-mcp-server</a></h1>
            <p>Exa MCP for web search and web crawling!</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,617</p>
            <p>Forks: 211</p>
            <p>Stars today: 123 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Exa MCP Server 🔍
[![npm version](https://badge.fury.io/js/exa-mcp-server.svg)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/exa-mcp-server)
[![smithery badge](https://smithery.ai/badge/exa)](https://smithery.ai/server/exa)

## 🆕 `exa-code`: fast, efficient web context for coding agents

Vibe coding should never have a bad vibe. `exa-code` is a huge step towards coding agents that never hallucinate.

When your coding agent makes a search query, `exa-code` searches over billions
of Github repos, docs pages, Stackoverflow posts, and more, to find the perfect, token-efficient context that the agent needs to code correctly. It&#039;s powered by the Exa search engine.

Examples of queries you can make with `exa-code`:
* use Exa search in python and make sure content is always livecrawled
* use correct syntax for vercel ai sdk to call gpt-5 nano asking it how are you
* how to set up a reproducible Nix Rust development environment

**✨ Works with Cursor and Claude Code!** Use the HTTP-based configuration format:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {
        &quot;Remove-Me&quot;: &quot;Disable web_search_exa tool if you&#039;re just coding. To 100% call exa-code, say &#039;use exa-code&#039;.&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

You may include your exa api key in the url like this:
```
https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp?exaApiKey=YOUREXAKEY
```

You may whitelist specific tools in the url with the `enabledTools` parameter which expects a url encoded array strings like this:
```
https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp?exaApiKey=YOUREXAKEY&amp;enabledTools=%5B%22crawling_exa%ss%5D
```

You can also use `exa-code` through [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/server/exa) without an Exa API key.

---

A Model Context Protocol (MCP) server that connects AI assistants like Claude to Exa AI&#039;s search capabilities, including web search, research tools, and our new code search feature.

## Remote Exa MCP 🌐

Connect directly to Exa&#039;s hosted MCP server (instead of running it locally).

### Remote Exa MCP URL

```
https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp
```

### Claude Desktop Configuration for Remote MCP

Add this to your Claude Desktop configuration file:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;-y&quot;,
        &quot;mcp-remote&quot;,
        &quot;https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp&quot;
      ]
    }
  }
}
```

### Cursor and Claude Code Configuration for Remote MCP

For Cursor and Claude Code, use this HTTP-based configuration format:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://mcp.exa.ai/mcp&quot;,
      &quot;headers&quot;: {}
    }
  }
}
```

### NPM Installation

```bash
npm install -g exa-mcp-server
```

### Using Claude Code

```bash
claude mcp add exa -e EXA_API_KEY=YOUR_API_KEY -- npx -y exa-mcp-server
```

### Using Exa MCP through Smithery

To install the Exa MCP server via [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/server/exa), head over to:

[smithery.ai/server/exa](https://smithery.ai/server/exa)


## Configuration ⚙️

### 1. Configure Claude Desktop to recognize the Exa MCP server

You can find claude_desktop_config.json inside the settings of Claude Desktop app:

Open the Claude Desktop app and enable Developer Mode from the top-left menu bar. 

Once enabled, open Settings (also from the top-left menu bar) and navigate to the Developer Option, where you&#039;ll find the Edit Config button. Clicking it will open the claude_desktop_config.json file, allowing you to make the necessary edits. 

OR (if you want to open claude_desktop_config.json from terminal)

#### For macOS:

1. Open your Claude Desktop configuration:

```bash
code ~/Library/Application\ Support/Claude/claude_desktop_config.json
```

#### For Windows:

1. Open your Claude Desktop configuration:

```powershell
code %APPDATA%\Claude\claude_desktop_config.json
```

### 2. Add the Exa server configuration:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;-y&quot;, &quot;exa-mcp-server&quot;],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;EXA_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;your-api-key-here&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

Replace `your-api-key-here` with your actual Exa API key from [dashboard.exa.ai/api-keys](https://dashboard.exa.ai/api-keys).

### 3. Available Tools &amp; Tool Selection

The Exa MCP server includes powerful tools for developers and researchers:

#### 🔥 **Featured: Code Search Tool**
- **get_code_context_exa**: 🆕 **NEW!** Search and get relevant code snippets, examples, and documentation from open source libraries, GitHub repositories, and programming frameworks. Perfect for finding up-to-date code documentation, implementation examples, API usage patterns, and best practices from real codebases.

#### 🌐 **Other Available Tools**
- **web_search_exa**: Performs real-time web searches with optimized results and content extraction.
- **company_research**: Comprehensive company research tool that crawls company websites to gather detailed information about businesses.
- **crawling**: Extracts content from specific URLs, useful for reading articles, PDFs, or any web page when you have the exact URL.
- **linkedin_search**: Search LinkedIn for companies and people using Exa AI. Simply include company names, person names, or specific LinkedIn URLs in your query.
- **deep_researcher_start**: Start a smart AI researcher for complex questions. The AI will search the web, read many sources, and think deeply about your question to create a detailed research report.
- **deep_researcher_check**: Check if your research is ready and get the results. Use this after starting a research task to see if it&#039;s done and get your comprehensive report.

You can choose which tools to enable by adding the `--tools` parameter to your Claude Desktop configuration:

#### 💻 **Setup for Code Search Only** (Recommended for Developers)

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;-y&quot;,
        &quot;exa-mcp-server&quot;,
        &quot;--tools=get_code_context_exa,web_search_exa&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;EXA_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;your-api-key-here&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

#### Specify which tools to enable:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;-y&quot;,
        &quot;exa-mcp-server&quot;,
        &quot;--tools=get_code_context_exa,web_search_exa,company_research,crawling,linkedin_search,deep_researcher_start,deep_researcher_check&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;EXA_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;your-api-key-here&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

For enabling multiple tools, use a comma-separated list:

```json
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;exa&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;-y&quot;,
        &quot;exa-mcp-server&quot;,
        &quot;--tools=get_code_context_exa,web_search_exa,company_research,crawling,linkedin_search,deep_researcher_start,deep_researcher_check&quot;
      ],
      &quot;env&quot;: {
        &quot;EXA_API_KEY&quot;: &quot;your-api-key-here&quot;
      }
    }
  }
}
```

If you don&#039;t specify any tools, all tools enabled by default will be used.

### 4. Restart Claude Desktop

For the changes to take effect:

1. Completely quit Claude Desktop (not just close the window)
2. Start Claude Desktop again
3. Look for the icon to verify the Exa server is connected

## Using via NPX

If you prefer to run the server directly, you can use npx:

```bash
# Run with all tools enabled by default
npx exa-mcp-server

# Enable specific tools only
npx exa-mcp-server --tools=web_search_exa

# Enable multiple tools
npx exa-mcp-server --tools=web_search_exa,get_code_context_exa

# List all available tools
npx exa-mcp-server --list-tools
```

---

Built with ❤️ by team Exa
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Chrome DevTools UI]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend">ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend</a></h1>
            <p>The Chrome DevTools UI</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 3,534</p>
            <p>Forks: 593</p>
            <p>Stars today: 12 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Chrome DevTools frontend

&lt;!-- [START badges] --&gt;

[![npm package](https://img.shields.io/npm/v/chrome-devtools-frontend.svg)](https://npmjs.org/package/chrome-devtools-frontend)

&lt;!-- [END badges] --&gt;

The client-side of the Chrome DevTools, including all TypeScript &amp; CSS to run the DevTools webapp.

### Source code and documentation

The frontend is available on [chromium.googlesource.com]. Check out the [Chromium DevTools
documentation] for instructions to [set up], use, and maintain a DevTools front-end checkout,
as well as design guidelines, and architectural documentation.

- DevTools user documentation: [devtools.chrome.com](https://devtools.chrome.com)
- Debugger protocol documentation: [chromedevtools.github.io/devtools-protocol](https://chromedevtools.github.io/devtools-protocol)
- Awesome Chrome DevTools: [github.com/paulirish/awesome-chrome-devtools](https://github.com/paulirish/awesome-chrome-devtools)
- Contributing to Chrome DevTools: [goo.gle/devtools-contribution-guide](http://goo.gle/devtools-contribution-guide)
- Contributing To Chrome DevTools Protocol: [goo.gle/devtools-contribution-guide-cdp](https://goo.gle/devtools-contribution-guide-cdp)

### Source mirrors

DevTools frontend repository is mirrored on [GitHub](https://github.com/ChromeDevTools/devtools-frontend).

DevTools frontend is also available on NPM as the [chrome-devtools-frontend](https://www.npmjs.com/package/chrome-devtools-frontend) package. It&#039;s not currently available via CJS or ES modules, so consuming this package in other tools may require [some effort](https://github.com/paulirish/devtools-timeline-model/blob/master/index.js).

The version number of the npm package (e.g. `1.0.373466`) refers to the Chromium commit position of latest frontend git commit. It&#039;s incremented with every Chromium commit, however the package is updated roughly daily.

### Getting in touch

- [@ChromeDevTools] on Twitter
- Chrome DevTools mailing list: [g/google-chrome-developer-tools]
- File a new DevTools ticket: [goo.gle/devtools-bug]

There are a few options to keep an eye on the latest and greatest of DevTools development:

- Follow [What&#039;s new in DevTools].
- Follow [Umar&#039;s Dev Tips].
- Follow these individual Twitter accounts:
  [@umaar](https://x.com/umaar),
  [@malyw](https://x.com/malyw),
  [@kdzwinel](https://x.com/kdzwinel),
  [@addyosmani](https://x.com/addyosmani),
  [@paul_irish](https://x.com/paul_irish),
  [@samccone](https://x.com/samccone),
  [@mathias](https://x.com/ziyunfei),
  [@mattzeunert](https://x.com/mattzeunert),
  [@PrashantPalikhe](https://x.com/PrashantPalikhe),
  [@ziyunfei](https://x.com/ziyunfei), and
  [@bmeurer](https://x.com/bmeurer).
- Follow to [g/devtools-reviews@chromium.org] mailing list for all reviews of pending code,
  and [view the log], or follow [@DevToolsCommits] on Twitter.
- Checkout [all open DevTools tickets] on crbug.com
- Use Chrome Canary and poke around the experiments.

  [Chromium DevTools documentation]: http://goo.gle/chromium-devtools
  [set up]: https://chromium.googlesource.com/devtools/devtools-frontend/+/main/docs/get_the_code.md
  [chromium.googlesource.com]: https://chromium.googlesource.com/devtools/devtools-frontend
  [What&#039;s new in DevTools]: https://developer.chrome.com/docs/devtools/news
  [Umar&#039;s Dev Tips]: https://umaar.com/dev-tips
  [g/devtools-reviews@chromium.org]: https://groups.google.com/a/chromium.org/forum/#!forum/devtools-reviews
  [view the log]: https://chromium.googlesource.com/devtools/devtools-frontend/+log/main
  [@ChromeDevTools]: http://x.com/ChromeDevTools
  [@DevToolsCommits]: http://x.com/DevToolsCommits
  [all open DevTools tickets]: http://goo.gle/devtools-bugs
  [g/google-chrome-developer-tools]: https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/google-chrome-developer-tools
  [goo.gle/devtools-bug]: http://goo.gle/devtools-bug
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[google-gemini/gemini-cli]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[An open-source AI agent that brings the power of Gemini directly into your terminal.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli">google-gemini/gemini-cli</a></h1>
            <p>An open-source AI agent that brings the power of Gemini directly into your terminal.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 77,161</p>
            <p>Forks: 8,283</p>
            <p>Stars today: 347 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre># Gemini CLI

[![Gemini CLI CI](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/actions/workflows/ci.yml)
[![Gemini CLI E2E](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/actions/workflows/e2e.yml/badge.svg)](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/actions/workflows/e2e.yml)
[![Version](https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@google/gemini-cli)](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@google/gemini-cli)
[![License](https://img.shields.io/github/license/google-gemini/gemini-cli)](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/blob/main/LICENSE)

![Gemini CLI Screenshot](./docs/assets/gemini-screenshot.png)

Gemini CLI is an open-source AI agent that brings the power of Gemini directly into your terminal. It provides lightweight access to Gemini, giving you the most direct path from your prompt to our model.

## 🚀 Why Gemini CLI?

- **🎯 Free tier**: 60 requests/min and 1,000 requests/day with personal Google account
- **🧠 Powerful Gemini 2.5 Pro**: Access to 1M token context window
- **🔧 Built-in tools**: Google Search grounding, file operations, shell commands, web fetching
- **🔌 Extensible**: MCP (Model Context Protocol) support for custom integrations
- **💻 Terminal-first**: Designed for developers who live in the command line
- **🛡️ Open source**: Apache 2.0 licensed

## 📦 Installation

### Quick Install

#### Run instantly with npx

```bash
# Using npx (no installation required)
npx https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli
```

#### Install globally with npm

```bash
npm install -g @google/gemini-cli
```

#### Install globally with Homebrew (macOS/Linux)

```bash
brew install gemini-cli
```

#### System Requirements

- Node.js version 20 or higher
- macOS, Linux, or Windows

## Release Cadence and Tags

See [Releases](./docs/releases.md) for more details.

### Preview

New preview releases will be published each week at UTC 2359 on Tuesdays. These releases will not have been fully vetted and may contain regressions or other outstanding issues. Please help us test and install with `preview` tag.

```bash
npm install -g @google/gemini-cli@preview
```

### Stable

- New stable releases will be published each week at UTC 2000 on Tuesdays, this will be the full promotion of last week&#039;s `preview` release + any bug fixes and validations. Use `latest` tag.

```bash
npm install -g @google/gemini-cli@latest
```

### Nightly

- New releases will be published each week at UTC 0000 each day, This will be all changes from the main branch as represented at time of release. It should be assumed there are pending validations and issues. Use `nightly` tag.

```bash
npm install -g @google/gemini-cli@nightly
```

## 📋 Key Features

### Code Understanding &amp; Generation

- Query and edit large codebases
- Generate new apps from PDFs, images, or sketches using multimodal capabilities
- Debug issues and troubleshoot with natural language

### Automation &amp; Integration

- Automate operational tasks like querying pull requests or handling complex rebases
- Use MCP servers to connect new capabilities, including [media generation with Imagen, Veo or Lyria](https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/vertex-ai-creative-studio/tree/main/experiments/mcp-genmedia)
- Run non-interactively in scripts for workflow automation

### Advanced Capabilities

- Ground your queries with built-in [Google Search](https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/grounding) for real-time information
- Conversation checkpointing to save and resume complex sessions
- Custom context files (GEMINI.md) to tailor behavior for your projects

### GitHub Integration

Integrate Gemini CLI directly into your GitHub workflows with [**Gemini CLI GitHub Action**](https://github.com/google-github-actions/run-gemini-cli):

- **Pull Request Reviews**: Automated code review with contextual feedback and suggestions
- **Issue Triage**: Automated labeling and prioritization of GitHub issues based on content analysis
- **On-demand Assistance**: Mention `@gemini-cli` in issues and pull requests for help with debugging, explanations, or task delegation
- **Custom Workflows**: Build automated, scheduled and on-demand workflows tailored to your team&#039;s needs

## 🔐 Authentication Options

Choose the authentication method that best fits your needs:

### Option 1: Login with Google (OAuth login using your Google Account)

**✨ Best for:**

- Individual developers.
- Google AI Pro and AI Ultra subscribers.
- Anyone who has a Gemini Code Assist license.

_See [quota limits and terms of service](https://cloud.google.com/gemini/docs/quotas) for details._

**Benefits:**

- **Free tier** with 60 requests/min and 1,000 requests/day
- **Gemini 2.5 Pro and Flash** with 1M token context window
- **No API key management** - just sign in with your Google account
- **Automatic updates** to our latest models

#### Start Gemini CLI, then choose _Login with Google_ and follow the browser authentication flow when prompted

```bash
gemini
```

#### If you are using a paid Code Assist License from your organization, remember to set the Google Cloud Project

```bash
# Set your Google Cloud Project
export GOOGLE_CLOUD_PROJECT=&quot;YOUR_PROJECT_NAME&quot;
gemini
```

### Option 2: Gemini API Key

**✨ Best for:** Developers who need specific model control or paid tier access

**Benefits:**

- **Free tier**: 100 requests/day with Gemini 2.5 Pro
- **Model selection**: Choose specific Gemini models
- **Usage-based billing**: Upgrade for higher limits when needed

```bash
# Get your key from https://aistudio.google.com/apikey
export GEMINI_API_KEY=&quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
gemini
```

### Option 3: Vertex AI

**✨ Best for:** Enterprise teams and production workloads

**Benefits:**

- **Enterprise features**: Advanced security and compliance
- **Scalable**: Higher rate limits with billing account
- **Integration**: Works with existing Google Cloud infrastructure

```bash
# Get your key from Google Cloud Console
export GOOGLE_API_KEY=&quot;YOUR_API_KEY&quot;
export GOOGLE_GENAI_USE_VERTEXAI=true
gemini
```

For Google Workspace accounts and other authentication methods, see the [authentication guide](./docs/cli/authentication.md).

## 🚀 Getting Started

### Basic Usage

#### Start in current directory

```bash
gemini
```

#### Include multiple directories

```bash
gemini --include-directories ../lib,../docs
```

#### Use specific model

```bash
gemini -m gemini-2.5-flash
```

#### Non-interactive mode for scripts

Get a simple text response:

```bash
gemini -p &quot;Explain the architecture of this codebase&quot;
```

For more advanced scripting, including how to parse JSON and handle errors, use
the `--output-format json` flag to get structured output:

```bash
gemini -p &quot;Explain the architecture of this codebase&quot; --output-format json
```

### Quick Examples

#### Start a new project

```bash
cd new-project/
gemini
&gt; Write me a Discord bot that answers questions using a FAQ.md file I will provide
```

#### Analyze existing code

```bash
git clone https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli
cd gemini-cli
gemini
&gt; Give me a summary of all of the changes that went in yesterday
```

## 📚 Documentation

### Getting Started

- [**Quickstart Guide**](./docs/cli/index.md) - Get up and running quickly
- [**Authentication Setup**](./docs/cli/authentication.md) - Detailed auth configuration
- [**Configuration Guide**](./docs/cli/configuration.md) - Settings and customization
- [**Keyboard Shortcuts**](./docs/keyboard-shortcuts.md) - Productivity tips

### Core Features

- [**Commands Reference**](./docs/cli/commands.md) - All slash commands (`/help`, `/chat`, `/mcp`, etc.)
- [**Checkpointing**](./docs/checkpointing.md) - Save and resume conversations
- [**Memory Management**](./docs/tools/memory.md) - Using GEMINI.md context files
- [**Token Caching**](./docs/cli/token-caching.md) - Optimize token usage

### Tools &amp; Extensions

- [**Built-in Tools Overview**](./docs/tools/index.md)
  - [File System Operations](./docs/tools/file-system.md)
  - [Shell Commands](./docs/tools/shell.md)
  - [Web Fetch &amp; Search](./docs/tools/web-fetch.md)
  - [Multi-file Operations](./docs/tools/multi-file.md)
- [**MCP Server Integration**](./docs/tools/mcp-server.md) - Extend with custom tools
- [**Custom Extensions**](./docs/extension.md) - Build your own commands

### Advanced Topics

- [**Architecture Overview**](./docs/architecture.md) - How Gemini CLI works
- [**IDE Integration**](./docs/ide-integration.md) - VS Code companion
- [**Sandboxing &amp; Security**](./docs/sandbox.md) - Safe execution environments
- [**Enterprise Deployment**](./docs/deployment.md) - Docker, system-wide config
- [**Telemetry &amp; Monitoring**](./docs/telemetry.md) - Usage tracking
- [**Tools API Development**](./docs/core/tools-api.md) - Create custom tools

### Configuration &amp; Customization

- [**Settings Reference**](./docs/cli/configuration.md) - All configuration options
- [**Theme Customization**](./docs/cli/themes.md) - Visual customization
- [**.gemini Directory**](./docs/gemini-ignore.md) - Project-specific settings
- [**Environment Variables**](./docs/cli/configuration.md#environment-variables)

### Troubleshooting &amp; Support

- [**Troubleshooting Guide**](./docs/troubleshooting.md) - Common issues and solutions
- [**FAQ**](./docs/troubleshooting.md#frequently-asked-questions) - Quick answers
- Use `/bug` command to report issues directly from the CLI

### Using MCP Servers

Configure MCP servers in `~/.gemini/settings.json` to extend Gemini CLI with custom tools:

```text
&gt; @github List my open pull requests
&gt; @slack Send a summary of today&#039;s commits to #dev channel
&gt; @database Run a query to find inactive users
```

See the [MCP Server Integration guide](./docs/tools/mcp-server.md) for setup instructions.

## 🤝 Contributing

We welcome contributions! Gemini CLI is fully open source (Apache 2.0), and we encourage the community to:

- Report bugs and suggest features
- Improve documentation
- Submit code improvements
- Share your MCP servers and extensions

See our [Contributing Guide](./CONTRIBUTING.md) for development setup, coding standards, and how to submit pull requests.

Check our [Official Roadmap](https://github.com/orgs/google-gemini/projects/11/) for planned features and priorities.

## 📖 Resources

- **[Official Roadmap](./ROADMAP.md)** - See what&#039;s coming next
- **[NPM Package](https://www.npmjs.com/package/@google/gemini-cli)** - Package registry
- **[GitHub Issues](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/issues)** - Report bugs or request features
- **[Security Advisories](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/security/advisories)** - Security updates

### Uninstall

See the [Uninstall Guide](docs/Uninstall.md) for removal instructions.

## 📄 Legal

- **License**: [Apache License 2.0](LICENSE)
- **Terms of Service**: [Terms &amp; Privacy](./docs/tos-privacy.md)
- **Security**: [Security Policy](SECURITY.md)

---

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Built with ❤️ by Google and the open source community
&lt;/p&gt;
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[microsoft/playwright-mcp]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/microsoft/playwright-mcp</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/microsoft/playwright-mcp</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Playwright MCP server]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/microsoft/playwright-mcp">microsoft/playwright-mcp</a></h1>
            <p>Playwright MCP server</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 20,532</p>
            <p>Forks: 1,607</p>
            <p>Stars today: 65 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>## Playwright MCP

A Model Context Protocol (MCP) server that provides browser automation capabilities using [Playwright](https://playwright.dev). This server enables LLMs to interact with web pages through structured accessibility snapshots, bypassing the need for screenshots or visually-tuned models.

### Key Features

- **Fast and lightweight**. Uses Playwright&#039;s accessibility tree, not pixel-based input.
- **LLM-friendly**. No vision models needed, operates purely on structured data.
- **Deterministic tool application**. Avoids ambiguity common with screenshot-based approaches.

### Requirements
- Node.js 18 or newer
- VS Code, Cursor, Windsurf, Claude Desktop, Goose or any other MCP client

&lt;!--
// Generate using:
node utils/generate-links.js
--&gt;

### Getting started

First, install the Playwright MCP server with your client.

**Standard config** works in most of the tools:

```js
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;
      ]
    }
  }
}
```

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-VS_Code?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Server&amp;color=0098FF&quot; alt=&quot;Install in VS Code&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22playwright%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22%40playwright%2Fmcp%40latest%22%5D%2C%22cwd%22%3A%22%24%7BworkspaceFolder%7D%22%7D) [&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code Insiders&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code_Insiders-VS_Code_Insiders?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Server&amp;color=24bfa5&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode-insiders%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22playwright%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22%40playwright%2Fmcp%40latest%22%5D%2C%22cwd%22%3A%22%24%7BworkspaceFolder%7D%22%7D)


&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Claude Code&lt;/summary&gt;

Use the Claude Code CLI to add the Playwright MCP server:

```bash
claude mcp add playwright npx @playwright/mcp@latest
```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Claude Desktop&lt;/summary&gt;

Follow the MCP install [guide](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/quickstart/user), use the standard config above.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Codex&lt;/summary&gt;

Create or edit the configuration file `~/.codex/config.toml` and add:

```toml
[mcp_servers.playwright]
command = &quot;npx&quot;
args = [&quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;]
```

For more information, see the [Codex MCP documentation](https://github.com/openai/codex/blob/main/codex-rs/config.md#mcp_servers).

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Cursor&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Click the button to install:

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://cursor.com/deeplink/mcp-install-dark.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Install in Cursor&quot;&gt;](https://cursor.com/en/install-mcp?name=Playwright&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoibnB4IEBwbGF5d3JpZ2h0L21jcEBsYXRlc3QifQ%3D%3D)

#### Or install manually:

Go to `Cursor Settings` -&gt; `MCP` -&gt; `Add new MCP Server`. Name to your liking, use `command` type with the command `npx @playwright/mcp@latest`. You can also verify config or add command like arguments via clicking `Edit`.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Gemini CLI&lt;/summary&gt;

Follow the MCP install [guide](https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/blob/main/docs/tools/mcp-server.md#configure-the-mcp-server-in-settingsjson), use the standard config above.

&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Goose&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Click the button to install:

[![Install in Goose](https://block.github.io/goose/img/extension-install-dark.svg)](https://block.github.io/goose/extension?cmd=npx&amp;arg=%40playwright%2Fmcp%40latest&amp;id=playwright&amp;name=Playwright&amp;description=Interact%20with%20web%20pages%20through%20structured%20accessibility%20snapshots%20using%20Playwright)

#### Or install manually:

Go to `Advanced settings` -&gt; `Extensions` -&gt; `Add custom extension`. Name to your liking, use type `STDIO`, and set the `command` to `npx @playwright/mcp`. Click &quot;Add Extension&quot;.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;LM Studio&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Click the button to install:

[![Add MCP Server playwright to LM Studio](https://files.lmstudio.ai/deeplink/mcp-install-light.svg)](https://lmstudio.ai/install-mcp?name=playwright&amp;config=eyJjb21tYW5kIjoibnB4IiwiYXJncyI6WyJAcGxheXdyaWdodC9tY3BAbGF0ZXN0Il19)

#### Or install manually:

Go to `Program` in the right sidebar -&gt; `Install` -&gt; `Edit mcp.json`. Use the standard config above.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;opencode&lt;/summary&gt;

Follow the MCP Servers [documentation](https://opencode.ai/docs/mcp-servers/). For example in `~/.config/opencode/opencode.json`:

```json
{
  &quot;$schema&quot;: &quot;https://opencode.ai/config.json&quot;,
  &quot;mcp&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;type&quot;: &quot;local&quot;,
      &quot;command&quot;: [
        &quot;npx&quot;,
        &quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;
      ],
      &quot;enabled&quot;: true
    }
  }
}

```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Qodo Gen&lt;/summary&gt;

Open [Qodo Gen](https://docs.qodo.ai/qodo-documentation/qodo-gen) chat panel in VSCode or IntelliJ → Connect more tools → + Add new MCP → Paste the standard config above.

Click &lt;code&gt;Save&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;VS Code&lt;/summary&gt;

#### Click the button to install:

[&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code-VS_Code?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Server&amp;color=0098FF&quot; alt=&quot;Install in VS Code&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22playwright%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22%40playwright%2Fmcp%40latest%22%5D%2C%22cwd%22%3A%22%24%7BworkspaceFolder%7D%22%7D) [&lt;img alt=&quot;Install in VS Code Insiders&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/VS_Code_Insiders-VS_Code_Insiders?style=flat-square&amp;label=Install%20Server&amp;color=24bfa5&quot;&gt;](https://insiders.vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode-insiders%3Amcp%2Finstall%3F%7B%22name%22%3A%22playwright%22%2C%22command%22%3A%22npx%22%2C%22args%22%3A%5B%22%40playwright%2Fmcp%40latest%22%5D%2C%22cwd%22%3A%22%24%7BworkspaceFolder%7D%22%7D)

#### Or install manually:

Follow the MCP install [guide](https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/copilot/chat/mcp-servers#_add-an-mcp-server), use the config with `cwd` set to your workspace:

```js
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;
      ],
      &quot;cwd&quot;: &quot;${workspaceFolder}&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

You can also install the Playwright MCP server using the VS Code CLI:

```bash
# For VS Code
code --add-mcp &#039;{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;playwright&quot;,&quot;command&quot;:&quot;npx&quot;,&quot;args&quot;:[&quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;],&quot;cwd&quot;:&quot;${workspaceFolder}&quot;}&#039;
```

After installation, the Playwright MCP server will be available for use with your GitHub Copilot agent in VS Code.
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Windsurf&lt;/summary&gt;

Follow Windsurf MCP [documentation](https://docs.windsurf.com/windsurf/cascade/mcp). Use the standard config above.

&lt;/details&gt;

### Configuration

Playwright MCP server supports following arguments. They can be provided in the JSON configuration above, as a part of the `&quot;args&quot;` list:

&lt;!--- Options generated by update-readme.js --&gt;

```
&gt; npx @playwright/mcp@latest --help
  --allowed-hosts &lt;hosts...&gt;            comma-separated list of hosts this
                                        server is allowed to serve from.
                                        Defaults to the host the server is bound
                                        to.
  --allowed-origins &lt;origins&gt;           semicolon-separated list of origins to
                                        allow the browser to request. Default is
                                        to allow all.
  --blocked-origins &lt;origins&gt;           semicolon-separated list of origins to
                                        block the browser from requesting.
                                        Blocklist is evaluated before allowlist.
                                        If used without the allowlist, requests
                                        not matching the blocklist are still
                                        allowed.
  --block-service-workers               block service workers
  --browser &lt;browser&gt;                   browser or chrome channel to use,
                                        possible values: chrome, firefox,
                                        webkit, msedge.
  --caps &lt;caps&gt;                         comma-separated list of additional
                                        capabilities to enable, possible values:
                                        vision, pdf.
  --cdp-endpoint &lt;endpoint&gt;             CDP endpoint to connect to.
  --cdp-header &lt;headers...&gt;             CDP headers to send with the connect
                                        request, multiple can be specified.
  --config &lt;path&gt;                       path to the configuration file.
  --device &lt;device&gt;                     device to emulate, for example: &quot;iPhone
                                        15&quot;
  --executable-path &lt;path&gt;              path to the browser executable.
  --extension                           Connect to a running browser instance
                                        (Edge/Chrome only). Requires the
                                        &quot;Playwright MCP Bridge&quot; browser
                                        extension to be installed.
  --grant-permissions &lt;permissions...&gt;  List of permissions to grant to the
                                        browser context, for example
                                        &quot;geolocation&quot;, &quot;clipboard-read&quot;,
                                        &quot;clipboard-write&quot;.
  --headless                            run browser in headless mode, headed by
                                        default
  --host &lt;host&gt;                         host to bind server to. Default is
                                        localhost. Use 0.0.0.0 to bind to all
                                        interfaces.
  --ignore-https-errors                 ignore https errors
  --init-script &lt;path...&gt;               path to JavaScript file to add as an
                                        initialization script. The script will
                                        be evaluated in every page before any of
                                        the page&#039;s scripts. Can be specified
                                        multiple times.
  --isolated                            keep the browser profile in memory, do
                                        not save it to disk.
  --image-responses &lt;mode&gt;              whether to send image responses to the
                                        client. Can be &quot;allow&quot; or &quot;omit&quot;,
                                        Defaults to &quot;allow&quot;.
  --no-sandbox                          disable the sandbox for all process
                                        types that are normally sandboxed.
  --output-dir &lt;path&gt;                   path to the directory for output files.
  --port &lt;port&gt;                         port to listen on for SSE transport.
  --proxy-bypass &lt;bypass&gt;               comma-separated domains to bypass proxy,
                                        for example
                                        &quot;.com,chromium.org,.domain.com&quot;
  --proxy-server &lt;proxy&gt;                specify proxy server, for example
                                        &quot;http://myproxy:3128&quot; or
                                        &quot;socks5://myproxy:8080&quot;
  --save-session                        Whether to save the Playwright MCP
                                        session into the output directory.
  --save-trace                          Whether to save the Playwright Trace of
                                        the session into the output directory.
  --save-video &lt;size&gt;                   Whether to save the video of the session
                                        into the output directory. For example
                                        &quot;--save-video=800x600&quot;
  --secrets &lt;path&gt;                      path to a file containing secrets in the
                                        dotenv format
  --shared-browser-context              reuse the same browser context between
                                        all connected HTTP clients.
  --storage-state &lt;path&gt;                path to the storage state file for
                                        isolated sessions.
  --timeout-action &lt;timeout&gt;            specify action timeout in milliseconds,
                                        defaults to 5000ms
  --timeout-navigation &lt;timeout&gt;        specify navigation timeout in
                                        milliseconds, defaults to 60000ms
  --user-agent &lt;ua string&gt;              specify user agent string
  --user-data-dir &lt;path&gt;                path to the user data directory. If not
                                        specified, a temporary directory will be
                                        created.
  --viewport-size &lt;size&gt;                specify browser viewport size in pixels,
                                        for example &quot;1280x720&quot;
```

&lt;!--- End of options generated section --&gt;

### User profile

You can run Playwright MCP with persistent profile like a regular browser (default), in isolated contexts for testing sessions, or connect to your existing browser using the browser extension.

**Persistent profile**

All the logged in information will be stored in the persistent profile, you can delete it between sessions if you&#039;d like to clear the offline state.
Persistent profile is located at the following locations and you can override it with the `--user-data-dir` argument.

```bash
# Windows
%USERPROFILE%\AppData\Local\ms-playwright\mcp-{channel}-profile

# macOS
- ~/Library/Caches/ms-playwright/mcp-{channel}-profile

# Linux
- ~/.cache/ms-playwright/mcp-{channel}-profile
```

**Isolated**

In the isolated mode, each session is started in the isolated profile. Every time you ask MCP to close the browser,
the session is closed and all the storage state for this session is lost. You can provide initial storage state
to the browser via the config&#039;s `contextOptions` or via the `--storage-state` argument. Learn more about the storage
state [here](https://playwright.dev/docs/auth).

```js
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;npx&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [
        &quot;@playwright/mcp@latest&quot;,
        &quot;--isolated&quot;,
        &quot;--storage-state={path/to/storage.json}&quot;
      ]
    }
  }
}
```

**Browser Extension**

The Playwright MCP Chrome Extension allows you to connect to existing browser tabs and leverage your logged-in sessions and browser state. See [extension/README.md](extension/README.md) for installation and setup instructions.

### Configuration file

The Playwright MCP server can be configured using a JSON configuration file. You can specify the configuration file
using the `--config` command line option:

```bash
npx @playwright/mcp@latest --config path/to/config.json
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Configuration file schema&lt;/summary&gt;

```typescript
{
  // Browser configuration
  browser?: {
    // Browser type to use (chromium, firefox, or webkit)
    browserName?: &#039;chromium&#039; | &#039;firefox&#039; | &#039;webkit&#039;;

    // Keep the browser profile in memory, do not save it to disk.
    isolated?: boolean;

    // Path to user data directory for browser profile persistence
    userDataDir?: string;

    // Browser launch options (see Playwright docs)
    // @see https://playwright.dev/docs/api/class-browsertype#browser-type-launch
    launchOptions?: {
      channel?: string;        // Browser channel (e.g. &#039;chrome&#039;)
      headless?: boolean;      // Run in headless mode
      executablePath?: string; // Path to browser executable
      // ... other Playwright launch options
    };

    // Browser context options
    // @see https://playwright.dev/docs/api/class-browser#browser-new-context
    contextOptions?: {
      viewport?: { width: number, height: number };
      // ... other Playwright context options
    };

    // CDP endpoint for connecting to existing browser
    cdpEndpoint?: string;

    // Remote Playwright server endpoint
    remoteEndpoint?: string;
  },

  // Server configuration
  server?: {
    port?: number;  // Port to listen on
    host?: string;  // Host to bind to (default: localhost)
  },

  // List of additional capabilities
  capabilities?: Array&lt;
    &#039;tabs&#039; |    // Tab management
    &#039;install&#039; | // Browser installation
    &#039;pdf&#039; |     // PDF generation
    &#039;vision&#039; |  // Coordinate-based interactions
  &gt;;

  // Directory for output files
  outputDir?: string;

  // Network configuration
  network?: {
    // List of origins to allow the browser to request. Default is to allow all. Origins matching both `allowedOrigins` and `blockedOrigins` will be blocked.
    allowedOrigins?: string[];

    // List of origins to block the browser to request. Origins matching both `allowedOrigins` and `blockedOrigins` will be blocked.
    blockedOrigins?: string[];
  };
 
  /**
   * Whether to send image responses to the client. Can be &quot;allow&quot; or &quot;omit&quot;. 
   * Defaults to &quot;allow&quot;.
   */
  imageResponses?: &#039;allow&#039; | &#039;omit&#039;;
}
```
&lt;/details&gt;

### Standalone MCP server

When running headed browser on system w/o display or from worker processes of the IDEs,
run the MCP server from environment with the DISPLAY and pass the `--port` flag to enable HTTP transport.

```bash
npx @playwright/mcp@latest --port 8931
```

And then in MCP client config, set the `url` to the HTTP endpoint:

```js
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;http://localhost:8931/mcp&quot;
    }
  }
}
```

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Docker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

**NOTE:** The Docker implementation only supports headless chromium at the moment.

```js
{
  &quot;mcpServers&quot;: {
    &quot;playwright&quot;: {
      &quot;command&quot;: &quot;docker&quot;,
      &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;run&quot;, &quot;-i&quot;, &quot;--rm&quot;, &quot;--init&quot;, &quot;--pull=always&quot;, &quot;mcr.microsoft.com/playwright/mcp&quot;]
    }
  }
}
```

Or If you prefer to run the container as a long-lived service instead of letting the MCP client spawn it, use:

```
docker run -d -i --rm --init --pull=always \
  --entrypoint node \
  --name playwright \
  -p 8931:8931 \
  mcr.microsoft.com/playwright/mcp \
  cli.js --headless --browser chromium --no-sandbox --port 8931
```

The server will listen on host port **8931** and can be reached by any MCP client.  

You can build the Docker image yourself.

```
docker build -t mcr.microsoft.com/playwright/mcp .
```
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Programmatic usage&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

```js
import http from &#039;http&#039;;

import { createConnection } from &#039;@playwright/mcp&#039;;
import { SSEServerTransport } from &#039;@modelcontextprotocol/sdk/server/sse.js&#039;;

http.createServer(async (req, res) =&gt; {
  // ...

  // Creates a headless Playwright MCP server with SSE transport
  const connection = await createConnection({ browser: { launchOptions: { headless: true } } });
  const transport = new SSEServerTransport(&#039;/messages&#039;, res);
  await connection.connect(transport);

  // ...
});
```
&lt;/details&gt;

### Tools

&lt;!--- Tools generated by update-readme.js --&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Core automation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;

&lt;!-- NOTE: This has been generated via update-readme.js --&gt;

- **browser_click**
  - Title: Click
  - Description: Perform click on a web page
  - Parameters:
    - `element` (string): Human-readable element description used to obtain permission to interact with the element
    - `ref` (string): Exact target element reference from the page snapshot
    - `doubleClick` (boolean, optional): Whether to perform a double click instead of a single click
    - `button` (string, optional): Button to click, defaults to left
    - `modifiers` (array, optional): Modifier keys to press
  - Read-only: **false**

&lt;!-- NOTE: This has been generated via update-readme.js --&gt;

- **browser_close**
  - Title: Close browser
  - Description: Close the page
  - Parameters: None
  - Read-only: **true**

&lt;!-- NOTE: This has been generated via update-readme.js --&gt;

- **browser_console_messages**
  - Title: Get console messages
  - Description: Returns all console messages
  - Parameters: None
  - Read-only: **true**

&lt;!-- NOTE: This has been generated via update-r

... [README content truncated due to size. Visit the repository for the complete README] ...</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[idosal/mcp-ui]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/idosal/mcp-ui</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/idosal/mcp-ui</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[SDK for UI over MCP. Create next-gen UI experiences!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/idosal/mcp-ui">idosal/mcp-ui</a></h1>
            <p>SDK for UI over MCP. Create next-gen UI experiences!</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 2,389</p>
            <p>Forks: 160</p>
            <p>Stars today: 18 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>## 📦 Model Context Protocol UI SDK

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;250&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/65b9698f-990f-4846-9b2d-88de91d53d4d&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mcp-ui/server&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@mcp-ui/server?label=server&amp;color=green&quot; alt=&quot;Server Version&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@mcp-ui/client&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@mcp-ui/client?label=client&amp;color=blue&quot; alt=&quot;Client Version&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/gems/mcp_ui_server&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/gem/v/mcp_ui_server&quot; alt=&quot;Ruby Server SDK Version&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/mcp-ui-server/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/mcp-ui-server?label=python&amp;color=yellow&quot; alt=&quot;Python Server SDK Version&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/CEAG4KW7ZH&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/discord/1401195140436983879?logo=discord&amp;label=discord&quot; alt=&quot;Discord&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitmcp.io/idosal/mcp-ui&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/endpoint?url=https://gitmcp.io/badge/idosal/mcp-ui&quot; alt=&quot;MCP Documentation&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-whats-mcp-ui&quot;&gt;What&#039;s mcp-ui?&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-core-concepts&quot;&gt;Core Concepts&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-walkthrough&quot;&gt;Walkthrough&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-supported-hosts&quot;&gt;Supported Hosts&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-roadmap&quot;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-contributing&quot;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; •
  &lt;a href=&quot;#-license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

----

**`mcp-ui`** brings interactive web components to the [Model Context Protocol](https://modelcontextprotocol.io/introduction) (MCP). Deliver rich, dynamic UI resources directly from your MCP server to be rendered by the client. Take AI interaction to the next level!

&gt; *This project is an experimental community playground for MCP UI ideas. Expect rapid iteration and enhancements!*

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;video src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7180c822-2dd9-4f38-9d3e-b67679509483&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

## 💡 What&#039;s `mcp-ui`?

`mcp-ui` is a collection of SDKs comprising:

* **`@mcp-ui/server` (TypeScript)**: Utilities to generate UI resources (`UIResource`) on your MCP server.
* **`@mcp-ui/client` (TypeScript)**: UI components (e.g., `&lt;UIResourceRenderer /&gt;`) to render the UI resources and handle their events.
* **`mcp_ui_server` (Ruby)**: Utilities to generate UI resources on your MCP server in a Ruby environment.
* **`mcp-ui-server` (Python)**: Utilities to generate UI resources on your MCP server in a Python environment.

Together, they let you define reusable UI snippets on the server side, seamlessly and securely render them in the client, and react to their actions in the MCP host environment.

## ✨ Core Concepts

In essence, by using `mcp-ui` SDKs, servers and hosts can agree on contracts that enable them to create and render interactive UI snippets (as a path to a standardized UI approach in MCP).

### UI Resource
The primary payload returned from the server to the client is the `UIResource`:

```ts
interface UIResource {
  type: &#039;resource&#039;;
  resource: {
    uri: string;       // e.g., ui://component/id
    mimeType: &#039;text/html&#039; | &#039;text/uri-list&#039; | &#039;application/vnd.mcp-ui.remote-dom&#039;; // text/html for HTML content, text/uri-list for URL content, application/vnd.mcp-ui.remote-dom for remote-dom content (Javascript)
    text?: string;      // Inline HTML, external URL, or remote-dom script
    blob?: string;      // Base64-encoded HTML, URL, or remote-dom script
  };
}
```

* **`uri`**: Unique identifier for caching and routing
  * `ui://…` — UI resources (rendering method determined by mimeType)
* **`mimeType`**: `text/html` for HTML content (iframe srcDoc), `text/uri-list` for URL content (iframe src), `application/vnd.mcp-ui.remote-dom` for remote-dom content (Javascript)
  * **MCP-UI requires a single URL**: While `text/uri-list` format supports multiple URLs, MCP-UI uses only the first valid `http/s` URL and warns if additional URLs are found
* **`text` vs. `blob`**: Choose `text` for simple strings; use `blob` for larger or encoded content.

### Resource Renderer

The UI Resource is rendered in the `&lt;UIResourceRenderer /&gt;` component. It automatically detects the resource type and renders the appropriate component.

It is available as a React component and as a Web Component.

**React Component**

It accepts the following props:
- **`resource`**: The resource object from an MCP Tool response. It must include `uri`, `mimeType`, and content (`text`, `blob`)
- **`onUIAction`**: Optional callback for handling UI actions from the resource:
  ```typescript
  { type: &#039;tool&#039;, payload: { toolName: string, params: Record&lt;string, unknown&gt; }, messageId?: string } |
  { type: &#039;intent&#039;, payload: { intent: string, params: Record&lt;string, unknown&gt; }, messageId?: string } |
  { type: &#039;prompt&#039;, payload: { prompt: string }, messageId?: string } |
  { type: &#039;notify&#039;, payload: { message: string }, messageId?: string } |
  { type: &#039;link&#039;, payload: { url: string }, messageId?: string }
  ```
  When actions include a `messageId`, the iframe automatically receives response messages for asynchronous handling.
- **`supportedContentTypes`**: Optional array to restrict which content types are allowed (`[&#039;rawHtml&#039;, &#039;externalUrl&#039;, &#039;remoteDom&#039;]`)
- **`htmlProps`**: Optional props for the internal `&lt;HTMLResourceRenderer&gt;`
  - **`style`**: Optional custom styles for the iframe
  - **`iframeProps`**: Optional props passed to the iframe element
  - **`iframeRenderData`**: Optional `Record&lt;string, unknown&gt;` to pass data to the iframe upon rendering. This enables advanced use cases where the parent application needs to provide initial state or configuration to the sandboxed iframe content.
  - **`autoResizeIframe`**: Optional `boolean | { width?: boolean; height?: boolean }` to automatically resize the iframe to the size of the content.
- **`remoteDomProps`**: Optional props for the internal `&lt;RemoteDOMResourceRenderer&gt;`
  - **`library`**: Optional component library for Remote DOM resources (defaults to `basicComponentLibrary`)
  - **`remoteElements`**: remote element definitions for Remote DOM resources.

**Web Component**

The Web Component is available as `&lt;ui-resource-renderer&gt;`. It accepts the same props as the React component, but they must be passed as strings.

Example:
```html
&lt;ui-resource-renderer
  resource=&#039;{ &quot;mimeType&quot;: &quot;text/html&quot;, &quot;text&quot;: &quot;&lt;h2&gt;Hello from the Web Component!&lt;/h2&gt;&quot; }&#039;
&gt;&lt;/ui-resource-renderer&gt;
```

The `onUIAction` prop can be handled by attaching an event listener to the component:
```javascript
const renderer = document.querySelector(&#039;ui-resource-renderer&#039;);
renderer.addEventListener(&#039;onUIAction&#039;, (event) =&gt; {
  console.log(&#039;Action:&#039;, event.detail);
});
```

The Web Component is available in the `@mcp-ui/client` package at `dist/ui-resource-renderer.wc.js`.

### Supported Resource Types

#### HTML (`text/html` and `text/uri-list`)

Rendered using the internal `&lt;HTMLResourceRenderer /&gt;` component, which displays content inside an `&lt;iframe&gt;`. This is suitable for self-contained HTML or embedding external apps.

*   **`mimeType`**:
    *   `text/html`: Renders inline HTML content.
    *   `text/uri-list`: Renders an external URL. MCP-UI uses the first valid `http/s` URL.

#### Remote DOM (`application/vnd.mcp-ui.remote-dom`)

Rendered using the internal `&lt;RemoteDOMResourceRenderer /&gt;` component, which utilizes Shopify&#039;s [`remote-dom`](https://github.com/Shopify/remote-dom). The server responds with a script that describes the UI and events. On the host, the script is securely rendered in a sandboxed iframe, and the UI changes are communicated to the host in JSON, where they&#039;re rendered using the host&#039;s component library. This is more flexible than iframes and allows for UIs that match the host&#039;s look-and-feel.

* **`mimeType`**: `application/vnd.mcp-ui.remote-dom+javascript; framework={react | webcomponents}`

### UI Action

UI snippets must be able to interact with the agent. In `mcp-ui`, this is done by hooking into events sent from the UI snippet and reacting to them in the host (see `onUIAction` prop). For example, an HTML may trigger a tool call when a button is clicked by sending an event which will be caught handled by the client.

## 🏗️ Installation

### TypeScript

```bash
# using npm
npm install @mcp-ui/server @mcp-ui/client

# or pnpm
pnpm add @mcp-ui/server @mcp-ui/client

# or yarn
yarn add @mcp-ui/server @mcp-ui/client
```

### Ruby

```bash
gem install mcp_ui_server
```

### Python

```bash
# using pip
pip install mcp-ui-server

# or uv
uv add mcp-ui-server
```

## 🚀 Getting Started

You can use [GitMCP](https://gitmcp.io/idosal/mcp-ui) to give your IDE access to `mcp-ui`&#039;s latest documentation! 

### TypeScript

1. **Server-side**: Build your UI resources

   ```ts
   import { createUIResource } from &#039;@mcp-ui/server&#039;;
   import {
    createRemoteComponent,
    createRemoteDocument,
    createRemoteText,
   } from &#039;@remote-dom/core&#039;;

   // Inline HTML
   const htmlResource = createUIResource({
     uri: &#039;ui://greeting/1&#039;,
     content: { type: &#039;rawHtml&#039;, htmlString: &#039;&lt;p&gt;Hello, MCP UI!&lt;/p&gt;&#039; },
     encoding: &#039;text&#039;,
   });

   // External URL
   const externalUrlResource = createUIResource({
     uri: &#039;ui://greeting/1&#039;,
     content: { type: &#039;externalUrl&#039;, iframeUrl: &#039;https://example.com&#039; },
     encoding: &#039;text&#039;,
   });

   // remote-dom
   const remoteDomResource = createUIResource({
     uri: &#039;ui://remote-component/action-button&#039;,
     content: {
       type: &#039;remoteDom&#039;,
       script: `
        const button = document.createElement(&#039;ui-button&#039;);
        button.setAttribute(&#039;label&#039;, &#039;Click me for a tool call!&#039;);
        button.addEventListener(&#039;press&#039;, () =&gt; {
          window.parent.postMessage({ type: &#039;tool&#039;, payload: { toolName: &#039;uiInteraction&#039;, params: { action: &#039;button-click&#039;, from: &#039;remote-dom&#039; } } }, &#039;*&#039;);
        });
        root.appendChild(button);
        `,
       framework: &#039;react&#039;, // or &#039;webcomponents&#039;
     },
     encoding: &#039;text&#039;,
   });
   ```

2. **Client-side**: Render in your MCP host

   ```tsx
   import React from &#039;react&#039;;
   import { UIResourceRenderer } from &#039;@mcp-ui/client&#039;;

   function App({ mcpResource }) {
     if (
       mcpResource.type === &#039;resource&#039; &amp;&amp;
       mcpResource.resource.uri?.startsWith(&#039;ui://&#039;)
     ) {
       return (
         &lt;UIResourceRenderer
           resource={mcpResource.resource}
           onUIAction={(result) =&gt; {
             console.log(&#039;Action:&#039;, result);
           }}
         /&gt;
       );
     }
     return &lt;p&gt;Unsupported resource&lt;/p&gt;;
   }
   ```

### Python

**Server-side**: Build your UI resources

   ```python
   from mcp_ui_server import create_ui_resource

   # Inline HTML
   html_resource = create_ui_resource({
     &quot;uri&quot;: &quot;ui://greeting/1&quot;,
     &quot;content&quot;: { &quot;type&quot;: &quot;rawHtml&quot;, &quot;htmlString&quot;: &quot;&lt;p&gt;Hello, from Python!&lt;/p&gt;&quot; },
     &quot;encoding&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
   })

   # External URL
   external_url_resource = create_ui_resource({
     &quot;uri&quot;: &quot;ui://greeting/2&quot;,
     &quot;content&quot;: { &quot;type&quot;: &quot;externalUrl&quot;, &quot;iframeUrl&quot;: &quot;https://example.com&quot; },
     &quot;encoding&quot;: &quot;text&quot;,
   })
   ```

### Ruby

**Server-side**: Build your UI resources

   ```ruby
   require &#039;mcp_ui_server&#039;

   # Inline HTML
   html_resource = McpUiServer.create_ui_resource(
     uri: &#039;ui://greeting/1&#039;,
     content: { type: :raw_html, htmlString: &#039;&lt;p&gt;Hello, from Ruby!&lt;/p&gt;&#039; },
     encoding: :text
   )

   # External URL
   external_url_resource = McpUiServer.create_ui_resource(
     uri: &#039;ui://greeting/2&#039;,
     content: { type: :external_url, iframeUrl: &#039;https://example.com&#039; },
     encoding: :text
   )

   # remote-dom
   remote_dom_resource = McpUiServer.create_ui_resource(
     uri: &#039;ui://remote-component/action-button&#039;,
     content: {
       type: :remote_dom,
       script: &quot;
        const button = document.createElement(&#039;ui-button&#039;);
        button.setAttribute(&#039;label&#039;, &#039;Click me from Ruby!&#039;);
        button.addEventListener(&#039;press&#039;, () =&gt; {
          window.parent.postMessage({ type: &#039;tool&#039;, payload: { toolName: &#039;uiInteraction&#039;, params: { action: &#039;button-click&#039;, from: &#039;ruby-remote-dom&#039; } } }, &#039;*&#039;);
        });
        root.appendChild(button);
        &quot;,
       framework: :react,
     },
     encoding: :text
   )
   ```

## 🚶 Walkthrough

For a detailed, simple, step-by-step guide on how to integrate `mcp-ui` into your own server, check out the full server walkthroughs on the [mcp-ui documentation site](https://mcpui.dev):

- **[TypeScript Server Walkthrough](https://mcpui.dev/guide/server/typescript/walkthrough)**
- **[Ruby Server Walkthrough](https://mcpui.dev/guide/server/ruby/walkthrough)**
- **[Python Server Walkthrough](https://mcpui.dev/guide/server/python/walkthrough)**

These guides will show you how to add a `mcp-ui` endpoint to an existing server, create tools that return UI resources, and test your setup with the `ui-inspector`!

## 🌍 Examples

**Client Examples**
* [Goose](https://github.com/block/goose) - open source AI agent that supports `mcp-ui`.
* [LibreChat](https://github.com/danny-avila/LibreChat) - enhanced ChatGPT clone that supports `mcp-ui`.
* [ui-inspector](https://github.com/idosal/ui-inspector) - inspect local `mcp-ui`-enabled servers.
* [MCP-UI Chat](https://github.com/idosal/scira-mcp-ui-chat) - interactive chat built with the `mcp-ui` client. Check out the [hosted version](https://scira-mcp-chat-git-main-idosals-projects.vercel.app/)!
* MCP-UI RemoteDOM Playground (`examples/remote-dom-demo`) - local demo app to test RemoteDOM resources
* MCP-UI Web Component Demo (`examples/wc-demo`) - local demo app to test the Web Component integration in hosts

**Server Examples**
* **TypeScript**: A [full-featured server](examples/server) that is deployed to a hosted environment for easy testing.
  * **[`typescript-server-demo`](./examples/typescript-server-demo)**: A simple Typescript server that demonstrates how to generate UI resources.
  * **server**: A [full-featured Typescript server](examples/server) that is deployed to a hosted Cloudflare environment for easy testing.
    * **HTTP Streaming**: `https://remote-mcp-server-authless.idosalomon.workers.dev/mcp`
    * **SSE**: `https://remote-mcp-server-authless.idosalomon.workers.dev/sse`
* **Ruby**: A barebones [demo server](/examples/ruby-server-demo) that shows how to use `mcp_ui_server` and `mcp` gems together.
* **Python**: A simple [demo server](/examples/python-server-demo) that shows how to use the `mcp-ui-server` Python package.
* [XMCP](https://github.com/basementstudio/xmcp/tree/main/examples/mcp-ui) - Typescript MCP framework with `mcp-ui` starter example.

Drop those URLs into any MCP-compatible host to see `mcp-ui` in action. For a supported local inspector, see the [ui-inspector](https://github.com/idosal/ui-inspector).

## 💻 Supported Hosts

`mcp-ui` is supported by a growing number of MCP-compatible clients. Feature support varies by host:

| Host      | Rendering | UI Actions |
| :-------- | :-------: | :--------: |
| [Postman](https://www.postman.com/)   |     ✅    |     ⚠️      |
| [Goose](https://block.github.io/goose/)     |     ✅    |     ⚠️      |
| [LibreChat](https://www.librechat.ai/)    |     ✅    |     ⚠️     |
| [Smithery](https://smithery.ai/playground)  |     ✅    |     ❌     |
| [MCPJam](https://www.mcpjam.com/)    |     ✅    |     ❌     |
| [fast-agent](https://fast-agent.ai/mcp/mcp-ui/) | ✅ | ❌ |
| [VSCode](https://github.com/microsoft/vscode/issues/260218) (TBA)    |    ?    |    ?     |

**Legend:**
- ✅: Supported
- ⚠️: Partial Support
- ❌: Not Supported (yet)

## 🔒 Security
Host and user security is one of `mcp-ui`&#039;s primary concerns. In all content types, the remote code is executed in a sandboxed iframe.

## 🛣️ Roadmap

- [X] Add online playground
- [X] Expand UI Action API (beyond tool calls)
- [X] Support Web Components
- [X] Support Remote-DOM
- [ ] Add component libraries (in progress)
- [ ] Add SDKs for additional programming languages (in progress; Ruby, Python available)
- [ ] Support additional frontend frameworks
- [ ] Add declarative UI content type
- [ ] Support generative UI?
      
## Core Team
`mcp-ui` is a project by [Ido Salomon](https://x.com/idosal1), in collaboration with [Liad Yosef](https://x.com/liadyosef).

## 🤝 Contributing

Contributions, ideas, and bug reports are welcome! See the [contribution guidelines](https://github.com/idosal/mcp-ui/blob/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md) to get started.

## 📄 License

Apache License 2.0 © [The MCP-UI Authors](LICENSE)

## Disclaimer

This project is provided &quot;as is&quot;, without warranty of any kind. The `mcp-ui` authors and contributors shall not be held liable for any damages, losses, or issues arising from the use of this software. Use at your own risk.
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[netless-io/flat]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/netless-io/flat</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/netless-io/flat</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:04:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Project flat is the Web, Windows and macOS client of Agora Flat open source classroom.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[
            <h1><a href="https://github.com/netless-io/flat">netless-io/flat</a></h1>
            <p>Project flat is the Web, Windows and macOS client of Agora Flat open source classroom.</p>
            <p>Language: TypeScript</p>
            <p>Stars: 6,245</p>
            <p>Forks: 855</p>
            <p>Stars today: 44 stars today</p>
            <h2>README</h2><pre>&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;92&quot; height=&quot;92&quot; style=&quot;display: block;&quot; src=&quot;./assets/flat-logo.svg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/netless-io/flat?color=9cf&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub repo size&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/repo-size/netless-io/flat?color=9cf&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub commit activity&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/netless-io/flat?color=9cf&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/netless-io/flat/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22good+first+issue%22&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub issues by-label&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/netless-io/flat/good%20first%20issue?color=9cf&amp;label=good%20first%20issue&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AgoraFlat&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Twitter URL&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Twitter-AgoraFlat-9cf.svg?logo=twitter&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/netless-io/flat/issues/926&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img alt=&quot;Slack URL&quot; src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Slack-AgoraFlat-9cf.svg?logo=slack&amp;style=flat-square&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Agora Flat&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Project flat is the Web, Windows and macOS client of &lt;a href=&quot;https://flat.agora.io/&quot;&gt;Agora Flat&lt;/a&gt; open source classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./docs/readme/README-zh.md&quot;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;./assets/flat-showcase-en.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

## Features

-   Real-time interaction
    -   Multifunctional interactive whiteboard
    -   Real-time video/audio chat (RTC)
    -   Real-time messaging (RTM)
-   Login via
    -   GitHub
    -   WeChat
-   Classroom management
    -   Join, create and schedule classrooms
    -   Support periodic rooms
-   Classroom recording and replaying
    -   Whiteboard replaying
    -   Cloud recording for video and audio
    -   Messaging replaying
-   Cloud Storage for multi-media courseware
-   Screen sharing

## Quickstart

You can build and run the Flat client without a server. This repository includes the following projects:

-   [Flat Electron client](./desktop) is an Electron implementation of Flat client.
-   [Flat Web client](./web) is a web implementation of Flat client.

### Installation

&gt; If you don&#039;t have pnpm installed:
&gt;
&gt; ```bash
&gt; npm i -g pnpm
&gt; ```

Clone or fork this project, at project root run:

```bash
pnpm i
```

### Build and run Flat Electron client

Run the following commands at the root of the repository to build and run Flat Electron client.

```shell
pnpm start
```

You can use one of the following methods to package your executable:

-   Run `pnpm ship` at project root to package based on current system.
-   Alternatively, run `pnpm ship:mac` or `pnpm ship:win` at project root to package for a specified system.

### Build and run Flat Web client

Run the following command at the root of the repository to build and run Flat web client.

```shell
pnpm start:web
```

Alternatively, run the following command:

```shell
cd ./web/flat-web/ &amp;&amp; pnpm start
```

UI and business logic are separated in Flat. You can view and develop Flat components UI via Storybook. You can either visit the ([Online address][flat-storybook]) or run `pnpm storybook` at the root of the repository to run Storybook locally.

## References

-   [Release Version Description](docs/releases)
-   [Environment Variables Reference](docs/env/README.md)
-   [Debugging Flat](docs/debugging/README.md)

## Related Projects

-   [Flat Android client][flat-android]
-   [Flat Server][flat-server]
-   [Flat Website HomePage][flat-homepage]

## Contributing

Writing code is great, but there are many other ways to make meaningful contributions to the project:

-   [Improve documentation](CONTRIBUTING.md#improve-documentation)
-   [Improve issues](CONTRIBUTING.md#improve-issues)
-   [Give feedback on issues](CONTRIBUTING.md#give-feedback-on-issues)

For more info about how to contribute, see [CONTRIBUTING.md](CONTRIBUTING.md)

## Code Contributors

Thank you to all the people who already contributed to Flat!

&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/netless-io/flat/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://opencollective.com/agora-flat/contributors.svg?width=890&amp;button=false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

## Disclaimer

You may use Flat for commercial purposes but please note that we do not accept customizational commercial requirements and deployment supports. Nor do we offer customer supports for commercial usage. Please head to [Flexible Classroom](https://www.agora.io/en/products/flexible-classroom) for such requirements.

## License

Copyright © Agora Corporation. All rights reserved.

Licensed under the [MIT license](LICENSE).

When using the Flat or other GitHub logos, be sure to follow the [GitHub logo guidelines][github-logo].

[flat-homepage]: https://flat.agora.io/#download
[flat-web]: https://web.flat.agora.io/
[flat-server]: https://github.com/netless-io/flat-server
[flat-android]: https://github.com/netless-io/flat-android
[flat-storybook]: https://netless-io.github.io/flat/
[github-logo]: https://github.com/logos
</pre>
          ]]></content:encoded>
            <category>TypeScript</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>